I had this badass
professor in med school.
She seemed invincible.
Then one day, she
needed her gallbladder out.
And the surgery killed her.
Her platelets stopped clotting.
She bled out on the table.
Everything that
could've gone wrong...
Did go wrong.
Surgeons have a name for it.
We call it a perfect storm.
Funny.
Never thought it
would happen to me.
Ethan, so they're
moving you and your dad
to a safer hospital
for now, okay, buddy?
Can't you come, too?
They need me here. Okay?
Hang out a minute. We'll
send the gurney back down.
It won't be so loud
once you're inside,
and then it's just...
It's just fun, okay?
I don't know how you can
even pretend this isn't an issue.
Because it's not.
Were you even gonna tell
me you wanted to adopt him?
Well, that didn't happen, so...
But you wanted to.
Owen...
You want kids.
This is about one kid,
this kid who needed...
Okay, but the fact that
you are lying to yourself
doesn't make me feel
better about you lying to me.
I am not lying about
the fact that I love you
and I want my
life to be with you.
You don't think you're
gonna look at me one day
and only see the things
I couldn't give you?
God, has it ever occurred to you
I might know my own
mind better than you?
Oh, my God.
Figures you'd go into labor
in the middle of a super storm.
Okay, we need to go
over your birth plan.
We never talked
details. Hang on.
I can't bully people unless I
know what to bully them about.
Maybe you should get back into
bed. You want to go back to bed?
No! She says no.
What do you need, a
pillow, a bouncy ball?
Ice chips. She says ice chips.
Are you gonna do
this the whole time?
Okay, I'm gonna check on Connie,
see what's taking her so long.
She's with other laboring
moms right now. She's busy.
You're the only one I care
about. The rest can wait.
Did you talk to Owen?
Yes and no.
God, how is your
pain now, seven, eight?
Nine. Talk to me
about Owen. It helps.
Owen is...
At a 10.
This guy was cleaning his
gutters in hurricane-force winds.
It's like he wanted to spend
the night on an OR table.
Not that I'm complaining.
You're awfully excited about
another man's misfortunes.
No, I just meant I'm glad
Dr. Bailey's getting back into an OR.
Yeah, so am I.
I can't do this.
Miranda...
Go back inside.
All right, what is our
risk of flooding here?
You got water pumps.
You got sandbags.
The lights keep flickering.
Now are the generators...
I tested 'em last month.
Listen, you guys got
patients to worry about.
You take care of them.
This hospital's my patient.
These beds are filling up fast.
Yeah, people think this is the
safest place to sit out a storm.
Half these people aren't
even sick. They're just scared.
Yeah. Christian.
Dr. Chaney to ER Triage...
Not used to it yet?
It just feels really weird on my
finger. I keep running it into stuff.
Pin it to your scrub top.
Oh. Cool.
Mmm-hmm.
Chief. Hey, there's
a patient in OR two
who needs an exploratory
lap immediately.
The patient's already under.
Do you have any general
surgeons available?
You look available.
I'm not, sir.
Excuse me.
You're my son's doctor,
Jimmy Strickland?
Is he done with surgery already?
No, sir. We haven't started yet.
Is everything okay?
Everything is fine, sir.
I'll be the doctor
operating on your son.
Will you walk with me, Mr. Strickland,
and fill me in on what happened?
Dr. Simmons to the ER.
I would like to help out,
Chief, however I can.
Well, it makes it hard when
you won't touch a patient.
Actually, I was gonna
suggest that we get someone
to make sure there's enough
surplus blood in the ORs.
Dr. Grant, extension 2-2-7-9.
Yeah. Okay.
Cut her some slack.
What happened to you?
A tree.
Karev, if you're free,
the NICU needs help getting
all these babies out of here.
I thought Arizona
was overseeing this.
Has anyone seen her?
Hey, you okay?
Yeah, no.
The NICU's just understaffed,
and I should be there already.
You need an extra set of hands?
Oh, no. Please, just...
No.
I understand your concerns, Tim,
but we were just told to
evacuate the highest priorities first.
So Crystal's baby gets taken
to safety and mine is stuck here?
It's perfectly safe
here, Tim. Okay?
The pit says we have to suspend
evacuations due to the weather.
Wait. We were just down there.
The last rig to leave couldn't
even make it out of the parking lot.
Okay. Don't worry. Don't worry.
All of our staff is very well trained, and
your babies are in very good hands, okay?
I only see two nurses. No one
else made it in for their shift?
Okay. All right.
This is important.
The makers of tiny
humans get easily spooked.
It is our job tonight to keep
the tiny human makers happy,
or they will mutiny, and
we are outnumbered.
We remain calm.
We remain confident.
Because everything is
just fine. Understood?
You need some help?
Yes. No.
I thought that I told you...
I'm not gonna sit on my hands
while there's a roomful of babies
that need help. What can I do?
You can cross-check the med rec
forms so we can get the correct dosages.
We're outnumbered. Keep the
tiny human makers happy, right?
Well, I didn't expect to
see you again so soon.
Her contractions are
every three minutes.
And she doesn't want drugs.
I have Dr. Knox available in
case she changes her mind.
Look, she doesn't want drugs.
Okay, can everybody
just please shut up?
I want to push. I feel like I
need to push. Can I push?
I just need to check first...
What's going on?
Meredith, I need
you not to push.
Why?
There's face presentation.
I can feel your baby's face.
So we're gonna need
to do a C-section.
A C-section? I do not want
to have surgery. I know.
All right. You know what? It's
just a "C." That's barely surgery.
A moron could do a "C."
I... No offense.
Okay.
Well, don't panic. It's
just a power outage.
We have generators. The
power's gonna go on any second.
Yeah, it's gonna be fine.
Derek?
Yeah, any second.
Okay, stay calm.
Let's get some flashlights,
all the light that you can find.
- Somebody get me a headlamp.
- Right away, doctor.
Dr. Warren, how's the gas?
Good. Backup battery
switched itself on.
His BP is still
dropping, though.
I can't see what the problem is.
Why isn't the echo
on battery power?
There should be a manual
switch. Ross, go look.
I know the generator
should be on.
I'm asking why it's not.
Webber, I'm checking
in. Do you need anything?
Some light would be good.
The emergency lights should
have kicked on. Well, they didn't.
Frank, when the
generator went out in '06,
you said there was
air in the fuel system.
Then you told me that it
would never happen again.
Yes, sir.
Well, then maybe you should get
your ass down there and get lookin'.
I've got a man open on
the table here. Yes, sir.
Hang in there, people.
We're working on it.
That probably helped.
Yelling at the guy.
Yes! I got it!
Damn it. Pericardial effusion.
Page Russell.
I don't believe he made it
in, sir, because of the storm.
Dr. Yang's the senior
cardio surgeon in charge.
Okay, then get Yang.
Can't you just rotate the
baby and push his face away?
It's very risky, for
the baby, for Meredith.
Dr. Yang.
Dr. Webber needs you in OR two.
To do what? I can't
operate in the dark.
No one is operating in the dark.
Okay, just go. I'll be fine.
Okay, happy, come here
and update me as soon
as they've made a decision.
So what are the risks of
repositioning the baby?
Not the minor risks.
The big, ugly, scary risks.
Because I'm a
lightning rod for those.
It's not an option. Why not?
Are you saying babies with face
presentation can't be born naturally?
It's not a good option.
Neither is cutting into
my wife in the dark.
How many babies have you
delivered in your career, Dr. Shepherd?
What, a couple, maybe more?
When I say a vaginal
delivery isn't an option,
I mean, it's not an option.
Now I could stand
here and waste time
explaining how your baby is
in a mento-posterior position
and how pushing a baby like that
will hyperextend its
neck, which can be fatal,
or I can better spend my
time prepping your wife
and baby for a delivery that will
not endanger either of their lives.
So, which do you prefer?
We're having a
C-section in the dark.
Yes. We are.
The vents kicked
on to battery power?
I checked them all
twice. They're working.
All the babies are breathing.
Good.
Listen, uh...
We were talking before the
whole tree thing happened...
It's fine. We... You
can just forget that I...
No sudden moves.
Wilson, don't turn around.
Karev, can you discreetly
check out that monitor behind me,
the one for Crystal's baby
vent? Do you see that red light?
Yes. That's the
low-battery light, right?
Oh, crap. Keep smiling.
Okay, Wilson, will you go
check the drawer over there
where we keep the spare
batteries? Tell me what you see.
Slowly and casually.
No batteries.
Okay.
Okay. No one panics.
I am going to look for spare batteries
while you all act like nothing's wrong.
Understand me? Nothing's wrong.
Something's wrong?
No.
Blood's here.
Thank you, nurse.
I'm sorry, Bailey. I
thought you were...
I'm just trying to do
what I can to help out.
Four units AB neg.
I yelled at her.
I thought it would work,
that tough love is what she
needed to get her back inside the OR.
I joined in as an
anesthesiologist on this surgery
because I thought that
would get her back in this OR.
My way didn't work either.
There's blood in
there, exiting the heart.
I can't find out where
unless I open him up.
And I'm not opening
his chest with no light.
I am not operating
on people in the dark.
Sir, I cannot operate
under these conditions.
Didn't we just teach the Syrians
how to operate under these conditions?
I'm not in Syria. Yang!
This is James Strickland. He's got a
wife, Carol, and four kids back in Arizona.
James' dad is 80 and alone since
James' mom died on Christmas.
And he's far too stubborn
to move into assisted living,
which is why James found
himself on his father's roof
trying to clean out his
gutter when the storm hit.
He was just trying to
take care of his dad.
He's a good man.
And he will die on this table
if you don't operate, Yang.
While we stand around
and watch, this man will die.
I'll scrub in.
You two own the hospital.
Can I request that ORs be stocked with
more than one flashlight in the future?
You get this baby
out of me safely,
and you can have
whatever you want.
What about William?
I like Sebastian.
Sebastian Shepherd?
That's a bit of a mouthful.
Brooks?
I'm not giving birth
to a country singer.
No, It's... I see
Heather. Brooks.
Dude, you're operating
in the dark on your wife?
Yeah.
Chief Hunt asked
me to go to the ORs
and let them know that the guy is
trying to fix the emergency lights.
We could use a
hand with these lights.
Okay, here we go.
Wait. I'm scared.
There is nothing to be
scared of. We can do this.
Everything will be fine.
Okay?
Don't mess this up.
Sit down, please, so I can work.
Okay, let's go. Ross, light.
A couple of people have
asked for two blankets.
One per person. That's it.
Matthew, what
are you doing here?
My rig stalled out in the river
that used to be Pike Street.
I walked the rest of the
way here. How can I help?
Grab some blankets. Okay.
Okay, now ordinarily, I'd discharge
you, but for now, this is home, all right?
Torres, blood's been distributed.
Anything else I can do?
You hear that noise?
Oh, my God!
It flipped right over.
Oh, my God. MAN 2: Oh, man.
- What happened?
- I don't know. I just...
Oh, my God. Fire!
Oh, my God. MAN 4:
The bus caught on fire!
Hurry! Hurry!
I smell gas.
There's a fuel leak somewhere.
We were coming from the
church, trying to wait out the storm.
Careful. The roof,
it caved in on us.
We didn't know where else to go.
We've got to get everyone
away from this fire.
Easy. Easy.
All right, if you can walk,
let's get you inside! This way!
We're gonna need to setup
an emergency triage inside.
We're gonna need meds.
Bailey, can you handle this?
Yeah. Murphy!
We gotta move, Hunt.
This thing's gonna blow.
Avery, hurry up!
I got one more.
She's jammed between two
seats. Help me get her out.
This is not how I
wanted to do this.
Well, you once said
that about marrying me.
Look how that turned out.
I love you.
And your baby is out.
What do you see?
I don't know. It's too dark.
I don't hear him crying.
Why isn't he crying?
Somebody talk to me.
I don't hear him crying.
All right.
Here you go.
Look at that.
He's perfect.
He's just perfect.
Derek?
His breathing is
shallow. His sats are low.
Why are his sats low?
Well, in the dark like
this, it's hard to be sure.
But it's not uncommon,
especially in babies like
these that come out early.
We'll get him to the NICU and
make sure everything checks out.
Derek, go with him. Do not
leave his side for a second.
Do you hear me? Okay.
Okay, guys, don't
leave her side.
Make sure she's okay.
You understand me?
Got it, boss. Yes, sir.
Another battery light
just went on in there.
Any luck? No.
No one thought
about spare batteries.
And pretty soon, all those
machines are gonna die out there,
and then all those
babies are gonna die,
and all because I didn't think
ahead to stockpile batteries.
And also, I cheated
on my wife with that...
Woman out there, and
I'm a horrible person.
I'm horrible.
Hey.
I'm in love with that intern
out there, but I won't tell her.
And I keep saying to
myself I won't tell her
because everyone I
love turns out to be crazy
or mean or cancer-y or leaves.
But the thing all those
women have in common is me.
They were all fine
before they met me.
I'm damaged goods or something.
So you're not the worst
person in this closet.
There are no batteries in here.
What the hell are we gonna do?
I have no idea.
Okay, we need antibiotics,
anti-inflammatories,
and pain meds,
lots of pain meds.
I've never heard
screams like that before.
Oh, no. It's dead.
There's no way for me to...
Punch in my code.
How are we supposed
to get meds if...
Come on. Open.
He looked good,
right? That cry was loud.
And he looked good.
You saw him, right?
I guess so. I didn't
get a good look.
Say good things.
When you don't
have the information
and you're talking to
the mother of a newborn,
you say good things.
'Cause nine out of 10 times,
that's what's going to happen...
The good things.
What are you teaching
these guys anyway, Dr. Grey?
I know, right?
Dr. Ryan, it's an emergency.
I've got a mom with
a placental abruption.
Okay, Meredith, I've
closed your uterus,
and I just started to
suture your incisions.
Do you trust these
guys to finish?
Have you taught them
that much? I'll do it.
No, you stole neuro.
You're not stealing this.
This is my surgery, my
patient, my incision, mine.
Dr. Grey, I'm sorry.
That was inappropriate.
It's okay, Ross. I
like the enthusiasm.
Go scrub. Thank you.
Thanks, Connie.
Good luck, Mommy. Congrats.
More light.
To your left.
I can't find the source.
Everything I look at
turns out to be a shadow.
I could kill him if I do this.
Well, you'll certainly
kill him if you don't.
Will you stop saying that?
It's not helping. I can't see.
Then don't look.
Everyone, turn out your lights.
What do you mean?
I'm sorry. What?
Yang.
Listen for it.
You know what a
healthy heart sounds like.
Listen and tell me
where the problem is.
Now, everyone, lights out
and quiet.
It's...
Wait.
I think it's...
It's here.
I got it.
I got it. I have my
finger on the leak.
It's ventricular.
Lights, please.
If the ventilators stop working,
then these babies die
unless we manually bag them.
Crystal's battery light
has been on a while,
so when it dies,
you switch her baby over to
manual ventilation calmly and quietly.
You guys, go check
on the other babies.
Dr. Shepherd?
His sats are low, even with
oxygen. I think he needs c-pap.
This yours? Yeah.
Congrats, man. Let's
take a look at him.
Thank you.
Wilson, go. Excuse me.
Hey, Crystal.
I'm just gonna switch your little
girl over to a manual vent, okay?
Look at her. I think she's
grown since yesterday.
Found another red light, on
the Hitchens baby in the back.
That makes two more so far.
Three. I just found another
one, too, but it's fine.
I'll just jump in and bag
my baby when it's time.
And Dr. Edwards can bag hers.
We don't know how long
the power's gonna be off.
We could be bagging
these babies all night.
We'll bag all night.
It's fine. We can do this.
Thank you.
Okay, the important
thing is that we keep calm
and we don't alarm the parents,
cause there's no reason to...
Excuse me, Dr. Robbins?
Yes, Tim. What is it?
This red thing right here,
is this a low-battery light?
Where are Hunt and Avery?
That fire's getting bigger.
Where are the pain meds? I
got a patient in pain over here.
I tried to get the meds.
The machine, it won't
open without power.
I can't get it to open.
All right. Never mind that.
I've got at least two open fractures
and some nasty lacerations.
You want to jump in over there?
I... I don't...
Uh, you need meds.
I'll figure out the
meds. Murphy.
Smell that? There's
gas everywhere.
I have a daughter. She's three.
Have you seen her? Is she okay?
All right, I'm gonna have to
wrap this arm to stop the bleeding.
No, no, she's
wearing pink high-tops.
Her name is Evelyn.
I call her Evie.
Everyone's inside, ma'am.
I'm sure that she's there.
If we can move this thing even an
inch, I think we can get her out of here.
Let's do it fast.
Need some more light over here.
Ross, what is taking so long?
It's fine. It's just... It
won't stop bleeding.
Oh, God. That's...
That's a lot of blood.
How much blood?
I don't know. It's not
coming from your uterus.
Brooks, shine a light over here.
I feel something on my hand.
There's blood coming out
around my IV. I'm in DIC.
I need FFP, packed red
blood cells, and platelets.
I had a fall. What?
Yesterday, I fell
down the stairs.
I might have injured
something in my abdomen.
Did you feel any
pain? I've been in labor.
Go get help, now.
Ross, we don't have time.
You need to open me back up
and find the source of this bleed.
I can't. I've never...
Shane, it's a basic midline
laparotomy. Pack the four quadrants.
Find the source of the bleed.
Do not let me bleed
out on this table.
Dr. Grey... Shane,
do it, right now.
Good. Good. It's moving.
Pull her out. Pull her out.
All right, go, go. I got her.
All right, we're gonna walk
you out through the door.
We're gonna... You're
gonna have to walk...
No, no, no. My leg, I can't.
Ma'am, I'm gonna need you
to cover your eyes, all right?
Ready? Here we go.
Stay down.
All right.
This is ridiculous.
So you're saying you don't
have any extra batteries?
Manual ventilation
is just as effective...
My monitor just
went black. I'm on it.
My baby can't die. Is
my baby gonna die?
Mine's out, too. All
right. I'm on my way.
See? We're handling it.
Everything is under control.
Under control? Do the math.
You have doctors on four
different babies right now.
You're the only one left.
You're telling me you can ventilate
a dozen babies all by yourself?
Okay, okay...
This is not okay!
Everybody.
Everybody, shut up!
You're right. There are not enough doctors
in this room to ventilate every baby.
But there are enough people.
He's right. We can teach you.
You want us to
bag our own babies?
Actually, it's pretty easy.
I learned how to do it
my first day in med school.
I'll show you.
You just take the bag
with your dominant hand,
give a good, hard
squeeze every second.
So one, one thousand,
two, one thousand,
three, one thousand.
You want to try?
Not really. No, you'll
be fine. I'll be right here.
Come on.
One, one thousand,
two, one thousand...
That's great. That's great.
Everything's gonna be just fine.
It looks like the spleen is
the source of the bleeding.
Okay, so mobilize the spleen, divide
it by its ligamentous attachments...
I can't. I've never done it.
You can. You've seen me do it.
Mobilize, assess the injury,
and stop the hemorrhage.
Okay. Okay.
I need metz and
lap pads, please.
And follow me with suction.
That's right, Ross. That's it.
You got this. This is your OR.
You don't need
my help. Yes, I do.
No, you don't, because I'm gonna
lose consciousness in a few seconds.
And you're gonna be on your own.
And you're not gonna freak out.
And, Shane, if I arrest
for more than nine minutes,
let me go.
Don't revive me. I do not
want to be a vegetable.
Do you understand me?
Shane, I need you to respond.
I need to know
you understand me.
Dr. Ross,
your superior is
asking you to respond...
Yes, Dr. Grey.
Ross, you can...
You can do this.
And...
Tell Derek
I know
the baby's name.
It's...
You okay?
That was...
You made me a better
doctor tonight, Dr. Webber.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
I'm gonna go check on Meredith,
see if we have a baby yet.
Grey's having her baby?
Well, what do you know?
Well, I oughta see
what's holding up Frank.
Now I see what she means...
Miranda, when
she talks about you.
She says that you can
pull greatness
right out of people.
I wasn't able to pull it
out of her, apparently.
It's not working. It's jammed.
"In case of emergency,
use the key."
A bus crashed. This
is an emergency.
We are using the damn key. Here.
Dr. Bailey, can you help?
It's Dr. Grey. She's in
surgery, and she's in bad shape.
Dr. Grey is very capable.
She'll figure it out.
She's not operating.
She's the one on the table.
Dr. Bailey!
Dr. Bailey?
Don't just stand
there. Get the meds.
Let's go.
Move fast. This thing's
a ticking time bomb!
Come on. Come on. Come on.
Almost there. Done.
All right. Let's go.
Start a large-bore
IV. Where's Jackson?
Right behind us. No, he's not.
Hey. Your name is Evie, right?
I like your shoes, Evie.
Those are really cool.
Bet you can run pretty
fast in those, huh?
Hey, you want to race?
I bet I could beat you.
Come on. Just grab my
hand. We can go right now.
Come on. Here, take my hand.
I've mobilized her spleen.
I considered splenic salvage,
but I can't control the bleeding.
I did everything she said.
Everything she said, Dr. Bailey.
Another set.
Move over.
Where is Meredith Grey?
I delivered her baby hours
ago. She should be in recovery.
She's not. Where is she?
Hey, I have an idea. Why don't
we go find your mommy, huh?
Yeah, come on.
I know where she is.
We'll go find her right now.
Come on, Evie.
We're not gonna be
able to salvage any of this.
I need to do a complete splenectomy
to get control of the hemorrhage.
What happened?
Can you see him?
Wait, is that him
behind the bus?
Avery! Jackson!
Avery, come back here!
Evie! Why is he...
No! No! OWEN:
Avery, get back here!
April! What is he doing?
No, no, no! It's too
dangerous. What's going...
Get back!
Jackson!
No!
Evie?
Evie! Oh, God, baby.
Thank you so much.
Thank you.
Frank!
Frank.
Frank. Frank?
I got you. I got you, Frank.
Stay with me. Stay
with me, Frank.
Hold it right there.
Hold it right there for me.
You idiot!
Don't...
You could have... April!
Hey, Kepner. Died! You...
Stop. Kepner, what
is your problem?
Kepner, take a walk.
Take a walk!
Okay.
He looks like her.
Did you see him?
Um, no. I didn't.
Yeah, he looks like her.
His APGARs are good.
Six and a nine.
He's gonna be fine.
He's gonna be great.
Cristina?
Meredith Grey has survived a
bomb, a drowning, a gunman
and a plane crash,
and she's still here.
She's gonna die when she's
90, old and warm in her bed.
She is not gonna die today.
Today's she gonna be fine.
I hope so.
She has to be.
She's our person.
Meredith had a
massive splenic bleed.
I removed it, but...
She...
Oh, God. Oh, God, no.
She's fine. Bailey did it.
With an assist from Dr. Ross.
Bailey decided,
with the power out,
it's safest just to keep
her here till she wakes up.
She's alive? She's alive.
I'm sorry, guys. I
didn't mean to cry and...
And scare you. I just...
I just...
Let's get him upstairs, have
him worked up for an MI.
All right. You were right.
Air in the fuel system.
Solenoid stopped the injector
from firing. I'm sorry, man.
Don't, Frank, forget it.
I'm sorry I yelled at you.
I feel like I gave
you this heart attack.
You were right, though.
But I fixed it. I just gotta
flip the transfer switch.
Okay.
Good job, Frank.
Okay. MAN: Let's go.
She did great tonight.
I have to believe it's 'cause
she had a great teacher.
If you're gonna feel responsible
for making your ladies
crazy or giving 'em cancer,
then you should at least take
credit for helping make 'em great.
My baby's doing great.
I extubated her. She's
on a nasal cannula.
We gonna talk?
I made a mistake.
I can't...
I don't wanna talk
about this right now.
I'm not gonna leave
things like this, though.
I like you a lot.
So if you change
your mind, then...
You will not believe the
night I have had so far.
Hey, Callie. Hey.
Lights.
Is that...
Is that Arizona's ring
pinned to your scrub top?
Yeah. It must be.
We had a pyloric stenosis baby.
Projectile-vomited all
over the place. I got soaked.
Arizona was nice enough
to lend me some scrubs.
Thank you, by the
way. You're a lifesaver.
This place looks so
different in the dark.
Yeah.
You think the tree
ruined my couch?
I think it ruined your
entire living room.
Listen, I have to tell you
something. No, you don't.
You don't even know
what I'm gonna say.
I think I do, and you shouldn't.
Jo... I'll mess it up, Alex.
I mess everything
good in my life up,
and we work as friends really
well, and I don't wanna mess that up.
You won't mess anything up.
Last night, before the tree,
you asked me a question.
You wanted to hear
me say the words.
So I'm...
Saying them right now.
I don't hear anything. Shut up.
Okay, but I'm... I'm serious.
Fine. I love you.
Don't.
Whatever it is that's bugging you,
just keep it to yourself, all right?
I want you...
Jackson.
I want you.
April...
I haven't been fair to
you, I know, and I've...
I've really hurt you.
And you're getting married.
When that bus exploded,
and I thought
you were gone, I...
You're getting married.
Unless you can give
me a reason not to?
There you are.
How's Meredith? How's the baby?
Good.
Think she's ready
for visitors yet?
Yeah, sure. Go for it.
Well, we could go together.
Do you know how much I love you?
I do.
I felt such joy today
in that dark OR.
I could hear the blood moving.
I knew exactly what the
heart muscle was thinking.
And I realized after...
I feel that way all the time.
I'm made for the OR.
Even the boring
procedures, I can feel
pure joy, content.
You feel that
with just me?
What kind of a question is that?
Derek watches Zola put
applesauce in her ear,
and he's enchanted.
You felt that way with Ethan.
You're reading way
too much into this.
Okay, if you could stop for a
second and listen to your heart...
Cristina, you don't know
what I want in my life.
Am I enough, Owen?
Do you really
believe I'll be enough?
I wish it were different.
No, no...
I'm sorry.
Cristina... Owen.
It already happened.
Cristina, I said no.
I thought we were past the hard
stuff. I thought we were finally good.
We were. We are.
We're married! I know.
We... God, we have a child!
I know! How could you do this?
I don't know, except I did. After
all that's happened this year,
everything we've been through,
everything we've survived,
the bankruptcy,
Mark, the plane...
You weren't on
the plane, Callie!
You weren't in the woods,
and you did not hear Meredith
crying for Lexie and
Mark moaning in pain
or hearing me scream in pain.
You weren't there, and you
keep acting like you were,
but you weren't, and it
wasn't your experience!
I lost Mark. You
almost died. You...
"I lost Mark. You almost died."
You weren't on
the freaking plane!
You want it? The street cred?
The badge of honor?
The warrior wounds?
Then great. Stick out your leg,
and I will go grab a bone saw,
and let's even the score!
It always comes back to the leg.
I trusted you,
more than anything,
more than anyone in my life.
And you decided to cut it off.
To save your life!
You didn't lose anything!
I did!
I did.
There's an end to every storm.
Apparently, I lost you.
Once all the trees
have been uprooted.
Once all the houses
have been ripped apart.
What do you think about Bailey?
Bailey? You like it?
I love it.
What do you think?
The wind will hush.
The clouds will part.
The rain...
Yeah, that's
your little brother.
Will stop.
Hey. I heard what you did.
I couldn't be more impressed.
Hey, hey, hey.
Are you all right?
I need to talk to Richard.
Look, he came to me.
He tried to help me,
and I called him a drunk.
I blamed him.
I turned on him. Of
all people, that man...
Hey, hey, hey. Okay. It's okay.
He knows you,
better than you think.
Maybe you owe him an apology.
No, I owe him everything.
Now do you know where he is?
The sky will
clear in an instant.
And only then...
In those quiet moments
after the storm...
Do we learn...
Who was strong enough
to survive it.