♪ Ohhh ohhh ohhh ♪
Archer and I
were terrible sailors.
Heh,
it broke the captain's heart.
Every time we'd tack,
that's when you turn
the sailboat across the wind,
the captain would yell out,
"ready about!"
And Archer and I would go
and get ready.
And then "hard alee!"
Which is when you push
the tiller hard to the Lee side.
Anyway, if you do it right,
you pick up good wind
and everything's fine.
But if you do it wrong,
as we often did,
you'd wind up in irons.
What's "in irons"?
It's when you're
pointing straight at the wind.
And you can try and fight,
but you are stuck.
Thank you for staying over.
This was fun.
Well, I thought so, heh.
I mean, I know that staying up
all night talking and not...
Doing it?
Right.
It's fine.
It's not.
It is fine.
It's not fine.
I know you wanted to do it.
I just...
I'm not sure if I'm ready,
you know? I just...
I just got separated
and, you know, you are...
You are very...
What?
Young?
Violet, this is your issue,
it's not mine.
You're right, you're right,
you're right.
Do you wanna stay a little
longer and eat some breakfast?
Mm-hm.
You excited?
I am
cautiously optimistic.
Today you meet
the surrogate candidates?
- So I'm told.
- I have narrowed it down
to a couple of women who I think
would be a good fit for her.
Oh. No. It's like when
the guy buys you a sweater.
It's fluffy, tight and low cut.
What women want
and what men think they want--
there are criteria
they have to meet.
They have given birth to their
child whom they are raising.
Really want a car
with all that mileage?
We have to make sure that she's
gone
through a healthy pregnancy,
devoid of major complications.
Exactly.
It's also essential
that the surrogate knows
how she's gonna feel
- being pregnant and giving birth.
- Makes sense.
You don't want her to run away
with the baby.
Thank you.
Heh.
Thank you, Amelia.
Now I can worry about that.
We're going
through an agency.
Everything's aboveboard.
There will be a contract.
It'll be fine.
You're right. Yeah.
Because so far getting pregnant,
ivf, adoption,
it's all gone so swimmingly.
I've been a smashing success
on all fronts. Heh.
Thanks.
Morning.
Violet?
Good morning, heh.
Why are you grinning at me?
I'm happy to see you?
You've never said that
to me before.
Maybe I should change that.
Hmm.
Someone rung your bell
last night.
Charlotte,
nobody rang anything.
I'm not asking for details,
I'm just saying.
Whoever he is and whatever
he's doing, keep him around.
It's a nice version of you.
Violet?
Joanna.
Help me.
- I need some help here.
- Stay with me.
I need an iv set-up
and a gurney.
- Right away.
- Can you hear me?
- She's diaphoretic.
- Joanna?
Can you tell us what happened?
My baby.
- Are you pregnant, Joanna?
- It's okay.
Shh. Joanna? Stay with me.
It's okay.
Joanna? Hey.
Joanna. Joanna.
I never would have met Mason
if Erica wasn't sick.
I never would have known I had
this amazing son out there.
But you do know.
So now we need to focus on
what we need to focus on.
She went to two specialists,
there was nothing they could do.
If she doesn't wanna fight--
you're gonna let her give up?
Amelia is a world-class
neurosurgeon.
Erica knows that,
and she said no.
I can't kidnap her
and force her into an mri.
One of the most annoying things
about you
is that you don't give up.
I don't know
what to do here.
This is Dr. King.
Yeah, I'll be right there.
I gotta go.
What am I supposed to do?
Think of something.
Thirty-seven year old female.
Unconscious with blunt trauma
to the face and abdomen.
Wide-bore iv times two,
- cross and hold four units.
- She's pregnant.
I need an ultrasound.
Brain scan and trauma panel.
Her husband did this.
I met Joanna six months ago
in an airport.
She was afraid to go back
to New York
because he hit her
during an argument.
- There's blood in her belly.
- The baby looks 12 weeks old.
Get the police.
She told you that he hit her?
- She didn't have to.
- What's going on?
Who's that?
Husband. You should not be here.
How did this happen?
She was beaten badly.
I need to be with her.
That's not gonna happen.
I don't understand.
You did this.
You don't have to play innocent.
What? No.
When you talked at the airport
and made her stay?
That was my wake-up call.
I got help,
and I've been doing the work.
Anger management, therapy.
Jo and I are doing much better.
I swear to you,
this isn't... it wasn't me.
I need to be with her.
Hey.
Get your hands off of me.
You don't even know me.
Back up.
Dr. Wilder, that is enough.
Hey.
I heard you guys
had quite a night out.
Ah. Sorry
you couldn't make it.
Yeah. I also heard it was,
uh, pretty successful?
Cooper?
Heh. He was very impressed.
Look, I'm not trying to have
everybody know about that.
Of course.
It was a one-time thing.
Oh, are you retiring
from the league of men
sleeping with
20-something supermodels?
Because if
there's a spot on the roster...
No, I'm just...
I'm looking for something real.
You know what I mean.
I feel the same.
Hey, hey, hey.
What's going on, fellas?
What's happening?
- Everything good?
- Yes.
We were discussing
where to meet
smart, beautiful,
eligible women
to take our minds off the smart,
beautiful, unavailable women.
- The million-dollar question.
- Mm-hm.
If you can get beyond
the cheese factor,
I've always loved the gym.
Unlike a bar,
if you don't have any luck,
at least you're getting
a workout in.
Well, I do enjoy multi-tasking.
What's going on with Joanna?
She's unconscious.
Her blood pressure is down,
and she's bleeding
into her abdomen.
What does that mean?
Is the baby okay?
I couldn't find
the baby's heartbeat.
I'm so sorry.
But because of the trauma,
Joanna lost the baby.
Look, I know
that this is awful,
but we need to make a decision
right now.
There's a tear in Joanna's
uterine wall.
I might have to do
a hysterectomy to stabilize her.
Do the hysterectomy.
If I stop the bleeding, I might
save her uterus and her life.
Might?
It's riskier, but I think--
do the hysterectomy.
You can't listen. He did this.
Shut the hell up.
Watch it.
Please.
She can live without a uterus,
I can't live without Joanna.
You're a liar.
He's her husband.
It's his decision to make.
Take her uterus out
and save her life.
He's the one who beat her.
You cannot let him decide
what's best for Joanna.
It's not up to me.
She's unconscious,
the law says
her husband gets to decide.
We don't know what happened.
She told me. David hit her.
Once that we know of,
six months ago.
If he hit her once,
he hit her again.
What do you think
else happened?
This is as hard for me
as it is for anyone else here,
but the police will sort it out,
sooner rather than later.
Until that
or she regains consciousness,
we have to follow the law.
Unfortunately, that means
listening to David Gibson.
This is not the time
to cover your ass, Charlotte.
Really, Pete?
Joanna wants kids, okay?
She told me she does.
Maybe that baby wasn't David's
or maybe he didn't want it,
but you cannot go in there
and take her chance for becoming
a mother. That lets him win.
This isn't any disagreement
Joanna and David had.
It's about saving Joanna.
And David isn't wrong.
Removing her uterus
might be the safest course.
Not to mention that if Addison
tries to save her uterus,
but Joanna dies and it turns out
David didn't do it,
it's not just gonna be my ass
that needs covering.
"Decidedly, I can't draw back.
But at least if I am killed,
I shall be killed
by a musketeer."
Heh, good job.
Can we read
another chapter?
Actually that's enough
for today.
You have a closet to clean.
All for one...
And one for all.
What's this?
I spoke to my lawyer,
and I got all the paperwork
to make sure that, uh,
I'll be Mason's legal guardian
in the event of, uh...
In the event of the situation
we're actually in.
Um, do we have
to deal with this now?
I wanna make sure
that there's no custody issues.
Oh, come on, Cooper.
We don't deal with this, Mason,
he could end up
in the care of the state.
I, uh, will sign it later.
Later when?
Later.
I don't think
that you are preparing, Erica.
I am preparing. I brought him
to see you, didn't I?
I told you I was sick.
After Charlotte found out.
Look, come here.
If you were really preparing,
you would be
taking care of details.
Your will would be done. We'd be
talking about Mason's future.
That's what you do
when you've accepted your fate.
But you're not there yet.
Acceptance is not a stage
that you have reached.
Which means
you have not given up.
I think you still have hope,
Erica.
Don't waste it.
Uh...
Is, uh, what's-her-name really
better than those other doctors?
It's better this way.
We doctor, they investigate.
Don't worry,
they'll find out what happened.
How'd it go?
She's still sedated,
lost a lot of blood,
but she's gonna make it.
Thanks, Addison.
- How is she? How's Joanna?
- She's gonna be okay.
I was able
to control the bleeding
without having to perform
a hysterectomy.
Really? That's great.
What? I thought you said--
That's a good thing.
Just a second.
I specifically told you
not to take that risk.
I don't-- you had no right.
You shouldn't have any rights.
Calm down.
I've done nothing wrong.
Because your wife is still
recovering from what you did,
and she can't tell us
what happened.
As soon as Joanna's stable,
I'm moving her.
It's gonna take time.
Not when my lawyer's involved.
That's not necessary.
No, clearly it is.
I've been assaulted
by a doctor in this hospital.
I'm treated
like a criminal here.
We will transfer her
as soon as possible.
Officer,
can you do anything?
As far as I understand it,
you didn't witness
the first alleged attack.
Mrs. Gibson never filed a report
or a restraining order.
Mr. Gibson
has no history of violence.
And there are no witnesses
to account for what happened.
You cannot allow him
to take her.
My department will continue
to investigate this,
but without evidence,
until the victim wakes up
and files a complaint,
my hands are tied.
I'm so sorry. I had an emergency
surgery. I'm Addison, heh.
Donna was just telling me
about her husband
who's stationed
on an aircraft carrier.
Oh, that's terrific.
He's a Navy pilot and we're
proud, but it's challenging.
We have two great kids,
10 and 6.
But they miss their dad,
and it's busy for me.
So, uh, being a surrogate
would...?
Will help out financially.
Being a surrogate is noble,
but it's a business.
You're a professional,
Dr. Montgomery,
you must recognize that
I have a valuable skill set
that I wanna put to work
for you.
Hello.
Hey.
How'd it go
with the surrogate?
She's very business-like.
Well, that's good, right?
Oh.
No, I mean, you want her
to carry the child and give it
to you, not be the mother.
That'll be your job.
Okay.
And your job is to tell me
everything's gonna be fine.
I'm gonna know the right
surrogate when I meet her.
I don't think it's about
finding the right one,
it's finding a good one.
Hey, um, do you know, um...?
Do you know this, um, young--?
This, uh, paramedic
named Scott?
Hot Scott?
Heh, yes.
Violet.
I know. It's so crazy.
What? What's crazy?
He's young and, you know...
What the hell am I doing?
Are you having fun?
Yes.
Good.
Young is great.
Young is virile.
Virile young buck.
Oh, Violet, gosh.
You like him, he likes you.
Don't think about it and enjoy.
You deserve it. Hmm.
Sorry, doctors,
but Joanna Gibson? She's awake.
The gliosarcoma has grown
considerably
since the last scans.
Because of its size
and its proximity to
the intracranial blood supply,
surgical intervention
is unlikely to succeed.
So the sky is blue,
and tacos taste great.
Tell me something
I don't already know.
Is this impossible to treat
or just impossible to cure?
The best we can do
is aggressive radiation therapy
with combination chemotherapy
to slow the tumor's growth.
Maybe that could give Erica
six months or so,
depending on the efficacy
of the chemotherapy.
Six months
of what kind of life?
Honestly? Rough.
Any time you do chemo,
there are side effects:
Fatigue, nausea, infection.
But the most important thing in
cancer treatment is buying time.
Because there's always progress
being made.
There's new trials, new drugs.
Come on, Cooper.
You really think they're gonna
have a cure for cancer
in six months?
Look, I came, I listened,
I'm done.
What did you do with Mason
on his last birthday?
What?
No, just tell me.
We did go-karts.
He loves driving.
He can't wait
to get his license.
And what's he wanna do
on his next birthday?
Screw you.
If you don't want to believe
in a miracle, that's fine.
But you could give Mason
one more birthday together,
one more summer vacation,
one more Christmas.
And that's not much,
it's not enough,
but it would mean
everything to him.
Ugh, I feel like we're
two sides of a poetic debate.
I mean, which is better?
To have loved and lost
or to have never loved at all.
You don't have to fight
the memories.
Don't discount
the agony of regret.
I mean, if only I had said yes
when Amelia was interested...
The imagination is a powerful
tool of self-torture.
Okay.
This isn't working for me.
Me neither.
Hi.
Hi, i'm, uh, I'm Sam.
Hi, Sam.
Hey.
Are you done with that bike?
There's a time limit
on the cardio equipment.
Oh. Okay. Sorry.
David didn't want a baby.
I thought it would help us
start over.
I planned this
special breakfast to tell him.
Poached eggs and orange juice
from the tree in my mom's...
My mom died.
Oh, I'm so sorry.
It's better. If she saw this,
if she knew her grandchild...
I was so excited
to be pregnant.
I just figured
he would be too.
But he wasn't.
It happened so fast.
I...
I got up to get him more food,
and when I turned around,
I saw his fist coming at me,
but it was in slow motion.
I, uh, couldn't move.
He killed our baby.
Joanna, the police wanna
build a case against David,
but they're gonna need
your statement.
I, uh, don't wanna do that.
Joanna, I will help you do it.
I will be with you
every step of the way.
I know you're scared,
but--
I'm not scared.
I am furious.
And I understand that but--
no, Violet, you can't.
He hit me.
He came at me,
and he punched me in the face.
My husband
punched me in the face.
There was nothing I could do.
David needs to go to jail.
No. He beat me.
And he killed my baby.
No. No.
No, I want him dead.
I, uh, want him to die.
Joanna...
I wanna kill him.
I'm gonna kill him.
So she said she wanted
to kill David?
Who, Joanna?
I hope that wasn't the statement
she gave the police.
She wouldn't talk to them.
She told me.
Did you tell the police?
Or David?
Confessing a plan
to murder someone
isn't protected by
doctor-patient confidentiality.
And if a therapist hears it,
she can be held liable
if she doesn't report it.
There's a difference between
a threat and a plan.
Joanna didn't tell the police
so she could kill him.
Come on, Charlotte.
She just heard
her husband killed her baby,
a baby he never wanted,
and tried to force her
to have a hysterectomy.
She is allowed to have
an emotional response.
And she needs to feel the safety
to express that anger
to a therapist.
And now you have a legal
obligation to deal with it.
Wait a minute. Violet's
not technically her therapist.
Your license was suspended
most of the time
you were talking to her.
She's not a formal patient.
I mean, there's no file--
Pete is right.
We're just friends.
Friends do not have
a legal obligation, right?
No, Violet,
you can't have it both ways.
You do have your license
back now.
The moment you heard the threat,
you were a therapist.
Not hers.
Would a court see it that way?
I won't second-guess Violet
and say this guy
isn't a dirtbag criminal,
but if David's life
is really threatened,
we have
a moral obligation here.
Where is he, anyway?
I sent him home last night
before she regained
consciousness.
Say Violet does warn David,
and then he retaliates
against Joanna. What then?
Look, Violet, I'm on your side,
but how do we protect everyone?
You have to go into this
with an open mind.
She's not right.
You haven't even met her yet.
I can feel the warmth
from her every pore.
It's nauseating me
all the way over here.
Have you secretly been giving
yourself hormone shots again?
Look, I'm gonna go in there,
I'm gonna ask June
what the best part
about being a surrogate is,
and she's gonna give me
some weird, hippy-dippy answer
about the magic of motherhood.
You have no idea
what she's gonna say.
Okay, fine. Let's go.
So, June, what was the best part
of your last experience?
That's easy. The parents let me
keep the placenta,
and they came to my house to
help me Bury it in the garden.
And we planted a tree there.
Hmm.
Okay, so what about church?
Hmm. No, that's
too much commitment for me.
I know,
but the whole point
is to meet women
who want commitment.
If only there was
some computer-based system
where eligible people from
all over the land could connect.
Online dating is the number one
way to meet women.
We're looking for women of more
depth than those cyber-honeys
you used to meet
on those sites.
Heh, I met my wife
on one of those sites.
Yeah, but, I mean,
you knew her in real life.
And hated her and she hated me.
But by going online
and stripping away
all the preconceived notions,
we were able to find out we were
actually very compatible.
Portable X-ray to the er.
Where's my wife?
I released her.
I told you I wanted to take her
to another hospital.
It was Joanna's request
to leave.
I never got a chance
to talk to her.
Not my problem.
This is not over.
Yes, it is.
Now back the hell away from me
before I have your ass
dragged out of my hospital.
Your solution
was to bring Joanna home?
All she'd do
in the hospital is recover,
and I can take
better care of her here.
Yeah.
Better than the nursing staff?
What if there's a complication
or emergency?
I'll call the ambulance. There's
not gonna be an emergency.
And I can change a bandage.
I am a doctor, Pete.
I just...
I need you to take Lucas
for a few days.
There are shelters where she'd
be safe. And you would be too.
A shelter is not ideal
for somebody
recovering from surgery.
And this way I'll be able
to talk to her. Really talk.
You know, find out
if the threat is real.
She's protected because
he doesn't know where she is.
He's protected because
I'm not leaving her side.
I'm protected
because both of them are.
I don't like you
putting yourself in the middle.
Well, there's a lot of decisions
I make that you might not like,
but you don't really get a say
in them anymore.
But what you do get a say in
is whether Lucas
is in the middle of it too.
Okay.
You give my truck.
- You wanna hold it, baby?
- Daddy's gonna take you, okay?
Okay, pal. Are you ready?
Up.
Do you want the truck?
- Yeah. Here.
- My truck?
Here it is. I love you.
Be good.
- Bye-bye.
- Here we go.
Hey, Pete?
If you were me,
what would you have done?
The same thing.
Thank you.
Bye-bye.
Hey, how's it going?
Fine.
Are you mad at me?
Mad? No.
I'm not trying to be a pain
about the surrogate stuff.
You don't have
to apologize, all right?
But let's stop wasting time,
because your heart's
definitely not into this.
You'll find a flaw with anyone
who wants to do this for you.
That is not true.
It is.
And there's nothing wrong
with these surrogates.
They're all fine.
So what? I'm the problem?
You said it, not me.
Hey.
Um, I need to ask you
a question,
and I want you to give me
an honest answer.
Um, whatever you say,
I won't tell Cooper.
Okay.
Um...
They give you these pamphlets
on the side effects of chemo.
You know, the hair loss,
nausea, vomiting, bleeding.
Not specific, bleeding
from where. I've read them all.
What I wanna ask is, um,
if you were in my shoes,
would you put yourself
through this?
Destroying
your quality of life
for the chance at maybe
a few more painful months?
Or would you spend
every possible healthy moment
with the most important person
in your life?
I wouldn't.
I wouldn't do the treatment.
Yeah.
No, no, no. Sam,
you can't put hair color: Bald.
Why not?
I shave my head.
No, no, no. You put
what color your hair would be
if it grew out, you know?
And... what?
You put you're a grandpa on
the first line about yourself?
Heh.
What, are you crazy?
Well, I'm proud
to be a grandpa.
No, listen,
you can be forthcoming,
but you can still be delicate
with the truth.
So bald is well-groomed and
grandpa is just a family man.
Okay, the section
on physical attributes
is depressing
in present company,
so I'm just gonna move on
to questions of substance.
"What is your biggest flaw?"
Too sensitive.
That's gold.
Yeah, well, maybe for you.
Your answer, prince charming?
Too passionate about my work.
Hmm. That's good.
Okay, yeah. No, you're good.
I see my sage advice
is being heeded.
Okay, Mr. Sage, what would be
Sam's ideal first date?
Well... excuse me.
Sure.
I used to start with, uh, this.
- Yeah.
- Ugh.
No, no, no.
That's...
Cooper, this is
a family practice. Please.
Whatever it is,
I need to see it.
They're writing
their online dating profiles.
What's wrong with that?
Nothing. But why is Sam
bothering to write anything?
He should just post
a shirtless picture of himself
with "Dr. Bennett" above it.
He'll have a thousand dates
in an hour.
And Sheldon,
it's not like he needs the rest
of you yahoos to tell him
what a girl wants to hear.
Well, maybe loved and lost
is better, man.
I'm sorry.
The last thing you need
is to be taking care of me.
It's fine.
You have Lucas to worry about.
- Plus Pete.
- Lucas is doing fine.
And Pete and I, you know,
we're working through it.
It's a lot better.
There's less anger.
So you don't have
to worry about it.
Pull your shirt up.
I read your book.
It made me feel like a failure.
Why?
You went through
this terrible thing,
and you overcame it. But I...
I knew in my heart.
I mean, hit me once,
shame on you, hit me twice...
But I went back to David anyway.
Well...
That was a mistake,
and you can correct it.
By going to the police?
I've seen those women
on the stand, in court.
The victims.
I'm not a victim.
Being a victim
does not mean you're powerless.
But I chose to be with him.
I let him back in.
It's my fault.
You don't understand that,
because what happened to you
wasn't your fault.
It felt like it was.
It always does.
I have great faith
in people's capacity to change.
My patients. My husband.
And when they don't, I assume
that I did something wrong.
And sometimes I did.
But a lot of times I didn't.
But I can't tell the difference
in my own life. No one can.
It's understandable that
you would think he could change.
Joanna, we need to talk about
what you said.
About David.
Oh, Violet, no. No, please.
I, unh...
You really think I'm gonna
kill David? I was just upset.
I was frustrated and hurting.
You can understand that,
can't you?
Yes, yes, yes.
Of course I can.
But I also know that,
you know, if a person
is pushed past
any reasonable limit, you--
oh, Joanna.
I can't believe that you would
think that I would do that.
I mean, no matter what happened.
I just...
I just wanna be somewhere
where I feel safe
and I don't have to be scared,
and I can start putting my life
back together again.
You are.
How's the rent-a-womb search
going?
They're all wrong.
And Jake thinks I'm being
unfair and judgmental,
but it is a huge decision.
You know?
Finding someone
to carry my baby.
The first one was like
a breeding machine.
The second one looked like
she just wandered off a commune.
I don't know.
I could do it.
What?
I'm the closest thing you have
to a sister.
And I can do this.
Amelia.
I know. I'm the anti-surrogate.
I'm an addict and I wouldn't
pass the psych eval,
and it's semi-creepy
that I'm your ex-sister-in-law.
It would be a monumental failure
of your brilliant mind
to pick me.
But I wanna do it.
I wanna do this one
completely selfless thing.
There are people
that we can't help.
There are inoperable
brain tumors
and kids who face
too much tragedy and...
And Ryan.
Bringing a life
into this world,
it could be the thing
that I can do to make up for--
I can help you.
I wanna help you.
Let me, Addie. Please.
I love you, Amelia,
and I'm honored
that you've offered this,
but the most important thing
that you can do
now that you're sober,
is to figure out who you are.
And who you are,
can't be my surrogate.
Hi. Declaration of paternity.
Application to amend
the birth certificate.
We can go to your lawyer
tomorrow to sign these.
That should cover
your custody concerns.
This is acceptance.
You won't try the treatment?
Even for Mason?
Everything I do is for Mason.
Every single thing
since the moment
I found out I was pregnant.
I brought him here to meet you,
which I wasn't gonna do
in a million years.
I did it for him.
I'm changing
the birth certificate for him.
Erica. You have to fight.
I can't win.
I don't wanna fight if
there's not a chance I can win.
There is.
There's always a chance.
Even if at first
it just means buying time--
Cooper, please, stop it.
Now you need
to accept it. Okay?
He says he wants to see
the Grand Canyon.
For his next birthday.
Just so you know.
Hey, hey.
Now you're spoiling me.
Please, you haven't
tasted the eggs yet.
You need anything else?
For you to get back
to your life.
I'm fine.
I'm gonna get the paper.
And, uh, you can eat,
then we'll, uh, plan the day.
Maybe we'll get you up
for, uh, a walk later.
Where is she?
I wanna talk to my wife.
She's not here.
I love you so much. I'm sorry.
I don't want to see you,
David!
- Get out of my house.
- I just wanna talk to her.
I'm not leaving without my wife.
No, I'm leaving you, David.
Please, don't say that.
You are a bastard
and a bully and a coward.
I don't love you.
I could never love you again.
Shut up! Stop saying that.
This is your fault.
- Just leave.
- Leave her alone! Go!
You killed my baby! I'd never
love someone who did that!
- Shut up!
- Shut up and go!
I hate you. I hate you.
You bastard.
You killed my baby.
I hate you. I hate you.
I hate you.
- I hate you.
- Oh, my god.
- Joanna. Joanna. Joanna.
I hate you.
He's dead! You have to stop!
Stop. Stop.
Stop.
I had to. I had to.
He didn't give me a choice.
I had to protect myself.
And you. I had to.
You'll tell the police that,
right?
I had to.
Hey.
So I was, uh, surprised
that you called.
Thank you for coming.
Look, have a seat.
I just wanna tell you,
you were right.
About what?
There is something wrong
with me.
Oh, no, Addison,
I didn't mean
to make you feel like--
no, it's not your fault.
It's just, um...
I just need a break.
From all of it.
You're giving up?
No. I want a baby.
I will have a baby.
I just...
Right now, I just need
to be for a while.
I need to focus on something
else, on anything else.
Yeah. Yeah,
I think that's smart.
So you, uh, want some company?
Yeah, I do.
I understand. I--
I go to the station,
I could call a lawyer.
So when you woke up,
he was already dead?
Dr. Turner?
He was already dead.
So you didn't see
what actually happened
before she stabbed him?
Well, it was self-defense.
He broke into my home.
He attacked both of us.
It was self-defense.
Oh, my god. Oh, my god. Violet.
Are you all right?
Let me see.
Yeah. I'm okay.
I just gotta move out
of this place, but yeah.
What can I do?
What do you need?
Uh, can you just
keep taking care of Lucas?
I'm just gonna clean up.
Of course. Of course.
Thank you.
I tried to make her go
to treatment.
I know you did.
I really tried.
I know.
No. It was...
If Erica wasn't sick,
I never would have met Mason.
So you keep saying.
No, Charlotte.
If Erica wasn't sick,
I never would have met Mason.
And you feel guilty
because of how grateful you are
that this happened?
Hey.
Can I come in?
Yeah. What happened?
Did somebody hit you?
I don't wanna talk about it.
Okay. All right. Let's, uh,
sit down. Let me take a look.
Head's up.
It's not broken but, man...
Lie down.
Let me get you some ice.
Here.
Hey. I'm here for you.
Whatever it is,
whatever you need, I'm here.
Addison.
Yeah?
- Can I ask you a question?
- Sure.
Uh, heh...
What do you think
my biggest flaw is?
What?
It was just something
I'm thinking about.
Other than the fact that
you don't wanna have a baby?
Uh-huh.
Um...
Well, let's see.
You know, you don't recognize
how great you truly are.
I'm serious.
You're kind of the perfect man,
but you just
judge yourself so harshly
and kind of hold yourself to
this impossibly high standard.
You gotta learn how
to just relax a little.
And for the record,
that is not your only flaw.
It's just your biggest.
Addie.
Yes.
I took a chance
and guessed you were
a "beer out of a bottle"
kind of girl.
Sam, what were you gonna ask me?
Uh... hey, man.
Sam, you want a beer?
No, no. I am good.
I'll see you guys later.
See you.
Yeah.
Sometimes when we were stuck,
we'd stop for a minute to rest,
regain our strength.
You know, let the waves
take us for a while.
Even if we weren't going
anywhere, it was still sailing.