In 1952,
Dr. Virginia Apgar
pioneered a scoring
system to quickly evaluate
a newborn's physical health.
Oh, my God!
It's given at one minute and
five minutes after birth,
and it assesses the baby's
appearance, pulse, reflexes,
muscle tone, and breathing.
♪ I'm not bad, I'm not good
♪ I drank every
sky that I could ♪
♪ Made myself mythical
The baby's medical team
gives a score for each category,
then adds them to gauge whether
the baby needs immediate care.
♪ Daffodil
Designed to fight
infant mortality,
the idea was simple...
♪ Every night
♪ Raising the dead...
if we knew which babies were
in trouble, could we save them?
♪ And in the gloaming,
I start to cry ♪
♪ You're a perfect pearl
Incoming!
♪ Hung in the sky
♪ There is no bad
Okay, we're clear.
Let's get her out.
♪ There is no good
What do we got? Tia Marwood.
29, 28 weeks pregnant,
auto versus pedestrian,
blunt trauma to the abdomen,
GCS 14, she reports
sharp abdominal pain,
no vaginal bleeding.
Get her to trauma
three, let's go!
Kwan and Bailey are right
behind us with Addison.
Are you okay? I'm okay.
Until law enforcement confirms
that there is no
longer a threat,
Grey-Sloan is on a
hospital-wide lockdown.
All nonessential personnel
are being dismissed.
Only employees and
incoming trauma patients.
Hang on, hang on. Alright.
I was only clipped by the car.
It's my shoulder.
Alright, Addison.
We can only do it until
we fully assess you. Aah!
Okay, sorry, sorry. Okay, okay,
okay, sorry. My shoulder. Ow!
Bed 5.
I need an update from
Chief of Security.
Bailey! Yeah, I'm still here.
Bailey. Go check on Tia.
- Someone page X-ray.
- Come on, come on.
- I'm on it.
- Go.
OB-GYN has room upstairs for
the rest of the clinic overflow.
Once we're cleared, we can start
doing intake on this group here.
Thank God. Proof of life.
They said you were
handling clinic patients...
I wasn't out there. and so I
called and you didn't answer
and my mind went to a
place. I'm sorry, I just...
Hey, um...
It's all good.
Question answered.
I've gotta get back.
Yeah, of course.
Okay, Yasuda, let's type
and cross for blood.
Call the blood bank and
tell them to activate
massive transfusion protocol.
On it. Okay.
What do you see, Adams?
Free fluid in the perihepatic
and perisplenic areas.
We need to get her to CT.
Not until I see
the baby's tracing.
I wish I wasn't a doctor.
I wish I didn't understand
how bad this is.
We're doing everything we can.
Connor. Who's Connor?
C-Connor, that's his name.
A-After my father-in-law.
Dr. Wilson, promise me that
you're not gonna deliver him.
It's too early. His lungs
are not mature enough yet.
He's not ready. He
needs more time.
You and I both
know he needs more time.
Please.
ACB has been activated,
blood is on the way.
I need you to take
some deep breaths.
Okay, repetitive late decels.
The baby's in distress.
We need to get her
upstairs right now.Yeah.
Damn it, V-fib.
Let's get a crash cart.
Okay, let's turn her on her left
side and get ready to intubate.
Let's drop some
etomidate and succs.
Here's a cardiac
board. Good girl.
Alright, and I'm coming
around to do compressions.
Okay.
Charge to 200, okay?
Clear!
Okay, alert the O.R.
Again. Charge 200.
You didn't lose
consciousness, get dizzy,
notice any vision changes?
I'm fine. Left
shoulder's dislocated.
We need to reduce it under
sedation and get you an MRI.
I'm fine. I... Ow!
I need to help Tia.
She's right next door
and she's got six
very capable doctors around her.
I'm gonna lift your
arm a little bit.
Ow!
What happened to you?
I was grazed with a brick.
The one thrown
through the window?
Has anyone ruled
out a head injury?
Let's go. I'm fine.
People need to stop saying that.
Ready for the ambu bag.
Ooh. Just pop it back in.
Not without some sedation.
Just pop it back in, damn it!
Griffith, stand behind her.
Stabilize her shoulder.
Charge to 300.
Okay. Clear!
One, two...
Aah! F...
Okay.
Okay. Griffith, come with me.
And clear!
What's happening?
No variability on fetal monitor.
It's category three tracing.
How long?
How long?!
Almost two minutes.
We tried multiple rounds
of shock, epi, and boluses.
She is bleeding out
through her abdomen.
CPR's not gonna work.
Go ahead and prep the
abdomen for a C-section.
Addison. Gown and glove me.
That baby is not gonna survive
in the uterus any longer.
We've got to get the baby out.
I'm not gonna let that
person behind the wheel
take two lives out
of this family.
Okay.
Let's get an ex lap
tray and some towels.
- Hang two units of blood.
- Page the NICU.
We need an incubator and a
resuscitation team down here.
Okay, I'll get gowned and
gloved. Adams, take over.
Alright, get the lap pads ready.
I'm so sorry.
Okay, we need to move faster.
Come on, come on.
Are we ready?
10-blade.
Stopping compressions.
Incision.
Resync By M_I_S
www.opensubtitles.org
I'm going to
extend the incision.
Suction. Let's
give another round of epi.
Dr. Yasuda,
break's over.
If they don't need you in
there, go do intake on bed 4.
I need more retraction.
Okay, there's bleeding
in the liver and spleen.
Lap pads. Isn't
she already gone?
Why are we packing her...
'Cause we don't stop
until we do everything
that we can, okay?
More lap pads.
How we doing, DeLuca?
I've got
him. He's out.
Wilson, cut the cord. Yep.
Oxygen mask and prepare
for suction and intubation.
Hey, baby boy. Hang on for us.
Okay, restarting
chest compressions.
Okay, hang two units of blood and
push one of epi. Come on, Tia.
Come on.
Come on, Tia.
There!
- Wow.
Okay.
Oh, thank God.
Let's get her to the O.R.
while she still has a pulse.
And can somebody get me
her husband's number?
I'm on it.
Okay, I'm
intubating the baby now.
Griffith, make sure
NICU knows we're coming.
Yes, Dr. Montgomery.
Essential personnel only.
We're first responders.
You guys got patients with you?
My wife runs the
clinic. Miranda Bailey.
Our daughter is
upstairs in the daycare.
This entrance is closed.
Dr. Altman! Teddy!
It's okay. They're with me.
Essential personnel only.
I'm chief of surgery.
They're essential.
Have you seen Carina?
She's in surgery.
Oh, my God. No, she...
she's doingsurgery.
She's okay and
Bailey's okay, too.
Oh, thank God.
If anyone else gives you
trouble, just have them page me.
Alright. Thanks,
Teddy. Thank you.
This process seems
to take a lot longer
when you're on the
other side of it.
Almost done.
Remember when being a doctor
was considered heroic?
Like firefighters and teachers?
Who does this?
I mean, who throws bricks
and runs cars into doctors?
Scans are up.
What do you see?
Uh, no bleeding, no fractures...
No traumatic brain injuries.
Then can someone
get me out of here
so I can go back to
work? Not so fast.
You could be concussed,
so you should go home.
I live alone.
If I go home and fall asleep,
I could die and
no one would know.
Okay, fine, but you
need to be supervised
and undergo regular
neuro checks.
Wha... I-I don't want
to supervise him.
Well, I don't care.
He can't do any
procedures or scrub in.
Only let him do notes
and patient intake.
And page if he has any
dizziness or headaches.
Hello?
Hey. Hey.
Did you need something?
No, I just wanted to check in.
Dr. Pierce.
Well, Mr. Lingenfelser's post-op
cardiac index is improving.
I think we can discharge
in the morning.
Okay, that's good.
I was actually checking on you.
Uh...
Is everyone okay?
Uh, there's a pregnant
doctor who might not be.
I just...
I cannot process this, so I just
need to focus on my patients.
Like, if I keep telling myself
that everything is fine,
then eventually, that
will make it true, right?
Yeah. The world doesn't make a
whole lot of sense right now.
No, it doesn't.
Oh, uh, Sound Science
sent copies of the issue
for the partial heart
transplant feature.
So I left one for
you in the lounge.
Oh.
What did you think?
You didn't read it?
I got paged as soon
as I started it.
But I'm sure you did great.
Winston.
Yeah?
Thanks for checking in.
"M" as in "Mary", "I" as in
"Igloo", "L" as in "Larry."
Yes, Ms. Anderson.
I have paged Dr. Millin,
but Dr. Yasuda should
have done your intake.
Max? Where did she...
Jules!
What are you doing here?
Being paranoid.
Norma needs a knee replacement.
Maxine thinks she's a doctor.
Ms. Douglas, your
knee isvery swollen.
You see? I told you.
We heard some doctors
got hit by a car.
Was that you?
No, no.
Uh, I'm okay, but
thanks for your concern.
Ms. Douglas, have you
had a fall recently?
No. Any history of gout,
rheumatoid arthritis,
osteoarthritis?
Unh-unh. Okay.
Dr. Millin, page
ortho for her knee.
Wait. She won't tell
you, but I will.
It burns when she pees.
Norma!
Max, you have to say something.
Remember what
happened last time?
Could be another UTI.
I'll get you a
cup for a urinalysis.
Anything else?
Orange spice tea?
You know the one I like.
I'll see what I can do.
Your grandma's a piece of work.
Oh, Max isn't my grandma.
She's my roommate.
How severe
are her injuries?
Uh, we won't know
until we get her into the O.R.,
but your wife has
lost a lot of blood.
Dr. Bailey, I've been married
to a doctor for five years.
I know when you're hedging.
Please just tell
me what's going on.
Okay, uh, Tia went into cardiac
arrest in the trauma bay,
which forced us to have to
perform an emergency C-section.
We have a team resuscitating
the baby as we speak.
The baby? That's our baby?
Yes. Your baby.
Your... Your son.
I will be on the first flight.
Do whatever you have
to do to save them.
Please. You have my word.
Thank you.
Okay, tell reception to keep
an eye out for Mr. Marwood,
and then scrub in.
Will do.
Thank you.
I'm okay.
Umbilical
lines are in.
First hurdle's cleared.
What's that?
Getting him here alive.
O2 is dropping.
Heart rate's in the
60s, falling fast.
Ambu him.
Yeah, breathing's
equal on both sides.
I'm gonna start
chest compressions.
Okay, little man.
When your mama gets
out of surgery,
she's gonna want to see
you on the other side.
She's been through way too much
for you to give up now, okay?
So I am not gonna
let you give up.
Not today.
Sats are improving.
He's back.
Oh, thank God.
You doing okay over there? Yeah.
I think I held my breath
for that entire time.
That was... Scary?
Abject terror is more like it.
Welcome to the NICU.
What's the best approach
for dural sutures?
Do youknow the best
approach for dural suturing?
Eh, you're fine. And
it's continuous sutures.
Okay.
I got a question for you. Hmm?
Why do you live
with a 90-year-old?
Uh, Maxine is 81,
and I was friends with her
grandson in med school.
She offered to sublet
me her extra room
for a third of what I
would pay anywhere else.
She also makes amazing
matzo ball soup
and I don't have to worry
about being quiet
when I come home late
because she takes her
hearing aids out at night.
It's a win-win.
Hi.
So, her knee's okay?
According to the X-ray, there
is no sign of a fracture.
Told ya. However, there
is a lot of fluid buildup.
I'd like to take a sample to
rule out septic arthritis.
Can I take a look?
You can look at
anything you want.
Hey, easy, Norma.
For God's sake, Norma.
Jules tells me all the time.
We can't talk like that anymore.
Have you seen him?
What do you think, Doc?
These popsicle sticks
got me all the way
to State Championship
back in my majorette days.
Norma's
worse than me.
Okay, you ready to learn
how to aspirate a knee?
Absolutely.Uh. I'll do it.
Concussions to the back.
Okay, we're gonna
tap the knee now.
I'd like to tap that.
Okay.
Oh. Chief Altman!
Can I walk with you?
If you can walk fast.
How are you holding up today?
Today must be a crazy
day to be chief.
I've got Seattle PD
and hospital security
briefing me every minute,
planning for every
possible threat.
You know, I am really
good in a crisis,
but no matter how many times
you've been in literal warfare,
it never gets easier.
Also, I haven't eaten in hours,
and if one more person mentions
"risk assessment"
or "liability,"
I might just walk out of
here and never come back.
Though, I'm kinda feeling
better. Thanks for asking.
Yeah, I was actually going to
ask your advice about something.
So, the Sound Sciencearticle
came out today
about the partial heart
transplant.Congratulations.
Yeah. I'm looking forward to
reading it once things calm down.
Maybe skip the part
where they quoted me
saying that I assembled a team
of highly skilled assistants,
including my husband,
Dr. Winston Ndugu.
Did you say that?
I also said that
he's a highly skilled surgeon
and that it was a 50/50 effort,
but they didn't print that.
Well, now it looks like
you're taking all the credit
and insulting your
husband.Exactly.
Alright, how can I
help you out with this?
Can the hospital ask
for a correction?
Please.
I-I wouldn't ask if
this wasn't urgent.
Okay, I will put a call
into the PR department
once I get through today,
but, Pierce, you really
should talk to your husband.
Owen and I didn't
talk for months,
and it nearly broke us.
Do not wait for the hospital
to issue a statement.
Okay, let's get
started. Sorry I'm late.
Excuse me.
All that chaos
outside, and look at her.
Not a care in the world. Just
putting ears on a potato.
Really shifts your
perspective, doesn't it?
How's she doing?
It's Addison.
She isn't listening to anyone,
including her own body,
so that she can take
care of a patient.
But I know she's in pain
because she's biting her lip,
which is something that she does
when she's trying to distract
herself from something.
Yeah, I know she means a lot to
you. "A lot" doesn't describe it.
I think the universe felt badly
when I got stuck with my
three biological sisters,
so eventually, it gave me
Addison and Meredith and Maggie.
Mm.
They need me in the ICU.
Go. I could stay.
I'll observe her range of motion
and keep an eye out
for that lip bite.
She still needs that
follow-up X-ray, MRI,
and another neurovascular exam.
Amelia...
I've got her.
Dr. Yasuda.
Yeah.
Yasuda, are you okay?
I don't think I am.
- She's decompensating.
- Her spleen's shattered.
Multiple lacerations
to the liver, as well.
Let's prep for a
splenectomy and give her cryo.
You know she was our very first
applicant for the fellowship?
I remember.
In the interview, we told her
we were concerned her pregnancy
could make the
timing challenging
because she was coming all
the way from Tennessee.
Then she said, "I'm
about to become a mother.
What could be more
challenging than that?"
No one could've seen
this coming, Bailey.
Coming here wasn't a
requirement of her program.
But she came anyway,
while pregnant,
because she wanted to
help other pregnant women.
And today, she became a mother.
That's our patient.
That's who we're saving.
She's coding. Hold on, Tia.
Hang more FFP.
Removing the spleen.
Dr. Bailey, it's yours.
It's Tia's husband.
Okay, we'll call
him when we can.
Ugh, she's still
bleeding everywhere.
Her body can't
clot or oxygenate.
Liver's still oozing.
I just need a little more time
to control these bleeders.
- Dr. Bailey.
- Silence it!
- I'm on it.
- How are we, Knox?
She's severely acidotic.
Base deficit is minus 10.
I'm giving TXA.
There's blood in her NG tube.
Her temperature's
dropping fast. Dr. Hunt?
She didn't give up downstairs.
I am not giving up in here.
If we continue operating, she
won't make it out of this O.R.
Look, she's acidotic,
hypothermic, and coagulopathic.
Let's take her to the
ICU and give her a break.
Fine.
Let's pack her.
Give me as much lap
pads as you have.
Let's go, let's go, let's go.
You're okay.
I-I have a patient at
six centimeters, so I...
Yeah, you have to
go. I have to go.
Thank you for coming.
Hey, Jackie.
Um... the cold will help
ground you in the present...
break the shock.
Will you take a look
around this room
and name five
objects that you see?
A bedpan.
That's one.
Stool.
Two.
Lab coat.
Mm-hmm, three.
I am mortified.
I just froze.
Surgeons can't freeze.
You weren't in an O.R.
No, I can't get Tia out of
my head, just lying there.
And I-I just keep thinking that
it could have been any of us.
It could've been me. I'm
a monster for saying it.
You're not.
And do not apologize for your
reaction to a traumatic event.
Today was not normal.
It was violent.
The clinic was attacked.
Youwere attacked.
You didn't sign up for that,
and that is not what this
job is supposed to be.
So, look, take
whatever time you need.
Whatever space. Okay.
That's what makes you human.
What's 64 divided by 8?
Eight. I wasn't asking you.
Don't you have other
patients to bother?
Oh, Norma and Maxine's
prelim test results are in.
We have your initial results.
Uh, Max, would you
like to come with me?
Nonsense.
Whatever you have
to say to one of us,
you can say to both of us.
Are you comfortable with this?
Oh, you know me.
I haven't cared about
propriety since 1986.
You have gonorrhea.
Both of you, if that
wasn't... clear.
Yours settled in your knee.
It's called
gonococcal arthritis.
Uh, gonorrhea is contracted by
having sexual intercourse...
We know how you get it.
We have to ask you to call
all of your sexual partners.
Now?
I-It's advisable to, um, get
anyone who's been exposed
treated regardless of
their test results.
You didn't tell me
you were sleeping with someone.
You didn't tell me, either.
I wanted to, but it's not
exactly the conversation
for the Mahjong table.
Hi. This is Happy Hal.
I'm sorry I missed you.
I'm out on the town
doing my thing.
Please leave your
name and number
and I'll get back to you.
Well, this is awkward.
I thought we might
find you here.
Carina's delivering a baby.
She operated on the
doctor who got hit.
She delivered that
doctor's baby,
and now she's
delivering another baby
and she's a miracle worker.
I don't stop
to think about it enough,
but my wife is a
bringer of life.
I'm sorry, I just needed
to hear her voice.
No, I get it. I get
it. It's a scary day.
Guess this is what
it feels like.
What do you mean?
To be married to us.
When you and I found out
that something had happened
at the clinic, we both ran here.
We had to know that
they were okay.
We had to... Oh.
We had to see it. Yeah.
My stomach literally
went upside down.
Like, I-I felt it turn, like,
I actually might need surgery.
Well, we do that to
them on a daily basis.
God, it feels awful.
We're awful people.
But they knew what they were
getting into, though, right?
I think Carina did.
Bailey married you when
you were still a doctor.
Okay, vitals look good.
He looks stable for now.
Griffith, you need a break?
I mean, I'm kinda the one who
got hit by a car over here.
Sorry. I just...
I was in here when I was born.
In the NICU? In thisNICU.
My mom was somewhere on another
floor, fighting for her life.
And I'm just...
amazed.
Amazed by what?
Someone like you
did this for me.
Someone like you saved my life.
He's bradycardic.
Start chest compressions
and keep 'em coming.
No breath sounds. Ambu him.
Sats are dropping.
Do we need an X-ray?
There's no time for that.
Give me your pen light.
Wh... Wh... Ask questions
later, Griffith.
Okay, and turn that
light off. Now.
See how this side lights
up and this side doesn't?
He's got a pneumothorax. I need
a 22-gauge needle and a syringe.
Hurry, please.
Go ahead.
10 cc's of air.
And I have breath sounds.
Heart rate's coming up.
Sats are normalizing.
Are you okay? I'm fine.
Can you get an oscillator
and prep for a chest tube
and give him another
dose of surfactant?
Okay.
No, I've got this, Wilson.
Y-You go check up on
your other patients.
Are you sure? Because
I-I know that she just...
I'm sure.
Okay.
Hi. You've
reached Brandon Marwood.
Please leave a message.
Uh, y... Mr. Marwood, uh, it's
Dr. Bailey from Grey-Sloan.
I know you're on a plane right
now, but I have an update.
Tia has been
transferred to the ICU.
We're gonna let her
rest for a few hours,
and then take her
back to the O.R.
and finish repairing
her injuries.
Um... we'll be right
here waiting for you.
I won't leave her side.
So, she'syour Tuesday night
"standing canasta game"? Oh!
And she's your "Well,
I'll just go take a nap
in the community room"?
Ladies, please.
You said you didn't
even like blondes!
She's not a natural blonde.
I am so!
Okay, Max, calm down, calm down.
Norma, you calm down, too.
Hal, if you could
just sit by Dr. Kwan.
Sir, your results
should be back soon,
but we'd like to give
you the shot anyway
because you're
likely the... source.
That's impossible. I
am healthy as a horse!
The most common STD symptoms
are often no symptoms at all.
Oh, my God. You'll need to
contact your sexual partners.
All of 'em?
Yes. Hal.
Oh, geez.
Uh...
Hazel Rothman, Judy Booth...
Oh, yeah. Martha
from water aerobics.
Not Martha!
She's 98!
You're an ageist!
And you're a liar!
You son of a bitch!
And you're a filthy liar, and
you're not even that good in bed.
This is officially an outbreak.
Contact the housing
manager and let them know
that the residents are spreading
gonorrhea and need tests.
And condoms. But
Millin lives there.
Can't she just leave a note on
the social halls or something?
I don't care. Just
somebody let them know.
Sooner rather than later.
It's remarkable. Hmm.
It's the resilience,
the will to live.
Yeah. Never ceases
to amaze me.
Tia? Stable, for now.
And Dr. Lincoln is
waiting for you.
Yeah. Tell him
I'll be there soon.
Yeah, see, he said you'd say
that, and that I should say
if you want to operate again,
"soon" should be... now.
And then, he said that if I
couldn't get you to come out,
he'd make me pay for it.
Personally. Oh, my God.
Alright. I'm coming. Just...
page me if anything
changes, immediately.
Uh, mind if I stay with Connor?
I-I heard Tia tell Dr. Wilson
they were gonna name him Connor.
Hi, Connor.
What do you need, Yasuda?
Sorry I disappeared.
Did I miss anything?
Right.
Could I sit with
her for a minute?
Let you take a break,
grab some coffee?
No. Oh, um...
Okay. Then I'm... I'm...
No, she's hypotensive
and slightly tachy.
She's still bleeding
from her abdomen.
Oh, look at the wound vac.
Okay, uh, call the O.R.
Get the team up
here. Get over here.
S-Shouldn't we be taking
her back to the O.R.?
No time.
Y-Yasuda.
If I'm going to open this
woman up, I need your hands.
We're opening her up here?
We need to move, right now!
You'll have to wear the
sling for about four weeks,
but keep your elbow,
wrist, and hand moving.
It'll help.
And don't ignore
the PT exercises
no matter how exhausted you get.
Honestly, it...
it wouldn't be a terrible idea
to take a break from the
road for a couple of weeks.
Thank you.
It's me.
Talk to me.
You know, the irony...
of all of this is
that these people
are targeting me for
the abortion care
that I provide
when that is actually the
least common procedure
I am doing in the PRT.Mm.
I'm mostly providing
wellness checks,
prenatal care, annual...
pelvic exams, pap smears.
Since so many
clinics have closed
in the last several months,
I'm the only option they have.
It's exhausting.
It's a disaster.
Hmm.
And I can't take a break.
If I take a break, I mean,
who... who's gonna do the work?
When he suggested
that you take a break,
I thought you were gonna
throw the tablet at him.
Oh, I almost did.
What happened?
Wound vac was
soaked with blood.
She's still bleeding out.
I found it. It's the liver.
What do you want to do?
Uh, Pringle maneuver. Bedside?
Atraumatic clamps, please.
Yasuda, put your hand
where my hand is.
You're gonna hold
the bleeding here
while Wilson clamps the
blood flow to the liver.
Then I will try and
control the bleeding.
Come on, come on.
Follow my hand.
Okay. Yeah. Here, I'll help.
Alright, alright. Like that?
Exactly like that.
Okay, go, Wilson.Okay.
Hepatoduodenal
ligament is clamped.
Okay, good. O-chromic
liver suture.
Great. Okay, alright.
Alright, I'm going deep.
I see it.
Okay, pressure's climbing.
Okay, scissors.
Okay, let's pack her and
get a new wound vac.Okay.
Not yet, Tia.
Too many people need you.
No sexual activity for a week.
We want to give the antibiotics
time to do their job.
You already told me, dear.
And I heard it when
you told Norma and Hal.
Just making sure. Can't
have a sick roomie.
Who else is gonna make me
the world's best French toast
when I work the night shift?
It's all about a
drop of vanilla.
And I'm sorry that Hal
turned out to be such a jerk.
Me too. Guys can be pigs.
Gay ones, too.
Women can be...
At first, they tell us
not to have sex at all
and that we're sluts
if we enjoy it.
And then they tell us
if we get pregnant,
we must carry the
baby no matter what.
And once we're mothers,
whether by force or by choice,
they judge us for that, too.
Because there's certainly no
way to be a perfect mother.
So, as women, we get
judged and attacked
for every single
decision we ever make.
You want to know the
upside of this misogyny,
this patriarchy?
Women become invisible
around the age of 60,
and then you can do
whatever the hell you like,
including having a lot of great
sex, because no one cares.
And now, I have an
antibiotic and no regrets.
Except, perhaps, for waiting
so long to live my best life.
See you at home, dear.
Winston, I...
They cherry-picked my quotes,
took everything out of context.
But I'm making them change
it, and Teddy will help.
But you said it, so...
I also said that you were one
of the most brilliant surgeons
I have ever worked with, and
that we were equal partners.
We came up with that
procedure together.
I-I didn't even get
a mention.
Just one of the "assistants."
Journalists always
want to characterize me
as some kind of wunderkind
in a league of my own.
And it's just
clickbait. That's it.
Okay, so it's the
journalist's fault.
Winston, I... Take
some responsibility.
For once!
I can't control what other
people write about me.
Alright.
When did we stop giving each
other the benefit of the doubt?
I think it's when you
said you don't respect me.
And this article
reallydrives that home.
I want to fix this.
Tell me what to do to fix this.
I want to fix us.
Maggie, there's no fix.
T-There's just...
There's feelings.
Like, my God, say you're sorry.
Say you
got some things wrong.
Say you didn't mean to hurt me.
Say you understand how I feel.
Say you love me and mean it.
Say you respect me and mean it.
I respect you, Winston.
I don't believe you.
Dr. Sellers, 4619.
Dr. Mari Sellers, 4619
Hey.
They caught the driver.
They lifted the
hospital lockdown,
and if you want to
keep the clinic closed
for a couple days,
everyone would understand.
It'll be open tomorrow morning.
Dr. Bailey.
This is Brandon
Marwood, Tia's husband.
Sh... Is she, uh...
Is she gonna live?
Well, she's stable, for now.
We are giving her fluid and
putting her on sedation breaks
to monitor her brain function.
After all that she's been
through, there's no guarantees,
but we are hopeful
that she will wake up.
Okay. If Tia has shown
us anything today,
it's she's strong
and determined.
Yeah. She always has been.
Wanna go in and sit with her?
Yeah. Okay.
Tests and algorithms
don't tell the whole story.
They're snapshots in time.
♪ Time is a wheel
that is spinning ♪
♪ Always moving on
♪ The moments you
think last forever ♪
♪ You look up and one
day they're gone ♪
♪ Gotta hold on, hold on
There's not a roadmap for
every uncertainty we meet.
♪ I see little
glimmers of heaven ♪
♪ From the waves to my
own daughter's eyes ♪
♪ Of all the things
this life could offer ♪
With some things, we just
have to wait and see.
♪ Than to hold on, hold on
♪ Gotta hold on, hold on
Tia will wake up.
I hope so.
And that baby is gonna
come out of the NICU.
I hope that, too.
Well, you don't have to hope
'cause I have enough
hope for both of us.
Well, you need any
money, food, or...?
What?
I'm not going off to college.
♪ Give it all your
heart and soul ♪
Thank you for coming.
♪ They'll be gone
before you know ♪
Time to sweep up the glass
and get back to work.
Please be safe out there.
♪ Everything we're looking for
♪ Has been in our
reach all along ♪
♪ All we gotta do is listen
We have to reach
down inside ourselves
and find that last
piece of strength...
♪ Let it stop you and behold
♪ 'Cause it's
something beautiful ♪
♪ Gold
♪ All the little
seconds that we hold ♪
Tia! Tia! Tia!
I'm right here,
baby. I'm right here.
C-Can you hear me?
Is he...
Is he... Is he okay?
No, no, Connor's okay.
He's okay, babe. He's okay.
You've... seen... Seen him?
I saw him.
He is so beautiful.
He's so beautiful.
♪ From the morning
to the midnight ♪
♪ From the high roads
to the low tide ♪
♪ Feel it all 'cause
it's all part of it ♪
♪ Yeah, we watch
it as it goes by ♪
♪ Then we look back
and we realize ♪
♪ Every minute was
all just a gift ♪
You don't have to
hold it in anymore.
♪ Gold
♪ All the little seconds...
I'm right here.
♪ ...that we hold
♪ Every picture in our
mind we get to take ♪
♪ Don't let one get away
♪ Give it all your
heart and soul ♪
♪ They'll be gone
before you know ♪
♪ So treasure it like gold
as impossible as
it can be to find.
We have to rise to
meet the occasion...
♪ Cause it's
something beautiful ♪
Someone wanted to meet you.
Hi, Connor.
Hi, my sweet love.
♪ Every single breath
we get to take ♪
♪ Don't let them go to waste
♪ Give it all your
heart and soul ♪
♪ They'll be gone
before you know ♪
♪ So treasure it like gold
♪ From the morning
to the midnight ♪
♪ From the high roads
to the low tide ♪
♪ Feel it all 'cause
it's all part of it ♪
♪ Yeah, we watch
it as it goes by ♪
♪ Then we look back
and we realize ♪
♪ Every minute was
all just a gift ♪
♪ Gold
♪ All the little
seconds that we hold ♪
♪ Every picture in our mind...
We have to rise to keep going.
♪ Don't let one get away
♪ Give it all your
heart and soul ♪
♪ They'll be gone
before you know ♪
♪ So treasure it like gold