I'm thinking we
put the tub here.
That way, you can take a bath,
look out the window at the trees.
But that means we have
to move the sink here,
because there's no way we
can get two sinks on that wall.
- OK.
- OK, so do you
want me to move the tub
- or do you want
to share a sink?
- I... have one opinion.
And that is that I just
want a tub deep enough
that covers my
knees and my boobs.
Knees and boobs
at the same time.
- I gotta go. You're useless. Love you.
- Mmm.
The dude's building
you a dream house.
I can't read these
stupid things.
- You just don't give a crap.
- I'm taking baby drugs
to make my uterus less hostile.
I don't know, it makes my eyes
dry, and I have to squint to see, and...
I don't really care enough about the
tub-sink relationship to, you know...
You should talk to that hot OB.
You are always drumming up
reasons to talk to that hot OB.
Everyone figures doctors are the
most responsible people they know.
They hold lives in their
hands, they're not flakes.
They don't lose track
of important details,
or make stunningly
bad judgment calls.
'Cause that would be bad. Right?
- Look!
- Nice size.
- Good looking placenta.
- Is that an arm?
- Yep.
- Aww.
All good. Did you
schedule an amnio yet?
We don't need an amnio.
- Um... We don't?
- Of course we do. We'll set it up.
- Why do we need an amnio?
- I can think of a hundred
reasons why.
You want me to take 'em
down one by one or all together?
It's so nice that
there are three of you.
I gotta go.
Don't let her shove a
giant needle in your belly
- before we discuss this.
- It's not giant.
Nine inches.
OK. So I'm really
sorry about this.
But with a clinical trial,
the paperwork never ends.
Have there been any changes to
your memory in the last week or so?
I don't think it's worse.
I went to see Dr. Kesten,
and couldn't figure out what floor
he's on, but that's always the case.
Well, that place is a maze.
Did you have a problem
or was that scheduled?
No, he's the one who
first diagnosed me.
And I was kind of angry when
he said it was Alzheimer's.
I... I called him a quack. I
figured I should apologize.
Well, I'm sure
he gets that a lot.
Have there been any changes in
your schedule in the last week or so?
I don't work.
And... I get lost on the
way to the post office,
- so I don't do so many errands.
- - So how about your sleeping
- and your eating?
- Well, we have breakfast
together
before the boys leave.
And lunch...
Well, I... I'm not home till
pretty late, so I don't know...
Half a peanut butter
and banana sandwich.
I make one when we
get home, and we share it.
OK. And how about the
drugs, any side effects?
- No.
- OK.
- The pink ones
make you thirsty.
- Dry mouth. Yeah.
And water helps with that?
- Yeah.
- OK. Very good.
Ricky. Big day.
- Bring it on.
- Is this your sister?
This is my girlfriend. Julia.
You're kidding! He's been
talking about you for months.
I figure if there's ever
a day to take off work,
it's when your boyfriend's
getting new lungs.
Smart. She waited
for the real fun.
All right, let's do this.
Well, your new lungs should
leave Portland in about two hours.
You haven't taken any of your cystic
fibrosis meds since last night, right?
- No food, no water, no drugs.
- Great.
So we'll just do one last workup
and then we'll get you to the OR.
And Julia, write down your number,
please, and give it to Dr. Grey.
- Why?
- So we can call you
when Ricky's in surgery
if we have any news.
When was the last time you
put in an application to the FDA?
- It's been a while.
- Well, it would have to be,
because if you had any
recollection of what's involved,
then you wouldn't interrupt me in the middle
of compiling 357 pages of an application.
Do you know how easy it is
to lose one page out of 357?
- It's gotta be quite easy.
- They look for reasons to kill
a study.
Do you know what they
consider a good reason?
- A missing...
- One missing page.
Now, you're a smart man, Hunt.
You have leadership potential.
Management potential. I mean,
I think you shy away from that.
- That may well be, sir.
- You can handle a VIP patient.
If you don't mention
the chief of surgery,
they won't ask for the chief of
surgery. Did you mention me?
- I think I did, sir.
- Why would you do that?
- Did you not know
about my application?
- I didn't think...
Then what on earth
were you thinking?
Your wife, sir. That's
what I was thinking.
Just when you thought you
were done, we need more blood.
If there's any
left, it's all yours.
Well, Dr. Shepherd is going to
come up and take a look at you,
and if these labs are clean, we're
gonna move you up to the OR floor.
Hey. Let's keep our fingers crossed and
hope that Mom gets the good stuff, OK?
OK.
Hey, Kyle, what's
this on your neck?
That's just my bump. It
doesn't hurt or anything.
We've been meaning to
make an appointment, but...
with everything
that's been going on...
I'm a full-time job.
You're not, OK? I
should have called.
Well, we have doctors
coming out of our ears here.
So I'll have someone
come up and take a look.
It's just one less
thing to worry about.
- Thank you.
- OK.
I was in the cereal aisle, and I
tripped on one of those big displays.
Fruit spreads or some nonsense,
and the whole thing came down.
Lido and an epi,
please, 5-0 prolene.
It's a cut, Mark, you
don't have to show off.
You can give me a couple of
Band-Aids and be on your way.
- Yeah, that's not
how this is gonna go.
- You tripped on the display,
or you tripped over your feet
and fell into the thing, or...?
The chronology
escapes me, Richard.
I was more focused on
the fact that there was jam
and shard glass all over
my coat and my pants,
and the pants of the store manager,
who would not leave me alone
until he packed me away
into an ambulance! Ow!
- This whole thing
is just ridiculous!
- This is twice, honey.
- Your wrist...
- It's those shoes!
They are supposed to tone your
derriere, but I cannot feel the ground
when I walk on them. I am
going to throw them away.
If someone would just give me a
couple of Band-Aids, I can be on my...
- You're not going anywhere.
- If you make a big fuss about
this...
Mrs. Webber, I'm about
to put a needle in your face.
I'd be extremely grateful
if you'd stop moving.
- Did they come by
with the forms?
- I think I signed 200 of them.
That sounds about right.
You just gave us your first born.
- You need a drink of water,
Julia?
- Just...
- asthma. Sorry.
- Nothing brings people together
- like respiratory disorders.
- Romantic!
- Dornase?
- It's mine.
It has Julia's name on it.
- Rick, why is she on dornase?
- I'm gonna go.
Wait, Julia. Do you
have cystic fibrosis?
- Go!
- No, wait a minute. OK? Nobody's going anywhere.
You know how dangerous cystic
fibrosis patients are to each other?
- We know.
- - Your disease isn't contagious
to anybody in the general
population. It's not like you can't date,
you just can't... You
can't date each other!
You can infect each
other with bacteria,
- there's no way you can fight!
- We know!
You know how many times
we've heard the warnings?
Never get closer than three
feet from another CF patient.
It's a drag, OK? There's
no question, I get it.
No, you don't. Ricky
gets it. Nobody else gets it.
We both tried dating,
people can't handle it.
People cringe as soon as you start
coughing, like you're gonna kill them.
- This is dangerous.
- - Depression is dangerous.
Living by yourself,
with nobody who understands
you, that's dangerous.
We spent eight years
making small talk
on opposite sides of a
doctor's waiting room.
And one day, we
decided that life with risk...
was better than
not really living.
We deserve to be together.
- Kepner! You're on Peds today?
- Yeah, some kid already puked
on me.
OK, so one of my patient's
son has a lump on his neck.
So would you just do a workup on him,
if it's anything, kick it up to Robbins?
Fine. You owe me one.
- No, I don't.
- I'm doing you a favor,
you owe me one.
You're doing your job. I owe
you gratitude and respect.
I already had your respect.
Ah, hmm...
- Give Yang all your
patients today.
- I have an SMA embolectomy.
Well, I'll take your embolectomy,
Yang can take the rest.
- You take my wife.
- Now I want my embolectomy
even more than I did before.
She's fallen and ended up in my
ER, twice. Maybe it's an inner ear thing
affecting her balance. Maybe
it's a pinched nerve. I don't know.
All I know is you're going to
run every test that has a name.
I was looking forward
to my embolectomy.
Everyone's unhappy.
Get in here.
- You paged me?
- Yeah, I need you
to check my eyes.
I'm not an eye guy, I don't
know how this crap works.
Well, I already did the
chart, I'm like 20/25.
But I... now I need you to look
at my eyes through this thing.
Maybe it's glaucoma. Hey, you
could get a prescription for pot.
All right. Look up.
Look down. Doesn't
look like glaucoma.
- Your cornea looks fine.
- Good.
Yeah, but you still
can't read the chart.
- Yeah, but if I squint...
- Normal people don't squint,
all right?
Read the chart. Line eight.
No squinting.
D, C, P, I.
- You're blind.
- Shut up.
Can you even see me?
Yeah, and you look
like a real moron.
- I need a real eye doctor.
- Can you even see enough
to operate?
When I do the squinting thing, I
see fine. Don't quit your day job.
You keep squinting like that,
you're gonna get crow's feet.
But I'm good at plastics. You
want me to do something about that?
I've lost too many babies in my time.
Addison terminated, Sloan disappeared.
I'm not letting it happen again, I
don't care what kind of baby it is.
You can't be glib about this. A
special-needs baby can be a very sick baby.
We could be talking about a lifetime of
surgeries and hospital stays and pain.
It's not all hugging and
the Special Olympics.
Amnios come with
risks, too. One in some...
not insignificant number
result in miscarriage.
One in 300.
She's not 45, the Down's rate
isn't all that high in women her age.
Can... Can we have a
minute? Can I just...?
- There's no pulling anybody
aside.
- We have a relationship, Mark.
- Part of that
doesn't include you.
- She's carrying my kid.
She gets a minute,
then I get a minute, too.
You know what? No
one gets a minute!
I have a patient. The
patient gets a minute.
I've got a friend who can't see,
and she thinks it may
be her fertility meds.
- Your friend?
- You think I'm making it up?
You're looking for
reasons to talk to me.
Because the last time we spoke,
you asked me out and I said no.
So now you're
taking my temperature
to see if I was actually
busy or just not interested.
You can't ask me out again, not after
what you perceive to be a rejection,
because even though your
whole rap is about confidence,
you're about as
self-assured as a Chihuahua.
Your friend, she doesn't need
my help. If she did, she'd call me.
So I should just
ask you out again?
It's a lot simpler,
don't you think?
- You free for dinner?
- No. Busy.
At first I thought it
was a benign cyst,
but it looks like it's
probably a cystic hygroma.
Wow. The trachea
is starting to close off.
Well, I'll move your diverticulectomy,
or maybe Dr. Stark has time for it.
- Dr. Stark has time for what?
- I've got a diverticulectomy.
We were hoping
that you could take it.
'Cause this hygroma needs
to come out right away.
Oh, good Lord. Why did you wait
so long? This thing is a time bomb.
We just saw the patient
for the first time today.
So what? The parents
don't have health insurance?
They do.
Well, why didn't they
get this kid to a doctor?
Kyle's mother has Alzheimer's.
She was diagnosed a few months ago.
And the father has been working like
a dog so their insurance doesn't lapse.
Kyle's taking care of his mom as
much as anyone's taking care of him.
- They're just
underwater right now.
- Yeah. All right.
- Call Protective Services.
- What?
At least one of you here
understood that, right?
You can't take Kyle
away from his parents.
You just told me they're
not caring for their son.
They are dealing with an
extraordinary set of circumstances.
This happens all the time.
That's why the state set up a
whole department to deal with it.
I've got three specialists on their way in
here to look at a tumor. So I need this room.
- Dr. Stark...
- You've got a surgery
to perform,
assuming the patient's
airway has not already closed.
If it has, well, he's probably dead, and
then, yeah, nobody has to call anybody, right?
- You have to call him off.
- We can call a social worker,
have him go in and say
hello, ask if they need any help.
- It'll placate him.
- No!
Because once you're in the
system, it'll only get worse.
You're registered as a parent
who neglects his kid. It's over!
- You have to call him off!
- He's my boss.
Believe me, I like it
way less than you do.
This family just lost the
ground under their feet.
No one likes the idea of a
ten-year-old taking care of his mother,
but they're doing the best they
can. Maybe Derek's drug helps her,
or she could get the
placebo, and in 18 months,
she doesn't even know who Kyle is. We can't
let their last couple of years together
become some nightmare where they're
fighting to keep Kyle in their house.
- It's enough of a
nightmare already.
- We'll talk to him.
So he shoots us down.
Can't hurt to try, right?
You need me to take your diverticulectomy
while you remove the boy's mass.
Right? My assistant knows my schedule
better than me, just check with her.
We think calling Protective
Services is a bad idea.
Kyle's mother may not
have a lot of lucid time.
These years are gonna be
difficult, but it's all the family has.
- So pulling them apart...
- Do you know when
Protective Services
pulls families apart? When
the children are in danger.
When the children aren't in danger,
they go away. They do something else.
They can have a knee-jerk
reaction to certain circumstances.
- Do you think they're idiots?
- I am sure that they are not.
- Heartless wretches?
- No.
Pediatric surgeons can be heartless wretches.
Some would argue that I'm a case in point.
But social workers, on the
other hand, are bleeding hearts.
They're earning peanuts,
doing this thankless work,
and then they get painted
as what? Homewreckers,
for simply stepping in when
children are being harmed.
But the boy is not being harmed.
And you're sure
about that, right?
You're 100 percent sure?
No shadow of a doubt there?
Ah. That must be
a nice feeling, huh?
Why don't you be a good
example for your residents.
- Make the call.
- Mmm.
What are you writing?
- Dr. Bailey.
- I'm writing about your ears.
- What about them?
- There's nothing wrong
with them.
- Well, then can I go home now?
- No, ma'am.
We are wasting everyone's time.
I tripped at the pharmacy,
I have faulty shoes.
I should not be trying
to tone my derriere.
That flavor of vanity is
unbecoming in a woman my age.
- The supermarket.
- Excuse me?
You tripped at the
supermarket, not the pharmacy.
Whatever.
The pharmacy aisle. I
needed some cough syrup.
You don't have a cough.
Can you breathe
into this tube for me?
I've had an alcoholic
husband long enough.
I know a breathalyzer
when I see one.
Just breathe into
the tube, please.
My husband sent you in here
to test me for inner ear problems
- and balance issues.
- You don't have inner ear
problems.
You don't have balance
issues. You are having accidents,
and you are inconsistent with
your description of the accidents,
and those behaviors are consistent with
substance abuse. So I will run a tox screen,
I'd like a list of the prescription
drugs in your possession,
and I need you to
breathe into this tube.
The miscarriage rate is low. It's
even lower with wildly talented OB's.
And we have
wildly talented OB's.
- It's a risk no matter
who does it.
- OK, you know what?
I'm trying to eat, which is more
important than it's ever been now
because I'm an incubator. OK?
I know what each of you thinks,
I'm weighing the
options, I will decide.
- You'll decide?
- Yes, I'm the tie breaker.
And anyhow, I have the bigger
vote, because, as we've discussed,
I vote on behalf of the
baby and on behalf of the...
- Vagina. Right.
- Yeah.
That's not gonna cut it, OK?
We're co-parenting. All
of us. This isn't a joke.
It's not some cute arrangement
where you humor me
and use me for baby-sitting
when you want to see a movie.
This is my child. We're
doing this together.
You don't get a bigger
vote. I'm a parent!
Daddy's mad.
So he says we're only gonna
have one sink in the bathroom,
like he's hurting me.
Why do you need two?
Well, 'cause men leave
wads of toothpaste in the sink,
and when you have your own
sink, you don't have to look at it,
all dried and congealed and filled
with their fossilized oral bacteria.
I leave toothpaste in the sink.
You're supposed to rinse
it every time you brush?
Nobody parented you.
This is to be expected.
You're really gonna move
out and sell your house?
- You gonna miss me?
- I'm gonna miss having
a cheap place to live.
You know, I have trouble seeing fine print,
but I can still see your paws on my food.
Ooh.
The fact the two of you haven't
swapped a life-threatening
infection already is a miracle.
So maybe God has a
soft spot for you guys,
but once this transplant is done,
Ricky will be on immunosuppressants.
Ten times more likely
to get an infection.
Lots of things are risky.
- This is suicide.
- You don't know that.
It doesn't mean anything
to you. You've been happy.
We've been sick our whole lives.
Don't we deserve some happiness?
- You'll get it.
- Don't act like it's easy,
with your gorgeous eyes and
your white coat. It's insulting.
I won't tell you it's easy.
It's not.
But people need these lungs.
People can use these
lungs for decades.
Parents with small children. Teenagers
who are just starting their lives.
If the two of you stay together, you
could destroy those lungs within months.
These lungs are a
gift. If you squander it...
What we have is a gift.
Do you love someone?
If you do, you know.
It's rare. And it's a gift.
End the relationship, or
you don't get the lungs.
So it's a cyst. And it's
pushing on Kyle's airway,
so we should remove
it as soon as possible.
But once it's out, he'll be
fine. And Dr. Robbins is great.
Also, a social worker
may be coming by,
just to talk to you and see
how things have been going.
- Is that part
of the clinical trial?
- No.
- It's more of a
formality than anything.
- Yeah. Thank you, but no.
If it's part of the
experiment, we should do...
No. They're worried about Kyle,
OK? It's not part of the experiment.
What? Why? Kyle's fine.
You just said that he's...
- If we refuse, what happens?
- Wait. What's wrong with Kyle?
They think that we're
not taking care of him.
I'm fine. I don't need anything!
- What are you doing?
- No, Allison.
- I don't wanna do this.
- Allison, honey.
I don't wanna
stay here. I don't.
Allison. Stay in the bed!
I don't want them
to touch my son!
- I understand, but...
- I don't want this!
We are taking care of our son!
I don't want to be
here! I want to go home!
Listen, you need this
surgery. This is our chance!
- Don't let them touch our son!
- All right...
Please, just take me home!
She loves Johnny Cash.
He does this. It
always calms her down.
I need an answer. Is it over?
Yeah.
It's over.
OK.
You need to say goodbye.
- Right now.
- This minute?
We need to prep you, and
then cut your chest open.
So yes, this minute.
Hey, Meredith.
What was the deal with Adele Webber
when you saw her a few weeks back?
- She fractured her wrist.
- Yeah, but you ordered a head
CT.
- Just to be sure,
and it was clear.
- OK, I read the file.
What I'm asking for is a more
complete impression of the patient.
I myself just accused her of
being either a wino or a junkie,
and that seems not to be the
case, 'cause the tox screen is clear
and so was the breathalyzer. So
I'm wondering what the hell's going on.
She fell down, and she
couldn't get her story straight.
I tried to talk to the chief,
and he got very angry with me
because I suggested that there
was some indication of early dementia.
He thinks because I'm on Derek's
study, that I see Alzheimer's everywhere.
- Hmm.
- Are you concerned?
Yeah.
Did you really call
the chief's wife a wino?
My finest moment.
I am so grateful you're
not trying to knock me up.
You're welcome.
The Three Musketeers are all
freaked out about having an amnio.
And Meredith is getting shot
up every day with fertility drugs.
It is a nightmare, the
whole thing. And all for what?
To sign up for two years of
sleep deprivation and feces?
I'm so happy we're never
gonna have to deal with that.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Well... I want the amnio.
I just... I want to have the
information, whatever it is.
That doesn't mean I'm
gonna act on it, but just... I...
Whatever the situation
is, I want to know about it.
OK. Thank you.
W...
- That's it?
- I just wanted her
to think about it.
I wanted all of us to
really think about it.
And you did. There's
three of us, I got outvoted.
As long as my 33
percent is considered,
and nobody's body parts
get more of a vote than I do,
that's all I can ask for.
All right. Allison,
the anesthetic is in.
I just need to make a slight incision,
and we should be good to go. OK?
Yep.
All right, good. Want to celebrate
by drilling some burr holes?
- I would love to.
- OK, on the black mark.
Easy in, easy out.
OK. Ready?
What's the matter?
Just go ahead and start.
- I can't.
- You can't what?
I can't see it.
They're lying. She's just gonna
lay low for a couple weeks,
and then they're
gonna get back together
and destroy this perfectly
good pair of lungs.
She's probably
still in the hospital.
- You want
to stop the transplant?
- It's too late.
The lungs are on their way,
the clock's already ticking.
Maybe it'll be OK.
Maybe it's not a waste.
They love each other. It is
rare. What if they are soul mates?
- You're thinking
about Sloan again.
- No! Why?
He told Callie that he would be
happy to raise a special needs child.
He's a good man. I didn't think
about it when I walked away,
- I just got mad and I walked.
- You did think about it.
- You think about everything.
- OK. What if I was wrong?
You really want to be dating a
guy, two women and a baby?
- OK... Well, that sounds bad.
- You think?
- Doctor.
- Yeah?
I said I'm never having kids,
and you said, "Yeah, yeah, yeah".
What exactly does
"yeah, yeah, yeah" mean?
Of course you don't want to
have kids. You're a resident.
I felt the same when
I was starting out.
So I figure we could revisit
this conversation down the line.
- We already discussed this.
- Yes, but people change.
And it's possible, in a couple
years, you'll come around.
When have you ever
known me to come around?
The idea that your career
is the only thing that
will ever matter to you
is, frankly, a young
person's notion.
And after what you've been
through these last few months,
I would have thought
you had more...
nuanced vision of this
whole thing already.
So you assumed that
I was gonna grow up,
and that I'm going to get over
my childish vision of my life?
That's one way to
put it. I also thought
that you might find a little
room for my vision of life.
Well, I've grown up
as much as I plan to,
and I don't "come around".
- Dr. Avery?
- Ready?
- Yep. Out they come. OK.
- Got it.
Got it? All right, pickups.
And Potts scissors.
Dr. Grey, bring 'em over.
They're beautiful.
He wastes these, I
swear to God, I'll kill him.
Are you still gonna
love me if I'm blind,
or does it all go out the window
if I'm not a surgeon anymore?
It's not funny. I don't know
how you went into my OR
- and didn't say anything.
- It wasn't intentional.
It started out as
fuzziness in the morning,
and then I didn't
see the big black spot
until I started staring
at Allison's skull.
Metzger's gonna meet
you in ophthalmology
as soon as he's out of
surgery. He could be a while,
so cancel the rest of your day.
And you need to stop the
fertility drugs right away.
I can't. There's two
pills left in this cycle.
My egg's about to
drop. I can't stop now.
Yes, you can. You know all
the scary side effects they list
on the side of the box? One
of them's happening to you.
We need to make sure this doesn't
permanently damage your eyesight.
This cycle's over.
I had a feeling I'd find you here.
The lungs are in. So far, so good.
- Are you gonna
tell her I'm here?
- Dr. Altman? No.
No, I'm pretty sure
you're gonna leave.
Here's the thing.
You're killing him.
You're taking a
gun and killing him.
And there is nothing
romantic about a joint suicide.
It's cruel.
To you, to him, to your parents,
and to the family that
just buried someone.
Those lungs are gorgeous.
You can't do this.
It always feels like
there is just one person
in this world to love.
And then you find somebody else,
and it just seems crazy that you
were ever worried in the first place.
You'll tell him he
has to find someone?
He really has to try, 'cause...
I don't want him to be alone.
Hey.
Allison Baker is in
Dr. Shepherd's Alzheimer's trial.
She has to have follow-up visits
every two weeks for the next three years.
We'll make Kyle come every time.
I will do the exam
myself, every two weeks.
Look, Kyle, he's not
just loved, he's cherished.
I would like you to consider putting a
pin in the call to Protective Services.
I thought you
already made the call.
- We didn't.
- Oh.
OK.
Excuse me?
Better not stay too
long, I might reconsider.
- Run away, Dr. Kepner.
- OK.
She's gone.
For real. I don't
know how to tell him.
If I had to hear something like
that, I'd want to hear it from you.
- Everything's clear.
- Good.
- She's just got two left feet.
- Could be. I didn't check for
that.
Sir, something's clearly wrong.
Dr. Bailey, when you're rolling
down the far side of the hill,
things fall apart.
Look. If it was me, and my
wife was suddenly accident prone
and losing track of details, I
wouldn't ask the general surgeon
who's only been an attending
for a year to check her out.
I'd ask the neuro guy.
The very fancy, extremely
good neurosurgeon,
who happens to be studying
neurological disorders like Alzheimer's.
Who happens to
be a close friend.
That's who I'd ask.
But that's just me.
Just wanted to make
sure you were all right.
Ricky's not, that's for sure.
I told Julia that she'd
find somebody else, but...
- I'm not sure I believed it.
- She will.
- What if he's her...?
- Soul mate?
You gotta be kidding
me with this crap, Lexie.
Nobody has just one soul mate.
That'd be such a dumb system.
Look, Ricky and Julia deserve better
than someone who makes them sick.
You deserve better, too.
There is more than one
soul mate for everyone.
And someone like you?
There'd be a line out the
door, as soon as word got out.
Would you be in the line?
Yeah.
I'm in line.
I think I have veto power.
I think you don't bring a
human being into this world
if one of the parties, like
the mother, doesn't want it.
- What's there left to discuss?
- All right. Let me get this
straight.
You've made a decision,
and I have no say.
Zero. So, what if I
think having a family
is a huge part of what
it means to be alive?
Well, then you married the wrong
person. You know, maybe you did.
I mean, it was hasty. I was a PTSD
wasteoid, shivering on the couch. I...
- Maybe we didn't think this through.
- - Stop it.
You don't get to pull
that crap with me.
We got married, not because
you were a basket case,
but because we loved each
other and we wanted a life together.
So you don't get to
threaten walking out
just because I had the
gall to express an opinion
that is different to yours.
You need to think about it.
You have an obligation to at least
pretend that you care what the hell I want.
Oh, these are all done,
there's just two more.
- I'd like you
to join me for dinner.
- Come again?
- Dinner.
- Right now?
No, I already ate. I'm just
saying, some other night.
- Like...
- You know. I mean, a date.
Did you say you wouldn't
call Child Services
- because you wanted
to go out with me?
- No.
No, actually, I wanted
to go out with you
because you convinced
me not to call Child Services.
And nobody's changed
my mind in... ten years.
Is that a selling point?
It cuts both ways,
no doubt about it.
If I say no, will you stop
giving me surgeries?
No. Come on, that's sexual
harassment. That's not my style.
Look, just think it over. If
the answer's no, that's fine.
I mean, we'll probably have
to avoid eye contact for a while,
but, I mean, we can
still work together.
Anyway, think about it.
I gotta tell you, I was
impressed with Mark today.
He... He is really being
an adult about all this.
- I think he's gonna
be a great dad!
- Yeah.
- Right?
- It'll work.
You didn't think it
was that impressive.
Sure. He handled it.
And not like a four-year-old. Is
that supposed to make me excited?
I thought I was supposed to
be the cranky hormonal one.
I'm not cranky. I don't
get excited about Mark.
I'm not delighted
by Mark. I love you.
And I can honestly say
I'm gonna love this baby.
But Mark? I somehow ended
up agreeing to a lifetime with...
Mark.
A lifetime of decisions:
bottle or sippy cup,
basketball or tap,
Dartmouth or Berkeley.
Hmm.
- Christmas morning with Mark.
- OK.
I never picked him.
And I don't hate him, but
I don't want a life with him.
And yet, somehow,
that's what I got.
What am I supposed
to do, kick him out?
- I mean, it's his kid.
- You don't need
to remind me of that.
- I never, ever forget that.
- Wow.
OK, we're gonna go
down that road again?
Can we just be honest about
the fact that this is some kind of
bi dream come true? You
got the woman that you love,
and the guy best friend,
who's also a great lay.
And then you get a
baby. I mean, you get it all!
And me? This is not my dream.
My dream doesn't look like this.
Lexie?! Lexie! Are you in here?
- Yeah!
- OK!
Stark... Stark
just asked me out!
Is that not the weirdest
thing you've ever heard?
- It's pretty weird,
I'll give you that.
- It's weird,
it's weird, it's weird! I
mean, he's old! And mean!
He's like the Grinch. The
Grinch asked me to dinner.
- And I said yes!
- You said yes?
- There is a nice man
under there.
- April.
- You think it's weird.
- I do,
but I'm starting to come around.
- Can we talk about it later?
- Yeah, OK.
- Well, can I pee
before I go? What?
- April, go downstairs.
- This is a shared space.
- Just go downstairs!
Ah!
Oh, my God!
We are responsible...
with our patients.
The problem is, we
blow it all out at work.
In our own lives, we
can't think things through,
we don't make the sound choice.
We did that all day at the hospital.
When it comes to ourselves,
we've got nothing left.
He knows I don't want kids. Suddenly
I'm ruining his vision of the future?
Don't talk to me about vision.
What if I never get to operate again?
You could be a bartender.
I had a very good time.
Yeah, the whole five
hours you bartended?
- Free drinks.
- You stole those drinks.
Joe didn't give you free drinks.
Your eyes will
clear up. They will.
- How's it going?
- Oh, good. I'm good.
Metzger's gonna examine you
every day. Until he clears you,
you don't set a foot in an OR.
Well, I can't hold a scalpel,
but I can observe, right?
No. You can't.
- Did he just bench me?
- Damn.
She didn't think she needed
to tell me she couldn't see.
She figured it was,
you know, not relevant.
I don't know if I'm more mad at her
as her husband or as her attending.
You were extraneous to the
process. Kind of like Cristina.
She doesn't need to talk to me
about whether we're gonna have kids.
- That's nice.
- Yeah.
Not only do I not have a say,
she doesn't even want to discuss it.
They want to hold the cards.
I want you to
imagine, for a minute,
- what it's like trying to
negotiate with two women. Two.
- That's a nightmare.
At least you guys get 50 percent
of the vote. I get a measly 33.
I get 50 with Cristina?
I get maybe ten.
Meredith won't even put
anything down on the table.
She doesn't want me to vote,
she simply omits the information.
- Leaving me with zero.
- Gentlemen.
- Chief, wanna join us?
- Can I offer you a nine iron?
I can't stay, I just need to
borrow Shepherd for a minute.
Yeah, sure. What's up, chief?
And is it worth it?
Being responsible?
Adele was in the ER today.
- Is she all right?
- She just...
- She took a spill,
nothing serious.
- Mm-hm.
But it's the second time recently,
so I had Bailey work her up.
Nothing comes up.
CT, everything's clean.
But she's... foggy.
I need you to take a look.
'Cause if you take
your vitamins...
- Of course.
- And pay your taxes
and never cut the line,
the universe still gives
you people to love,
and then lets them slip
through your fingers like water.
And then what have you got?
Vitamins and nothing.