-Previously on The Resident...
-Palliative care doctors will
treat your symptoms
and make sure
you live your best life.
And this will give us
more time to do the things
that we love together.
I've been short-listed
for a seat
at the state medical board.
That's wonderful, Randolph.
I want this baby to be 100% me.
And since we're identical twins,
I was wondering,
would you give me one
of your eggs?
-Are you in trouble?
-No.
I'm fully in control
of my past, present,
and to some extent my future.
First...
we sterilize the tweezers.
Don't burn yourself,
Mr. Soriano.
Ever inspired by
your confidence, Jordan.
Now we use our sterilized
tweezer to place four
different antibiotics.
Bingo.
It'll take at least 24 hours
for us to see
which antibiotics fights off
the bacteria.
And that is just like
a real clinical trial.
Progress is incremental.
But that's the only way
for us to figure out
which treatments work
to heal people.
Like me.
So you're the petri dish?
-Ew. Gross.
-No, no,
Jordan is right,
isn't he, Dr. Pravesh?
Well, we have more
scientific terms for it,
but, yeah, your teacher is
a straight-up petri dish.
But a very brave one.
The risks are high,
but just think of
the potential rewards.
Scurvy, polio, diabetes.
All of those are treatable,
even curable
because of clinical trials.
So today, class, please listen
to your sub,
read chapter four
while I will go to
Chastain Memorial Hospital
so Dr. Pravesh can give me
my first infusion
of a potentially
life-saving drug
for my lung cancer.
It could be a cure
or it could be something else.
That is the beauty
of experimentation.
We only know once
we've taken a chance.
All right, let's chase
that last dose of epi
with another amp of bicarb.
Pushing bicarb now.
How long have we been
coding him?
30 minutes by my watch.
But since EMS found him
at the scene,
it's probably closer to an hour.
He's been asystolic
the last three pulse checks,
maxed out on meds.
Fixed and dilated.
All right, it's time.
Stop compressions.
Time of death 9:34 a.m.
He's too young.
And alone.
EMS couldn't find a wallet
or phone on him.
Olanzapine.
Aripiprazole.
Antipsychotics?
Unusual.
Explains why the Narcan
didn't work.
If you take enough of this,
you can still get high.
These doses are...
What?
These doses are what?
Then the unicorns have a party,
but the kitty has disappeared.
They have to save her, so they
call in Happy the bloodhound,
'cause he has a great nose
and he's a famous detective.
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
don't tell me any more,
you'll ruin it for me.
Hi, Tisha.
Can we read together, Daddy,
- and you do all the funny voices
the way you do?
Yes, of course.
Right after work, okay?
What is it, Daddy?
Have a great day
at school, Bubble.
Love you.
-Bye, Daddy.
-Bye.
Where you going?
To the pharmacy that filled
these prescriptions.
I've never heard
of this patient
and I didn't prescribe these.
That's not what you do.
You have to go straight
to the FBI.
Okay. And how do you know that?
I just do.
There's an office downtown.
I can give you a name.
Oh, perfect.
You can give me the name
of an FBI agent.
That's-that's great.
His name is Todd Barker.
I'll call him and let him know
that someone is using
your name and NPI number
to prescribe drugs,
-and he'll take it from there.
-Whoa, whoa, slow your roll.
What?!
- Irving is paging me.
I got to go.
Hold on.
Hey.
Dr. Hawkins told me
that Grace likes
the comfy chairs
from the fourth floor,
so I got you one.
And by "got" I mean stole.
-Just don't tell.
-Thank you.
Where is Dr. Hawkins,
by the way?
He was with us
through all the chemo.
Yeah, he'll still check in
on you, I promise.
Dr. Pravesh is our doctor now.
He's the clinical trial
specialist.
So, it doesn't look like much,
-but...
-My TILs.
This is Albert's first dose
of tumor-infiltrating
lymphocytes.
The cells that we harvested
last month from your lung biopsy
are now primed to target
your specific cancer.
-Pretty amazing, right?
-It's awesome.
As in the true meaning
of the word, inspiring awe.
Like the way I feel
about black holes
and atomic vibration.
You two are such nerds.
Damn right.
So you will get one dose
every few hours,
six in total.
It'll be some time before
we know if you respond.
But this is the first step.
Science never sounded so easy.
So I want you to be realistic.
This will likely make you
feel sicker
before you get better.
So expect flu-like symptoms,
maybe worse.
How much worse?
Hey, don't worry.
I could handle whatever comes.
This is my lifeline.
My last best chance.
All right, then, here we go.
Oh, Dr. Feldman, wait.
Can you cover for me
for a few hours?
No. My shift is over.
You're taking over for me
so I can have a life
outside these walls.
Yeah, totally.
So you can cover for me?
-No.
-Thank you.
I suppose I can't ask you
where you're going,
but where are you going?
12 hours on my feet,
what's another 12 to 13?
This is doctor abuse.
Mariana, 36 years old,
respiratory distress.
No breath sounds on the right.
Likely a collapsed lung.
Where do you want us?
Bay 11.
Do you have a set of vitals?
Heart rate 120. BP 80/palp.
90%, 92% on oxygen.
All right. Page Dr. Austin.
Dr. Austin
is on his way out of here,
but feel free to page Dr. Devi.
-You're leaving, too? Unfair.
-Yes, sir.
If I have to stay,
everyone else should stay!
-I'm here. You leaving?
-I have to visit my mother.
And Irving is whining
like a puppy dog in pain.
- You go. I got this.
- On my count.
-One, two, three.
-What do you need?
How do you feel
about a pneumothorax?
- Psyched.
- This is Mariana.
You live in my ER now, Devi.
Mariana, we're first gonna take
a listen to your lungs,
okay? Hundley, can I get
a chest tube kit, please?
Mm-hmm.
Your right lung has collapsed.
I need to do a decompression
to help you breathe better,
okay?
We're gonna numb you first.
This may hurt a bit.
Chest tube to me.
Mm-hmm.
Take a deep breath in.
All right, we're in place.
Pleur-evac.
I felt like I was about to die.
Well, you were, dear.
But Dr. Devi just saved you
like the boss she is.
Thank you.
Here we go, milady.
Back to its rightful owner.
You were only CEO
for a few days.
Wait, did you move my plant?
Yeah,
it has better light over there.
I have my first meeting
as a member of the state
medical board today,
so I can start a chapter
in my new life
and I can hand you
a smoothly running hospital.
Huh.
Looks like Trevor Daniels
-didn't show up
for work again today.
-He's been
AWOL since speaking out
on Billie's behalf.
She's trying to find him.
And Dr. Hawkins called to say
he's on his way to the FBI.
The FBI?
Oh. And our new ER doc
just took off
in the middle of her shift.
What were you saying about
a smoothly running hospital?
That in your capable hands,
it'll soon be silk.
-You look very sharp
in that suit, by the way.
-I know.
Okay, um, your own sister
being the biological mother
of your child is...
It's a little weird, right?
Am I allowed to say that?
Lots of women donate their eggs
to their sisters.
True, but Devon has a point.
Giving you
one of my eggs is complicated.
We have to be honest
about this, right?
You both would be
the baby's mother, technically.
No. I'd be the baby's mother.
I will give birth
and raise my child.
Leela's responsibility ends
with the donation of the egg.
Yes, but you are identical twins
with identical DNA.
If I could have a child
with my own egg
that's identical to hers,
you wouldn't think of my baby
as Leela's,
-would you?
-But who will be the father?
A sperm donor.
Okay, but who?
That's my call.
Just give me some time
to think about it.
I know I don't really
have a say here,
-but I...
-No, you don't, sweets.
My body. My sister.
My egg.
- Dr. Hawkins.
- We spoke on the phone.
Agent Barker.
Sorry for the delay.
We were waiting on someone.
Follow me.
Dr. Sullivan.
Agent Barker. Always a pleasure.
- Glad you could make it.
- Things go smoother
when you're around.
I realized I shouldn't leave
you alone to navigate this.
And what exactly
are we navigating?
- Mom?
- In the kitchen!
Ah.
I know that smell.
That brings me back
to sixth grade, after school,
racing home
so I could get my hands
on double banana nut muffins.
Yes.
With the streusel.
Well, my store-bought scones are
ashamed to be in your presence.
Nonsense. We need something
to feed the birds.
Honestly, Mom, when was
the last time you baked?
Chemo Carol is history.
- Mm.
Palliative care Carol is rocking
-this kitchen.
-Yeah, I can see that.
I have the incentive
now that I can enjoy food again.
Mm.
Doreen and I are visiting
the botanical gardens
this afternoon,
so what can I do for you,
baby boy?
Nothing.
Just seeing you like this
is all I need.
Thank you.
AJ.
I want you to know
I understand
my days are numbered,
but I'm truly living them.
I can see that, Mom.
And that makes me so happy.
Mmm.
Albert.
Talk to me, man.
What's going on?
It's just, um, some chills.
He's complaining of nausea
and muscle aches, as well.
Yeah,
it's just like the flu, right?
Okay, you're spiking a fever.
I'll order you some meds
-and a cooling blanket,
all right?
-It's hard to...
...breathe.
-What's happening?
-Probably has some fluid
in his lungs.
I'll put him on oxygen.
This isn't like the flu.
It's getting harder really fast,
Dr. Pravesh.
It's quicker than I expected.
This is the only hope
to get you better, right?
I'm here for you
every step of the way.
You still with me?
Okay.
Just breathe.
163 antipsychotic prescriptions
written in your name
in the last two months
at six different clinics
in addition
to high-priced asthma meds
and antihypertensives.
Well, I didn't do this.
No one's breaking out
the handcuffs, Dr. Hawkins.
We think you're a small part
of a much bigger case
we've been tracking for a year.
These are all brand-name drugs.
Highly reimbursed medications.
Medicare fraud.
Yes. Kickbacks. Drug diversion.
We think it's a pill mill.
A big one.
At least six clinics involved.
Probably busing people in.
You have a pole camera up yet?
A warrant just came through.
Classic mob operation.
The Mafia is often involved
in Medicare fraud.
There's little oversight,
scant punishment
and big rewards.
And we now have
mob levels of violence.
Federal investigators,
informants,
even doctors who assist
in our investigations
have been murdered.
Which is
why we're keeping an eye
on Dr. Sullivan as best we can.
Nice to know you've been working
with the FBI.
How did they get
- Dr. Hawkins' name and numbers?
- Few years ago,
there was a ransomware attack
on Chastain.
They were just idiots
in some basement.
Yeah, well,
typically these idiots
sell your identities,
DEA, NPI numbers
to larger
criminal organizations.
So, what do I do about it?
You go back to Chastain,
leave this to us.
If you don't,
it could be your life in danger.
I think we've heard enough
to understand.
Not nearly.
That's all I can tell you
right now.
And we have to get back to work.
Great seeing you again.
Talk soon.
Dr. Hawkins.
You and I need
to have a little chat.
Mariana, how are you feeling?
Better. Very well, actually.
Oh, glad to hear it.
I can't believe
this happened again.
Wait,
your lung's collapsed before?
Yes.
My doctor wasn't too worried.
He said I was young, healthy.
Is it possible
this is just a coincidence?
It's unlikely.
We're going to have to keep you
here to figure this out.
-No, I have an important meeting
with a client later.
-Cancel it.
Can you elaborate?
I'm sorry.
I did not mean
to sound so blunt.
I'm a surgeon,
so most of the patients
I deal with are unconscious.
My bedside manner
gets a little rusty.
But that's no excuse.
I'd be more concerned
if your scalpel was rusty.
And you do not need
to apologize.
Would a male surgeon apologize?
It's unlikely.
I've told my team to shoot me
if I ever apologize to a client.
Makes them trust you less.
What do you do?
I'm an architect.
My uncle's an architect.
He's never apologized
for anything.
Frank Lloyd Wright said,
"Early in life, I had to choose
"between honest arrogance
and hypocritical humility.
I chose honest arrogance."
Well,
I vote for honest humility.
And on that note,
your lung should not
collapse twice.
We'll have to consult
a specialist, okay?
I'll be back to check
on you later.
-Breathing better?
-Mm-hmm.
See? Everything's fine.
If he's this bad
after a first dose,
what will happen next?
He's got five more to go.
Everybody reacts differently.
We won't know until we proceed.
That's just how it works.
Grace, you haven't eaten
all day.
Why don't you go
to the cafeteria for a bit?
I'll be fine.
Okay.
I've tried to talk her through
this, explain the science.
I gave her a book
on Marie Curie.
Big mistake, since Curie
died experimenting on herself.
Yeah, still walking
that one back.
Albert, it's time
for your second dose.
I figured.
That's why I asked her
to step out.
You sure?
Yes.
I'll be back.
The Lord is my shepherd,
I shall not want...
Well, I don't think we've seen
anything too concerning today.
Certainly nothing
requiring punitive action.
Uh, actually, there is one case
we haven't discussed
that's alarming.
Emily Benesch, 32 years old.
Ms. Benesch had, uh, an anterior
cervical discectomy and fusion.
Dr. Elkins,
you're a neurosurgeon.
Did you see this complaint?
I did. As I recall,
the patient had
complications post-op.
The surgeon damaged
her spinal cord.
Now Ms. Benesch is a paraplegic.
Spinal surgery always has risks.
Well, uh,
after the operation,
she felt something was wrong,
she asked her surgeon Dr. Keith
Bosley for a follow-up,
and he "brushed her off."
I know Dr. Bosley personally.
I-I doubt he brushed her off.
Well, I found several
other complaints against him.
So wouldn't, uh,
multiple complaints
be a red flag?
I think we should dig into
Dr. Bosley's patient outcomes
and... give Ms. Benesch
a fair hearing.
Stories like this
flood our office.
Patients get emotional
when complications occur
and look to place blame.
This patient isn't emotional,
she's a paraplegic.
We can't fix
every patient's problem
or guarantee everyone
a perfect outcome.
No, I understand that.
But isn't it the job
of this board
to hear our patients' problems,
particularly when there are
repeat complaints?
Dr. Elkins, will you delve
into this more deeply?
Should a close friend
of Dr. Bosley's be the one
to lead his investigation?
State medical boards
are staffed by doctors
precisely because we are
the best people
to judge our own colleagues.
So let's just simmer down.
Just watch,
and learn how we operate.
Oh, I-I think I'm getting
a pretty good sense
of how you operate.
When you wouldn't answer
questions about your past,
I didn't push.
I respected your privacy,
but that's off the table now.
Talk to me.
It started with a phone call
back when I was a resident.
I was employed by a big
hospital system in Chicago
that took a lot
of Medicare patients.
They were overtreating,
doing unnecessary surgeries,
and ripping off Medicare
for millions of dollars.
That's almost standard
operational procedure
in some hospitals these days.
I couldn't let it stand.
I see a problem...
I try to fix it.
I get that.
So I called a Medicare
fraud tip line,
and the DOJ got involved.
Long story short,
I ended up wearing a wire
and collecting documents to help
them get the proof they needed.
You were hooked.
Yeah.
So when the FBI approached me
to keep working with them...
...I was all in.
They need doctors
to understand medically
what's fraud and what isn't,
and to work undercover.
Soon, we went after
the biggest fish.
The Mafia.
It was a much tougher world.
Lot of risk.
Eventually, I was identified
as an FBI operative, and...
...there was an attempt
on my life.
-Are you safe now?
-It's been two years.
But the Mafia makes a practice
of punishing its enemies.
I never know who I can trust,
so I say as little as possible
about my past,
and I don't stay long
in one place.
You should have told me.
I get that
you're in a tough spot.
Here's the thing.
I like you.
And I like you.
But it ends there.
I don't get involved
with anyone, Conrad.
And no one should
get involved with me,
for a number of reasons,
but the main one
is that I will disappear.
Well, maybe you should
stop running.
Trust me on this.
You take care of people.
You want to take care of me.
But you can't.
I take care of myself.
I'll see you at Chastain.
Dr. Pravesh, what's going on?
His pressure is plummeting
and he's spiking a fever again.
He still has three doses left.
More fluids should
bring up the pressure.
I-I don't think
he can handle the trial.
I don't think I can, either.
-I want it to stop.
-When Albert is stable,
we will discuss it,
but right now
we don't even know
if the trial is to blame.
It could be an infection,
and I don't want to deprive him
of a cure for the wrong reasons.
How are you gonna figure it out?
Grace.
You have to trust me
and this process.
You two and your
scientific method.
I don't trust this "process."
Look at him.
Whatever you're doing
is making him worse.
If this protocol's gonna work,
it's gonna take time.
Let's get him to the ICU
so we can stabilize him
and monitor him,
and I promise you
that all options will be
available to the both of you.
Fine, and thank you,
but I'd like to call in
Dr. Hawkins
for a second opinion.
I've already paged him
for a consult. He's on his way.
Albert?
I am right here.
It's gonna be okay.
I'm fine. Yes. Yes.
Don't worry.
Uh-- The doctor's walking in.
I love you, too. Bye.
My husband. Also an architect.
Which is why he isn't here.
He's on-site of a new project
in Memphis.
Dual-career marriage.
I know all about that.
And the people who do it
with children?
Boggles the mind.
Agreed.
My career is all-consuming.
And I'm a perfectionist.
It's a compulsion.
Cough sounds bad.
Let me take a listen.
Hey, what's going on?
Hemoptysis
in our pneumothorax patient.
Her lungs sounded clear,
but now...
There's still an air leak.
And there's no blood
in the chest tube.
Mariana, we're gonna confer
for a minute, okay?
Okay, so something
more serious is going on.
All right, well,
give me the differential.
It could be an abscess,
bronchiectasis or even cancer.
-A CT should help.
-All right.
Well, let's get her
in the magic box right now.
And then this Dr. Abernathy
dismisses the case
as though it was nothing.
Do you think the neurosurgeon's
really culpable?
Well, I'm not gonna condemn him
without solid consideration,
but they refused
to give it any air.
What?
-Does any of this
really surprise you?
-No.
This is why I wanted the job
in the first place.
So what will you do?
Hello?
Hello, is this Ms. Benesch?
Yes, who's calling?
This is Dr. Randolph Bell
from the state medical board.
I'd like to talk with you
about Dr. Bosley.
Finally. I'd given up hope.
Got your page.
I came as quickly as I could.
Is your emergency handled?
Hard to tell.
How's Albert doing?
Well, we're four doses in.
I've had to give him
broad-spectrum antibiotics
and three liters of fluids,
and he's getting sicker.
I had to start him on norepi.
-You think it's the trial drug?
-I do.
His blood cultures
came back negative,
there's no sign of infection.
And it's time for his next dose.
Ah, that's a tough call.
He's already on a non-rebreather
with a borderline blood gas.
With another dose,
you may have to intubate.
Which could be fatal for Albert.
A ventilator-associated
pneumonia,
with his immune system?
God, and his poor wife.
And the trial?
An intubation would be
an unexpected adverse event,
which could get the trial paused
or stopped altogether.
But if he doesn't
finish the protocol,
and his cancer
only gets worse...
So if I give him the dose,
it could kill him.
And if I hold it, then
everything he's gone through
up until this point
would be completely useless.
There's no good answer.
And Albert's wife, she doesn't
trust me, she trusts you.
Yeah, I'll talk to her,
but let's be clear:
you make the call.
No. Neither of us will.
Albert should decide.
So, your CT was clear.
Which means it's not an abscess,
inflammation or cancer.
Okay, so what's next?
It's good to rule things out.
I am going to circle back
with Dr. Austin, and I...
Are you still in pain?
Is it your chest?
It's just, it's just cramps.
The same every month.
Ooh, they're excruciating
sometimes.
Have they always been this bad?
As long as I can remember.
Sometimes I even
get a nosebleed.
It's a real thrill,
being a woman.
The last time
your lung collapsed,
were you also on your period?
Uh, a-as a matter of fact I was.
I... Yeah.
I-I remember I had to ask
for pain meds while I was here.
Why?
Sit tight, I will be right back.
I promise.
Endometriosis? Really?
Her pneumothorax coincides
with her periods,
which are abnormally painful.
Isn't it possible
that aberrant endometrial tissue
from her pelvis traveled
through tiny defects
in her diaphragm up
into her chest, where...
Where it continues to respond
to the hormones
of her menstrual cycle,
thus wreaking havoc.
Yeah, it's definitely possible,
but, Devi, that's...
-extremely rare.
-So is having repeated episodes
of pneumothorax with
no discernible cause on imaging.
What if these aren't random?
What if this is evidence
of a problem
her body's been trying
to hide this entire time?
Well, we could get
an MRI for a better look,
but ultimately
the only way to confirm
a catamenial pneumo
is with surgery.
That's thoracic and abdominal.
And if we find
what you think we will,
-that could be a hell
of a procedure.
-That can cure her.
I'm ready for this.
Oh, I know you are.
Devi, you just pulled off a
Conrad Hawkins-level diagnosis.
Let's get your patient ready
and scrub in.
Tell him we can stop,
Dr. Hawkins, please.
Of course we can.
- I've always said that.
- We can't quit
an experiment halfway through.
I tell my students all the time.
This is your life.
You get to be selfish.
You don't have to think
about the greater good.
I am being selfish.
Without the trial, I die.
But you may die sooner with it.
I can't lose you.
Do you think I'm not scared?
I am.
But this is what I want to do.
I'm willing to suffer
for the science,
just for a chance, however slim,
to survive this cancer.
I just need you
to support me, please.
-But, Albert...
-Listen, listen.
We're a team, right?
Don't fight Dr. Pravesh.
Just trust him.
And trust me
and honor
what I want and believe.
Okay.
I've decided, Dr. Pravesh.
Please give me the next dose.
I hope this isn't an imposition.
More like a surprise.
I thought the state
medical board
had lost all interest
in my case.
My lawyer certainly has.
Well, I'm sorry to hear that.
Thank you.
I don't blame her.
She took me on pro bono.
When we couldn't get
any traction with the board,
there wasn't any way forward.
Are you looking
for a financial settlement?
No, I'm looking
for accountability.
He nicked the artery
in my spine.
There was massive bleeding.
My spinal cord was damaged.
I did not have to end up
like this.
I don't want future patients
of Dr. Bosley to, either.
Hey, your case file
says that you received
a second and third opinion
about your outcome.
And that a post-op MRI
would have caught the damage,
and then a second emergency
surgery could have repaired it.
Yes. I might
still be walking today
if Dr. Bosley had
listened to me.
He didn't.
So he says you pushed hard
for the surgery,
That's not the point.
The harm I suffered
during the operation
could have been prevented.
I want the board
to do something.
Will they?
Honestly? Probably not.
But I will do something.
I'm maxed out on norepi,
adding vasopressin.
I hear crackles halfway up,
and he's losing consciousness.
Albert.
Can you hear me?
-We're gonna need to intubate.
-No, not intubation.
He's struggling to breathe,
Grace.
It may be the only thing
to help keep him alive.
I'll grab an intubation tray.
I knew we should have stopped.
My husband, him I understand.
He'll never quit. But you?
You're doctors. You know.
You're supposed to know better.
Why couldn't you stop him?
Grace, you know I respect you
and your husband.
He didn't want to stop,
we have to honor that.
And Dr. Pravesh
has my total support.
I'll be right back.
Add a dialysis line.
His kidneys are shutting down.
Yeah. Just let me know, please.
Albert's stable for now.
Yeah, well, it doesn't
change the fact
that he walked in here
in decent shape and...
now he's on dialysis
and he's being intubated.
Did you call the study sponsors?
I had to notify them
of the toxicity of the drug,
and now they're deciding
if they're gonna put
the trial on hold.
Grace was right,
I knew the dangers,
I knew the odds for Albert
were getting longer
every single hour.
I shouldn't have
listened to him,
except I know
that I should have.
You followed
the patient's wishes.
It was the right move.
Albert knew exactly
what he was doing.
I feel like a general
who's sending my soldiers
out into the battlefield
to face a line of machine guns
while I stand in safety.
All wars have casualties.
And they also have triumphs.
It's the same
with clinical trials.
I want Albert to survive.
I want him to teach his kids
for years to come.
So they can visit him
in his happy retirement.
He deserves that.
This isn't over.
The intubation bought him time.
So... next steps.
All right, what we know now
is that he's battling
massive inflammation
from the trial drug.
So, if we treat
the inflammation...
I hesitated to give him steroids
because I thought
he was infected, but...
We should go for it-- plus toci.
If all his cultures
have been negative, yeah.
It could help more
than it could hurt him.
Let's do it.
Endometriosis fits
your symptoms.
You check all the boxes.
You know, most doctors
don't ask women
the right question
to make these connections.
That's why it can
take years to diagnose.
But if we're right,
we can fix this.
But we do need to be clear
about what this means for you.
This condition can
affect your fertility.
Now, with surgery,
you should end up pain-free,
but if we find extensive damage,
you are aware that you may not
be able to have children, right?
I discussed it with my husband.
He's flying in to be with me.
He's okay with never
having children.
And you?
W-We're on the same page.
We're focused on each other,
and our careers.
And there's nothing
wrong with that.
You're absolutely right.
His MAPs are solid.
I'm gonna titrate down
the norepi.
-That's an improvement.
-Not enough.
What do the labs say?
Just tell me.
Look for yourself.
His blood gas looks good.
We can turn down
his oxygen to 40%.
And his liver function
is normalizing.
He's turning around.
He's gonna be okay.
Yes. Yes.
Albert will make it
through this trial.
You have given him
a chance to survive.
You did it.
He's looking better, right?
He already wants to send
a video to his students.
I tell them every day,
record even the most incremental
progress in your experiments.
This is more than incremental.
When you're ready,
I'll set up a transfer
back to the room
with the comfy chair.
Albert, I owe you an apology.
Grace, you, too.
I just had no idea
it was gonna get this bad.
You were doing your job.
I'm sorry I got so angry.
Oh, stop, both of you. I was
a willing guinea pig, remember?
A human petri dish.
Besides, it worked.
Well, we know you can get
through the doses.
But we don't actually know if
it's gonna help your cancer yet.
But I have a chance.
More than I had before.
See? I told you
to trust Dr. Pravesh.
-You were right.
-Mm.
Like two peas in a pod,
you science nerds.
That's right.
Now, here's the real question.
Who can recite
the periodic table faster?
-Did you just challenge me?
-Yes, I did.
No-- Actually, no,
y-you need to get some rest.
Hydrogen, helium, lithium...
Okay, okay, okay. You win.
You win.
Imaging,
please dial 2732...
Oh, well, well, well, if
it isn't the queen of Chastain.
Hey.
Ah...
-Oh. Nice.
-You like that, right?
Hey, man, I heard
Devon's clinical trial
passed the first test.
Yeah, barely.
The protocol was worse
than anyone imagined.
Your mom wouldn't
have survived it, AJ.
Well, we have no regrets.
You know what she did today?
She made three different
kind of muffins
and she took a walk
through the botanical gardens.
Telling you, brother,
palliative care was a good call.
So, uh...
do we need to talk
about the new ER doc?
-Okay.
-Yeah.
Look, I'm just saying,
I like her.
No BS, no sugarcoating.
Uh, she's definitely
an interesting case.
"Interesting."
That sounds mysterious.
Come on, man.
Give up the backstory.
No, do not go there.
You know something I don't?
I thought you two might have
something going on.
-Just colleagues.
-Yeah, for now.
No. I already have
one lady in my life.
Me.
-I'll catch you tomorrow.
-All right.
See you later, cutie-pie.
Bye.
The unicorn book, you promised.
What?
Unicorn book? I don't know
what you're talking about.
- Daddy.
- I didn't forget, sweetheart.
Happy the Bloodhound
is coming right up.
I'm so proud of you.
And I'm proud of you.
You made a tough diagnosis
most doctors would miss.
And you got your patient
through a very rough surgery,
Leela.
Well, I really admire Mariana.
And I'm really glad
I got to know her a bit.
She's a successful
businesswoman,
and an unapologetic
control freak,
with a very successful husband
in the same business.
Sounds familiar.
And she wasn't at all afraid
of a condition
that could make her infertile,
because she doesn't want kids.
I mean, there are people
like that.
I'm just not one of them.
I want to have a family one day.
With you.
We need to talk about this.
I don't know if I want kids.
At least not right now.
I could not manage
surgical residency and a family.
Yeah, I get that.
And it can wait.
We have plenty of time.
Devon, it could be a long while.
Leela, all kinds of doctors
manage it.
I mean, there are work-arounds.
I believe that, I just...
I don't know if it'll ever be
the right thing for me.
Which is why I-I realized
that what Padma wants
can help us both.
I can give her the egg
she so desperately wants,
so she can have a baby,
and at the same time,
I can freeze some for me.
For us.
For the future.
Yes.
Just to give me time
to think about it.
But that's all I can promise
right now.
Can you live with that?
Captioning sponsored by
20th CENTURY FOX TELEVISION
and TOYOTA.
Captioned by
Media Access Group at WGBH
access.wgbh.org