You did this skydiving?
Not exactly.
I fall 9,000 feet
and land, no problem.
And then I trip
walking to my car.
Isn't that ridiculous?
Well, sounds like
you got off easy.
Mmm. What can I say?
It was on my bucket list.
Okay. Let's take
a look at your head.
Ow!
Yeah, you got
a decent-sized laceration
on your scalp, Lyla.
Ah! Figured. I used
half a box of Kleenex
trying to stop the bleeding
on my way over here.
You didn't drive yourself,
did you?
No, no,
no, my boyfriend actually.
He's out parking the car.
All right, let's get
a picture of that wrist.
Okay.
Thank you.
Hey, I got requests
for schedule changes
that could
use your signature.
All righty.
Right there.
This one's frozen.
Oh, really? I just used it.
Well, I'll pull it up
on the desktop.
Sharon?
It looks like this screen
is locked as well.
Sharon, it's Bert.
Maggie. Sharon.
I'll go check
on that monitor.
What are you doing here?
Is something wrong
with one of the kids?
No, no, no, everything's fine,
as far as I know.
That's not why I'm here.
Honey, Bert, over here.
"Honey"?
That's my lady friend.
She... I think she
might've broken her wrist.
Excuse me.
Balloon catheter
is at the lesion site.
Inflating now.
Stent deployed.
All right,
let's have one last look.
Compress the pedal.
Dr. Bardovi?
I don't know
what's wrong
with the fluoro pedal.
I'm stepping on it.
Guys.
Is that...
What's happening?
Sharon?
Don't say anything, okay?
I need a moment to process.
No, no, no,
it's not that. Look.
What is all this
about malware and
decryption keys?
It's a ransom note.
Oh...
We've been hacked.
Our server has been
corrupted and shut down,
and until we can
restore the system,
we'll be operating
under downtime procedure.
That means paper charts.
And no tablets, people.
Hand them over.
So we have no access
to anyone's medical records?
How do we do stuff?
Well, there was
a time not so long ago
when we actually
treated patients without
the aid of computers.
Imagine that.
Tell them, Dr. Charles.
Can I keep it if I
promise not to use it?
Sorry, Dr. Charles,
IT needs to
check them all out.
Well, it's not just
the electronic medical records
that are disabled, right?
I hear imaging's
down as well.
Yeah, so that means, what?
No X-rays?
And no CT scans,
no MRIs...
We'll have to
cancel elective surgeries
for the time being,
but the IT
department is confident
they can disable the malware
and get us back online soon.
Isn't that right, Bruce?
We're doing our best.
And in the meantime,
we'll make do.
We'll use the transport
monitors to read the vitals...
Yeah, I'm sorry,
but the note says
that if we pay
them 30 Bitcoins,
they'll give us
a decryption key, so...
It's hospital policy
not to engage
with extortionists.
So we're going to fly blind
with one arm tied
behind our back?
It seems
a little shortsighted.
I mean, it's what
$30,000, $40,000?
It seems like nothing.
Says the guy
with the trust fund.
We're not paying
the ransom, Dr. Rhodes.
We don't need to.
We aren't so fragile
that we could be
knocked off our
game that easy.
Absolutely, Ms. Goodwin.
We're up for the challenge.
Thank you, Dr. Choi.
Okay, G.I. Joe.
G.I. Choi.
Back to your patients.
Increase communication,
people.
No blood is drawn,
no test is run,
and no medication is dispensed
without writing on this board.
Sharon?
Sharon, listen, I...
I didn't want you
to find out.
Then you could've
taken her to County.
But Med was
the closest
and the best,
not in small part
because of you.
Don't sweat it, Bert,
I've got bigger problems
to deal with right now.
I can't access
any of my files.
What are we
supposed to do?
Cross our fingers and hope
that some guy named Bruce
can save the day.
I can't say that
I'm optimistic.
Do you know how much
research that I just have
to put on hold now?
This is unacceptable.
Whoa! Easy there, babe.
It's not the end of the world.
Are you sure about that?
Because things are seeming
a little biblical around here.
I mean,
last night with the rats
and then today with the hacks.
Rats? What rats?
In the vents of my apartment.
It kept me up
all night last night.
Exterminator can't
come until tomorrow.
I'm gonna have to
check into a hotel.
No, you won't.
You stay with me
until this is resolved.
That is exactly what
I wanted you to say.
Give me that.
I need this
more than you do.
Bye.
He can't catch his breath.
I mean, I tried getting him
to lie back on the way over,
but he just...
He's tripoding.
Trying to clear
his secretions.
All right, it's okay,
Desmond.
Just try to take
a deep breath for me,
all right?
Does this hurt?
A little.
Okay.
His lymph nodes
are very swollen.
Do you know when he started
feeling like this?
Maybe three weeks ago.
Never as bad as this.
I mean, it would
come and go, so we just
thought he had the flu.
It's been going
around his school.
102.7.
He just started running
that fever this morning.
I mean, we got here
as fast as we could.
I had to find
someone to cover my shift.
I was out working, too.
I drive for a couple of
those ride-share apps.
We're just scrambling.
I understand.
Has he had all
his vaccinations?
Yes.
I think so.
Okay, let's get him
on an oxygen mask,
and give him racemic epi.
I'll be back to
check on him soon, okay?
April?
What do you think?
I don't know.
Maybe epiglottitis,
maybe mumps.
I mean,
who knows if he's really
had all his vaccinations.
Let's give him some steroids,
see if we can't
reduce the swelling,
and let's do a CBC, CMP,
blood cultures, and a DR-70.
Tumor marker?
Let's see if we can
get a rush on that.
Sorry.
This board's a mess.
Look around.
The whole ED's a mess.
We can't even send
patients upstairs
because we don't know
if there's beds available.
What a nightmare.
Okay, so before we
stitch up your head,
I wanna reduce
the fracture in your wrist.
Here, we'll give you a little
ketamine to sedate you.
I promise you
won't feel a thing.
Sure
I can trust you, Doc?
Seems I'm an enemy combatant.
Lover boy here
failed to mention
that his ex-wife is
running the place.
I told you Sharon
was a hospital administrator.
You didn't say it
was this hospital.
Before we get started,
you should know
our EMR system's down,
so I can't pull
up your records.
Really?
Yeah,
so I just need to confirm
the history you already gave.
Any medical problems?
Prior surgeries?
Anything I should
be aware of?
No.
Okay.
You taking any medications?
Any allergies to medications?
Nada.
Got a clean bill of health.
Lyla's the most active
person I've ever met.
Biking, tai chi.
We just got back
from whitewater
rafting in Chile.
It's all I can do
to keep up with her.
Look who's trying
to get in on my good side.
It's working.
Let's do it.
Okay.
New history and physicals
for everyone in
the psych ward?
Not everyone.
I mean, if they were
admitted before today,
we still have backups.
Still leaves about
six that we lost.
So, you know,
we just divvy them up.
Okay.
Here's the catch.
Even for us
so-called normal people...
Dr. Charles?
Thank you.
Getting hacked,
it really creates...
You know, it's a violation.
You know, heightens
your vulnerability,
and that's obviously
magnified for people
who are dealing with...
Anxiety and paranoia. Of course.
Yeah, yeah.
So I think it's just important
to not let them know
why their histories
are being retaken.
You know, we just
gotta finesse it a bit.
Understood.
Oh...
I heard that they
are having a hard time
filling the vacancy
left by Dr. Wheeler's death.
I'm sorry,
the ED residency?
Yeah.
I mean, you just
graduated from med school.
I thought maybe you might know
somebody who's interested.
Oh, darn it.
Hey, Daniel,
you got a minute?
Yeah.
Anyway, just give me a shout
if you're having any problems.
So I hear they went
zip-lining in Costa Rica.
I thought it was
South America somewhere.
You knew about this?
Daniel?
I went and had
drinks with Bert
about a month ago,
and, you know,
he let it slip.
A month ago?
And you've just
been sitting on this?
Well, I kind of thought
it was more up to
Bert to tell you,
and I advised him
to do exactly that.
Yeah, well, he didn't.
I'm sorry.
You know, it's not so
easy staying neutral
throughout all this, you know.
You want me to choose sides,
I'll pledge my
loyalty to you right now.
Not necessary.
I gotta get back to work.
Swelling's not coming down,
and his sats are dropping.
Are we gonna
need to intubate?
We can't.
If it spasms down,
we could lose his airway.
Let's get an analog X-ray up
here for a lateral neck, okay?
"Analog"?
What's going on here?
Mr. Rawls, please...
I hear you guys were hacked.
Do I need to take my
son to another hospital?
I seriously recommend
you not moving your son
in his current condition,
but I can assure you
that Desmond's care
will not be compromised
in the slightest.
Chad...
I hope you're right.
Workup back yet
on my 7-year-old?
The lab got them mixed up
with another patient.
They gotta run them again.
Are you kidding me?
It's the damn hack, okay?
Oh, Ms. Goodwin,
when are we
getting back online?
We're working on it.
You said that an hour ago.
I've got a dad
who wants to pull
his kid out of here.
You've got to stay
on top of the lab.
Don't worry.
We'll ride this whirlwind.
A little help here!
A little help!
Incoming!
My friend's been shot!
Dr. Choi?
Get out of the way, move.
I don't have
a room right now.
Out of the way.
Mags, where are
we taking him?
Wait, get that up.
I don't have a room right now.
Coming through!
Put him there.
Keep this area clear!
Lift him up.
Park him in
the hallway over there.
"We're gonna ride
this whirlwind"?
Keep telling me that.
Sats 100, BP 102
over 69, heart rate 110.
A little hypotensive
and tachycardic.
Let's get a 16 in each arm
and bolus a liter of LR
on the rapid transfuser,
and 50 of fentanyl for pain.
How's the leg looking?
A likely entrance hole
in the upper right thigh.
Big hematoma.
No apparent fracture.
All right, Noah, pop quiz.
Let's see how much you recall.
After we figure out
where the bullet went in,
what do we do?
Count the holes.
If there's an even number,
it came out.
Okay. Jason,
I need you to grab the rail
and roll on your side for me.
Want to tell me
what happened?
I shot him, actually.
By accident.
I thought the safety was on.
I'm so sorry, man.
We cool?
Yeah, don't sweat it.
What kind of gun was it?
Uh, 9 mil.
And you carry it why?
You don't know
my neighborhood.
They got guns,
I got a gun.
Making the world
a safer place?
I think I might
see an exit hole.
It's tiny, but...
Yeah, too tiny.
Probably shrapnel.
Bullet's still
in there somewhere.
We've gotta find it.
Systems are still down.
Then we'll use
the tools we have.
Hey, Natalie,
can I ask you a favor?
One second.
Hey, April, can you try
and track down Connor for me?
All right.
Thank you.
Sorry, what's up?
I was gonna give this to Will,
but it looks like he's busy.
Can I leave it with you?
Sure.
He's going to
watch the game
with his brother tonight.
I slept in it last night,
and when he left this morning,
I was still in bed.
I'd leave it in his locker,
but I want to
make sure he gets it.
Okay.
Thanks.
You're the best.
She just said she had
an out-of-body experience.
Oh, that's ketamine.
Lyla, do me a favor
and follow my finger
with your eyes.
That whole time
you were pulling on my wrist,
I was floating
up to the ceiling,
looking down at myself.
It was wonderful,
though you may want
to tell the cleaning staff
there's a lot of dust
on the light
fixtures up there.
I'll have them look
into that immediately.
Are you sure there's nothing
you left out of your history?
Is something the matter?
Probably not.
You're having a little trouble
focusing with your eyes.
That could be just
a reaction to the ketamine,
but considering you suffered
the head injury, though,
I am thinking I want to bring
someone in from neurology,
just to rule
some things out.
You know what?
I'm sorry, there is one thing
that I left out of my history.
Elavil.
I take it for insomnia.
You never said
you had trouble sleeping.
It's not
an every night thing.
Is it possible that, um...
The drug had a bad interaction
with the ketamine?
Yes, that might explain it.
Oh, good. Then mystery solved.
Hmm...
I'll tell you this.
He could have come
in here with Beyoncé,
and it'd still be
a step down from you.
You don't have
to say that.
It's true.
He's lost weight.
Mmm-hmm.
Could've been worse.
Could've been a blonde.
Hmm...
Ms. Goodwin.
Dr. Halstead.
Any chance you got a hold
of Lyla's records yet?
Are you kidding me? How?
I've got no idea
when things are
gonna get here.
Well, in that case,
let's repeat her labs,
but this time add
coags and a D-dimer.
Whoa! I thought you were
wrapping things up with her.
Her head lac's not
repaired yet, Maggie.
She's not going
anywhere anyway.
I hope this is not
another one of your
wild goose chases.
What's that
supposed to mean?
It means
keeping Bert in the ED
is the opposite
of what Goodwin
needs right now.
Well, this is
a hospital, Maggie.
I know I don't
need to remind you
whose needs come first.
You want new labs? Fine.
We're doing paper today.
How about filling these out?
Hey, what do we got?
You've really got to
retrace all your steps?
Uh-huh.
I don't understand
why the network
isn't constantly
backing itself up.
Hard drives are
so cheap these days.
Hey, Dr. Charles
says they're looking
to fill the open
residency in the ED.
That's great news,
isn't it?
Why?
Because now
you can take it.
Isn't that the position
that you wanted
before Dr. Charles pulled
you into psychiatry?
You're missing
the point, Joey.
What point?
Why would Dr...
Why would Dr. Charles
bring this up in
the first place?
I mean, he sounded
innocent enough,
and since I just
graduated med school,
maybe I knew someone
who'd want the job,
but I can't help thinking
that he's got
some kind of agenda.
Is he dissatisfied
with my performance?
Is he trying
to get rid of me?
Look at it this way.
Everyone thought that
you were really good
in emergency medicine.
Is that supposed to
make me feel better?
Yeah.
You know, Joey,
you and I don't
communicate very well.
You see there?
Look how narrow
this boy's trachea is.
It's no wider than
a cocktail straw.
I assume you've
started a workup?
Still gummed up in the lab.
I started treating
him for epiglottitis,
but that's
clearly not the problem.
Lymphs?
It's hard to exclude cancer
from the differential.
We need to address
his airway issue.
Can we remove the lymph nodes?
Get a biopsy?
Surgically,
we're never gonna get
an ET tube down him
in this condition,
and Marty's gonna be hesitant
to put him under general.
So what can we do?
How still do you think
this kid can be?
What's that
you're spraying on him?
Ethyl chloride.
And you're positive
he won't feel anything?
Maybe a slight pinch,
but that's it.
Now the most important thing
is for you to stay
extremely still
while we're
doing this, Desmond.
You think you can do that?
Yeah.
You know what I
find works sometimes?
Is if you close your eyes
and you squeeze my hand
as hard as you
can until it's over.
How does that sound?
Good? Okay.
Let's go. Okay.
Okay.
Oh, God.
Mommy?
It's okay, D.
Just a little bit longer.
No!
Okay,
okay, okay.
Okay.
I'm sorry.
No, it's fine.
I think we got enough tissue
to send to pathology.
You should
see this, Jason.
It's cool. The bullet's,
like, in your heart.
Cool for you.
He shot me in the leg.
What the hell is
it doing up here?
Bullets travel in
unexpected ways.
Well, we need to
get that out, right?
One step at a time.
I can't tell yet
whether it's actually
in the heart or
just behind it.
Well, what about those
X-rays we took earlier?
Well, they're not
that precise.
Well, find something
that is.
What about
that MIR machine?
MRI? And it's not
usable right now.
What do you mean?
Look, if we can figure out
the path the bullet took
to get to your chest,
we should be able to determine
exactly where it is.
There are only
two options, right?
Right, well, either it caromed
through your midsection,
or it hitched a ride up
through your venous system.
Good. Grab a DPL.
DPL?
A diagnostic
peritoneal lavage.
We're gonna insert
a needle in your abdomen,
fill it with fluid,
then drain it to see
if there's any
internal bleeding.
Don't worry,
we'll drape off this area
before we insert the Foley.
What do you mean,
"Insert the Foley"?
Oh, this goes up your urethra.
First you shoot me,
then you bring me to a place
from the Dark Ages.
You really suck, Marius.
My fault.
Um...
Excuse me.
Hey, Bert,
can I ask you...
Have you talked to
the children about this?
Not yet.
I was waiting to see
if it was serious or not.
And is it?
Sharon...
You know, maybe,
you should speak
to your children.
Oh, man, she's a trip wire.
How'd you
expect her to react?
This city is
filthy with hospitals,
but you decided to come here.
To do what?
To rub it in
Sharon's face?
Oh, come on.
How old is she anyway?
What does that have
to do with anything?
Okay.
When did you meet her?
I know what
you're implying.
Lyla wasn't
even in the picture
till way after
Sharon and I split up.
Split up?
Uh-uh.
You walked out on her.
Okay, so Bruce is no closer
to fixing this malware.
And the FBI?
Oh, come on, let's not
hold our breath there.
You know, I...
I think it's time
to consider putting
the hospital on bypass.
What is that?
Sending patients
to other hospitals?
Do you know how much revenue
that is gonna cost?
A few hundred thousand.
That's just today.
You can double it tomorrow.
I mean,
the board is gonna plotz.
What do you suggest then?
We're full up.
My doctors are treating
gunshot wounds in the hallway.
Listen,
we keep a little cash on hand
for a rainy day, okay?
So we could pay this ransom,
and no one would ever know.
No.
Why not?
And do not say,
"Because it's bad precedent."
It's a horrendous precedent.
These hackers are putting
people's lives at risk.
They're compromising
their care.
You can't reward
behavior like that.
Besides, you pay them now,
what stops them
from doing it again
or holding the hospital
next door hostage?
I don't care about
the hospital next door.
We cannot
let them win, Peter.
You want to stick to
your guns, that's fine,
but you are the one
who's going to tell the board.
Spread the word
and notify IDPH
the hospital's now
on full diversion.
Yes, ma'am.
Give me IDPH.
Yeah, I need
a home for a chest pain,
a dog bite, and a flu.
Thank you. You got any room?
Oh, thank you.
I owe you.
Leah, tell any walk-ins
who can fend for themselves
that we'll be
arranging for transport
to Rush and Mercy.
Okay?
Hey, have you heard
from pathology yet?
Let me give them
another call.
Please.
It's busy.
I'll check back in a minute.
Okay.
You look worried.
I do? That's not good.
I just...
I lost so many kids
to cancer this year
that every time
one comes in now
with the same symptoms,
I just...
I can't help but feel
the fear rising in me,
and it's all I can
do to control it,
so that I don't
scare the family.
Dr. Manning,
I've got your biopsy results.
Pathology called me in.
Why is an epidemiologist
getting called in on this?
Coccidioidomycosis?
Otherwise known
as Valley Fever,
and it's highly infectious.
Oh! Thank God.
You realize this is
a serious illness?
Yes.
No, yes, absolutely.
But at least
it isn't cancer.
That's what was causing
the fever and the swelling?
A fungal infection?
Spores are
typically found in soil,
predominantly
in desert locales.
Valley Fever isn't endemic
of the Great Lakes region.
Have you spent any time
in the Southwest recently?
California?
Nevada? Arizona?
No, Desmond's never been
further away from home
than Grand Rapids.
None of us has.
Okay, well,
we'd like to start your son
on a round of IV
antifungals right away.
But I do have to warn you,
it's strong medicine with
the potential of side effects,
but it is what he needs.
Thank you, doctors.
I'll get started on Desmond.
I'm sorry, uh, but your
son is the second person
I've seen with this disease.
I'm gonna need
a detailed history
from the both of you.
It could help me find
the source of the infection.
I mean, can we do this later?
We just want to be
with our child right now.
It's important
that we find this
before someone else's
child gets infected.
I can sit with you
one at a time
if that's better.
You go. Be with Desmond.
Thank you.
At first, I thought it
was just the sedation.
You know, but her eyes,
she's just not able to focus.
I had her fix on my finger
from about this distance.
They dart back and forth
to a random space over here.
Almost mechanical.
A square wave jerk.
Exactly.
So any time I get
an eye thing after
a fall on the head,
I'm thinking, you know,
possible stroke, but...
Did your workup
come back negative?
Yeah.
Any idea what else
this might be?
It could be anything
from a basal ganglia
disorder to normal aging.
It's impossible to tell
without a head CT or an MRI.
You know,
maybe if you just
examine her yourself...
Do I need to explain
the definition of
"impossible" to you?
I'm a neurosurgeon,
not a magician.
Just find someone
who can get the scans
back up and running,
and then maybe
we can all do our jobs.
Any word on when
we might be getting
our network back?
Sorry.
You think they
still need my tablet?
I'm afraid so,
Dr. Charles.
Dr. Charles, hey,
about those H and Ps,
Mrs. Kornbluth in Room 17,
she was admitted
experiencing hallucinations.
Okay, okay...
At intake, it was determined
that she was having
a psychotic episode,
but after speaking with her,
I think she simply
might have had an
adverse reaction to Ambien.
This is all proving to be
an incredible inconvenience,
I just wanna say.
I cannot believe
that our patients'
psychiatric histories
aren't hosted on
a separate secure network,
and that HIPAA
hadn't mandated that.
Moving forward,
you know, maybe...
But in the meantime,
it might've been beneficial
for us to retrace our steps.
I am running some tests now,
but I think we might
be able to discharge
Mrs. Kornbluth later today.
Oh, there's the IT guy.
Bruce.
Old rule of thumb.
If you can read
through the bag,
the test is negative.
So there's no
bleeding in the abdomen?
No.
Well, that's
good news, right?
So you want me to crack
this guy's chest open
and put him on
bypass on a hunch?
Not a hunch.
The diagnosis of exclusion.
And what if
you're wrong?
He's not wrong
I mean, the DPL
ruled out the bullet traveling
through the peritoneum,
and if it went through
the retroperitoneum,
then he would have
reported back pain,
so it had to have embolized.
Dr. Choi,
he knows his stuff.
It's how he does it
on the battlefield.
So we can't just
transfer this guy
to another trauma center
with a working CT?
Too risky. He could
decompensate at any moment,
and every second
we wait just ups the risk
of a massive
pulmonary embolism.
All right,
I'll call the OR.
Thanks.
I don't understand
what is taking so long.
Get him going.
I'll meet you up there.
Yeah.
If I could just
access my files,
I'm sure I could find a link
between these cases.
I'm sorry,
but I was told by IT
that the malware is
quite sophisticated.
Then why don't you
just pay the ransom?
It's not that simple, Robin.
But it is that simple.
It's right there
on every screen.
Easy instructions
to pay the ransom
and obtain a decryption key.
A 3-year-old
could figure it out.
Hey, Robin, what's going on?
What's going on is
there might be an epidemic
of Valley Fever breaking out,
and no one seems to care.
Let me remind you,
Ms. Charles,
in case the air
is too thin to breathe
atop that soap box,
that you are
an epidemiologist,
and I am the one responsible
for running this hospital.
Why don't we just take
a second to cool down?
Why don't we?
Don't handle me.
Hey.
Barry Lindheim again.
Thinks you're
dodging his calls.
Smart man.
Tell him you can't find me.
Okay.
Back online?
I guess this means
that we are off of bypass?
Yes, we are
off of bypass.
Hallelujah.
Thank you, Sharon.
No, no, thank him.
He's the real hero.
Bruce, great job.
I'm sorry.
I didn't do anything.
What?
The system came
back up on its own.
Someone must've
paid the ransom.
You didn't
authorize this?
Then who did?
Peter.
I thought we agreed
we weren't gonna
pay the ransom.
We didn't pay the ransom.
Then what happened?
Who knows?
Look, maybe the hackers
felt the feds were getting
close and they bailed.
In any case,
the problem's been resolved,
and we can get
back to business,
saving lives, making money.
Someone countermanded
my orders, Peter.
Sharon,
whoever that person was,
they did us a huge favor,
so let's not look a gift horse
in the mouth, okay?
Preliminary visual
inspection shows no
pericardial effusion.
Thank you, Dr. Bardovi.
I was just informed
that we're back online,
in case that's pertinent.
Well, we're not
gonna close him back up
and send him to radiology
just to wind up
where we are now.
So let's ultrasound
the heart directly
and see if we
can't find the bullet.
There,
in the right ventricle.
Yeah,
that could be our culprit.
Scalpel?
Forceps.
Hey.
Nice work.
I guess that Navy training
wasn't a waste after all.
That's how we do it
on the battlefield.
Well, if it hadn't worked,
I would've blamed you anyway.
I know.
Hey, Dr. Rhodes,
I don't know if you heard,
but somebody paid the ransom,
an open violation
of hospital policy.
What, you think it was me?
I'm sorry, Ms. Goodwin,
but as much as I
would like to take credit,
I didn't do it.
Well, somebody paid.
Was it you, Sam?
My kid starts
Sarah Lawrence in the fall.
Not a chance in hell
I'm cutting a check that size
to solve your problem.
Okay, so you're telling me
nobody here knows
anything about this?
You got a second?
What? You think
I need a timeout?
No.
I'm not endorsing
any kind of palace coup,
but I just...
I understand any
number of motivations
why somebody would
wanna get that thing paid.
I've completely
freaked myself out
how much I miss
this thing, you know?
Which has clearly
become a powerful tool
that I use to
maintain distance
between myself
and the world, you know?
Control my environment.
And that's
a slippery slope, man.
Control, you know,
for all of us.
I mean, one second
you're steady in command.
Next second, it's like, ah,
rogue wave, you know,
hackers, relationships
we can't control.
Come on, Daniel.
Are you trying to
bait and switch me?
I'm not in denial.
I know my husband is gone.
I may never get a good answer
for why he left,
but I sure as hell
can find out
who paid that ransom.
Your son is taking
well to the medication.
Hopefully,
in a couple days,
he'll be able to
take this orally
and we can send him home.
Thank you, Dr. Manning.
I'm glad we brought him here.
We did, however,
get your test
results back as well.
Ivie,
yours came back negative.
Chad, however,
you tested positive.
Positive? But I feel fine.
It just means
you've come in contact
with a spore.
A lot of people
never become symptomatic,
but moving forward,
it is something to monitor.
Mr. Rawls,
I think I found a connection
between Desmond
and my other patient.
You told me earlier
you use your car
to ride-share.
Yeah. Why?
My patient last week,
she rode in your
car 18 days ago.
I mean,
if you say so. No way I can
remember everyone I drove.
Did you park it here?
I'd like to take a look at it.
I don't understand.
Why would my car be
making people sick?
I apologize,
Lyla, for the delay.
I know you must be
eager to get out of here.
Yeah, are you gonna
stitch me up or what?
I am, but now that
our imaging system's
come back online,
I'd like to get you
down for a CT scan
of your head first.
I just grazed my head.
It's really
not a big deal.
I hear you.
Still, standard of care
requires me to get a head CT.
So blame it on
insurance companies,
if you must.
Hey, I couldn't
decide what to get.
So I bought the whole rack.
Did I miss something?
Uh...
Dr. Halstead just said
that it might be
a couple more hours
until he can stitch me up.
You mind running to my place
and walking the dog?
No, of course.
I'll hurry back.
Okay, thanks, babe.
Why do I get the impression
there's something going on
you don't want
either of us to know?
You don't have
to send me down
for the CT scan.
I can tell you what
it's going to show.
Dr. Halstead,
I got a message
you wanted to see me.
Yes and no.
Actually, Ms. Dempsey
would like to speak with you.
Why?
I was told
you wanted
to speak with me.
Yes, thank you.
Yeah, this is pretty much
as awkward as I imagined.
But now that I told
Dr. Halstead,
I assumed it was
a matter of time
before the head
of the hospital
found out as well.
Last year, I was
diagnosed with a disease
called progressive
supranuclear palsy, PSP,
which is a poor
relation to Parkinson's.
I'm familiar with PSP.
I'm sorry.
What's your prognosis?
Five more years,
maybe ten.
What are you going to do?
Seize the day, right?
I'm still able to
hide the symptoms
for the most part,
at least from lay people,
which is why
I wanted to talk to you.
You haven't told Bert,
have you?
Want to scare off
a potential guy
lickety-split?
Tell him, in three years,
you won't be able
to swallow or chew
or breathe
without their help.
I didn't get a lot of
calls for a second date,
so when I met Bert...
Look...
Bert and I may
have run our course,
but keeping this
from him is a mistake.
I'm selfish, I know.
I'm scared to spend
the last few years
of my life alone, you know?
Yes, I do.
How long have
you owned this car?
About two months.
Bought it used
from some place
out in Hillside.
Only had
40,000 miles on it.
Do you know anything
about the previous owner?
No.
So what exactly
are we looking for here?
That's the ride-share app.
Yeah.
What's this?
Uh, I don't know.
It was on there
when we bought it.
"FAT." It's not something
you really wanna advertise,
but we couldn't get
the sticker off the car.
That's actually
an IATA code.
It's an airport abbreviation.
That's Fresno International.
California, Central Valley?
I suspect
your car might have spores
in the air filters.
They could stay
active that long?
Yeah, I'm sorry,
but the CDC's gonna
have to impound your car.
And we're gonna need
to check and notify every
passenger you have had.
Okay, it's... I know...
Hey, Mags,
I need to leave early.
I gotta let the plumber
into my apartment.
Why can't your girlfriend,
Vicki, do that for you?
She got deployed. Germany.
Oh, that must be hard
on the two of you.
Well, it's not
the two of us anymore.
Oh.
Hi.
Hey.
I hear we dodged a bullet
with that GSW earlier.
Ah... So to speak.
So to speak.
Noah thinks you're
some sort of a miracle worker.
No, just a guy who's seen
way too many shootings.
Oh, Dr. Charles,
hey, I just finished
the last history.
It's fascinating, really.
The patient thought
I was an...
An FBI agent. I saw.
The system's back up.
But thank you.
Dr. Charles?
If you want to fire me,
why don't you
just do it already?
Fire you?
Wait, why would I
want to fire you?
Okay, I might not be
the greatest psych
intern of all time,
but I know
a little bit about subtext
and the cognitive unconscious.
And so when you tell me
that there's an opening
in the ED, I'm left to wonder
does that mean you
want me to quit psych
and take that job?
No. No, it does not
mean that at all.
Because I am not quitting.
I am sticking with this
all the way, and so
if you wanna get rid of me,
you're going to have to
do more than just
try to get in my head.
Leah, thank you.
That was a good job today.
Thank you, Ms. Goodwin.
I forgot you were a pacer.
Wore out the rug every time
you were in the delivery room.
I don't know
why I'm doing it now.
Lyla's just getting stitches.
Nobody ever died
of that, right?
Well, I'm sure
it'll all work out.
Sharon, um...
I know it was
incredibly insensitive of me
to bring Lyla into your ED.
You don't deserve to
be treated like this.
Bert...
I owe you
an apology, Sharon.
I've crafted
a few in my head.
I've even written some down.
I'm just so...
Bert, please, it's fine.
Mr. Goodwin?
You wanted to know
when Lyla was all sewn up?
Yeah, yeah. Thanks.
You know, maybe someday,
I can introduce
the two of you formally.
Yeah, sure.
Hey, Nina left
this for you earlier.
Oh.
Thanks.
Mmm-hmm.
So I heard Goodwin's ex
brought his new girlfriend in.
Yeah, Lyla.
Mmm.
That's gotta be tough,
seeing someone
you care about so much
with a new lover.
Yeah, tell me about it.
I mean,
I was the one treating Lyla.
Right.
Good night.
Good night, Ms. Goodwin.
Night.
I was going to
get a little drink.
Yes.
You find out who
paid the ransom yet?
You know what?
I don't care.
Who do we have next?
Two CABGs, back to back.
At least the hybrid
suite's back online.
Everyone's wondering
who paid the ransom.
I did.
Thirty Bitcoin versus
the continued integrity
of our services?
Pretty simple math,
don't you think?
Honey, what's going on?
Why are you up?
Seriously,
who can sleep through that?
Through what?
The rats.
My God, it's like
nails on a chalkboard.
This whole city
must be infested.
Can't you hear them?