♪ Ho, ho-ho-ho-ho-ho-ho,
Ho ho, ho-ho, ho ♪♪
It's freezing out there, babe.
Carol?
What are you doing?
Oh, the furnace
went out in the night.
I tried to start the
pilot, but I think it's shot.
It's below zero in here.
It's not so bad when
you start moving.
There's frost on the blankets.
I thought you said
we weren't going to
try to use that fireplace
until the chimney
sweep checked it out.
No, look. I just have
to pull this thing.
Oh!
Come on.
Let's just go out and
get some breakfast.
I'll never get someone
to come here and
open it before Christmas.
Well, let's just have
Christmas at my place.
At least I have
heat and plumbing.
I've got plumbing... almost.
I wanted to wake up here
on Christmas morning.
You know, the tree was
going to look so beautiful.
So it's a little chilly.
We'll put something
under the door, you know,
to stop the draft.
That's not a draft.
That's a gale-force wind.
We're going to get pneumonia.
Put on some socks.
Look, old houses are chilly.
Some...
Some houses need show shovels
in the parlor?
♪ Hark, how the bells
Sweet silver bells ♪
♪ All seem to say
Throw cares away ♪
♪ Christmas is here
Bringing good cheer ♪
♪ To young and old
Meek and the bold ♪
♪ Ding dong, ding
dong That is their song ♪
♪ With joyful
ring All caroling ♪
♪ One seems to hear
Words of good cheer ♪
♪ From everywhere
Filling the air ♪
♪ Oh, how they pound
Raising their sound ♪
♪ O'er hill and dale
Telling their tale ♪
♪ Gaily they ring
While people sing ♪
♪ Songs of good cheer
Christmas is here ♪
♪ Merry, merry, merry
Merry Christmas ♪
♪ Merry, Merry Merry,
merry Christmas ♪
♪ On, on they send
On without end ♪
♪ Their joyful tone
To every home ♪
♪ On, on they send
On without end ♪
♪ Their joyful tone
To every home ♪
♪ Ding dong ding dong ♪
♪ Bom... ♪♪
Ladies and gentlemen,
straight from the 4th floor,
the Recovery Room Choraliers.
Recovery has way too
much time on their hands.
Well, thanks again.
You guys are great.
We can't wait to hear you folks.
Us folks?
4:00 on our floor.
You promised.
Who promised?
Carol Hathaway.
See you then.
Oh, I'm sorry I'm going
to miss Carol's solo.
You ever heard her
sing? She needs your help.
Uh-uh. I'm off at 3:00,
and I got all the
kids still to buy for.
I can't carry a tune.
So, who's representing the docs?
You need a consult, right?
Uh, yeah. I believe
that the dulcet baritones
of Mark Greene
would be a fine
addition to any ensemble.
That's what he
gets for being late.
He's at the attorney's
this morning.
Not letting any grass grow
under that split-up.
Couldn't he and Jen
wait till after the holidays?
Uh, no. The hospital attorneys.
His deposition on the
O'Brien wrongful-death suit.
The pregnant woman last winter?
Oh. Oh! Ugh.
In case his holidays
weren't cheerful enough.
The important
thing is to stay calm
and stick to the facts.
I am calm.
Well, then, maybe you
should take off your coat.
Sure.
Mark, this is going
to be a long process.
It could be another year
before we reach a settlement.
Or go to trial.
We'll try to avoid that.
And why is that again,
if there's no obvious
breach of standard?
But in a case where
the injuries are inflammatory,
like leaving a
newborn motherless,
we'd still prefer to settle.
And if we settle,
it goes on my
record permanently?
Looks better than losing
a 1.5 million judgment at trial.
I gotta use the men's room.
Back there.
Whoa! Hey, whoa, little guy.
Mr. O'Brien.
Dr. Greene.
He's doing well.
Yes, he is.
Come on, Mark.
They're ready to begin.
What is this?
"Living Nativity
on Ice" v. Zamboni.
What?
First Korean Baptist youth group
waiting to rehearse
at the Skate on State.
Zamboni driver plowed
right into the manger.
Six injured, I think.
What's the bullet on this one?
Multiple trauma.
Complaint of pain in
legs, ribs, and head.
Vitals stable.
LOC for approximately
two minutes. GCS 15.
Moves extremities
times four now.
IV saline.
Okay, get X-ray down here
and do a CT On her head.
Uh, check out the lamb.
Put the Virgin Mary in 3.
Oh, careful. Looks like
partial thickness burns
to forearms and hands.
I didn't even want to be a lamb!
Okay, let's get some
cool saline dressing.
How'd she get burnt?
The Zamboni
shoots out hot water.
Lucky she landed
flat on the ice.
Ow! It hurts!
75 Demerol, 25
Vistaril. I'll be right back.
Somebody help my son!
Can you feel this?
Wiggle your fingers.
Ma'am, did he lose
consciousness?
No? All right. Come
here. What's your name?
I'm a wise man. Did
they have names?
Jesus, Mary, and Joseph.
Right you are. There you go.
Okay, take a seat.
Please tell me you
weren't using a real infant.
Jesus was a doll.
Thank you. Who's this?
Zamboni driver.
Fell five feet from the
driver's seat onto the ice.
LOC on the scene.
Ooh! Smell that breath.
Merry Christmas.
So you're asking to observe
this morning's clamp-and-run?
Yup, because I
missed your last two.
And at the same time,
you're telling me
you didn't finish
last night's discharge
summaries?
I'll catch up right
after surgery.
Plus I kind of implied
to Macy I'd be there.
Macy? The patient's wife.
They were really
nervous last night.
He's got a history
of thoracic aneurysm.
They thought his
backache was a strain
from putting up
the Christmas lights.
Ah, which you
chatted about last night
instead of finishing
your charts,
so this morning,
you're going to do
what you were
supposed to do last night.
The patient... No, the patient
will not notice that
you're not there.
Carter, this is
not a social hour.
This is surgery.
The Star of the East
is heading up for a
tooth reimplantation.
You're overreacting.
It's just a couple
of Christmas carols.
I don't know any.
"Jingle Bells."
Everybody knows "Jingle Bells."
Never heard of it.
And... I can't sing in public.
Why?
I hate it when
people stare at me.
Oh, I can tell.
Things were pretty wild
around here for a while.
It seems to be
under control now.
Yeah? How about with you?
How'd your deposition go?
♪ Fa la la la la... ♪
Hey, Mark, that's the spirit.
How about 4:00?
4:00. Uh, I... I can't make it.
It's a miracle
none of those kids
were critically hurt.
You know, the cops
are charging that driver
right now.
They can charge him with a DUI
on a Zamboni?
No, ZUI.
Last year, I gave her
a T-bond for Christmas.
She accuses me of
not being romantic.
But, thinking long-term...
That's exactly what I said.
You know, I mean, a
diamond may be forever,
but hey, a ten-year
maturity at six percent
is not chopped liver.
This year I had a brainst...
Uh... damn.
Bender, could you,
uh... do me a favor
and open me up a
new brush? Thanks.
This year on Christmas morning,
I'm getting her 10
shares of AT&T.
It's Benton.
Right. Next day,
she gets 20 shares
of General Electric.
On the third day, 30
shares of Dupont, right?
On the fourth day, I'm gonna...
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
You gotta repeat this for Carl.
Later, please.
I'm here to tell you
we can all relax.
It seems that our patient
has had second thoughts,
and he's withdrawn his
consent for the procedure.
Doesn't he realize
that he was our last
chance to beat the clock
before the new year?
Can't we change his mind back?
Well, actually, Dr. Benton and I
are going to find
that out right now.
If you care to join me?
Sure.
That's a pretty nasty cut
you got there, Mr. Calus.
Stan. And it's my own fault.
I've been carving the toys
by hand for a million years,
but business has
gotten so hectic,
I went to a power jig and router
for some of the
more popular items,
like the rolling
ducks on a stick.
Oh, I love those.
What a great job, making toys.
Got rich and fat without
even asking for it.
Sometimes, though,
I miss the old days,
just me and my old
lady packing up the VW
and hitting the craft fairs.
Now I've got a whole crew
working for me 'round the clock.
Still can't keep up
with the back orders.
Well, this hand's
going to slow you down.
Lucky we're down to
shipping and handling.
I hate to disappoint any kids.
When was the last time
you had a tetanus shot?
Oh ho...
it's been ages.
Well, the doctor's
probably going to want you
to have one.
You would make a great Santa.
Ah!
I bet you hear that
pretty often, huh?
Eh, this time of year.
So, it goes with
the territory, Peter.
I mean, if you're
going to develop
cutting-edge techniques,
you'd better learn how
to sell it to the masses.
I mean, I know it's
a pain in the ass,
but if you find the simple
metaphor for people,
you could help define
the procedure for yourself.
Hmm. I can imagine. Yeah.
We had the same problem
with endarterectomies.
Nobody knew of them.
Nobody wanted one.
At first, I shied away from
the Roto-Rooter metaphor.
I thought it was
a bit too crass,
but in the long run,
that's what people
can understand.
Now, why don't you see
if you can get the Chamberlains
to understand?
I'll do my best.
Well, here we go.
Mr. Chamberlain. I'd like
you to meet Dr. Benton.
He works with me.
Pleased to meet you.
Elderly victim of a
carjacking coming in.
Head trauma with ALOC.
How nice.
Here you go.
This is my Christmas bonus?
A hearty handshake
and a "job well done"?
No, that's a check for my share
of tonight's Christmas party.
I love it when the docs pay.
Yeah, especially
when we guilt them
into booking the Knickerbocker.
Hey, is everybody dressing up?
I'm going to wash
behind my ears.
Hey, they're pulling up now.
Listen, I noticed
that you signed up
for Christmas Eve
and Christmas Day.
I don't mind working then.
Oh, me either.
Kerry Weaver
made the same offer,
but Jen has got
Rachel in Dayton,
and I won't get her back
until Christmas night,
so I'd just as soon work.
Okay, well, if you
change your mind.
Carjack victim?
Unidentified female
pulled from her car
at the corner of
Roosevelt and Ashland.
Some Salvation Army
bell-ringer saw the whole thing.
Said she hit her head
on the curb pretty hard.
BP's 160/120.
She was awake en
route, but disoriented.
We got two IVs of normal
saline, O-2 15 liters by mask.
All right, let's do it
on my count... gently.
One, two, three.
Cross-table C-spine,
and, uh, get a head CT.
She's going to
be a sore little lady
at Christmas Mass.
I don't think
this little old lady
goes to Mass.
What's that?
She's a survivor.
Of what?
Concentration camp.
All right, let's get a
CBC, type and hold,
spin a crit, dip
the urine for heme,
update her tetanus, and
hang a gram of Ancef.
The technique that
you gave consent to is...
I don't know techniques.
Macy said she wants to
wait, and that's fine by me.
Macy is your wife? Yes.
Well, maybe we
should talk to Macy.
Be my guest.
I don't blame you one bit.
You have every
right to have cold feet.
Carter?
Dr. Benton,
Dr. Vucelich. I was just...
I bumped into Macy in
the cafeteria having coffee,
and I was just explaining to
her that she's not the first spouse
to have second thoughts
on the day of major surgery.
I feel like a fool.
Well, you're not.
Flip-flopping this way and that.
I guess I'm pretty
much scared to death.
Hope you don't
think I'm crazy, honey,
but after talking
to Dr. Carter...
I know. You're not a doctor yet,
but I feel so much better...
So if it's not too late, can
we get on with the surgery?
Yes.
Yes, ma'am, we certainly can.
Is Mr. Carter free to join us?
Yes, I am.
Do you know where you are?
Good news for her.
The police just called.
They found a car matching
the eyewitness' description
off the 290 in a snow
bank near Berkeley.
If she's Hanna Steiner,
she's got her car back.
Hanna? Are you Hanna Steiner?
Uh... yeah.
You're in a hospital.
You were pulled from
your car at a stoplight.
Oh.
We're just going to
check you out here
and make sure
everything's all right.
Oh no.
But you need to stay calm,
'cause you've got...
you've been hit in the head.
Tirzah. What about Tirzah?
Tirzah?
The baby. Oh, my
God... the baby.
What baby?
My granddaughter.
She was in the car.
She was in the car seat.
They didn't say
anything about a baby.
Is she okay?
Call the police.
Oh, no.
Tirzah!
Mrs. Steiner. Mrs. Steiner.
Try and stay calm
and lie still, okay?
The police are going to
do everything they can.
No! No!
Get me back that
police dispatcher again.
It's about the carjacking.
Just try and relax.
Breathe easy.
She's refused the Ativan
and doesn't want to go for a CT.
I think she's still hoping
to hear some good news.
Mmm. Me too.
Any news?
Not yet.
We're still trying
to reach your son.
That won't do any good.
They live too far out.
Mrs. Steiner, are you
sure you don't want Ativan?
It will calm you down.
I never should
have driven with her.
We need to finish
your evaluation.
If you go for a CT,
I promise I'll come find you
as soon as we hear anything.
You really need a CAT scan.
Like a loch in kop.
No, to make sure you
don't have a loch in kop.
Hole in her head.
Okay.
I'll go.
Mark, your wife's on the phone.
I'll take it in the lounge.
But please... find me
if you hear anything.
I will.
You think they're okay?
She'll love them.
You're sure?
I mean, they're 22 karat.
They're beautiful.
I mean, they're not, like,
real rubies or anything.
Yeah, but... they're
really, really lovely.
You still here?
I'm leaving right now.
They're perfect for her.
Red is her color.
Mmm.
No, Jen. No.
I'm not gonna let you
walk all over me on this one.
You should have thought of it
before you started
screwing your coworker.
Hey.
Oh, man. Jen had
the nerve to suggest
that Rachel stay
with her in Dayton
for two more days.
What for?
Some skating party
Rachel's cousins are having.
Jen is really pushing it.
She's the one having an affair,
and I'm supposed to
give up my daughter
at Christmas.
She really has
great timing, huh?
Mid-December kamikaze strike.
Maximize pain and suffering.
And I know you don't
want to take it out
on Rachel.
Of course not.
I'm taking Susie over
to Cookie and Henry's tomorrow.
It's, uh, dreadful
family fare, and...
we'd love you to join us.
Thanks, but...
Dr. Greene?
Randi has Mrs. Steiner's
son on the phone.
He's calling from Glen Ellen.
I'm on my way. Later.
Somebody hit fast forward?
Carl, you're at warp speed.
You should have seen
my mother darn a sock.
Time?
You're at 55 minutes
and 30 seconds.
Well, gentlemen, we're
about to make a run
for beating the clock.
Personal best still
stands at 57:07.
Peter, you're a lucky man.
Am I?
You have a student
who talks to patients.
Must save you a
lot of headaches.
Sometimes.
How many of these
have you assisted on?
This is my fifth.
Really? You ready
to finish this one?
Yeah.
Really? And still have
us break the record?
Now, don't say yes
unless you can be sure.
I'm sure.
All right. Carter,
do the suctioning.
Simon, watch the clock.
Come on. 56:14 and counting.
All right, now, go
inside-out on the aorta,
outside-in on the graft.
That's right.
Long bites. Move it along.
Pick up the pace. Come
on, find your stroke.
56:30.
That's it. Don't... Don't...
don't twist the Gor-tex.
Go, go, go. Pull up the slack.
57 on the nose.
Okay. Ready to tie off.
Do it, Carter. Cut it
at three millimeters.
57:06.
Did it.
No, not yet. We still
have to check for leakage.
Release the distal Satinsky.
Looks good.
Proximal clamp.
Looks very good.
Time?
57:16.
Oh, isn't that too bad?
We didn't break the record.
Would have been a nice
way to ring out the year. Hmm?
Randi, did Mrs. Steiner
come back from CT yet?
On her way.
Any news on her granddaughter?
Must be 20 miles of highway
between here and
where they found the car.
People are sick.
Well, the parents are on
their way in from Glen Ellyn.
And in this weather,
it's going to take them a while.
Oh, my poor roof.
Mlungisi?
Kerry!
Mlungisi.
I came straight
from the airport.
If you'll have me.
I was just about
to go on a break.
Uh... everyone,
this is Mlungisi.
Hi.
My pleasure.
I'll be back in half an hour.
Fine.
Mark, Mrs. Steiner's back.
No?
Not yet. They're
still searching.
My son and I could
use some help here!
We need a doctor!
Uh, Dr. Ross!
Dr. Ross!
Right this way.
He took a bullet
in his shoulder.
Okay. Are you all right?
Can you walk on your own?
Yeah, yeah.
Hang tough, kiddo.
Trauma 1!
She's only been
missing a short time.
Now, don't give up.
I guess I don't
have to tell you that.
Mm-hm.
It's easier when you're young.
You know nothing else.
They call you, uh...
"dirty Jew" in school.
You've seen the worst of people.
And the best.
This little baby...
She's so sweet.
They just wanted the car.
I don't think they
would hurt her.
But they would.
No.
You go on after
you have seen evil.
Oh, you laugh,
you work, you have children.
You don't let it own you.
That's your revenge...
To live.
And then...
something like this,
and you know that it
can all be taken away.
We still hope for the best.
Yeah. You hope.
You know what I was thinking
when I was upstairs here
in this... this machine,
lying so still?
I did something
that I stopped
doing 50 years ago.
I prayed to God.
You know Yiddish, Dr. Greene?
A little from my grandmother.
But you are a religious man?
I'm the son of an agnostic Jew
and a lapsed Catholic.
You're no good at all.
I can't ask you, you...
to pray for my family.
Well, I can try.
Yeah.
Dreaming of a white Christmas?
Oh, I'm hoping the tarp
stays tied on my roof.
I hope the party's not history.
The drive's already
at a standstill.
All the more reason
to celebrate, right?
So I was thinking
4:00 up in recovery...
You've heard me sing.
Poor Susie hears the first line
of "Rock-a-bye baby"
and goes to sleep as
a defense mechanism.
Well, you just mouth the words.
That's what I do.
While who sings?
I'm working on that. Carter?
No, no, no, no.
Chronic tone deafness
and acute stage fright.
Do you have time now?
Oh yeah. Find me in Radiology.
Carol, Mr. Calus is
ready for sterile dressing.
Mark, who's in there with him?
It's his family.
Don't you think... doesn't
he remind you of somebody?
Are you kidding?
He's the spitting image.
I mean, I know it's
ridiculous, but still...
No, no. He looks just like him.
You know, when he was
old, right before he died.
Before who died? Jerry Garcia.
That's who we're
talking about, isn't it?
Oh, Carter, she'll love them.
You think?
Yeah, they look just like her.
They're not too much?
No. They're fun.
I know, Harper and I
haven't been seeing
each other that long...
They're great.
I saw them, and
I just thought...
you sure they're not too much?
Carter...
are you telling me these...
are these real?
They're too much.
No!
I mean, they're
beautiful. She'll love them.
I went overboard.
No, of course not.
You thought of her,
she'll be touched.
Yeah? Yeah.
Susan, we need
a doctor out here.
Somebody help us!
Our priest has been shot!
Here, here. Put him here.
You're all right, B-Pop.
You're gonna be all right now.
You're at the hospital now.
What happened?
We found him at the church.
LG shot him up like a dog.
How much blood did he lose?
A lot, man. 911
didn't even show up.
We drove him in ourselves.
Okay, we'll take
care of him now.
Jeanie, you're on.
You're going to be okay, man.
They shot a priest?
I am out of here.
Bet I beat you out the door.
See y'all at the party.
Careful on the roads.
Mark, I hope it's not too late
for me to withdraw my
offer to work the holidays.
No, no. Looks like
you have a visitor.
Yeah. I think I
may skip the party.
I'll be right there, Mlungisi.
Kerry, you didn't expect him?
Uh-uh. A complete surprise.
I love surprises.
Mlungisi's full of them.
So, how do you, um, know him?
I, uh...
I had a farm in Africa.
Sinus tach.
Good bilateral breath sounds.
No tracheal shift.
Doctor, please...
Father, please, try
to relax. Pulse ox?
96.
Good. He's not hypoxic.
Where the hell's X-ray?
On their way.
Here you go.
I have to speak to
Diablo, the boy outside.
Father, not now.
Please...
I need to talk to
him before I die.
You're not going to die.
Please.
I'm gonna find that kid.
Okay, okay. Okay.
Squad car's on its way in
with an infant that
fits the description
of Hanna Steiner's grandchild.
Do we need warming blankets?
I don't think so.
They found her in
this triple-X theater
on Ashland.
Police aren't sure
of her condition,
except that she's
screaming her head off.
That's a good sign.
I got her.
Lungs are working.
Tell the grandmother.
No, let's check
her condition first.
Take her to T-1.
Get the warmer.
It's already done.
No signs of trauma.
Good one. Here.
She's alert and interactive.
Makes good eye contact.
Good breath sounds.
Let's get a core temperature.
What?
A core temperature.
No apparent injury.
Mad as hell.
Tirzah!
Mrs. Steiner.
I knew it was you.
Please.
All right. Okay. Go ahead.
Yes, yes, yes. Yes, my darling.
Oh, sweetheart, bless you.
Oh, sweetheart.
Yeah, shush, shush, shush.
She's... she's hungry is all.
I don't believe you, B-Pop.
No. Listen to me.
Shooting.
We have to step away.
No.
AP chest.
Get the shoulder vest.
Man, you're trying
to protect the LGs.
Man, I know you are.
I know they did
this to you, B-Pop.
I saw him. I saw him.
He wasn't from the 'hood.
You're trying to keep the
truce, B-Pop. I know, man.
Father, stop talking.
Shooting again.
Diablito. Stay still, Father.
It wasn't the LG.
I swear to God.
You need to go now.
Malik?
Let's go.
No, man. No.
Come on.
B-Pop, man.
Let's go.
For him.
For Diablo.
I need a wet read
on those. Top priority.
Give them to me.
Thanks.
Sorry I left you with all
the last-minute deliveries.
Oh, no problem. I like to drive.
You call that driving or flying?
It's nice that you're all
willing to help out your dad.
The whole brood will
be charging me overtime.
See you back at the homestead.
Got your maps?
The naughty and the nice.
Okay, Mr. Calus,
I will be right back
with your tetanus shot.
And I would just like to say
how much I've enjoyed
taking care of you today.
Well, that's
awfully nice to hear.
I've been surrounded by
bah-humbuggers all day.
No one's in the spirit.
They won't even sing
a few Christmas carols,
But you have been the exception.
Well, you can't
count on other people
to give it to you.
Know what I mean? The spirit?
It's in you.
You're right.
You are absolutely right.
Thank you.
I'm going to sing
some Christmas carols.
Anybody care to join me?
It's 4:00. I'm going
up to Recovery.
Last chance to spread
some holiday cheer.
What?
And God bless us, everyone.
Pressure's still falling.
All right, let's get him up.
What about x-rays?
Can't wait. Father cannot wait.
Watch it.
Coming through.
Diablo...
Move! Move! Watch it!
Look out!
Get him up.
Man, what's going on?
Damn! He's bradying down.
We're losing his
pulse. Get him back.
What's going on?
All right. Bag him.
I'll start compressions.
Malik? I got you.
Back to trauma.
B-Pop! Where are you taking him?
Hurry up!
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
No room at the inn.
Pulse is gone.
Damn it! He's
bleeding out. Curtain 2.
Mark! Mark, 2!
Out of the way!
Move out of the way!
Run the IVs wide open.
Rapid infuser. Thoracotomy tray.
Scalpel.
Rib spreader.
Man. What's going on,
man? What's wrong?
Suction. Malik,
hold the retractor.
Suction! Come on!
Oh, damn it.
Cross clamp him now.
All right. Satinsky!
Bullet severed the aorta.
Start internal compressions.
Come on! Hurry up in there!
Damn.
Thank you!
Hey! Watch out!
Where's the priest?
Curtain 2.
Widened mediastinum.
Time of death: 4:17.
Oh, man...
Oh, man, no.
Oh, man. Come on. Do something.
Do something else.
Like, try and do something, man.
It won't help. I'm sorry.
Oh, man.
Well, get... get him a priest.
You guys can do that, right?
You guys can get him a priest?
Lydia, can you,
uh... run upstairs
and try to find the chaplain?
He'd want a priest.
♪ Four calling birds
Three French hens ♪
♪ Two turtle doves ♪
♪ And a partridge
In a pear tree ♪
♪ On the twelfth
day Of Christmas ♪
♪ My true love gave to me ♪
♪ Uh... ♪
♪ 12 tone-deaf doctors ♪
♪ 11 lords a-lording ♪
♪ 10 drummers drumming ♪
♪ Nine something something ♪
♪ Eight maids a-milking ♪
♪ Seven swans a-swatting ♪
♪ Six geese a-gagging ♪
♪ Five golden rings! ♪
♪ Four calling birds
Three French hens ♪
♪ Two turtle doves ♪
♪ And a partridge
In a pear tree ♪♪
Thank you.
♪ We wish you A
merry Christmas ♪
♪ We wish you a
♪ We wish you A
merry Christmas ♪
♪ And a happy new year ♪♪
And suddenly there
was with the angel
a multitude of the heavenly host
praising God and saying
"Glory to the
God in the highest,
and on Earth, peace
and good will toward men."
LOL with sudden back pain.
She's diaphoretic,
short of breath.
What's her history?
Hypertension. She's
220/140 right now.
Call Mark. Get
Carter down here now.
Aye-aye, sir.
My back. It's ripping apart.
Doctor, help her.
When did this pain start?
20 minutes ago.
We were shopping.
Loss of pulses.
Aortic regurge.
Let's get a chest
film, an angiogram.
Propranolol, one
milligram IV bolus.
Set up an art line.
Is it a heart attack?
No, sir. Your wife's
EKG is normal.
I'm ordering some tests now
to see if she has a
dissecting aneurysm.
Pressure's coming down.
Start sodium nitroprusside,
50 micrograms per minute.
Titrate to a diastolic of 100.
Alert the O.R.
What do we got?
Acute aortic dissection.
Want me to call up to the O.R.?
Done. I need you
to talk to Mister, uh...
Rubadoux.
Okay. Explain the procedure.
Get her consented
for the clamp-and-run.
You understand?
Okay.
Does my wife need an operation?
She might, sir.
If you'll just come with me,
I'll be happy to
explain it to you.
Okay. I got to go with
the doctor, sweetheart.
I'll be right back.
Just down this way.
Were we as bad as
we thought we'd be?
It was worse. It was great.
Mr. Calus, I'm so sorry...
Mark, have you seen Mr. Calus?
Yeah he was just in there.
This shows what
Dr. Benton feared is true...
Your wife has a
dissecting aneurysm.
The wall of the
aorta is tearing,
and with your wife's age
and her history
of hypertension...
But she's very active.
Still, surgery's a risk.
What are the odds?
About 50/50.
But if your wife's
aorta continues ripping,
then she has no odds at all.
Well, sounds like we
have no choice here.
Okay, I'll sign.
Well, you have a choice
of a new surgical technique,
the clamp- and-run procedure.
This has the benefit
of being completed
in a fraction of the time
the standard surgery takes.
Why is that better?
You always run a risk
of heart attack or
paralysis with this operation.
It's new?
Mm-hmm.
Developed by one of
the top vascular surgeons
in the country,
and he works here.
Newer is better?
I don't know. I don't know.
Well, it's up to you.
But...
You... you'd go
with the new thing?
I would.
You would. Okay. All
right, where do I sign?
See if the church
wants to stop by
to pick these up.
Don't want to hand them
over to his parishioners?
Right? He's dead.
Oh, man, they did
it man, all right?
Those guys are going to pay.
He said it wasn't them.
He was just trying
to keep the truce.
I know those
cabrones killed him.
No. He said they didn't.
Did he ever lie to you?
Did he?
B-Pop...
see, he thought one
man can change things.
He was wrong.
So you shoot them
and they shoot you,
and that's what
the Father died for?
You're right, Diablo.
One man couldn't do it.
Help him now.
Please, will you
tell them to go on?
They won't listen to me.
Your mother does have
to stay for observation.
That's why we're staying too.
But you will spoil the
children's Hanukkah.
No. We brought Hanukkah
here, if that's all right, doctor.
We brought a menorah...
Okay. Okay. I think
I can find a place.
James. I haven't
seen you in a long time.
How are you?
Well, she's
definitely a candidate.
Obviously, she's high risk.
Has she consented?
She's being prepped right now.
Well, unfortunately,
I've had one of these,
so Simon will assist
and you will have
a second chance
at breaking the record, Peter.
I'm ready.
We'll see. Shall we, gentlemen?
Oh, no!
I am so disappointed.
What's wrong?
We're canceled.
The Gold Coast area's snowed in.
No Christmas party?
The roads are pretty bad.
Are they still going to bill us?
Oh, I wish my house was ready.
I'm only a few EL stops away.
So what's not ready?
Uh, no furniture, no
walls, and no roof.
I got the fireplace working.
You did?
Yeah. I figured I'd
surprise you with it.
Sounds perfect.
What should we bring?
Mark, hey! Party at Carol's.
Oh yeah? I'll try
and make it later.
Oh, hang on. I'll
go get little Susie.
Hang on.
What's your address again?
We'd better call the others.
I guess it's BYO everything.
We'll stop at the market.
I'll see you there.
♪ Amen ♪♪
And now what do we play, Sammy?
Dreidel.
And what do those letters mean?
"A miracle happened there."
Yeah. Today we
had our own miracle.
Tirzah came back
to us safe and sound,
and also Dr. Greene
and I said our prayers,
and that's a miracle too.
Yeah.
You know, I thought that...
that God and I had
forsaken each other,
and then I found out
that he was always
with me... in each of you.
Bless you.
And now, who goes first?
Me!
Oh. What did you get?
What did you get?
What's that again?
You see that?
Don't you ever dance like that.
Hey, it's the champion.
Everybody, the man
who broke the 1995 record
for the clamp-and-run procedure
and saved a life.
Carter...
Hey, where can I put this?
In the back room.
What a hero.
Oh, they're outrageous.
I like yours.
You think they'd
notice if we switched?
No! I mean, I think they would.
Hey. Look who's drunk.
Leaving?
Oh, no, no. I just
needed my coat.
Yeah. It's chilly in here.
I thought about
you today, Peter.
Your first Christmas
without your mother.
I hope it's not too hard.
She had her favorite
Bible verse in Luke.
Had me memorize it
before I could even read.
On Christmas,
she liked to hear it.
"Keeping watch over their flocks
by night."
Yeah. That's the one.
So, I um...
I guess it's your first
Christmas alone too, huh?
Well, um...
have a good one.
You too.
Wait for the toast, now.
I know I've got
more cups up here.
Hey, will this do?
What?
Uh...
I love you.
Aah!
Oh!
I do. I said it.
I do.
I... I want you to
have my babies.
Shep...
No, no, I mean,
I think that we would
have really good ones.
I think they would look nice.
You know, I think that
we should spend every
Christmas together.
You know, forever.
I mean, don't think about it.
Just say yes.
Shep, stop.
And I know this is sudden,
I know it's out of the blue,
but I said it and I
don't take it back.
You know? I think this... you...
this is the best.
You don't have to say
anything back, okay?
You just...
just stay... just
the way you are.
Don't move.
Find any more? Whoops.
Say the first part again.
I love you?
Mm-hmm.
I love you.
No, honey, Mommy's right.
If you hang your
stocking at Grandpa's,
Santa will find it.
So I hear your cousins
are having a skating party.
You want to stay for that?
Okay. Well, then, I'll see
you in a couple of days,
and you and I are
going to celebrate
our biggest most
special day of the year.
That's the first annual
Rachel and Dad
post-Christmas, post-Hanukkah
pre-New Year's Day celebration.
Well, that's the good part,
because you and I
are going to make it up.