Sometimes, you just
need to get out of town,
get a new perspective.
But you can't always see that
you need a new perspective
because you, well,
need a new perspective
to be able to see that.
Hey, Cleveland
Clinic wants to know
if you can come
present your paper there.
It's complicated. Why?
'Cause the guy who won
the Harper Avery's too busy?
This loss does not
define you. Well, good.
So then stop trying to get me
to go somewhere to get over it.
And Zurich's been
calling three times a day,
wanting you to
present there, too.
Owen... This past year has been
all about the conduit trial.
Let yourself be flown
first-class to the Alps
and take the time to figure out
what it is you want to do next.
I know what I want to do next.
Get this board
meeting over with.
Okay, that's everybody.
Shut the door.
Well, wait. Where's Avery?
We can get started without him.
I asked Hunt to share
some news with you.
Dr. Russell spoke
with me yesterday.
He's leaving the hospital.
My boss Russell?
He assured me four times
that it had nothing to do with
this Harper Avery situation.
Which means it
has everything to do
with this Harper
Avery situation.
I'm sorry, am I missing
something? What situation?
No one from this hospital
will ever win a Harper Avery.
Catherine Avery
told that to Richard.
Richard thinks we should appeal.
You mean I should appeal
and humiliate myself further?
This is not about you, Yang.
This is about the hospital
being able to get money
for research and to
attract more surgeons.
We're already losing top talent.
Uh, Russell's a loss,
but he's no Cristina Yang.
Yeah, but Cristina Yang
can't be Cristina Yang
if we lose funding.
The NIH funds winners,
people with track records.
People with Harper Averys.
Appealing the decision is
not the worst idea in the world.
What do you think, Yang?
You in?
Let me go.
I hate this, Mer.
I just want one day where I'm
not reminded of the Harper Avery.
And now the hospital's
in danger of losing grants?
How is being nominated for this
award going to cost me grants?
Did everyone forget
that I put a printed conduit
in a kid and it worked?
A bunch of guys in
Zurich didn't forget.
They want you to
come and speak about it.
It's a free trip.
I mean, an hour of talking
for five days in the Swiss Alps?
I'm not running away.
I know that.
Yeah, but that's what
everyone's gonna think.
No, they don't.
Everyone here is angry for
you. Everyone supports you.
Okay, can we just
stop for a minute
about how the hospital
is one big, happy family?
It's a business. I get it.
Catherine Avery made
a business decision.
I've moved on.
Everyone else should, too.
And... There you go.
See right there?
That little blueberry's what
you've been waiting for.
Or not.
This wasn't the idea?
Uh. Well, sure.
Are you looking to terminate?
God, no, no. No, no.
Okay, then.
Well, get dressed and
meet me in my office.
You don't want to
terminate, do you?
No.
I want us to be
happy about this.
I am happy.
The Coopers chose
to do their surgery here
because we've
done so many of them
that we're getting good at it.
This one is a little bit tricky
because it involves the brain.
Are you ready for
this? Third time, yeah.
I'm just saying, this
is a very big surgery.
Derek, you asked me to do it.
If you're having second
thoughts about me, just...
It's too late for
that now, isn't it?
You must be Annie and Liz.
Nothing gets past you, huh?
Be nice. I am.
It's just unlikely he's gonna
confuse us with another patient.
Dr. Kenzie?
Yes. The girls' pediatrician.
But, for the record, we're 25,
and he's no longer our doctor.
He's more like our... Groupie.
I was gonna say family.
Our mom died a few years ago,
and since then,
he's really been...
There for us.
Well, it's nice to
finally meet you.
I'm Dr. Shepherd. And so am I.
His sister.
Good-looking doctors
run in the family.
And these are some
of the roughly 40 people
who will be working on you.
I'm not gonna ask you
to learn their names.
Maybe you should.
We could take a test,
before and after surgery.
See if you cut through
our memory centers.
Will you stop saying
things like that?
I'm just keeping it real.
Oh, you're impossible.
Oh, I am so late.
This has got to stop.
We can't stay up until
3:00 in the morning,
talking about how much
you love your new job.
Well, that's not
all we were doing.
I miss having you here.
You can always call
me if you need help.
That's not why I miss you.
And why would I need help?
I'm not saying you
do. I'm saying if you do.
I am perfectly capable of
making medical decisions
without the help
of my boyfriend.
Dude, you're being weird.
Get out of the car
before you escalate.
These are the most complex
brain scans you will ever see.
As you will see, these
women share brain matter.
Separating them is made even
more complicated by the fact...
There is one
shared sagittal sinus
supplying blood to the brain.
First, we need to
determine which lucky twin
gets to keep that, and
the other twin gets a graft.
Dr. Grey and Dr. Webber...
Will harvest the saphenous vein.
Which will be used as
the new sagittal sinus.
Meanwhile, Dr. Torres will...
Be making a mold of
the cranial bone flap,
so then we'll be able to replace
the missing part of the skull...
Which we will cover
with a flap for now.
But I'll place skin expanders
so we're able to fully
cover the entire defect.
We need to move
quickly and meticulously
to turn one brain into two
with the least amount of deficit.
If this surgery scares you,
if you're not up to the
challenge, let me know.
I need everybody
confident in there.
Get ready.
Oh...
Hey, I'm on Dr. Bailey's
service today, and...
Dr. Bailey's avoiding us.
Uh, we wouldn't let
her put HIV into our son.
It's replacing an
enzyme. It's not...
Oh, we know.
But we stuck to our
guns, and now look at him.
Um, his numbers are fantastic,
so I'll see if Dr. Bailey wants
to graduate him to solid food.
Oh, and tell her
we're not mad at her.
Oh, we're a little mad.
We're just thrilled that
Braden's doing so well.
Okay.
Sabine?
This was Frankie's pillow.
I just bit the head
off of an orderly
who tried to take
the pillowcase.
I should... I should
probably go and apologize.
Don't worry about it.
But he's been so good to me.
He came to Frankie's funeral,
and he's been taking
care of my family.
I'm discharging you.
What? All of you.
Link is on the transplant list.
He can wait for a heart at home.
And Ivy is stable.
She should recover
in her own bedroom,
with her stuff and her friends.
We can go home?
We can go home.
You suffered an
unimaginable loss,
and you have two kids who
are alive and getting better.
Your family needs to heal,
and you can't do that here.
All right. That's
one ticket, round trip.
And your destination is?
Zurich. Zurich it is.
You've reached the voicemail
of Dr. Meredith Grey.
Please leave a message.
Hey, you're probably
asleep or something.
I have no idea
what time it is there.
I barely know what day it is.
I love Zurich!
Well, what I've seen of
it, which is my hotel room.
But, Meredith, it is huge!
This bed is like a
giant's bed or something,
if a giant were rich and
liked weird-shaped pillows.
I have slept for
24 hours, literally.
And I have to give my
talk, which is in a few hours,
and then I'm flying back. So
you can't get my chocolate.
So I don't think I'm gonna
have time to get you your stuff.
Why can't you just
get it at the airport?
Wait, you know what?
Maybe I can just grab
something at the airport.
Good morning. Good morning.
Ultrasound's ready. Okay.
We're gonna see which
saphenous vein to harvest.
Ooh, that's so cold.
Oh!
Wait. How did you...
We share some of
the sensory cortex.
When they were little, I'd give
Annie a shot, and Lizzie would cry.
The whole office would come in
and watch us do our party trick.
It's gonna be so weird
not having an audience
for everything we do.
Good weird, Annie.
I know. It's just I don't know
how to do anything without you.
I mean, I walk
by leaning on you.
I don't drive, because
you're on the driver's side.
And at work, when a
client gets obnoxious,
I let you yell at them.
Well, I'll still yell at people
for you and drive you to work,
but you're gonna have to
learn to walk on your own,
or that's just gonna be weird.
Stop making everything a joke.
Stop thinking
about mom. I'm not.
Dude, we share a brain.
She just always said it was
too dangerous to separate us.
Your situation has
changed, Annie.
I think even your mother would
see how necessary it is now.
Your blood supplies overlap.
Liz's heart is doing
more work than yours,
which is causing
high-output cardiac failure.
Your bodies can't
sustain this much longer.
Meaning if we don't do
anything, we both die.
I'm gonna do the stupid surgery.
Don't get all weepy, Kenzie.
Dr. Bailey.
Braden Morris' parents think
that you're avoiding them.
I'm not avoiding them.
Yeah, well, they
want to make sure
that you know that
they're not mad at you.
Imagine my relief.
They're thrilled, because
Braden's doing great.
He's got 500 T cells.
It's a miracle. Can
he have solid food?
He can have whatever he wants.
Um, monitor his
vitals every two hours
and get a full set
of labs again in four.
Okay.
Wilson, I have
back-to-back patients,
and Babs Martin, my colectomy
patient, needs a central line.
She has no peripheral
access. Got it. I'll do it now.
Good. Oh, no you won't.
3922 needs her JP drain removed,
and the delightful but
demon-like little girl next door
also needs a new feeding tube.
And they're kids,
little, tiny humans,
and we don't make
little, tiny humans
wait for things like feeding
tubes and drain removals, do we?
No, we don't.
Thanks. You're awesome.
Okay, I will take
care of twin A.
Amy will take care of twin B
Dr. Shepherd. What?
No, I mean my
name is Dr. Shepherd.
You said Amy, and that makes
me sound like some sorority girl
tagging along on
your brain surgery,
when, in fact, I am
your co-surgeon.
Okay, I apologize.
Everybody clear on
their role? Torres?
Yeah, I'm good. Avery?
Yeah, me too.
Amy... Dr. Shepherd?
I'm ready.
All right. See
everybody in surgery.
Get some food, people. This is the
last time you'll be eating for a while.
Amy, let's go over
this one more time.
All right.
Mer, would you grab
me an energy bar?
Yeah.
You know, he
thinks you're great,
so I don't know why
he treats you like...
I'm incompetent.
Because he's twin A.
Always has been, always will be.
Which makes me
twin B. Super fun.
Hey, Raynbow
Williams in bed three
needs an abdominal exam
to rule out appendicitis.
Ooh. "Raynbow."
I'm gonna add that to
my list of baby names.
Really? Yep.
Right after Bubba,
Toolio and Agamemnon.
Agamemnon?
That's pretty.
No, it's not. It's child abuse.
But Callie keeps shooting down
all the cute names
that I suggest,
so my new strategy is
to bury the cute names
in a sea of terrible ones.
So... Zamboni,
Hashtag and Digger.
Wow. You guys aren't even
pregnant yet, and you're so...
Crazy? No, no.
I was gonna say excited.
Imagine how insufferable I'll be
when there's an actual
baby to talk about.
Once we came up with
a closed seeding system,
we were able to speed the time
between bone-marrow
aspiration and graft implantation.
Next.
I have a question.
Yes.
Does the difference
in tensile strength
between the patient's tissue
and the bioprinted conduit
increase the risk of turbulent
flow at the anastomosis?
No. Our conduits
exhibit laminar flow.
And testing revealed a tensile
strength of 0.6 megapascals.
Without long-term follow-up,
how can you claim
that your conduit
supercedes the standard
prosthetic conduit?
We expect our conduits
to grow and remodel
throughout the
patient's lifetime.
Thus obviating the
need for serial operations.
Exactly.
More time-consuming up
front, but worth it in the long run.
Don't you run the risk
of your cells
undergoing apoptosis
when seeded on the hydrogel?
That was a concern initially,
but we discovered
90% of the seeded cells
remained viable after one week.
I was very surprised.
Fascinating.
Thank you, Dr. Yang.
We would love to see the
data from your initial patients.
Oh, well, your
office has my e-mail.
I'd be happy to share
it with you. Beautiful.
You were wise to
bring her, Burke.
She'll teach us
all a thing or two.
She certainly will.
You did this?
I thought it was
someone named Weiss.
Weiss is one of my staff.
I didn't think you'd respond
to an invitation from me,
given the circumstances
of our last interaction.
Me in a white dress
and you fleeing the state.
Well, a follow-up
to that is delicate.
Why am I here?
Because I wanted to talk to you
about your unpublished
details of your protocol.
And you brought me
6,000 miles to discuss it?
Well, this is my hospital.
I get to fly people 6,000
miles to ask them questions.
Let me return the favor.
Show you what I've
been working on.
I have a surgery this afternoon.
I would really love
for you to scrub in.
Unless you have plans.
I have to make a phone call.
Oh, go ahead.
I'll catch up with you later.
And, uh...
Tell Meredith I say hello.
Hey, is that her?
Voicemail. We keep
missing each other.
Is she having a good time?
Yeah, she's just saying
her speech went well and...
Burke is here.
What?
Burke. Here. Shut up.
Yeah, he brought me here.
Nothing, nothing.
She's saying that she
got a standing ovation.
I knew this trip was
gonna be great for her.
Mer, call me back.
I can't do this. You guys,
the last time I did this, I went...
Through the table. We know.
That's why we're practicing.
What are we doing?
Dr. Shepherd picked Leah to do
the burr holes on the Cooper twins.
Doesn't he know
that last time she...
Shut up.
How's scut?
Fine. I'm actually killing it.
You're killing her!
I can't do this.
Stop it. That
was your first one.
You know how hard to go now.
Try it again.
I just think it's kind of
shocking that the first option
tossed onto the table
for a pregnant woman
with mixed feelings
is termination.
I think she's just
doing her job.
Can you just be on my side?
I am on your side.
I just don't think we
need to vilify the OB
for one comment. I wasn't.
I was...
Maybe I was. I don't know.
I don't want to
fight. Me neither.
What about
Phoebe if it's a girl?
Phoebe freebie? Slutty.
Uh, but cute. Terrific.
It's one of the better names.
Dr. Webber.
Did I hear that you called
a meeting of the board?
Yeah, I did.
Well, next time, could you
please make sure I'm available?
Well, we needed to discuss
some issues with the foundation.
Your input wasn't needed.
Excuse me, sir.
If you have something to say
about the foundation, you say it to me.
I would appreciate that.
Okay, well, here's
what I'll say, then.
I built this place with
certain ideals in mind,
and I'm not gonna
let them be trifled with.
We got in bed with
your foundation too fast.
It's clear that there are
certain fundamental differences
of philosophy.
It's not gonna work.
It's a doomed marriage.
Okay, Babs, let me know if
you feel any pain or discomfort.
Wilson, everything okay in here?
Yeah. All good. Just
passing the catheter.
Well, you're running
Braden's labs?
Yeah, just like you said.
Good. Keep me updated on them.
All right. Catheter's in.
Babs, we're almost done here.
I just need to remove the wire.
My lucky charm.
Didn't feel a pinch.
I've had lots of practice.
Oh. Ow!
That hurts.
It's not coming out. The
wire snagged on something.
What's happening?
Push 0.5 of hydromorphone.
Babs, just try and relax, okay?
The contours are
virtually seamless.
I'm impressed, Torres.
It took hours of meticulous work
to perfect these pieces, Derek.
Amelia better not screw it up.
Why would you think that?
You treat her like
she's the village idiot.
I do not. Yes, you do.
And I need you to tell me
that she's not the village idiot.
She is not the village idiot.
I wouldn't let her
near the Coopers
if she weren't
exceedingly capable.
Hey, is that the...
A fully functioning
robotic leg? Yes, it is.
Well, I thought my absence
totally stalled the progress.
It did.
So I kind of took it in
a different direction.
I'm redirecting the
peripheral nerve signals
to send commands
directly to the prosthetic leg,
eliminating your
sensors entirely.
I've cut out the middleman.
Oh, so I'm the middleman?
No, I still need you
to connect the nerves.
So I'm just the
mechanic? Kind of.
But I would never
let you near it
if you weren't
exceedingly capable.
You have one new message.
Before you do something
rash, remember a few things.
Remember that he
cut away pieces of you.
Remember that his
mama took your eyebrows.
And remember that you've worked
the past seven
years to get over...
It's just coffee.
You still drink it, right?
You know, I'm gonna go. I
don't want to miss my flight.
Oh, you're fine. I had Weiss put
another ticket on hold for you.
You know, all this
secret making of plans
and shuttling me around
on your own schedule...
It's manipulative.
I'm sorry you see it that way.
You've been following my work?
You gonna tell me you
haven't been following mine?
This surgery you're about
to see is new, though.
I didn't want to publish it
until I was sure I had
what I thought I had.
Do you?
Come on. I'll show you.
They're prepped and ready to go.
Which one is twin A?
Um...
You need to identify the
twin with the best prognosis.
If things start to go
poorly in surgery,
the team throws
all of their resources
toward the stronger
twin. Twin A.
It's better to have
one alive than neither.
I'm a doctor. I
know how it works.
I delivered these
girls, Dr. Grey.
I've been to their
college graduation,
met their boyfriends.
I helped bury their mother.
And I'd like for you to
tell me which is twin A,
so I can ask God to take a
little extra care of her sister.
Lizzie is twin A.
If things go bad in there,
all of our resources
will go to her.
God help Annie.
Dr. Grey, we're ready.
See you on the other side.
And we're gonna want
doughnuts, Kenzie.
Don't worry, Annie.
I'll get you doughnuts.
We're almost finished
procuring this vein.
Okay, Murphy, how are we doing?
She's doing great.
She's done seven burr holes
and hasn't punctured the dura.
Checking the last burr hole.
Well done, Murphy. Perfect. Yay!
Delicate vascular work here.
I'm sorry.
Okay, next, I'll need
a number 3 Penfield
to strip away the sagittal
sinus from the bone flap.
Alex, pick up, pick up, pick up!
See? I was right. You need me.
So, what did you screw up now?
Alex, I... Look, I'm kidding.
And I'm in the
middle of a thing here.
Can I call you later?
Yeah. Okay.
I'll see you later. Hi.
Babs, the wire's caught
on something in your chest,
so we're going to take an X-ray to
help us see what's going on inside.
Wilson. Oh, hey, I know...
You know that you still haven't
done the drain removal on 3922?
I'm glad that you know that,
because for some reason it's not...
I'm coming right now.
Babs, just hang on.
Everything's going to be okay.
This vessel looks
like it belongs to Liz.
Agreed.
I'll continue my dissection
millimeter by millimeter,
until we're sure
they're stable enough
to start ligating the
remaining vessels.
The vitals, please?
Twin A, 110/70. Twin B, 140/90.
Okay, now I'm going to start
clipping the bridging veins.
Oh, no. Does that look like...
- Yes.
Damn it. It's getting dusky.
Probably propagating.
Tissues are edematous,
moving medially...
Towards the sinus.
If it gets there...
Both flows are
compromised. I know.
What's happening?
Liz developed a clot, and
now they're trying to keep it
from spreading to Annie's brain.
They have to move quickly if
they're going to save Annie's life.
We have to separate them
now, and fast. Dissector!
Try to stay midline.
We'll control the bleeding
once they're separated.
Okay. Medium clips,
keep them coming.
Come on, Annie.
I'm confused. I thought
that Liz is twin A.
I thought that if things
went wrong, we were supposed
to throw all our resources to her.
Not anymore.
A transcatheter aortic
valve replacement.
What's so special about this?
You'll see.
You lost the Harper Avery.
Yes, I did.
You shouldn't feel bad about it.
Well, it's easy for you
to say. You won one.
That's why I can say it.
There was a high after I won,
and I rode it for a long time.
Then there was
a truly awful crash.
The fear that my best
work was behind me.
And the pressure I put
on myself was enormous.
I had to get away,
so I came here.
Started working
quietly at first, and...
Then I met a gentleman
that made a billion in the
European bond market.
Wanted to put his
name on something.
He bankrolled this whole place.
I brought in people
from all over the world,
just to study hearts.
You don't get
government funding?
Don't need it.
The interesting thing
about this patient is that
he has an irregularly
shaped valve.
That does not
make this interesting.
Does this?
That's his heart
in the hologram.
Composed of pre-op scans.
Complete intraoperative visualization.
You can see it from
all angles in real time.
And even slice it
to see the anatomy.
Assess the ramifications without
bearing any of the
risks of blind entry.
That's what I've been
waiting to publish.
I just wanted to
get the kinks out.
Was it worth you
sticking around for?
Yes, it was.
Wait till you see
the rest of the place.
And, now!
Irrigate the field.
Drape her loosely.
Derek, you go with the
viable twin. I'll stay here.
No, you go. I'll be right there.
I just want to try
and retrieve the clot.
It's a last-ditch effort, but it
may work. Can you save her?
Well, if I remove all
the clot fast enough,
but she'll still have deficits.
Okay, my count, on
three. One, two, three.
Don't worry about
Annie. I've got her.
I know you do.
Okay, let's get Annie
next door, ASAP.
I need more light,
heparinized shunt,
and every nonessential
person out of here.
All these printers are yours?
Yes.
There's... Forty-nine.
We had 50. One went
buggy. We sent it back.
So, you've completed
a phase one trial with
your conduits. What's next?
I don't know. I can't...
I don't know now.
Everything's...
Because of the award?
I don't care about the award.
Of course you do.
At least, you should.
It's an assessment
from people who know
that you are what
you think you are.
Even you crave
that, regardless...
I know how valid my work is.
So do I.
I know what's
next, and it's big.
But?
But...
You're afraid you
can't raise the support
after you lost the award.
What is it?
I want to print a functional
human heart, a beating heart.
We'll do it here. It's
not impossible here.
You can start tomorrow.
All you have to do is say yes.
So, where is Yang on the appeal?
I don't know. I haven't
spoken to her since she left.
Well, where is she?
She's visiting a
hospital in Switzerland.
She's what?
Is she looking for another job?
You see what you did?
You're going to lose the
good ones, one by one.
She just went to go give a talk.
I hope you're happy. Thanks
to you and your mother,
pretty soon the only doctors
working here will be you and Knox.
You have to stop!
It was your relationship with
the Harper Avery Foundation
that brought them
here in the first place.
You're embarrassed and
you're ashamed, and I'm sorry,
but I will not let you take it
out on Dr. Avery anymore.
He deserves your respect.
He's not his mother. So stop it.
I never received Babs' films.
I sent them up to Dr. Hunt.
What? Why?
It was a critical result, and
he's the attending on the chart.
Where is she?
With Dr. Hunt. Took
her upstairs to surgery.
Oh, Steph, I need you! Can you
go check on Braden Morris' labs?
Bailey is checking for
leukocytosis to rule out leukemia.
Thank you, thank you, thank you.
Leukemia? Why is Bailey...
How's Annie's saphenous
vein graft coming?
Patent, thankfully.
Good. Need an
extra set of hands?
No, I'm just about
to close the dura.
Good.
Wow. Shepherd
fix Lizzie already?
He didn't fix her.
Dr. Hunt, I should
have called you but...
If not me, then someone. This
hospital is full of doctors, Wilson.
Because you tried to
remove the wire by yourself,
forcefully, you perforated
the posterior wall of the
subclavian vein, causing her to bleed.
Oh, God. And now
I have to perform
an emergency venous repair and
her colectomy has to be postponed.
I was trying to
handle everything.
And you made it worse.
Sit down. I'll
order some dinner.
Are you not hungry?
You want me to come work here?
That's what I said, yes.
I no longer have the ability
to interpret your noises.
Is this some ploy to
get me back in your life?
Because I'm not interested.
My wife, Edra. That is Simone,
she's five. Vivianna just turned four.
I'm happy, Cristina.
Edra is the love of my life.
She's my world. My
family is my world.
That's nice.
I don't want you, Cristina.
Okay, I don't mean
it like it sounds.
No, I mean Edra
wants to be a mom.
She trained as a surgeon
and she gave it up.
Now she stays home
and takes care of the kids.
She's supportive of
me, of my dreams.
Well, that's good for
you. I'm happy for you.
When you do what you and
I do, as fiercely as we do it,
you need somebody
that's willing to stay home
and keep the home fires burning.
That's the only way you and I
are ever going to have someone.
You don't know me anymore.
I see your life has moved on.
I want you to know mine has too.
You're right. I don't know you.
But I know that you've
become a magnificent surgeon.
You've become everything
I dreamed you'd be.
You should be in a place like
this. You should consider it.
He has a family, and
a holographic heart,
and he wants to
bankroll my research
for printing a functional heart.
I mean, he's got
like 49 printers
and a bottomless
pit of money, and...
How the hell are you not
answering your phone right now?
Mer, everything I have
ever wanted is here.
Except he's here.
So what the hell
am I supposed to do?
I mean, what would
you tell me to do?
Yeah.
Annie decided to withdraw care?
Mmm-hmm.
Any change on Lizzie?
No. They'll be
withdrawing care soon.
You do remember
how hard it was to
find the money to
keep this place going.
The foundation was our
Hail Mary and you saved us.
We have to find a way
to make it work with them.
I was there, the night your
mother won her first Harper Avery.
I wasn't with her. I
was sitting in the back.
Because my father was with her?
That award was
our gold standard.
It was the measure
of our success.
It was everything we worked for.
And I had to be there to
see the look on her face.
She was radiant.
Catherine made it meaningless
with this. She cheapened it.
She cheapened our goals.
She cheapened her memory.
I can't stand that.
Uh, Richard. You got a minute?
Dr. Bailey, I have Braden's
most recent results.
Oh, thank you, Dr. Edwards.
You're testing his white
blood cell differential?
I'm running many tests.
His T cell count is up.
A boy with no immune system
grew over 500 T cells overnight?
I think you administered
the deactivated virus against
his parents' wishes.
Okay! It worked!
And it's working! It's
amazing. You're amazing.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
So, you agree?
This resident's not
cut out to be a surgeon.
Yep. Either you're a
surgeon or you're not.
I can't get fired. My
parents will disown me.
I'll end up back in school.
I'll end up back in jail.
Will you stop? If any
one of us is fired, it's me.
I went crazy, very publicly.
I disrupted an entire
OR. I'm a surgical liability.
And Shepherd hates me now.
Hunt hates me. You
should have seen
his face today
when I screwed up.
My ex owns the
hospital. It's me.
I heard that residencies
sometimes clean house,
like fire an entire class of
residents and start fresh.
Hey. What?
Nothing. I just had
a really good day.
Next round's on him.
Ah.
You spoke to Meredith.
No. And no, I
can't take the job.
Thank you for the offer, but no.
Ah. Meredith carries a grudge.
This has nothing
to do with Meredith
or a grudge. It's
far from that simple.
Really? Please don't.
You got me here. We had
our fun. Take no for an answer.
Why?
"Why"?
Honestly, it doesn't
make any sense.
You think I want to
work for you again?
I never wanted to work
for you. I wanted to be you.
The best thing that
ever happened to me
was you walking
away from our wedding.
It made me stand
on my own two feet.
I am better for it.
You are better for it.
Will you just hold...
So why bring me here?
Why offer me a job
you know I can't resist?
You're going to dangle a carrot
and I'm supposed to chase it
until you snatch it
away? I don't want the job!
Are you done? No!
Now I am.
I don't want you to work for me.
Us working together would
destroy my marriage, my life.
The way I loved you was
consuming. And eventually...
You hold the carrot.
I'll be chasing you.
I have a family
now, a life that...
A life I want.
I don't want you to work for me.
You just offered me a job.
I don't want you to work for me!
I want you to take over for me.
I'm leaving.
Edra's parents are in Milan
and she wants to
be closer to them.
Wait. She's made so
many sacrifices for me.
And now I think it's time for
me to do the same for her.
Wait.
I've been wanting
to leave for a while.
But I just haven't been able
to find anyone that I was willing
to give the institute
to, until now. Wait.
You're offering
me your hospital,
like you're Willy Wonka and you're
handing me a chocolate factory?
Cheer up, Charlie.
You're not serious?
You are serious.
This place is yours,
Cristina, if you want it.
Do you?
Open your eyes.
Hi. Hey.
How did you know I was...
I know who you hang out with.
You okay?
Yeah.
Yeah. I just needed
to sit down for a bit.
Should probably get used
to these seats, though.
I can't change who I am.
But that doesn't mean
I want to sit at home
every Sunday when
my family's off at church.
You would go to church with me?
You're my wife.
Of course I will.
As long as we can
get waffles after.
We can have waffles after.
What do you see?
More possibilities?
Agamemnon.
I kind of love it. Yeah.
Callie Torres has a
really interesting project.
She needs an exceptional
neurosurgeon. I recommended you.
Derek, I don't live here.
Maybe you should.
I like having you here.
You're my favorite sister.
You say that to all of us.
But I will choose to believe you
because you are
my favorite brother.
Does your new view
give you more hope?
That's the goal. Although it
doesn't always work out that way.
Chocolate. I ate some.
You're leaving.
Sometimes, a shift
in perspective just
makes you see what you've lost.