I'm testing to see if I can
give you my kidney.
You went to Sean
against my wishes.
It felt like Sean
needed to know
how bad you're
actually doing.
Hannah's smart, kind,
and super cute.
You're still in recovery.
So is Hannah,
for that matter.
I have a bad feeling
about the direction that
Jack is taking us.
Since we stopped taking
walk-ins without insurance,
numbers are down.
Heard rumors of you
acting like a cowboy.
That's not what
happened today.
Who you trying to convince
with that? Me or you?
I know the tech.
I promise you.
It won't let you down.
2.0, guide me
to the next lesion.
Calculating. Calculating.
Richard, can you hear me?
Sometimes,
patients don't survive.
But it's the burden we bear.
He's selling seats
on a rocket ship,
making up rules only
his rich pals can play by.
It's not right.
Yeah. So how was
your date last night?
God, I wouldn't
consider a guy
talking at me
for 90 minutes
straight a date.
Oh.
I swear, Hannah,
he didn't ask me
a single question
about myself.
Oh, that sounds awful.
You met him on the apps?
Yeah, but I think after
last night, I'm just
gonna delete them all.
No, don't lose hope.
Dean!
Over here.
Cuevas. You bellowed?
Here it is.
What is this?
It's a bomb.
It's a renal-friendly
snack bar.
Yeah? Does it taste
like cardboard?
I'm happy to report
that it does not.
I even tried it myself.
Well, you enjoy
those disgusting
green smoothies,
so your taste is suspect.
I'll see both
of you in the ED.
So what about
your dating life?
Hmm.
It's been a while since
you've dated, right?
Not since Will?
I mean, who's counting?
But yeah.
Actually...
Wow, I didn't realize
it's been that long.
Well, maybe it's time
to put yourself out there.
Hi.
Morning.
You look nice.
Thanks.
Big media blitz
today with Jack.
This for the IPO launch
tomorrow?
2.0's going public, right?
Correct.
And Jack will go
from billionaire
to gazillionaire.
More importantly,
it'll expand 2.0's
global reach.
Look, I know
you're not Jack's
biggest fan, but...
I don't like the direction
he's taking Med in.
It's becoming a place
I don't recognize anymore.
Well, maybe that's not
such a bad thing.
Jack's tasked me with
assessing the state
of the hospital,
and I found numerous
examples of inefficiency.
How are we
inefficient, exactly?
Treating patients
or turning a profit?
I know you're deeply
invested in Med
and that makes it difficult
for you to see the flaws.
I guess I could say
the same for you, Grace.
Jack was your mentor.
You got a lot of
respect for the guy.
I know that.
But he's only
out for himself.
That's not true.
I guess we're gonna
have to agree to
disagree on this one.
Self-portrait?
No.
My friend Owen
drew it for me.
Owen?
Natalie Manning's son?
Hang out at the
nurses' station,
hear some things.
I bet.
Look, Natalie and I
keep in touch, but...
You really don't owe me
any explanation.
It's not like we're...
Anything.
Are we?
Grace...
I'm not sure this is
gonna work.
Good luck today.
Mrs. Abrams.
I am Dr. Asher.
Please, call me Michelle.
I am so sorry my husband
roped you into this.
Oh, I don't mind at all.
I'm happy to help.
It's just my doctor
couldn't get me in
until next week and...
Mm-hmm.
Honey.
Please tell me you did not
just leave surgery.
No. Our part was over,
so I had an underling close.
Dr. Asher, thanks again
for doing this.
Yeah.
As if you gave
her a choice.
Next time a family member
needs a craniotomy,
I'm your man.
Well, I will hold
you to that.
So, Michelle,
what's going on?
I'm 99% sure
I have a UTI.
I had one about a year ago,
and I'm experiencing
the same symptoms
like abdominal pain,
um, pelvic pressure,
and frequent urination.
Okay, well, let's
get you in a gown.
Excuse me.
We will start by
taking a urine sample.
Okay? Okay.
Sounds good.
Morning, Will.
I thought you
were off today.
Jack roped me into
speaking at the IPO
press conference.
Tried to get out of it,
but he was conveniently
unavailable to
take my calls.
Makes sense
he wants you there.
You are the face
of the machine.
Ha.
Yeah, well, I'm not
exactly feeling
camera ready.
Haven't been sleeping much.
Yeah? What's going on?
I can't stop thinking
about Richard Evans.
I feel you.
Been weighing on me too.
Keep trying to
piece together
what went wrong.
What do you mean?
CT showed he
suffered a stroke.
His echo revealed
a ventricular
septal defect.
That's true.
So he must have thrown a clot,
traveled to his brain
through the septal defect.
Deep vein clots are one of
the most common surgical
complications, aren't they?
Yes, they are.
But in those cases,
where would you expect
the clot to originate?
His pelvis or his legs.
Richard's CT showed
the clot was in his liver.
Wait, how did he get
a clot in his liver?
That's what I can't
seem to figure out.
What, are you gonna
do an autopsy?
No, his wife
didn't want it.
But 2.0 records
a massive amount of
intraoperative data,
so I'm gonna have...
I'm gonna have Grace
pull his files on
Richard's surgery,
see if I can find
some answers there.
Keep me posted.
Yeah. Will do.
What's up?
One second.
Grace, talk to me.
The data from
Richard Evans' surgery,
it's missing.
What do you mean missing?
It's not on the server.
I don't know
where it could be.
There must be a backup.
I tried the backup server.
It's not there either.
Has this happened before?
Data just disappearing?
No. Never.
Wow! Somebody looked
pretty happy for having just
gotten off the night shift.
I get the appraisal back
on my new home today.
If it appraises for
what I expect,
I remove my
final contingency.
Wow. Big day.
Yeah.
So you've given notice
to your landlord
and everything?
Oh, yes. I think he's
more excited than me.
Day after I move out,
he has a contractor
coming in
to start renovations.
Anything I can do to
help with the move?
Uh, I will be packing
all day and night.
Company would be nice
when you get off work.
I can do you one better.
Me and wine, plus pizza.
You know the way to my heart.
I do, don't I?
Yeah.
See you later.
All right.
Let's get you guys home.
Let's go, guys.
Okay, and you'll wanna
change the bandage
every day
and apply this ointment
at night.
Just generally overall
stay off the foot
as much as possible.
I'll try.
Now Penny, if the wound
turns red or develops pus
or you start running
a fever, I want you
to come back.
Just say you're having
chest pain so
you don't have
any trouble checking in
without insurance.
Right. Got it.
I really appreciate
your help.
Because of my
immigration status,
I'm careful about
where I give my name,
and I always come to Med
'cause I know it's safe.
It still is.
We just got some
new policies
to contend with.
Well, thanks again.
Come on, boys. Let's go.
Bye, guys.
How long do you think
you'll be able to get
away with this?
With what?
Another patient
complaining of chest pain?
It's the only way to
get around Dayton's
new policy.
I'm not mocking you.
I'm applauding
your creativity.
I'm just as fed up
as you are.
But unfortunately,
it's not a long-term
solution.
I know.
Yeah.
Dr. Asher.
So, Michelle,
I got your lab
results back,
and it turns out
you do not have a UTI.
You're kidding.
I thought for sure.
Well, sometimes
symptoms of a UTI
can mimic those
of pregnancy.
What? Are you saying...
Yes.
Michelle, you are pregnant.
No. No. That...
That's a mistake.
I had a vasectomy
seven years ago.
Oh, well, we can absolutely
run a beta to confirm.
I was also about to do
an ultrasound and
a pelvic exam as well.
Well, there's just...
There's no way
this is possible.
Well, recanalization can
happen after a vasectomy.
Right. Not seven years later.
If it's gonna happen,
it usually happens
in year one.
Sam.
Stop debating whether
it's possible
and let's just get the
ultrasound so we can confirm
I'm actually pregnant.
Right, right, right. Yeah.
Yeah. Okay.
Do you mind lifting
your gown a little?
Mm-hmm.
Okay.
So this will feel
a little cold.
You ready?
Mm-hmm.
Oh, wow!
Do you wanna hear
the heartbeat?
Yeah.
I'm gonna sue my urologist.
Told me he never had
a vasectomy fail.
Seriously?
That's all you have to say?
I am going to give you
guys a minute.
Michelle, I will be
back for your pelvic
exam in a bit.
Yeah.
Dr. Charles?
Dr. Nellie Cuevas.
What's up?
David Sullivan's back.
Really?
I was just talking
to his mom,
like, last week.
She said that he's doing
really well on his ECT
maintenance regimen.
They might have even just
lowered his risperidone.
I mean, how does he seem?
I haven't spoken to him.
I thought it would be better
if you did the intake.
Why is that?
Well, the last few times
he's been in the ED,
my presence has only
agitated him
and tightened his paranoia.
Just for the record,
that's probably
got a lot less
to do with you than
the paranoid delusions
he was experiencing.
I just don't wanna
risk upsetting him
right off the bat,
but he looks calm
right now.
So if you wouldn't mind?
Give me two minutes.
Okay, thanks.
Oh, good.
Dr. Charles, I was hoping
you'd be here today.
So your mom said
you decided
on U of Illinois?
Dude, that's a great school.
Congratulations.
Thanks.
But I'm not sure
it's gonna work out,
that I'll be able to go.
How come?
Dr. Charles, you can't
tell my parents this.
Okay. They don't know
you're here?
I just didn't want
them to worry.
All right.
But I've been hearing
voices again.
Okay. Well, what are
they saying?
That a diploma
doesn't matter
if I'm still crazy.
You know, that I should
stay in my room
all the time.
That if I go places,
I'll just embarrass myself.
Places like what?
What kind of places?
College.
Graduation.
Prom this weekend.
You're going to prom?
That's fantastic.
Yeah.
With this girl Amber
and her friends.
But I have to back out.
Because of the voices?
Yeah. They're saying
it's gonna be the
worst night of my life,
that I'm gonna make
a fool of myself,
and Amber won't even
wanna talk to me
when it's all over.
Huh.
Buddy, can I ask you,
what exactly do these
voices sound like?
Can you get specific for me?
What do you mean?
Well, in the past,
you've often described
the voices as loud,
aggressive, abrasive,
like, scary, even.
Do these voices...
Do they sound like that?
No.
No, they don't really
have a sound,
but they're there.
I know they're there.
Huh.
Listen, pull up
my schedule.
Cancel the 4:00 today.
Sharon, you're going
the wrong direction.
Good morning, Jack.
Yeah, the IPO conference
is in the amphitheater.
I'm aware.
Did you forget
you're making
a statement?
I did not, but after
giving it more thought,
I decided that it would
be inappropriate
for me to speak
on behalf of
the hospital.
And why is that?
Well, because 2.0
hitting the stock exchange
benefits Dayton Corporation
and not Chicago Med.
Well, 2.0 put Med
on the map. Made it a
destination hospital.
Well, I'm of a different
opinion, and the
bottom line, Jack,
hawking your wares
is not in
my job description.
Hey, Grace.
Any luck getting
the data back?
Not yet. I'm working on it.
Got a bit of
a surprise plan,
so just roll with it
and we'll touch base
later on. Okay?
Jack...
Hi, everyone.
So, um,
I'm gonna keep this
short and sweet
because I'm gonna be
asking all of you,
well, to come back
in about 24 hours.
Tomorrow, we are gonna be
inviting the general public
to invest in the future
of OR 2.0,
and I want them to
see exactly what
they're investing in.
So I am very excited
to announce that tomorrow
we will be live streaming
a surgery on the 2.0
for the entire
world to watch.
Who's the patient?
That's a great question.
I'm gonna put my life
in its hands
and in the very
capable hands
of Dr. Marcel here,
who I'm sure you're
all quite familiar with
at this point.
So let's open this up
to some questions.
What the hell was that?
Oh, listen, I'm...
I'm sorry I didn't
give you more
of a heads up.
Had this idea last night.
I just had to go with it.
What surgery
am I performing
on you anyway?
It's nothing. It's a redo
ventral hernia repair,
something I've been
meaning to do for a while.
Total softball surgery.
This way, you can focus
on highlighting
the bells and
whistles of 2.0.
Yeah, well,
speaking of 2.0,
we got a problem.
What do you mean?
It deleted a surgery's
worth of data.
What surgery?
A patient by the name
of Richard Evans.
Right.
Yeah, the gentleman with
the pancreatic cancer
spread to his liver, right?
Yeah. How'd you know that?
It's 2.0's
first recorded fatality.
Of course I know.
Dr. Song briefed me.
Yeah, well,
the data's gone.
I'm trying to
figure out what caused
Mr. Evans' death.
Look, his liver was
riddled with lesions.
He was a ticking time bomb.
Never gonna
survive long term.
Yes, but I was trying
to buy him more time...
Just leave it alone,
Crockett.
What does that mean?
Nothing.
Nothing, look, it's...
Let it go, all right?
It's a fool's errand.
Where's the data, Jack?
Jack?
I'm trying to
protect you here, man.
What do you mean protect me?
You made a mistake.
Hey, there.
Did Sam have to go
back upstairs?
No. He's taking a walk.
Figured we could both
use a breather.
Yeah.
Mm-hmm.
All right, well, let's take
a quick look inside, okay?
You're gonna feel
some pressure, but...
It won't last long,
I promise. Okay?
All right. You ready?
Mm-hmm.
No unusual discharge.
Everything's looking good.
Almost to the cervix.
Dr. Asher?
Is everything okay?
So, Michelle,
what I'm seeing is
what we call cervical
insufficiency.
In other words,
your cervix is starting
to open prematurely.
Am I gonna lose the baby?
In order to prevent
a miscarriage,
I'd recommend a cerclage.
It's a minimally
invasive procedure
where we stitch
the cervix closed.
It takes about an hour.
How soon can I have
the operation?
I would like to do it today,
if that's okay with you.
When the cervix
starts opening,
the condition can
progress pretty quickly.
Yes.
Yes. Absolutely.
Okay.
Can you check
if an OR's open?
Of course.
Thank you. All right.
Oh. Hey. Mark,
you're glowing.
Listen, I really should
talk to Sean first.
That's the protocol.
But I called
and got his voicemail.
Yeah. Well,
he's working today.
What's going on?
Just got all of his
test results back.
Uh-huh.
He's a donor match
for you, Dean.
Really?
Wow.
Well, that's, uh...
Fantastic?
Hey.
I already checked
with transplant.
They think we can
get you and Sean
in for surgery next month,
maybe even earlier.
So let the powers that be
know that you're gonna
need some time off.
Will do.
Congrats.
Happy for you, my friend.
Hey, thanks. Thanks.
Hey. Maggie,
you're early.
I thought we were
doing lunch at 1:00.
Yeah, about that.
Um, can we rain check?
Of course.
Is everything okay
in the ED?
Yeah, um,
that recruiter I've been
working with, she called.
I have a job interview.
Oh.
Wow. That was fast.
And this is
a job you'd want?
Well, I thought
I'd at least hear
what they have to say.
It's a new hospital
opening up in Hyde Park.
Yeah. Uh, Midwest Advocate.
Yeah, apparently
they're looking
for a charge nurse.
I see.
I wouldn't normally
schedule an interview
during work hours...
Maggie,
you don't have to...
And I don't want you
to think that...
I don't. I don't.
Yeah.
Good luck.
Yeah. Thanks.
Learn what you need
to learn about this
and please move on.
I haven't lost
any confidence in
your surgical skill.
I still want you
as my surgeon
tomorrow...
And as a key partner
in 2.0's future.
Don't blow up your
career over this.
We can still do a lot
of great work together.
What are you doing?
Yeah, that's my wife
on the table.
Yeah, I understand,
but you're a neurosurgeon.
I'm sorry to be blunt,
but you have
nothing to offer
when it comes to
performing a cerclage.
You expect me to sit
in the waiting room?
Fine.
You can stay,
but no backseat driving.
I mean it.
Understood.
Unlike your colleagues
in the ED, I can
follow directions.
Okay.
So I'm not
hearing voices?
I think what you're
actually hearing is
your own voice...
You know,
your own thoughts.
We all have this ongoing
inner dialogue, right?
It helps us navigate
and process the world
around us.
How do I make it stop?
Well, I think rather than
trying to silence it,
you can learn a whole lot
by actually engaging
with it, you know?
And that's something that
I wanted to explore today,
and, uh,
I actually asked
Dr. Cuevas if she would
help us with that.
You remember Dr. Cuevas.
Hi, David.
Hey.
Anyway,
I thought it might help
to kind of actually
talk through the scenarios
that are making you anxious.
You know, for instance,
senior prom, right?
When you think about prom,
what is the first
big snag you hit?
Probably the drive there.
Just me and Amber alone.
Dr. Cuevas, you had
a really good idea
about how we might
go about that.
Uh, yeah. Yeah.
We can practice
the car ride here.
You know, act out
what you might say
and what Amber
might say back.
Um, actually, David,
how about you sit here?
This can be
the driver's seat,
and I will be Amber.
What is it specifically
about the car ride,
about that conversation
that makes you nervous
about what might come up?
Not knowing
what to talk about.
What if she asked me
why I missed so much
school this year?
Do I have to
tell her that...
That I'm...
Do you have to tell her
that you were diagnosed
with schizophrenia?
Is that something
you think you might feel
like revealing to her?
Not really.
No. No, I don't.
Well, you know what?
That's just fine
because it's actually
your private information
and it's your choice.
I would just hope
that if it did come up
that it would
not be something
that you were,
you know, embarrassed
or ashamed about.
Sometimes I am.
Having a disease,
any disease,
lupus, cancer,
schizophrenia,
that's not something
that makes you
less than anyone else.
And, David, I'm also really
confident that over time
you are not gonna feel
like this is something
that defines you.
You get to decide
what defines you. Right?
I mean, just like you get to
decide who you wanna share
this information with.
I just...
I feel like it's gonna
come up, why I missed
so much school.
You know, if you wanna take
the attention off yourself,
you just ask
Amber questions.
What kind of questions?
Just about herself.
You know, speaking
from experience,
it's actually really nice
when someone shows interest
in learning more about you.
Do you think I could just
spend the whole ride
asking her questions?
I don't think
you're gonna
need to, buddy.
I mean, look,
I think all you have
to do, I don't know,
just lob in an icebreaker.
Uh, what kind of music
you been listening to?
And that'll start
a back and forth and
you're off to the races.
Do you think that'll work?
I do, but I don't know.
You want to try it out?
So...
Yeah. What kind of music
do you listen to?
You know, you would actually
be really surprised.
See if you can guess.
Um...
East Coast hip-hop?
No, but I will add
that to my list.
Keep guessing.
West Coast hip-hop?
Yes.
Mm.
Mm-hmm.
I knew it.
Yeah.
I'm not exactly sure
how long I'll be down.
Probably around
eight weeks.
Well, you take as much
time as you need.
I'm just so glad
your son is a match.
Right.
Well, thank you.
You were hoping
he wouldn't be a match.
Here I'm thinking
I'm doing such a good job
acting excited.
Even though I agreed
to let Sean donate,
a part of me, a big part
of me was hoping
it wouldn't work out.
Hmm.
You know,
for what it's worth,
you can't always trust
cold feet.
You know, that fear
when the theoretical
becomes reality...
Because more often than not,
it's just trying to
sabotage a good thing.
And this is
a good thing, Dean.
Slight change of plans.
Put her in a steep
Trendelenburg position.
Wait, what's wrong?
The amniotic sac membranes
are protruding out through
the cervix.
That wasn't the case
when you examined
Michelle earlier.
You said her cervix
was shortened,
but only slightly dilated.
Yes, at that point it was,
but as I warned Michelle
could happen, her condition
has progressed.
I'm going to insert
a balloon that
will push the membranes
back into the cervix
and then tie it off.
Wait, that's a different
procedure with a much
greater risk to Michelle.
If you break her water,
she could become septic.
I'm not going to
let that happen.
I've done this a dozen times.
I don't care.
As her husband,
I'm her medical
surrogate, right?
Do not even try me
right now, Sam.
This is not a surgical
decision point
that I would ever consult
the family about.
I am well aware of
Michelle's wishes and...
I'm instructing you to stop.
And I am telling you
to leave now.
If anything happens to her...
The longer Michelle stays
anaesthetized on this table,
the greatest risk to her.
So stop distracting me
and let me finish.
Okay.
I need a 30 CC foley
and a ring forcep.
Oh, man.
I messed up.
I injured the hepatic vein
going after a nearby lesion.
That's what caused the clot.
Are you sure that's
what the data shows?
See for yourself.
Clear as day.
It's my fault, Will.
That's why Jack erased it.
He was trying to protect me.
Jack looking out for
someone else?
Nah, I don't buy that.
Well, maybe he was
protecting his investment.
Like you said,
I'm the face of
the machine, right?
It doesn't look good
when your star surgeon
makes a fatal error.
Crockett.
You know anytime
you ablate a lesion
there's a risk of injury
to proximal veins.
You can't avoid that.
Mm-hmm.
Michelle is just fine.
We got the membranes
pushed back
into the uterus
without breaking the water.
They'll take her
to post-op
in a few minutes
and you should be able
to see her soon after.
And the fetus?
Will Michelle be able
to carry to term?
I can't make any promises.
Yeah, yeah. Of course.
The odds are in her favor,
and I'm cautiously optimistic.
Good.
Good, good. Good, good.
Thank you.
Um...
For the record,
I do want this baby.
I'll admit that the news
surpri... Shocked me.
I'm an empty nester
Um...
My daughter, Lucy,
just started
graduate school,
and I didn't expect
to see diapers again
until I became a grandfather.
I'll bet.
But I love being a father,
and I'm actually
quite good at it.
What I'm not so
good at historically
is being a good father
and a good partner
at the same time.
Trying to parent with
my first wife destroyed
our marriage.
You'll be surprised
to hear this,
but I can be stubborn.
I've built a great life
with Michelle.
I just don't wanna ruin it
by making the same mistakes.
Come here.
So this is just a hunch,
but I'm guessing you lacked
this level of self-awareness
in your first marriage.
My ex-wife would certainly
agree with that assessment.
Look, you're not
the same person
anymore, Sam.
And the fact that
you can honestly admit
your shortcomings
is a pretty good sign
that you won't repeat them.
Been cruising the Hallmark
aisle in your free time?
Hmm...
Um, but your little
homily assumes
that human beings
are capable
of two things,
learning from their
failures and change.
I think we are.
Having trouble
finding data from
Richard Evans' surgery?
How did you...
Let me save you time.
It's all there.
Where'd you get this?
Jack erased it
from the system.
What?
Crockett made a mistake
during surgery
and Jack didn't want
a spokesmodel tarnished
before the IPO launch.
He wouldn't...
It's true.
I'm telling you,
Jack cannot be trusted.
Dr. Archer?
Yeah?
I'm Harrison Jenkins,
the supervisor
down at valet.
Your boy Sean
works with us.
Yeah, is everything okay?
Well, first let me say,
Sean's been doing
a stand-up job.
He's got
a positive attitude.
He's always on time.
Sure.
Everybody loves him.
Yeah, yeah. No. Thank you.
Thanks. So what's...
He didn't show up
for work today.
No call, nothing.
Tried him,
he didn't pick up.
I was wondering if you
heard anything from him.
I just wanna
make sure he's okay.
I haven't heard anything.
I didn't mean to rat
on him or anything...
No, no, no. No, no, no.
You did the right thing.
I'm sure there's
an explanation,
so thanks for letting me know.
Yeah. I'm sure.
Okay.
Oh, there you are.
Oh, hey.
I wanted to see how
your interview went.
Oh, it was fine.
Just fine?
Look, Maggie.
I was caught off
guard earlier.
I knew this day was
coming, but I just...
I just wasn't ready for it.
And to be honest,
neither was I.
And then I was really angry
with Jack because
he's driving away
one of our most
valuable people.
But I am so happy for you.
You know, you're always
looking out for
everybody else,
and you're finally
looking out for yourself,
and that is a
really good thing.
Now you better tell me
how that interview went.
It was great.
Yeah?
Really great.
They want me to
build the ED
from the ground up.
Well, they'll be
lucky to have you.
I don't have the job yet.
You will.
They won't find
anybody better.
You best believe that.
Girl, they gonna give me
the keys to that ED.
Gonna cut you loose
in the ED.
How you feeling, honey?
Not too bad.
I have a little cramping,
but Dr. Asher says
that's normal.
Very normal.
Um, this is for you.
Sam, you don't
even like baseball.
It was the only father-son
onesie in the gift shop.
What if it's a girl?
No, it's not.
Oh, damn it. I'm so sorry,
honey, Michelle.
Wait, what?
I had seen on the ultrasound
that it was a boy
and I was waiting to see
if you both wanted to know.
I forced it out of her,
and then promised
not to say anything.
We're having a boy?
We are. Yeah.
We're having a boy!
Hey.
You know all those apps
you're about to delete?
Yes.
Which one is
the least terrible?
Does this mean
you're officially putting
yourself out there?
I'm just...
I'm dipping toes
in the water.
Historically, romantic
relationships haven't
really gone well for me.
I've never been
a great partner.
Oh, Hannah, I'm sure
that's not true at all.
No. No, it's very true.
I've always been
unreliable and erratic.
You were dealing
with an addiction.
Yeah.
This is the longest
I've ever been sober
in my entire adult life.
I wanna believe that
I'm not that same
person anymore,
you know, that I can
be a great partner
for someone else.
Well, you're certainly
a good friend.
I can confirm that.
Thank you.
Okay.
So all of the dating
apps are terrible.
Ah!
Let me see your phone
and I'll show you
which ones I'm on.
I left it at
the nurse's station,
but I will be back.
Okay.
Hey. Did you talk
to Sean today?
No, why?
He's not
answering his phone,
didn't show up for work.
Yeah. Let me know
if you hear
from him, okay?
Of course.
Hey, try not to
think the worst.
Right.
Will, wait.
I need to show you something.
Can you come with me?
Sure.
This is Richard Evans'
pre-op CT.
This is his
intraoperative CT.
The large lesion near the
hepatic vein that Crockett
attempted to ablate?
Yeah?
It's not on
Richard's pre-op CT.
What?
A lesion doesn't just develop
over a matter of hours.
No, it doesn't.
So that means 2.0 created
the lesion on its own?
I believe so.
Crockett would never
have gone near
the hepatic vein...
If 2.0 hadn't directed him
to ablate a phantom lesion.
Jack thought he was
protecting Crockett
by erasing the data,
but Crockett wasn't
responsible for
Richard Evans' death.
2.0 was.
Sausage pizza,
extra cheese,
and whatever, you know,
the wine shop
said this was.
Thank you, Daniel.
Thank you so much.
Why you whispering?
Pawel just fell asleep.
Oh. Everything...
Everything okay?
What's going on?
I had to pull out of escrow.
What?
Why? Did the house
not appraise?
Pawel is having
financial difficulties.
All right, honey.
What's going on?
Talk to me. Tell me.
He has a very large
gambling debt.
And so you're gonna...
You're gonna pay it
off for him?
Well, of course.
I have to.
I mean, sweetie,
is that really
your responsibility?
Well, he's my brother,
and we are responsible
for each other.
Right. Okay. Okay.
Well, I don't know.
Can I...
Can I at least help you
unpack some stuff
or something?
There's no reason to.
I still have to move out
before the end of the month.
Why?
I talked to the landlord,
and he won't budge.
I still have to honor
the notice I gave him.
Wait, wait.
That's ridiculous.
Do you have his number?
Let me give him a call.
No, I don't want
you to call him.
It's my responsibility.
Okay, but, where are
you gonna live?
I don't know yet.
I haven't thought
that far ahead.
Why don't you come
live with me?
What?
You can come live with me.
I mean,
I got plenty of room,
that's for sure.
No. No, no,
no, no. I can't.
But, honey, why not?
I mean,
at least until you,
I don't know, find
another place to stay.
I can take care
of myself, Daniel.
I don't need your help.
I just don't have it
figured out right in
this moment.
I know you can take care
of yourself, okay?
I'm actually asking
you to do this
because I want to.
Really?
Then why didn't
you ask me before?
Why are you only
asking me now?
Gee, I don't know.
Maybe because you
bought a freakin' house
before I could?
Oh, so maybe my house
falling through
is not such a terrible
thing for you
because you can
come in here
and rescue me like I am
some charity case?
Are you serious?
What are you talking about?
I've never thought
of you that way.
You know what?
This is not a good
night for company.
I think you might be
right about that.
"Charity case."