Who's in?
Dr. Greene.
Dr. Greene, there's
this guy on the street.
Gunshot wounds, I think.
There's blood everywhere.
All right, you heard the doctor.
Here we go.
We got a G.S.W. on the street.
We're going to need
some hands out there.
Will you get this out of here?
Patients will strangle
on Christmas lights.
Let's get a move on.
There he is, between the cars.
I see him. Okay, I see him.
All right, yeah,
he's still breathing.
I got a pulse.
We got to get him out of here.
Lift him up.
All right, all right.
Easy. Watch his head.
You got him?
Bag him.
Connie, notify the O.R.
Get Benton in here, and order up
eight units O-negative.
Bob, call Security. We
got a gangbanger here.
Gangbanger?
Dial 432 and say, "Help."
Coming to Trauma Two.
In the winter, I wish they'd
dump the bodies inside.
Yeah. Pretty
inconsiderate of them.
This is Trauma Two.
Call the blood bank.
We need eight units
of O-neg down here,
and I need a page on Benton now.
Get his clothes off.
Terry, can you clear that?
Abdomen, chest
neck, legs...
Pulse 160 and thready.
Treat for the sounds.
Hypo-resonant on the right.
I'll decompress.
.14 gauge? Get
your souvenirs here.
I'll get it out of here.
Let's intubate him.
Carter, why don't
you jump in here?
Me?
Yeah. You've seen
about 50 of these
by now, right?
Okay.
All right, good.
Advance the blade
to the epiglottis
and then lift.
I can't see a thing in here.
I'll suction.
All right, good.
Visualize the vocal cords
and pass the tube through them.
Stay away from that esophagus.
Good.
I got it.
Nice work, Carter.
O.R.'s waiting.
What do we got?
Tube's in. Let's go.
Multiple gunshot wounds
to the neck, chest,
abdomen and legs.
Intubated. Tension
pneumo on the right.
Needs a thoracotomy
and a laparotomy.
Cole, clear that elevator.
I'd like to follow
him through the O.R.
There's going to be enough
bodies swarming around.
Still haven't been in there.
I'll take him from here.
I'm the one who
found him in the street.
Yeah? Well, you probably
saved his life. Let's go.
Captioning Sponsored
by WARNER BROS.
We got a dead shovel in Two,
and a paper cut
in the suture room.
Paper cut?
Yeah. Guy says
that his newspaper
jumped up and attacked him.
We're waiting for Psych.
Isn't it comforting to know
that 1995 isn't going to
be any different than 1994?
Excuse me. Carter?
Can you call the
medical examiner's office
and have them pick up
the dead shovel in two.
Sure. What's a "dead shovel"?
Fat man shoveling snow.
This is our lady with
heart palpitations,
and a fractured femur
who's waiting on the orthopods.
Excuse me?
I've been here for hours now,
and I feel absolutely fine.
Mrs. Davis is the
mitral prolapse
with resolved S.V.T.
Yeah. Resolved and forgotten.
Where's Dr. Lewis?
She'll be with you
as soon as she can.
I hope so, because I
have a seven-year-old
at home with the mumps.
So do I. Gets on
your nerves, doesn't it?
Yeah.
Thank you.
You can do it.
I can do it.
Just swing on.
You mean hang on?
I can't do it, Bob.
I can't do it.
Yes. Yes, you can.
Are you okay?
New year's revolution.
Resolution. I quit smoking.
She had a mental.
Menthols don't count.
My New Year's resolution
was to quit doing scut work...
after I take these urine
specimens to the lab.
He failed. Why can't I?
Is Dr. Benton back
from surgery yet?
Been and gone.
Thank you.
Ew! This is gross!
Come here.
Shut up, Stuey!
No, you!
Stop it!
Let the doctor do his work!
Perhaps Binky
wants to wait outside.
Mrs. Bentley, Stuey's
eye is going to be just fine.
Here's just a word of caution.
Keep all the guns,
even the paint guns,
away from the kids.
Yeah, well, obviously!
What do you think
I am, an idiot?!
Come on, Stuey, let's go.
Binky?!
I got a bumsicle for you.
Freeze-dried at the back door.
Okay, let's clear Trauma One.
Gotta go. Welcome back.
Found him under
the El on 43rd Street.
His name's Gilbert McCabe.
Legs frozen to the sidewalk.
I was just sleeping.
I feel fine. Put me down.
You can't even
stand up, Gilbert.
We had to chip
through the ice
with a tire iron.
They woke me
up is what they did.
Mr. McCabe, my name's
Dr. Greene, this is Dr. Hicks.
We're going to
check you over, okay?
I don't want some colored
woman working on me.
Hey!
Like I said,
'95's going to be just like '94.
I said put me down!
What are you, deaf?
Dr. Kayson?
I'm very busy, Dr. Lewis.
This will just take a minute.
I've got a patient with
mitral valve prolapse...
You'll have to wait, Dr. Lewis.
I've got a patient
coming out of surgery.
Miss Davis, everything
checks out okay.
Your heart rate's normalized.
We just need to
increase your Verapamil.
Oh. So I can go?
Not until the
attending cardiologist
gives the okay.
Don't worry, Miss Davis.
You'll have plenty of time to
enjoy your daughter's mumps.
They last a good seven days.
You have to take them off.
The hell I do.
You need Carter?
Not if you do.
Get off me.
Bowel disimpaction in one.
How was surgery?
Which surgery?
The gang kid from this morning.
He died ten minutes in.
This is supposed to
be my surgical rotation.
Your E.R. surgical rotation.
I haven't been in an O.R. yet.
Do you always treat your
students like this? Like what?
I hate to complain, but all I
do for you is your scut work.
Well, that's what I did
for my surgical resident.
It's what we all did,
and it's what you
will continue to do
until you can do
it in your sleep.
You are a medical student.
You're here to
make my life easier.
I'm also here to learn.
And have you learned?
Glove up and dig in.
And don't take all day.
Mr. McCabe, can
you feel anything here?
Keep it where I can see it.
Mr. McCabe.
What?
Are you feeling anything here?
Where?
Can you feel that?
No.
And don't touch those pants.
Now?
No. Nothing hurts. And don't get
into those pockets. I got all
my money in those pockets.
What do you keep poking for?
My feet feel fine.
It's just that they're...
you know, a little heavy...
Like a chunk of wood.
And I want to take
those shoes with
me, do you hear me?
Connie, let's set
up a morphine drip
and a gram of Anseph,
and give him a tetanus booster.
I don't want any drugs.
And Heparin, 5,000 units.
Mr. McCabe, you have severe
frostbite in both
your feet and legs,
ice crystals in the tissues,
and we need to
warm them up quickly
in a whirlpool bath.
You mean like a Jacuzzi?
Yeah, like a Jacuzzi.
After that, we'll see if
there's any tissue damage,
and then we'll decide
if you need surgery.
Oh, no. I won't need that.
A perfectly good
pair of hoofers here.
Just need a little
warming up, that's all.
But tell them I'm taking
my clothes with me.
Don't want some bonehead
stealing them.
Mrs. Davis is 38 years old,
known history of recurrent,
easily controlled S.V.T.
Should have released
her hours ago.
I did try to talk
to you about her,
but you were on
your way to recovery.
Should have come to
me a long time before that.
The patient's been
here for hours.
Hi, Susie.
Not now, Chloe. I did try...
I need to tell you something.
Hey, you one of
Susie's teachers?
Here's your release.
Next time, Dr. Lewis,
try harder.
Oh, Mrs. Davis needs you.
Okay. I told you to stop
coming by the hospital.
Let me just tell you something.
It couldn't wait until tonight?
No. I'm not going
to be here tonight.
Ronnie and I are
moving to Texas.
I've come to say good-bye.
Susan, you coming?
Yeah.
What are you going to do?
I don't know.
Learn how to cook chili.
This isn't funny.
You waltz in here and tell me
you and Ronnie
are moving to Texas.
You're not even
sure he can get a job.
I told you, He's got an uncle
that works in a refinery.
Where are you going to live?
I always figure that stuff out.
You're pregnant, Chloe.
It's a little
different this time.
This is crazy.
I don't think you should go.
You want me and
Ronnie and the baby
to stay with you?
You don't even want
me to have the baby.
I just think...
Well, I want to,
and I'm going to.
At least stay in Chicago.
Maybe I can talk
to Mom and Dad...
I don't want that.
I don't want
to stay with people
that always think I'm doing
the wrong thing.
I'm going to love this
baby, Susan, so much,
and I want everyone
else to love it, too.
You going to eat that?
No.
Hey...
I'll send you a postcard
from the Alamo, okay?
Chloe, wait.
You don't even
have a winter coat.
Thanks.
I'll wear it.
I'll wear it all the time.
All right, give him
a liter of Ringer's
the first hour,
16 Lines, start a Foley.
B.P. 70/40, Resp shallow at 28.
Full thickness
burns to both legs.
Check to see who's
covering plastics.
We need more sterile saline.
Lydia's coming with it.
Third degree, scalp and face.
Burn unit's notified, Mark.
Thanks, Lydia.
Pulse ox, 85. I'll
start a flow sheet.
Any other firemen hurt?
No.
Give him ten of morphine.
Want me to get rid of them?
No, no. Let them stay.
Jose, you're missing
my point, man.
We are not a pizza joint,
and we do not deliver.
Okay. Sure.
Take your business elsewhere.
Guy wants us to
make house calls.
How quaint.
You, however, Dr. Ross,
won the Pick Three Lotto.
You got a runny nose in One,
cough and a sore throat in Four,
and babies having babies
over at curtain number Two.
Babies it is.
Thanks.
So, how was New Year's Eve?
Sorry I didn't make it.
Neither did we.
Walt and I fell out by 10:30.
Oh, yeah? Yeah.
So what does he think
about your new job?
He's happy.
Kids me about it all the time.
Says working for Parks and Rec
is like being an
urban forest ranger.
Yeah, but I bet
Mom's proud, right?
That's what we need
to talk about, Peter.
Walt and I saw
this really nice place
across from Grimwald Park.
She'd have her own room,
people would
spend time with her,
nurses would look after her.
Jackie, what are
you talking about?
I don't think we can
keep caring for her, Peter.
Ever since the stroke, she's
been in and out, and you know that.
She needs constant
looking after.
I don't know "constant."
No, you wouldn't know "constant"
because you're never around.
Now, with this new job,
I'm not able to do it anymore,
and I don't want the kids to
have to take on that responsibility.
Steven made the basketball
team, and Joanie's doing plays,
and I'm not going to
ask them to give that up.
Why? Because that's
what you had to do
when you were
looking out after me?
When Mom went back to work,
we didn't have much
choice, now, did we?
Huh? Well, I do have a choice
about my own kids.
Okay.
Jackie, uh...
there's got to be
something else.
What about Mrs. Lukey?
Mrs. Lukey's only three
years younger than Mom.
She looked out after
that old man on the corner.
She lives right across the
street. She could come over.
She could spend the days.
All right, I'll make the
arrangements. I'll pay for it.
And since when do you
have all this extra money?
Look, Jackie, let
me worry about that.
Is this some kind of done
deal because you say so?
Where the hell have you been
for the past six years
while Walt and I
worried about it?
I can't put her in a home.
You won't have to.
It's our decision.
All of ours.
It can't always be about
what you want, Peter.
I'm going to miss my bus.
Doc...
what's the story?
How's our boy?
It's not great, guys.
Sorry.
He's got full thickness burns
to 60 percent of his body.
He needs to go up to
the O.R. for debridement,
and from there to the burn unit.
But he's going to make it?
I'll know a lot more
in about 12 hours.
Yeah.
Okay, thanks, Doc.
Dr. Greene, can I talk
to you for a second?
Yeah. Can I borrow your pen?
Uh... I don't know
if this is appropriate.
I'm just not sure
that Dr. Benton's
all that interested in
supervising me anymore.
In fact, I'm fairly
certain that he's not.
That warm, fuzzy demeanor...
It's not getting through to you?
Yes, that would be accurate.
When I was in medical school,
I had a ton of
residents like Benton.
Matter of fact, I think
Benton had a ton
of residents like Benton.
He's not the worst
one you're going to get.
My advice... get used to it.
Lydia, I need some help
with those teenagers.
I can't. I'm on my
way to Radiology.
She can't. She's on
her way to Radiology.
She's trying to quit smoking.
She's chewing that nicotine gum.
The whole pack?
You okay?
I've, uh...
I never seen anything like that.
I just started, uh...
three weeks ago.
Maybe I shouldn't be doing this.
But I didn't think it
would scare me like this.
Hey... you need
to get some rest.
Go home, okay?
Get some sleep.
Breathe.
The EKGs are normal?
That's right, Mr. Venerbeck.
So are your blood tests,
chest X rays and enzymes.
There doesn't seem to be any
damage to the heart muscle.
So what was this pain, then?
Probably muscular.
You take all this time
just to tell me I
pulled a muscle?
So what, I take that
anti-inflammatory again?
Again?
A couple of months ago,
my wife made me
clean the garage.
Threw my back out.
Two months ago?
That's what I said.
Oh, here it is. They
gave you Feldene.
Your pain stopped now,
so you don't need
to take it this time.
Okay, so I'm out of here.
I can't discharge
you exactly yet.
What's the deal?
You said I was fine.
I've got three customers
to see this afternoon.
I need to run your tests
by the cardiologist on call.
Then we can sign you out. Sorry.
Have you seen mark?
Room One.
Okay.
Mark.
Oh, it's okay, Mrs. Packard.
She's a nurse.
Sorry. Chopper setting down
in two minutes with an M.V.A.
Get Benton for it.
He's still at lunch.
Here's your pap
tray, Dr. Greene.
Thank you, Dr. Carter.
He's your man.
Right this way.
Okay.
Paramedics are bringing
in an M.V.A. on the chopper.
Benton's out. I need
you to bring him down.
Okay, wait. By myself?
Uh-huh.
Excellent.
Carter, it's 34 degrees out.
You might want to get your coat.
My coat.
Carter, is there some kind
of emergency?
All right, come on.
All right.
What have we got?
M.V.A... school bus
versus a two-door.
Blunt abdominal trauma.
25 Years old.
Pulse is thready.
B.P. is 50 palp.
Go! Go! Go!
Couldn't intubate.
Just scooped and flew.
All right, we'll take him.
Cap refill slow.
Sinus tack at 150.
Run a strip.
What do we got?
M.V.A. Blocked
trauma to the abdomen.
Okay, people, let's intubate.
I got it.
You help intubate.
I'll get x-ray down here.
Okay, Mr. Carter.
He's all yours.
Connie, can I get a 7.5?
Jim, it's Lily in E.R.
We need portable X
rays in Trauma Two.
C-spine and abdominal
series to start.
Okay, thanks.
He's got a lot of secretions.
I'm going to need some suction.
Where's the O-neg?
On its way.
Advance the blade.
B.P.'s at 50 palp.
Pass through the tube.
How much fluid has he had?
Two liters in the field.
This will make four.
I got it.
Give me a suction cap.
Respirator?
No, we're going
to bag him.
His abdomen's rigid.
Peritoneal lavage?
And would you like to
do that also, Mr. Carter?
No. You can do that one.
Oh. Why, thank you.
Don't bother, Peter.
I got a team scrubbing up.
Let's move him upstairs.
Okay. Give me the bullet.
M.V.A., 25 Years old,
brought in pale and diaphoretic.
Pulse is 150, B.P.'s 50 palp,
resp is 25. Intubated.
Blunt abdominal trauma.
Probable ruptured spleen.
Thank you, one and all.
We'll take it from here.
Let's go.
Morgenstern and I are doing
a gall bladder at 8:00 p.m.
Scrub in by 7:30.
We have made contact.
I repeat, we have made contact.
It was you who was
looking for him, right?
Yeah.
Dr. Kayson?
I'm on my way to the
cath lab, Dr. Lewis.
Then I'll ask you
to sign out Mr. Venerbeck now.
Admitted with
nonradiating left chest pain
reproducible with movement.
Tenderness, left sternal border.
Resolved without treatment.
EKG is normal?
Yes.
Enzymes? Chest X ray?
Normal.
Dizzy? Palpitations? No.
Diaphoretic? No.
Hyperlypoproteinemia? No.
History of chest
pain? No, but...
Risk factors?
None, but slightly
elevated blood pressure.
Doesn't sound cardiac.
Have him see his
doctor for a stress test.
Thank you, Dr. Lewis.
Thank you, Dr. Kayson.
You're free and
clear, Mr. Venerbeck.
See your own doctor.
Get a stress test.
Oh, great. I miss
two appointments,
and you take three hours
to tell me to see my own doctor.
Well, I'm sorry
that it took so long,
but we wanted to give
you a thorough checkup.
Sure, sure. Thanks, okay?
I'll send a nurse in.
Great.
Dr. Lewis?
When I was a resident,
I was always worried
about getting people's approval.
The attending, the patients.
Maybe because I was a
woman... a black woman.
Life was a lot easier
once I got over it.
Don't let the patients
get to you, Dr. Lewis.
We treat them as soon as we can,
and there is no
need to apologize
for how long it takes.
We're a busy hospital,
not a restaurant.
Don't touch me.
You started it.
I did not.
You did, too.
Ladies, you're sisters.
We can work this out.
Sally didn't want the name Emily
until I chose it.
Emily is grandmother's name.
There are plenty of
other names you can use.
You don't even
know if it's a girl.
Besides, I deliver
a week earlier.
Not if I have it induced...
Oh, no!
Connie... Get out of the way!
Connie, get a C.B.C.
and a Chem seven.
Get F.H.T.s with a
Doppler and call O.B.
Hey, Susan, you bored?
Looking for something to do?
Come on. Her name's Territa.
She's 19 years old.
She's complaining
of abdominal pains.
She needs Narceine
and an amp of glucose.
Hook up the suction
to the Yankower.
We need an amp of glucose.
Narceine given.
Where's that Doppler?
B.P. 70/30.
Resp shallow at eight.
She's somnolent.
Pupils pinpoint.
What's she on?
Boyfriend says
pills and cocaine.
Let's get a tox screen.
She needs an amp of D-5.
We're going to
help you, Territa.
Can you tell me
When your due date is?
I don't know!
Everything's going to be fine.
It's coming!
She's fully dilated.
100 percent effaced.
Membrane's ruptured.
Let's get her up to O.B.
Elderly couple's coming
in, both comatose.
E.T.A.'s two minutes.
Benton's in surgery,
and Dr. Hicks is
on her way down.
Please hurry. It's coming.
It's coming.
Don't push. Don't push.
Take short breaths,
like you're blowing
out a candle.
Oh, damn, we've
got a foot coming out,
and it's blue.
Okay, let's back her
up and take her in here.
Come on, people. Excuse us.
Help me.
Call O.B.
Tell them to get
down here right away.
Can't get much worse
than a cocaine toxic
footling breech.
Yes, it can.
Umbilical cord's prolapsed.
Grab those monitors.
Where are the leads?
In the crash cart.
Oh, God, no!
Are they going to be okay?
Who are you?
I live next door.
Their cat was scratching
to get in the apartment
but, when I knocked,
nobody answered.
Her skin is cherry red,
especially under the nails.
O2 is 15 liters. Call
Respiratory in here stat.
It's probably carbon
monoxide poisoning,
with both of them out.
Carol, do a sodium
hydroxide test.
Can you get a couple of
test tubes from the rack?
Were they using space heaters?
Yeah. They got
those little ones with...
It's not oil, but...
Kerosene.
We need a portable
X ray in here now.
They're going to
be okay, aren't they?
They've lived next
door to me all my life.
They're like my grandparents.
C.O.'s present, both samples.
Carboxy-hemoglobin.
Let's get the oxygen
hooked up here.
What kind of lab test you want?
Keep breathing.
Turn the warmer on.
Who's on in N.I.C.U.?
Son of a bitch! It hurts!
No, no!
Breathe slowly.
I can't...
Good. I got the other leg.
Who's on in N.I.C.U.?
N-n-no!
Shoulder blades are free.
Okay, rotate it sideways.
Keep the arms
down over the chest.
What are you doing?
Here we go.
No!
He's tremulous.
Suction.
Okay. Breathe. Keep breathing.
Here's a line.
My baby.
I'll stick a butterfly
in his scalp vein.
Get me a heel stick.
Blood sugar is 25.
Any vaginal tears?
Not too bad.
Let me get some cord blood.
Give him six milligrams
of ten percent DW
over three minutes.
Susan, didn't you just release
a patient named Venerbeck?
Honey, you're going to be okay.
I just know it.
What happened?
I don't understand.
The whole time he
was here, he was fine.
He's had five of morphine...
He's got a new holosystolic
murmur with a thrill.
Give me an E.T. tube, 7.5.
Why did you let him go?
500cc's D5W.
Ten mics per
kilogram per minute.
Would somebody please
tell me what is going on?
38-year-old bounce
back with chest pain.
Holosystolic murmur.
Hypertensive with possible
ventricular septal rupture.
Give me 40 milligrams
Lasix I.V. push.
Doctor, please.
Someone tell me
what is going on!
Get him on the portable monitor.
Order up his lab results.
Come on, let's go.
That will be all, Dr. Lewis.
Mrs., uh...
Venerbeck.
Mrs. Venerbeck.
I'm Dr. Kayson.
We need to take certain
emergency measures
to stabilize your
husband's cardiac...
Miss Marianski...
Miss Marianski,
I'm sorry it's not the news
that you wanted to hear.
No, I want this baby.
Is it your husband?
He doesn't want
to have the baby?
Miss Marianski,
this is something
that the two of
you, as a couple,
really should discuss.
He's infertile.
Well, um...
In that case, uh...
um... yeah, that would be...
These are the maxillary sinuses.
If you see opacification
on the affected site,
that's a subtle clue
that the inferior wall
of the orbit's fractured.
If this isn't a good time...
Sorry. It's been a long day.
Actually, it's not a
great time for me either.
I'm scrubbing with
Dr. Benton on a gallbladder
in seven minutes.
If I know Dr. Benton,
he'll be early.
Better get out of here.
Oh, Carter, remember
these three things:
Cystic duct, common duct, liver.
What?
Get out of here.
They're asleep.
Oh, you scared me.
Sorry.
The blood gases have normalized.
The C.O. levels are down.
They're going to be fine.
They're on a 2359 hold.
I just wanted to check
on them before I head out.
Mr. Babcock owned a bakery.
Started it the year
they were married.
He still makes a three-tier
cake every June 14
on their anniversary.
They got lucky today.
I think maybe they've
been lucky every day.
Carter...
you don't have to
butt in backwards.
You're not sterile yet.
Okay.
Turn on the faucet
with your knee.
Pop open the brush packet.
Come on, get it open.
Good.
Now, get your hands wet,
starting with your fingernails.
Scrub your
fingernails ten times...
Front, side, back, webbing.
Like this?
Yeah. Sort of.
Then scrub the palm ten times.
Back of the hands,
down the arm...
Front, side, back,
up to the elbows.
And rinse.
Let the water run down your arms
not your hands.
You got it?
Yeah. Think so.
Good.
Remember, ten times.
And hurry up.
Five, six, seven,
eight, nine, ten.
One, two, three, four,
five six, seven, eight.
One, two, three, four, five,
six, seven, eight, nine, ten.
Good. Just pull it right back.
Sometimes... You
know what I like to do?
Just pull the thing
back and hold it...
Get it out of your way.
Like this?
There you go.
It'll spring right back.
Good.
I'm going to get this
out of your way there.
So you saw a piano showroom?
Yeah. A piano showroom...
Right on the
Eisenhower Expressway.
Drove right by it.
Let's bougie this bleeder.
So what's so strange about that?
Well, I've been driving
that same route home
every night for six years,
and I never even
saw it until last night,
but there it was...
On the Eisenhower
right off Central.
Well, I guess that is strange.
Scalpel.
Okay, now, divide the
anterior rectus fascia.
Yeah, yeah, let's
Hoover that puppy.
Good.
Shirley, is it hot in here?
No, Dr. Morgenstern.
I think it must be
the change of life.
Pianos on the expressway?
Thank you, Shirley.
You may go now.
Zap it there, will you?
Ah, Mr. Carter, glad
you could join us.
Dry off.
Tonsil clamp.
Divide the rectus,
and grab the
posterior rectus sheath.
Straight arms.
Good. Very good.
Scalpel.
I got it.
Right hand.
Sorry, I thought you
meant your right hand.
No, your right hand.
Left hand. Grab it.
We'll straighten it out.
Good. Spin.
Still with us, Carter?
Yeah. Right here.
You're done.
Dr. Benton.
Okay. There's the fundus.
Dr. Benton...
Okay, grab it.
What is it, Carter?
Where should I stand?
Well, not right there.
Don't touch my shoulder.
You just contaminated yourself.
Shirley, would you take
Dr. Carter out of here?
Want to play a round
of foreign capitals?
No. I hate this game.
Yes, Doug. Yeah, Doug. Oh!
Oh, no!
No, no, no, no, no, no, no!
Don't move!
What was your name again?
Someday I'm going to
believe that line out of you.
What are you talking about?
Can you remember the names
of all the women
you've slept with?
No.
So? Someday you'll forget mine.
You're assuming
that we won't last.
Well... yeah.
Where are you going?
I've got that conference
in the morning.
All right.
We treated this
older couple today.
They were married 48 years.
Ai-yi-yi!
No, they seemed
pretty happy about it.
That's them, not us.
How do you know?
How did they know?
Because, if it were us,
we wouldn't be doing this.
We'd both be married.
Have daughters in Girl Scouts.
Be renting The Lion King.
We would never
have met each other
because we would already be
committed to somebody else.
Mm-hmm. Don't you want that?
Not now.
Not with me?
Same thing.
Then why don't I want it?
Because you are afraid.
Most men are afraid.
Of what?
Responsibility, aging, death...
diminished sexual capacity.
See you.
Iceland.
Reykjavik.
Don't move.
Belarus.
Minsk.
Ha!
Okay, pack off the colon,
duodenum and stomach.
Suction.
Zaire.
Kinshasa?
Perhaps your student
should step a little closer.
Yeah, I guess you're right.
We're all packed off here.
Peel it like a pear.
Grab at the ampulla and
dissect Calot's triangle.
Mr. Carter...
can you tell us what defines
Calot's triangle?
The cystic duct, the
common duct and the liver.
Hold this retractor, will you?
All right, let's get
a little bougie here.
Mr. Carter... have you ever
noticed that piano showroom
on the Eisenhower Expressway?
So then she blurts
out, "He's infertile."
Susan, that's my best
story of the new year.
Sorry. It's just been
another incredibly
hateful day with Kayson.
Yeah?
Well, you buy into it.
You can't let him
ride you like that.
I'd put salt on them.
Shouldn't eat salt.
What are you doing?
I need more Tabasco.
You haven't tasted them yet.
Don't need to.
But if you haven't
tasted them...
You have a problem with this?
No. No. Absolutely not.
Saw Chloe wandering
around the halls today.
She was so calm, I
hardly recognized her.
Thanks, Mark.
Sorry. That was stupid.
Actually, they're
moving to Texas.
Ronnie's going to dig for oil,
and she's going to have his
baby... assuming it is his baby.
Why don't they just stay here?
Probably because I told her
she should get an abortion.
Why did you do that?
Because I think she should.
That's not very supportive.
Supportive of what?
My sister's fantasy
of having a child?
She thinks it's like having
a pet, Mark... a little puppy
who will follow her around
and love her forever.
Who won't care that
she's an alcoholic,
that she abuses drugs,
that she's getting God
knows what diseases
from sleeping with
every guy on the corner.
Maybe this baby will turn
her around. You don't know.
Yeah. Like the one we
delivered this afternoon?
Maybe. I don't know.
Well, I do.
No, you don't, Susan.
That's the point.
None of us do. Chloe
will have a chance.
The baby will have a chance.
Who are you to decide?
I'm her sister.
I pick up the pieces.
It's still her choice.
And one that I would support
if she'd ever taken one ounce
of responsibility for her life
before wanting
to take on another.
I love my sister, Mark,
but she can't
even part her hair.
So do I think she should
bring a child into this world?
No, I do not.
Kayson?
Venerbeck is dead, Dr. Lewis.
Oh, God.
I've reviewed
this file thoroughly.
The man should never
have been released.
You approved his release.
I didn't have all
the information.
What information?
He came in here two
months ago with back pain.
The diagnosis was
musculoskeletal.
It was probably atypical angina,
and you should
have told me about it.
You didn't ask for
his medical history.
Do I have to ask for everything?
What are you suggesting?
I am suggesting this case
was more complicated
than you thought,
and that your
experience as a resident
was not sufficient to
either determine that
or to present it to
those who could.
I presented what you asked for.
But not the entire picture.
And, because of
that, a man is dead,
and his wife is
consulting their attorney.
Dr. Morgenstern has been
made aware of the situation,
and I have requested
a full case review.
Susan, E.M.T.'s
pulling up...
Woman in respiratory arrest.