The human life is
made up of choices.
Yes or no. In or
out. Up or down.
And then there are
the choices that matter.
To love or hate.
To be a hero or to be a coward.
To fight or to give in.
To live...
or die.
My name is April Kepner.
I'm 28 years old. I
was born on April 23rd.
In Ohio. I'm from
Columbus, Ohio.
My mom's a teacher and
my dad is a farmer... Corn.
Corn, he grows corn.
Their names are Karen and Joe.
I have three sisters.
Libby's the oldest, I'm next
and then there's
Kimmie and Alice.
I haven't done anything yet.
I haven't... I've barely lived.
I'm not finished yet.
No one's loved me yet.
Please, please.
I'm someone's child.
I'm a person. I'm a person.
Run.
Mr. Clark...
Live or die.
That's the important choice.
And it's not always
in our hands.
Derek could still be
alive! I'm going, Cristina.
- No, you are not.
- Let me go. Please.
You'll get killed, I'm not gonna let
that happen. You gotta go through me.
We made it all the way home from
Iraq alive and now there's this guy
with his people-shooting
hat on here in a hospital
which is the safest
place in the world.
- Is there a point to this or...
- I think you love me.
I think you love Cristina
and I think you love me too.
You tried to get
Shepherd to get rid of me
so you wouldn't have to choose.
But, people-shooting-hat
guy is here and Owen,
for my sake and for Cristina's
sake you have to choose.
- Her or me.
- Fine. No one. No one.
I'm choosing no one.
I am taking myself out
of this equation and I'm...
Oh, my God.
He's dead.
We can't go to the ICU.
We stay here,
we're sitting ducks.
We're taking this
patient out of here.
- Who are you calling?
- 911.
Why are they only getting
civilians out? Where's the staff?
Policy is to clear visitors
room by room, floor by floor,
before non-essential
hospital personnel.
Did they get the shooter? Do
you know where the shooter is?
- Do you know who
the shooter is?
- No, sir.
- Do you know anything?
- Dr. Owen Hunt
from Seattle Grace...
- Commander, I've got sound.
- We are coming out
with a critical patient.
Dr. Callie Torres.
I'm up on peds,
we've got a kid with
a ruptured appendix.
Dr. Miranda Bailey. I'm on five.
- He shot a doctor. In the ICU.
- There are two dead
security guards...
This guy, six-one,
graying hair, moustache...
Dr. Charles Percy's been shot...
he shot a nurse.
I got a doctor up here, Karev...
Please come, we need help.
We've got a GSW to the chest,
I need a way outta here
if he's gonna make it.
He was looking for the
chief, specifically the chief.
He shot him. He shot
Derek Shepherd...
right in front of
us. We need help.
Hold on, OK? Hold on. I
love you. Please don't die.
Get out of here, Meredith,
before he shoots you.
Do not die. Do you understand?
I can't live without you.
- I called the police.
- If you die, I die.
Good, they're coming.
The police are coming.
They're not gonna get here.
They're not coming for us.
- Not in time.
- I picked you!
- What are we gonna do?
- I choose you. You don't die on me!
- Derek needs surgery.
- You stay awake!
- What do we do?
Stay awake. Derek!
Derek, stay awake!
- OK. OK.
- Stay awake!
April. Come on. We're
taking Derek down to the OR.
Teddy, she's in the OR.
She can save him. Come on.
I saw on Oprah or somewhere
if you tell them
details about yourself,
they're less likely to kill you.
Kepner, get up.
Come on! Come on!
Follow me. Just follow me.
Gotta eat more bacon.
- What?
- You stop yourself
from doing a lot of crap
that you want to do in life.
I mean, I'm probably dying now
and I'm telling you, you
gotta eat more bacon.
Have more sex.
OK. I will. I'll eat more bacon.
But you gotta hang in there,
'cause she's gonna
be back any minute.
She had to go to the
blood bank and back.
Oh, Mr. Clark...
I didn't plan to shoot
all those people.
Of course, you didn't...
No, you were... sad,
you were grieving.
I only planned to
shoot Dr. Shepherd.
And Dr. Webber.
And you.
You unplugged the machines.
Your hands killed my Alison.
- Is he dead?
- He's unconscious.
His vitals are tanking. And there's
nothing more I can do for him.
Don't die, Alex.
Please don't die.
This was my fault.
I unplugged his wife. I'm
so sorry, this was my fault.
I love you. Do you hear me?
I love you.
Now you're gonna feel a poke, and it's
gonna hurt but only for a little while.
- No squirming.
- It hurts!
- All right. Squeeze my hand tight!
- Good.
Tight, tight. Come
on. Wow, you're strong.
There are only children here.
They shot me.
There are children in
here. Only children here.
There's only children here.
Mr...?
Clark. Gary Clark.
There are only children here.
Only children here.
Mr. Clark...
Here are some...
bandages.
Only children here.
I want my mommy.
Press them to the wound
and it'll stop the bleeding.
- I want my mommy.
- Only...
- children are here. Only children.
- OK.
Just take them. Take them.
Take them and go.
- There are only children...
- I want my mommy.
Thank you.
- I want my mommy!
- All right.
- All right. OK, I know you do.
I know. I know you do and
she's gonna be back soon,
but until she gets here,
you have the best doctor in the
whole world with you right now.
Yeah. Dr. Robbins is the best
doctor in this entire hospital.
I think in the whole world.
Yeah, people feel so much
better after she helps them,
sometimes people feel better
just after she walks in the room.
'Cause she has got
this super magic smile.
Yeah, and when
she smiles at you,
everything gets better.
You don't know it 'cause you
have your back to her now, but
she is giving you...
Wow, she's giving you
her best super magic smile.
Isn't that right, Dr. Robbins?
Right.
I am, Ruby.
- I am.
- OK.
I gotta call the police, tell
them what happened, OK?
I... I'm good.
I'm good.
Does the name Gary
Clark mean anything to you?
Yes.
Gary Clark's wife was a
patient here. She was my patient.
He's suing the hospital. Why?
Mer, you prep him.
April and I are
gonna go find Teddy.
- She should still be
on the floor.
- OK.
Everything's gonna be
fine, OK, Mer? I promise. OK.
OK, they're going to find Teddy.
It's gonna be OK.
Kiss me.
I'm not going to die. I promise.
Good. 'Cause that would
be the worst break-up ever.
Sorry, sorry, sorry.
- The packing isn't holding.
- - What does that mean?
It means I need to
get him to an OR.
Someone is coming,
someone will come. Like a cop...
No! We need to get him to
an OR. That's his last chance,
if he's going to live. OK?
How are we even gonna do that?
We can... We can barely
hold him up on his side.
Uh...
There. There, there.
Give me the sheet.
It's creepy quiet down here.
- He's down here.
- No. He is not down here.
God, he's down here
and he's gonna
come out and shoot us.
Will you shut up?!
You're freaking me out and I don't
have time to be freaked out right now.
Mer is a mess, Derek is a mess,
you are a mess,
and I am in charge.
And I say that no
one is down here.
Don't shoot, don't shoot!
You are not supposed
to be walking around.
- Damn it, Jackson.
- Is that your blood? Are you OK?
No, I'm fine. I'll
go get Altman.
- Altman's not down here.
- Hunt.
- They left.
- What, they left?!
OK, you know what? Someone shot
Derek. He's got a GSW to the chest.
He needs surgery now. Tell me
there's an attending on this floor!
April, in the OR there
are two OR nurses
and an anesthesiologist.
Get them.
Tell them to set up
for a cardiac procedure.
What? Why? If we don't have a
surgeon, what are we going to do?
We have a surgeon.
What? Who's gonna
operate on Dr. Shepherd?
I am.
You can do this,
right? You're sure?
Every GSW is different.
It's not a blueprint. It's
half-instinct, half-improv.
And... I'm very good.
For a resident, I'm very good.
You can't be in there.
I can't do this if you're
in there staring at me
with big, sad "Don't
kill McDreamy" eyes.
We're ready for you.
April...
Meredith is gonna
sit here on the floor.
I want you to stay with her.
If she tries to enter my OR,
or even if she looks like she's
gonna get up to take a peek,
I want you stop her. I don't
care how, you stop her.
- OK.
- He is my husband.
Do you want me to kill
him? Is that what you want?!
I will do my very best work.
But please, Meredith, I am
begging you, sit down and wait.
Izzie?
Alex? It's Lexie.
Alex...
Iz? I'm sorry.
Don't go.
We got married,
please don't go...
I'm not going anywhere.
You came back for me, Iz.
I came back.
Don't ever leave me.
Don't ever leave me again.
I won't. I won't ever leave you.
We're always gonna
be together, OK?
Always.
This floor is clear. We're
going to evacuate you now.
We've cleared one floor,
we'll clear the others.
You've got five guys searching
150,000 square feet of hospital...
That's how it
works. Don't worry.
He's not getting out of there.
- Casey!
- Yes, sir?
Pull a DMV photo of Gary
Clark, have Dr. Webber confirm.
Shut down the elevators.
We wanna isolate this guy.
- Where can I find Dr. Webber?
- He's right over...
We got a GSW straight
from the OR, he's still critical.
Let's get him to the paramedics.
- Have you gotten the shooter?
- We need to clear you...
- You gotten the doctors out?
- No.
This is a secure area. We
need to move you to holding.
She's still in there.
Go.
It's OK.
It's OK to choose.
We're good.
Sir, you're not allowed to...
Gonna need you to... Sir!
Come back now!
Stop crying.
Look, it took me a
long time to find him.
A long time.
And even then it took me a long
time to even know that I wanted him.
To be married, to be
his wife, to have his kids.
And now that I realize that...
He's lying on the table in there
and my best friend's hands...
are inside his chest.
You don't get to cry about that.
Reed was my best friend.
And she died today.
GSW to the right chest.
We put in a chest tube.
He's gotten three liters of LR
and two units of packed cells.
Get him into an ambulance.
Call Seattle Pres, let
them know we're coming!
- I need to update that chart...
- He's gonna be OK, right?
Do you feel anything? Can you
see where the blood's coming from?
Not yet. Damn it, I can't see
anything. Give me some suction.
No, no, no, no, no...
It's right by to the aorta.
- You can do this.
- I know that.
I just wanted it to be easy.
Not the hardest freaking
repair in the history of the world!
I don't know what to do.
There's massive
bleeding in the lungs.
There is a bullet lodged
right next to the aorta
and a huge hematoma.
Would Teddy use a graft
- or clamp and sew?
- I think she'd...
- Pig or cow.
- What?
Pig or cow, Cristina?
Clamp and sew.
Definitely clamp and sew.
Give me a clamp.
Badass.
- How much further?
- We're almost there.
We're gonna get
him on the elevator,
and then we'll be
right at the OR floor.
We're almost there.
We're almost there, OK, Charles?
- We're almost there?
- Just a few more minutes.
Dr. B?
There's a hum elevators make
when they are on. There's a hum.
There's no hum.
What does that mean?
It means the elevators...
they're off!
The elevators aren't working!
We need to get to the OR!
Turn the elevators back on!
Turn them back on!
Oh, damn it!
Turn the elevators back on!
Please! That man is still
here somewhere. He'll hear us!
Please, stop, stop,
stop. Please, Dr. B!
OK. OK.
What are we gonna do?
Dr. B, what's the plan?
You have a plan, right, Dr. B?
What do we do?
Please?
We can't get to the OR,
but he has to get to the OR.
He has to get to the
OR, or he's... Dr. B?
Miranda.
We should be on
a first name basis.
Miranda.
OK.
I'm dying, right?
Am I dying now?
Yes. Yes, Charles,
you are dying.
But I don't want you to worry.
I don't want you to be afraid.
'Cause I... am not
going to leave you, OK?
Mary.
Mary... Mary and I...
are gonna be with you...
the whole time.
You are not alone. You hear me?
You are not alone.
Owen, thank God!
Derek's been shot.
No one was down here,
we didn't know what to do.
Cristina's in there, told me not
to look, but she might need help.
She seems to be doing OK.
But I'll just head in there
and see what I can do.
But you're not scrubbing in?
I'll assess first. If she
needs me, then I'll scrub in.
Cristina was right. You
should stay down there.
OK? Don't move.
A real surgeon is here. That's good.
That means Derek's going to be OK.
Whoa, just calm down. Calm
down. Tell me what the problem is.
- Owen...
- I'm here.
- Hold on!
- Talk to me.
- Stop fixing him.
Let him die. Let
him lie there and die.
Do you want me to shoot you?
Stop fixing him!
- No.
- Cristina...
No, Jackson, clamp the hilum
so we get control
of the hemorrhage,
- so I can get visualization.
- Don't you dare.
Clamp the hilum so I can see.
You stay back.
Owen, I can't stop. I have to...
I know. Just keep
going. Keep going.
You stop or I will shoot you.
Hey! That is the woman I love.
If you shoot her,
touch her, I will kill you!
And I said stay back.
Maybe I shoot you first.
I shoot you and then I shoot
her and then I shoot Shepherd.
Is that what you want?
I didn't come here for this.
My wife is dead.
He's responsible.
I came here for justice.
An eye for an eye.
The only person I want
in this room is Shepherd.
Now back off!
And you step away
from that table.
Please...
Shoot me.
Meredith...
You want justice, right?
Your wife died. I know what
happened. Derek told me the story.
Lexie Grey pulled the plug
on your wife, she's my sister.
Dr. Webber? He
was your wife's doctor.
I'm the closest thing
he has to a daughter.
The man on the
table, I'm his wife.
If you wanna hurt them
the way that you hurt...
shoot me.
- I'm your "eye for an eye."
- Meredith.
You tell Derek that I love
him and that I'm sorry.
Meredith...
Wait! She's pregnant.
You wouldn't shoot a
woman who's pregnant?
Please.
No! No!
- No! What?
- Raise your hands.
Trust me, raise your hands. He's
going to shoot again, raise your hands!
- I'm stopping!
- No!
- See? I've stopped.
- Listen to me.
In a few seconds, his heart is
going to pump blood into his chest
and stop beating.
You'll see it on the
monitor. Just wait. Wait for it.
Watch the monitor
and wait for it.
- Please, don't stop!
- Shut up!
No, no.
No! Derek!
No, no, no.
See? It's over.
It's over. He's dead.
It's over.
No!
Derek!
Give me a 4-0 pledgeted
suture. Jackson, get me his vitals.
Got a pulse of
128. BP's cycling.
Mer? Is Owen dead?
Dr. Grey! Is Owen dead?!
He's alive. He's alive. He's
unconscious, but he's alive.
Take Owen to the
OR across the way
and take that bullet
out. Get April to help.
- Cristina.
- I can't talk now.
I'm trying to save your guy, now
please go and try and save mine.
- Remind me to thank you later.
- I will.
I don't hurt anymore.
Pain's gone. That's
a bad sign, isn't it?
Yes.
Can you do something for me?
Can you find Reed?
When this is over,
can you find her?
I always...
I always had a crush on
her. I don't think she knows.
She knows. Girls always know.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
But can you tell her anyway?
Can you find her and
tell her I loved her?
I loved her so much.
OK.
And you tell her...
You tell her I was a catch.
You tell her I was
a hot, hot catch
and she missed
out on a great guy.
All right.
And you tell her I was brave.
Even if I turn coward
and start crying and asking
for my mom in a minute.
You lie and tell her
I died brave, OK?
You are very brave, Charles.
OK? I'm the coward.
I'm the one that told
that man I was a nurse.
You're smart.
You were smart. I
wish I was that smart.
Tell her I loved her,
you won't forget?
I won't forget.
- I know you don't like me.
- I like you.
No, you don't.
You were always my favorite
doctor, I thought you should...
It's not bad, I'm fine.
Hey! Stop! Stop moving!
Upper left shoulder.
Through and through.
You're gonna be fine.
That's what I've been
trying to tell you...
Don't think about trying
to get off this table.
We need to irrigate,
get antibiotics on board.
Doing work on the shoulder...
- Are you OK?
- Yeah, I'm OK.
Are you sure? Oh, my
God! Did you get shot?
No, I didn't get
shot, OK? I'm OK.
You could be in shock and
not know it. Let me feel...
I'm...
I'm OK.
There's blood spreading
down your thighs.
I'm...
I'm having a miscarriage.
We need a stapler, lidocaine,
morphine and irrigation trays.
Come on, are you gonna
help me or not? Let's go.
I've been looking for you.
You wanna know something funny?
Do you?
OK.
Five days ago,
when I bought this gun...
Did you know you could
buy a gun at a superstore?
They have a whole
section off of aisle eight.
A gun section.
Anyway, when I bought the gun...
I got all this ammunition.
Ammo.
I bought a whole bunch of it
'cause it was on sale.
And then this morning,
I was packing it into my coat,
I didn't have enough room
for all of it in my pockets...
because...
I wanted to bring my flask.
You mind?
I'm not much of a drinker...
but I figured I'd need
some liquid courage.
You want some?
No, thanks.
The funny part is,
I didn't need a drink until now.
Right now.
And the only reason I
need a drink is because...
I only have one bullet left.
I left bullets at home because
I thought I'd need a drink.
And the only reason I need a drink is
because I don't have enough bullets!
See, I was gonna kill you...
shoot you right in the face...
watch you suffer and die.
And then I was
gonna shoot myself.
But I only have one bullet left.
Then it seems you
have a bit of a problem.
I do.
I have one hell of a problem.
You sure you don't want a drink?
Vodka.
That's nice.
Hey.
What's it gonna be, Mr. Clark?
Me or you?
You shoot me,
SWAT's gonna get you.
And they're not gonna shoot you.
They're gonna capture
you and take you to prison.
You shoot yourself,
then you're free.
Done.
Maybe you get to
see your wife again.
So you have a choice to make.
Me or you?
A life in prison?
Or an afterlife with your wife?
- Screw you.
- I've lived.
I mean, I've
really, really lived.
I've failed, I've
been devastated.
I've been broken.
I've gone to hell and back.
And I've also known joy,
and passion.
And I've had a great love.
See, death for me,
is not justice.
It's the end of a
beautiful journey.
And I'm not afraid to die.
The question is...
are you?
A life in prison...
or an afterlife...
with your wife.
Me or you.
Your choice.
Yes or no.
In or out.
Up or down.
OK, I'm almost done, just
finishing up the pericardial repair.
- V-fib!
- Oh, no.
- Give me the internal paddles!
- Give me one of epi.
- April, you got it?
- Yep.
Charge to 50.
Clear!
- Bill?
- Mary?
Mary!
Are you OK?
What was the name again?
Tell me. Dr. Reed who?
Epi going in.
Charge again to 50.
Clear.
I'm gonna go see if kids
need help finding their parents.
People died.
People are dead.
I don't want to have kids if
it means I can't be with you.
No, no.
We'll have kids. We'll
have all kinds of kids.
And I always thought that I
wasn't cut out to be a mom, but...
you'll be a great mom,
you'll be an amazing mom.
And I love you so much,
and I can't live without
you and our ten kids...
- We got him.
- Oh!
We got him.
Live or die.
Hero or coward.
Fight or give in.
I'll say it again to
make sure you hear me:
The human life is
made up of choices.
Live or die.
That's the important choice.
- Mer!
- Huh?
Derek's asking for you.
OK.
And it's not always...
in our hands.