How much can you actually
accomplish in an hour?
Run an errand, maybe?
Sit in traffic.
Get an oil change.
When you think about
it, an hour isn't very long.
Sixty minutes.
Thirty-six hundred seconds.
That's it.
In medicine, though,
an hour is often everything.
We call it "the Golden Hour".
That magical window of time that
can determine whether a patient lives...
or dies.
Thank you, doctor.
Are you gonna help me at all, or
just sit there and eat potato chips?
I performed four back-to-back
fem-pop bypasses today.
This is the first chair
I've seen since 7am.
And this is the first food
I've had since yesterday.
I choose potato chips.
You might wanna get that.
Seattle Grace Mercy
West Emergency.
You brought this on yourself.
- You volunteered
to help run the ER.
- Got it.
We've got a suspected appy on a
ten-year-old. Let's page Robbins.
You know, I saw a need and I filled it,
like any good chief resident candidate.
Sadomasochistic chief
resident candidate, maybe.
What is up with you?
You're all perky and cheerful.
You know, it's
the fertility drugs.
We have stepped it up.
I'm pumped full of hormones.
- You know what's perky?
-
My boobs. They're huge. Am
I supposed to like big boobs?
Oh, God, no. They'll
make you fall over.
So...
Callie mentioned a thing.
Or it may not be a thing.
At least, I hope it
doesn't become a thing.
Hey, I got a patient with a
headache, better after sumatriptan.
He's ready to be discharged.
Just need you to sign off...
Is he neurologically
intact? You did a CT?
I did, it was negative. Most
interesting thing about this guy
is that he came into the
ER for a glorified migraine,
- with a girlfriend from hell.
- Which one is she?
Just point with your eyes.
Mmm-hm.
- Here.
- Thank you.
- So Callie had a thing...
- Yeah.
- What kind of thing?
- Grey, you paged?
Yeah, we have a suspected appy
on a ten-year-old, two minutes out.
- An unexpected thing.
- Grey, call up.
- Tell them to get an OR ready.
- I already did.
OR five is prepped
and ready for you.
Callie asked me to be
her baby's godmother.
Oh.
Well, you said no to that,
right? You gotta say no to that.
Um...
- EKG results.
- Thank you.
The guys at work overreacted
and insisted I come to the ER.
Sweetie, I had a big lunch. It
hardly qualifies as chest pain.
No, what I need are some
antacids. I'll be there, I promise.
Just tell Max to put on his
jersey. I'll be out of here soon.
Hi, I'm Dr. Grey. I'll
be your doctor today.
Oliver Richter. Sorry
about the phone.
I'm supposed to be picking up my
son for the Huskies game right now.
- I'm sure he'll understand.
- - You don't know my son.
Very few things more
important to him than basketball.
Big fan, huh? I'm just
gonna take a quick listen.
Biggest nine-year-old
fan you ever seen.
OK. So it says here that you've
been experiencing some chest pain.
- When did that start?
- An hour ago,
maybe two.
But I'm already
feeling much better.
You wouldn't just be saying
that to get discharged faster?
I got my son tickets to
this game for his birthday.
He's been marking off the
days on his calendar for weeks.
I can't be the
reason he misses it.
OK, well, your EKG looks normal,
and your heart sounds
good. But if there's one thing
we don't take lightly around
here, it's chest pain, so...
Could we go back and just
pretend I said heartburn?
- Would that get me
out any faster?
- No, probably not.
But Tyler is going to do
a portable chest X-ray,
and we're gonna do
a chest pain work-up.
And we will try to make it
as quick as possible, OK?
Thanks, Dr. Grey,
so much. Thanks.
So, this is gonna be a thing.
Why am I telling Callie no again?
While you're here, I need a
second opinion on this EKG.
- Do you see anything?
- No. Looks normal.
What are you doing here? I
thought you had the night off.
Yeah, I do. I'm not here.
What's Medical
Records' extension?
Looks like you're here
to me, which is good,
because we're
swamped. Take your pick:
impacted bowel, suspicious rash
- or a really smelly guy.
- Forget it. I only came in
because Medical Records called and
said I had to sign all my unsigned charts
or they would
suspend my privileges.
You're getting suspended? Dibs
on his solo splenectomy tomorrow.
I better be able to finish this
crap before the game tonight.
I told a patient yesterday
he didn't have cancer,
and he was so happy, he
gave me two floor seats.
You took a gift from a patient?
Did you tell him you
cured his cancer?
Oh. Colectomy time. I'm out.
Excuse me. Hi, I'm sorry.
We were told that somebody would be
by to set our son's leg. Nathan Englundar?
It was a while ago,
several hours, actually...
No, I know, you've been here a
while. I'm sorry. The problem is
we just don't have enough ORs
available for non-emergent cases.
An OR? Why would you need an OR?
Your pediatrician hasn't
been by to speak to you yet?
Your son has a broken
femur, which is a severe break.
It requires a full cast
on the broken leg
connected to a cast on the other leg to keep
everything still so the bones will heal properly.
Two full leg casts
on a four-year-old?
And because your son is so young,
we can't set the bones properly
- without putting him under.
- Under, meaning anesthesia?
And that requires an OR. I'm sorry. I
know you've been waiting a long time.
As soon as an OR
opens up, I'll let you know.
- Thank you. Thank you.
- OK.
The losers in Medical
Records aren't answering.
Are you sure you can't stay and
help out with some of this stuff?
Floor seats!
I understand what
you are suggesting.
I know it is done by many medical
professionals in this hospital.
But I am not a medical professional
who would ever consider...
Maybe you should consider it.
Eli Lloyd! Do not test me.
Maybe you should consider
the potential benefits.
All the intensely exciting,
toe-curling potential...
benefits.
Dr. Bailey.
OK. This is gonna be for a
prescription-strength migraine medicine.
Just don't take it with alcohol.
We're missing our anniversary
dinner because you have a headache.
A headache. Do you know how hard
it is to get reservations at this place?
I'm sorry, Gia. I am.
But it really hurts.
Hi, I'm Dr. Grey. I'll
be... Mrs. Webber?
- Hi, dear. How are you?
- I'm fine. How are you?
- Does the chief
know you're here?
- Please don't bother him.
I had a little fall, is all.
Got home from work,
slipped off the step ladder...
Ooh.
Landed on my wrist.
It's basically nothing.
- Well, it's not nothing.
- I brought lots of magazines
and a good novel, I am perfectly
fine waiting until you make time for me.
I know you have far
more pressing patients.
Well, you're the chief's wife. So that
makes you my most pressing patient.
- They opened the doors for us.
- Are you sure about that?
We'll be in and out. But I can't
believe you wouldn't let me drive.
You're drunker than I am. I can't
believe you tried to stiff the cabbie.
Wow, it is bright in here.
Hey, could somebody
do something about this?
You're a little early. I
thought our date was at 6:30.
I'm here now because a guy
just walked into the pit with a knife
- sticking out of his head.
- Sweet.
- I mean, poor guy.
- Is he stable?
- He's neurologically intact,
but...
- All right.
Well, I need to check on him sooner
than later. So, Avery, take him down to CT.
- Stay with him
until I get there.
- Will do.
OK. So you'll be down to see
knife guy when you're done?
- I will.
- And then we'll have our date?
- Wouldn't miss it.
- 6:30. Don't forget.
How'd this guy get
a knife in his head?
Apparently, there was a
brawl at a tailgate party.
So you know how stupid
guys get... Dr. Bailey!
I'm taking a nap!
I'm sorry.
What I mean to say is,
I'm going to use this room
to take a nap. Because that's
what people do in these rooms.
When they are tired.
'Cause I have a child
and a full-time job and work
long hours, so I am just tired.
Just very, very tired.
- OK.
I was just gonna ask you,
had you seen Dr. Altman?
No! I have not seen Dr. Altman.
Nor any other doctors or nurses.
Because I will be in this room.
Asleep. By myself.
Actually, I see her
now. Dr. Altman!
I'm... I'm...
Dr. Altman, do you have
time for a quick consult?
I was supposed to be
off by six, but... OK. Sure.
- Just walk with me.
- OK, so...
Damn it, he's early. Um...
Just, Grey, gimme a second.
- Hi. William.
- Hey.
- It's, it's nice to see you.
- Wow. You look amazing.
- Oh.
- And so official.
I mean, I knew you
were a doctor, but you...
- are a doctor.
- Sorry, I didn't have time to
change.
- I'm just...
- No, the scrubs
are strangely sexy.
Thanks. You know, I have
a few things to wrap up.
Do you mind hanging out for
a few minutes? Like ten, tops.
Yeah, no problem. Take your
time. I'll just grab a seat here.
Hey, stranger.
Henry! I didn't... I didn't
know that you were here today.
Yeah. They wanted to run
a blood glucose test on me.
So they gave me this nasty,
orange Kool-Aid to drink.
In about an hour, I gotta go
give 'em some blood. Or pee.
And we really don't need
to talk about my bodily fluids.
- Sorry to be rude. Hi.
- Hey.
Oh, sorry. Yeah... William,
Henry. Henry, William.
- Are you a patient of Teddy's?
- Something like that.
Anyway, I gotta
go, but I'll be back.
Soon. Promise.
- All right, Grey,
what do you got?
- OK, 42-year-old male,
complaining of midsternal chest
pain. No cardiac risk factors, no angina,
pain doesn't radiate.
The EKG looks clean.
These are his films.
They're mostly clear, but...
I don't know. Does the
mediastinum look a little wide to you?
Because I know sometimes that
can happen with a portable X-ray.
- You got cardiac enzymes?
- Yes.
- Hey, Kepner!
- Yeah?
How good are you
at forging signatures?
Even if I were good at forging
signatures, I wouldn't do it.
It's unethical and probably
illegal, so I'm sorry,
you're just gonna have to finish
signing your charts on your own.
I'll check on Mr. Richter
right now. Call Radiology.
Get him in for a PA and lateral
films, and tell them to rush it,
'cause I would really like to get
out of here and go on my date.
I mean, did you see that guy?
No forging signatures, Karev!
- Radiology, please.
- Forgery? Why am I not
surprised?
Whatever. I just wanna get out of
here so I can get to this game tonight.
Wait, you have tickets?
Tonight? It's the
PAC-10 title game.
- Yeah, I know.
- Win this and the Huskies get
an automatic bid
to March Madness.
Why do you think
I'm powering through
all these stupid charts.
Hey, what are you doing?
Of my ten patients in labor right now,
none of them are past three centimeters,
which means I have some time to
kill, and you can't miss this game.
- Hand me a pen.
- I thought you
thought I was a loser.
You're a little less loser-y now
I know you like college hoops.
Hey. Where's the knife guy? Is
it true he's walking and talking?
- What about your colectomy?
- Ah, postponed.
The wife snuck him a cheeseburger
and fries before surgery.
So this thing with Callie.
I mean, you know
it's a bad idea, right?
You don't want to be
Callie's baby's godmother.
- I don't?
- No!
Think of how many people have to
die before you even get to step up.
Mark, Callie and Arizona.
- That's a lot of people.
- It is. Yes.
- A lot of dead people.
- Right!
Whereas, if you were my
baby's godmother-in-waiting,
it's only me and Derek. One
wrong turn down a dark, twisty road,
boom, you're in.
OK, let's be clear. If I am ever
a godparent to anyone's kid,
it will be in name only. I will
not be taking care of children.
That's what boarding schools are
for. Which way to Butcher Block?
- Trauma two.
- - Feels like a roller, dude.
- I've never seen...
- I understand you might be thirsty,
but I'm sorry, you
cannot drink beer in here.
- You're wasting it!
- Cool.
Oliver, did you see Dr. Altman?
She's sending me
off for another X-ray.
I know you guys have
to cover all your bases...
I know, I'm sorry. But I
put a rush on the X-ray,
- so hopefully it'll be quick. OK?
- Grey!
Excuse me.
I was finishing a
surgery just now,
when a scrub nurse asked
me how my wife was feeling.
Because she'd heard Adele
was in the ER, and I hadn't.
Would you like to explain to me
why I found out my wife was a patient
in this hospital from my
scrub nurse and not from you?
Richard, hush. Let
Meredith do her job.
She hasn't even had a
chance to examine me yet.
- Is that true?
- Don't mind him, dear.
He's just worried about me.
He gets gruff when he's worried.
I hurt my wrist.
I was trying to get out
the holiday decorations
and I, ooh, I slipped off
the step ladder. Stupid.
I should have waited for Richard to
get home. He's so much taller than me.
I requested an X-ray
and an ortho consult.
I will call and make sure that
they're coming down, but I...
Don't touch that!
- I think I better
go see what that is.
- You better.
Is everything all right?
- Yes.
- No.
I was just showing these guys
how, when I scrunch up my eyebrows,
- the knife moves, see?
- Oh, my God!
- Don't do that!
- Stop!
- Stop moving the knife!
- OK, OK!
You guys shoulda seen the brawl.
Stew-ball kicked that other guy's ass!
And now Stew-ball
has a knife in his head.
OK, let's focus. Stewart,
how much is 14 plus four?
- Eighteen.
- Twenty-seven minus 13?
- Fifteen?
- No. One seventy-two minus 60?
I have no idea, but it's
not because of the knife.
- It's just 'cause I'm so drunk.
- No, actually,
- it's just 'cause he's dumb.
- Thanks, David. Really?!
Unbelievable. His mental
status is completely intact,
if you don't account
for his math skills.
It's like the knife
did no damage at all.
So why don't you
just pull the thing out?
- We've got a games to gets to!
- I'll drink to that!
- No! No beer!
- Buzz kill.
- Uh-oh! Hey!
- No!
How many do you have?
OK. Oliver's in X-ray, Stewart
is stable and waiting for Derek,
who should be here soon.
Adele is waiting on Ortho.
And can I get the discharges
from the last hour, please?
Oh, and the boy in bed seven with
the broken leg, Nathan Englundar.
Let's check on the status
of the OR for him, please.
Is this Lexie's patient
with the headache?
- Yeah.
- Mitch Turner?
- How long ago was he
discharged?
- Not long, a few minutes ago.
Did he leave? Did
he already leave?
Mr. Turner! Mr. Turner, I need
you to try to smile for me, please?
- Who the hell are you?
- I need you to try
to smile for me.
Can you lift your arms
above your head like this?
Dr. Grey, is
everything all right?
No, it's not. We got a code CVA.
Let's get a stretcher out here
stat! Can you repeat after me?
"The dog chased after the cat."
The... The dog
chase... chased after...
What's going on?
What's happening to him?
- I need you to help me.
- What's happening to him?!
We need to get
him on the ground.
The dog ch...
OK. Get your purse under
his head quickly, please,
and help me secure
his arm. Hold it like this.
- OK, but why are we doing this?
- Because he's having a stroke.
Unsteady gait, slurred
speech, asymmetric smile.
Symptoms started no
more than 20 minutes ago.
So we should be well
within the golden hour.
I know, a stroke.
Right in front of me.
What if he'd been driving me
in the car when it happened?
- Hang on, here's the doctor.
- Hi. So the stroke team
is taking him up to CT.
We're gonna see if he's eligible
for the clot-busting medicine. We caught
the stroke early, which is very good.
So, on a scale of one to ten,
ten being I might have to cancel
our Aspen trip in a week, how is he?
You should cancel the trip.
You will not believe this.
Looks like the blade
landed in the maxillary sinus.
Chances are the knife itself is
tamponading any major bleeding.
Probably best just to go
ahead and open up the cranium.
Or we could just take him to
the OR and pull this thing out.
Really, Avery? Just pull it out?
Let me guess. You wanna get out of here early
to go to the game just like everyone else.
Or, since it looks like the blade
didn't hit any major arteries or veins,
he knows that a controlled
extraction would be both safer
and less invasive than
a complete craniotomy.
Is that true, Avery? That why you
suggest we pull it out of his head?
Yeah. And I want to get out of
here early to get to the game.
Me, too. I'm good with that.
Let's just do what he said.
Lexie, I need to speak with you.
Thank you for getting
me out of that room.
I swear, it takes everything just to
be civil to Mark lately. Such an ass.
- What's up?
- Take a look at this. Look closely.
What do you see?
This is the patient's admitting
signature when he came in.
And this is his signature
when he was discharged.
- Oh, no.
- Mitch Turner,
the patient you just
discharged, is up in Radiology
- being treated for a stroke.
- Oh, God.
I know you know the signs of a
stroke. How did you miss this?
Are you distracted by
the Mark thing? Is that it?
No! I checked the CT.
He was having a classic
migraine, he's had them before.
There's no way that he was
having a stroke when I treated him.
Lexie, I know you know. This kind of
headache can be a precursor to a stroke.
When you said you
needed an Ortho consult,
you could have mentioned
it was the chief's wife, Grey.
I would have been down
here a hell of a lot sooner.
I am so sorry to keep you waiting,
Mrs. Webber. You hurt your wrist in a fall?
It was so silly. I'd
just gotten home
and I was trying to get some... Oh!
Reach something on the top shelf.
- I just landed wrong.
- Her wrist absorbed
all the impact.
It looks painful. We'll get you some
more pain meds to help with that.
Your X-ray shows a hairline fracture.
So it could have been a lot worse.
We'll splint you up and get
you out of here in no time, OK?
You have me paged if
you need anything, OK?
OK.
Thank you for covering
for me before with the chief.
- You didn't have to do that.
- Excuse me?
When you said I hadn't
been by to examine you yet.
So you said that you fell
- when you got home... from work.
- Yes, yes, that's right.
Do you remember hitting
your head when you fell?
- Not that I recall.
- Dr. Grey?
I have the new X-rays
for Oliver Richter.
- OK. Let's get Mrs. Webber
a head CT.
- OK.
Oh, damn it. Excuse me.
- Hey.
- Sorry to make you wait.
- No. No problem.
Really, Henry here's
been keeping me company.
Although, he's probably
sick of me by now.
I've been grilling him
about the major leagues.
You didn't mention he
used to play pro ball.
I... I didn't know that he did.
It's not a big deal, really.
Although there is a
baseball card out there
with my face on it somewhere.
I don't mean to hold you guys up.
You probably have a reservation waiting.
Excuse me, Dr. Altman.
Mr. Richter, mediastinum looks
borderline on the PA films. Take a look.
OK, um...
That reservation may have to
wait just a little bit longer. I'm sorry.
- If you want to reschedule...
- No! Nonsense. I'm happy to wait.
You are saving lives.
The least I can do is take you
out to dinner when you're done.
Thank you.
Did you ever pitch
against Jeff Bagwell?
Once. And it wasn't pretty.
You were right. Get a CT to be safe.
I'll stick around to look the results.
At least somebody's
having a good night.
- Tell me.
- No, I can't possibly.
Good news?
Or not such good news.
Oliver, your second
X-ray is still concerning.
Dr. Altman and I agree that you should
have a CT to rule out anything serious.
And how long will that take?
Ah, that's my son calling.
He's worried we'll miss tip-off.
What should I tell him? Do I need to
tell him we're gonna miss this game?
I wish I had an answer for you,
but I think it's a safe bet you'll be late.
Max, hey buddy. How's
my little man doing?
Oh, Daddy'll be fine. Don't
you worry. Don't worry.
You just worry about all that
popcorn we're gonna be eating.
Make sure he's on broad spectrum
antibiotics. You booked an OR?
Wow. It didn't hit any
brain matter at all?
Doesn't look like it from this.
How long till Shepherd gets
down here to take a look?
He should be out of
surgery any minute.
Good.
The longer that
thing stays in there,
the higher the risk of infection
or abscess formation.
Ow!
So now can we get out of here?
How is he, Grey?
Pupils are equal and
reactive, he's alert and awake.
Can I get some more
gauze for this wound, please?
- Reflexes seem normal.
- Gimme that.
I'm fine. It's just a
little headache is all.
I've had hangovers
worse than this.
What's the status on the blade?
Well, about that...
Yeah, there is no blade anymore.
What happened? Sir, just lay
back. Let me examine you, OK?
Can you get a doctor, please?
I wanna look at the CTs.
- It's gonna be OK, Nathan.
- He's really hurting.
OK. I'm gonna write an
order for more pain meds.
It's OK, monkey. I know
you wanna go home.
It'll just be a little
while longer, OK?
It will be just a
little longer, right?
- Tyler, where is
the OR for Nathan?
- I haven't heard back yet.
OK, well, let's call them again,
and let's call the Ortho team
and make sure they're
ready to go. OK?
We will get to Nathan as
soon as possible, I promise.
- How's he doing?
- The blade went
through his skull,
didn't hit any major nerves
or arteries. He's gonna be fine.
- Flesh wound?
- Yeah.
That's the luckiest guy alive.
You're also pretty lucky, too.
It's past 6:30, and we
haven't had our date yet.
I'm swamped. I can't leave.
I have one patient in CT,
another one waiting for an OR.
- Your patient's CT
isn't ready yet.
- No.
And the OR you're
waiting for isn't either.
So OK, I mean, maybe I do,
right at this precise moment,
- have one minute,
but it's a minute.
- That's perfect.
That's all I need. Just a
minute. I need a minute.
Hey.
- Wha..?
- Oh, sorry!
- What?!
- No one. It was nothing. That room is occupied.
Never ask me what I might have
seen or might not have seen in there.
OK, well, if we can't go in
there, where are we gonna go?
I have an idea.
- Where are we going?
- Nowhere. We're gonna do it here.
- We...? No, we're not!
- Come on.
No! No way! Are you kidding me?
Drop your pants.
Come on, I'll be
quick. I'll be in and out.
Oh, my God! Eyes up here!
- Seriously, are you kidding me?
- I'm serious about this. Where
is your sense of adventure?
My sense of adventure
is down on the first floor.
- It's not in this elevator.
- Come on.
If not for me, then do it for
your future baby. Come on.
- Turn around.
- I cannot believe
I am doing this.
This future, imaginary baby
of ours better be worth it.
OK, here we go.
- Oh, there it is.
- Ouch.
Ooh. There. I told
you I'd be quick.
I can't wait to meet our
future, fictitious baby.
Me either.
We got through those charts
fast. Floor seats, here I come.
So I just helped you get
through three dozen charts
in a fraction of the time it would
have taken you to do on your own,
basically ensuring you get
to your floor seats on time.
How long do I have to wait till you
ask me to go to the game with you?
Oh...
I mean, I was supposed to
take Avery, but screw him.
Sure. You wanna go?
No, I'm on call
tonight, actually.
I just wanted to see if I
could get you to ask me out.
Excuse me.
- Just admit it. You like her.
- Shut up.
I don't think you do
understand, actually.
This has been going
on since yesterday.
We took our son to an after-hours
clinic, where he was misdiagnosed
and then he was sent home without so much
as a painkiller. He was up all night crying.
This morning, our
pediatrician sent us here
and now we've been waiting around
all day with our four-year-old son.
Believe me, I understand a kid with
a broken leg doesn't take precedence
over a guy with a knife in
his head, but my son is scared.
And he is in pain. So could somebody
please just get to his leg already?
- Please.
- Yes, sir.
You still haven't helped that kid
yet? He's four with a femur fracture.
- You know how much that hurts?
- I know, it's just one of those
days.
- Tyler, isn't that OR
ready yet?
- They're prepping it now.
Grey! My wife was
cleared by Dr. Torres.
You ordered a head
CT for a broken wrist?
- I can explain. I have some...
- Dr. Grey, they're calling
from CT.
- Your patient
is coding in the scanner.
- What?!
They say he's coding!
Hold CPR!
V-fib! Page Altman!
Give me the paddles
now! Charge to 200!
Clear!
Charge to 300! Clear!
- Got a pulse!
- Yes!
- Scans are up!
- Grey, talk to me.
He was coding when I got here.
I defibrillated him three times,
I gave him three rounds of epi,
two of atropine, I loaded
him up with amiodarone.
But he's tachycardic now,
he's barely hanging on.
- He needs surgery. Book an OR.
- OK.
- I'll get a room
prepped and ready.
- No time.
His aorta is dissecting
as we speak.
- He needs surgery right now.
- They're saying all the ORs
are booked.
Well, tell them to bump someone
because we're coming up either way.
I have an OR. Tell them to bump
mine and prep it for an emergency cardio.
All right, here
we go. Got it? Go.
All right, let's clear it.
Let's hold that elevator!
- Come on, come on, come on!
- Once these doors open,
we're gonna have to get him in the
OR and open him as soon as possible.
- I know.
- Even then,
if that aorta tears, we
may already be too late.
- We're not gonna
have time to scrub.
- I know, I know.
Thanks.
Just pour the betadine
straight onto the chest.
It doesn't need to be pretty.
We need to get in there.
All right, plug me in.
Scalpel.
Cautery.
Cauterizing now. Get in there
quickly, Grey. Time is myocardium.
All right, saw.
Get that retractor ready.
This guy thought he had
a bad case of heartburn.
He went from that to this
in less than 45 minutes.
That's how these work.
How's his pressure?
Seventies, and dropping.
Retractor! Every beat of his
heart rips this tear a little bit wider.
All right.
How many of these
ruptured dissections
have you caught
in time to operate?
Forty, maybe 50.
How many have you
been able to save?
Three.
All right, I'm in.
- Oh, no, no, no, no!
- Damn it!
He's bleeding out!
His aorta's wide open. Clamp!
Come on, come on, come on!
All right, Grey, let's
try sucker bypass.
OK.
Cannulas!
It's not working.
There's too much blood.
Once we get him on bypass,
it'll be easier to control.
Heart's fibrillating!
All right, cardiac massage!
- Paddles!
- I've almost got him
cannulated.
Charge to ten.
Clear!
Damn it. He's bleeding
out of his nose and ears!
I've been loading him up
with blood, FFP and Factor VII,
- but I can't keep up
with the losses.
- Foley's full of blood, too.
DIC. His cannula
sites are oozing.
Let's push three of epi.
Set me up for another shock.
Clear!
- Damn it!
- Well, what can we do?
- Just tell me what to do.
- Nothing. His aorta is in shreds.
- Well, what about...?
- There is nothing left to do. Call it.
- Call it, Grey.
- No...
Grey, we got here too late. These
are almost impossible to catch.
There's nothing that
we can do. I'm sorry.
We need to call it.
Time of death, 18:52.
Hey. I heard you lost a patient.
You know, it's not that I
don't want to share you.
I mean, I don't want to share
you, but that's not the reason
I don't want you to be
Callie's baby's godmother.
Oh...
OK.
It just seems like if you agree
to be Callie's baby's godmother,
you're saying that I'll never
have a baby of my own.
Meredith, you know I am
in no way saying anything...
I know. It just feels that way.
OK.
Well, I...
have to go have a really
uncomfortable conversation with Callie.
How about you?
What are you up to?
I have to go contact
Oliver's family.
Oh, hey, wait. You've got...
blood or something.
All right.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Hey, chief.
- About earlier...
- It's all taken care of.
I checked Adele's head
CT myself. It was clean.
Her wrist is in a splint, and
I'm taking her home now.
I still have some concerns.
And if her CT was clean,
- then I have
even more concerns...
- Thank you, Meredith,
but I assure you, Adele is fine.
Chief, she's been getting
things very confused.
Meredith, she is fine. And
I'm taking her home right now.
Why was she getting Christmas
decorations down in February?
- Good night, Meredith.
- She said she'd just
gotten home from
work. Didn't she retire?
- Meredith...
- Chief, something isn't right.
OK, that's enough. I know
what you are implying,
and while I appreciate
your concern, that's enough!
Adele had a scare
today. She had a fall.
Any number of things could account
for her mixing up a couple of details,
not the least of which is
her being interrogated by you!
If something bigger were wrong
with my wife, I would know it.
You've got Alzheimer's
on the brain.
You buy a car, you start
seeing it everywhere you look.
You've been working on this
Alzheimer's trial 24/7, I get it.
But Adele is not
your mother, Meredith.
She's my wife.
Now, good night.
Hi. I am so sorry,
I got pulled into an
emergency surgery.
- Where is Nathan?
- Actually, a doctor
came by to get him
a little bit ago. He's getting
his casts put on right now.
Great. That's great news.
Dr. Grey, we have a surgical
abdomen in bed three...
- Let's just get
Oliver Richter's chart.
- OK.
Hello?
Hi, Max.
This... No, it's
your daddy's doctor.
Is your mom around?
An hour.
One hour...
can change everything.
Forever.
We'll have to keep you
overnight for observation,
- but your prognosis
is very good.
- Great!
So maybe we don't have to
cancel our Aspen trip after all.
- I just had a stroke.
- I know.
And you're worried
about our travel plans?
It's a non-refundable trip.
Cancel the trip.
You know what? In
fact, cancel all our trips.
How have I put up
with you for two years?
I am done with this.
We're done. Get out of here.
Now, before you give
me another stroke.
Wait, wait.
Can I see your keys?
OK...
Here.
OK. Now you can go.
An hour can save your life.
So before he gets off the phone, and
since I now have to go pee in a cup,
I just have to say this.
I basically spent the past hour
on a first date
with William myself,
and I don't know how much
you know about the guy,
but this is what I know.
He wears driving gloves.
Yeah, and he doesn't
live with his mother,
but until recently, he
lived above her house.
And he used the word "shan't",
and he wasn't being funny.
And he's yet to tell me a story about
himself in which he is not the hero.
So, as your husband, I
think we can do better.
Good news. Not only was I
able to push the reservation,
but I also got us a table by the
window. Black truffle gnocchi awaits.
- Ready?
- Ready.
An hour can change your mind.
OK. So when's your next break?
OK, uh-uh, no...
This will never
happen again at work.
- Understood?
- Sure.
OK.
Until your next break.
Sometimes an hour is just a gift
we give ourselves.
All right, Stewart,
you're choosing to leave
against medical advice,
so you're free to go,
but this is my number.
If you experience any of the
neurological symptoms on this sheet,
you call me. Somebody
should stay with you tonight,
and have plenty
of fluids. Not beer!
- Not beer.
- Will do, doc.
- Thanks, doc.
- All right.
For some, an hour can
mean almost nothing.
I can't believe he walked
in with a knife in his head,
and is walking out an hour
later to go to a ball game.
Speaking of which, any chance
you wanna go to the game, too?
Apparently, Karev
didn't want his floor seats.
So you interested?
Actually, yes. Yes, I am.
For others,
an hour makes all the
difference in the world.
Now, Nathan, when you wake up, you're
gonna have two big casts on your legs.
But that's a good thing, because it
means it's gonna make your leg better, OK?
But right now, I have a very
important question for you.
And that is, what is
your favorite color?
Blue.
Blue it is, then.
Let's prep the blue
casting material, please.
All right, I'm gonna take this
mask, Nathan. I'm gonna lower it.
And you have to count...
But in the end...
it's still just an hour.
One of many.
Many more to come.
Sixty minutes.
Thirty-six hundred seconds.
That's it.
Then it starts all over again.
Hi. I'm Dr. Grey. I'll
be your doctor today.
It says here you've been
experiencing some abdominal pain.
When did that start?
And who knows what
the next hour might hold?