♪ The wheels on the
bus Go round and round ♪
♪ All over town ♪
♪ The door... ♪
♪ The doors on the
bus Go open and shut ♪
♪ Open and shut Open and shut ♪
♪ The doors on the
bus go Open and shut ♪
♪ All over to... ♪
Hey. Reece woke up early.
I'll go make breakfast.
Hey, no, no, no. I got it.
Why don't you go back
to bed? There's no point.
Do you want something
to help you sleep?
No, no, no, no.
Walt still asleep? Mm-hm.
Thought I'd come home
early from the hospital
and help with dinner.
Thought you were
going to Cleo's.
I don't have to.
I'm not making a big
Thanksgiving dinner.
Please go. Have
Thanksgiving over there.
Jackie, I'd rather be here.
Please, go.
Hey.
Have you seen the Tylenol?
Uh, I took the last two.
Did you put it on the list?
Uh, no.
That neck still bothering you?
I know. No more hockey games.
There you go.
Greene's eggs and ham.
I'm sorry, Mark.
I'm just not hungry.
Well, I hope you have
an appetite tonight
'cause I am gonna
be grilling filet mignon,
and baking potatoes.
On Thanksgiving? No
turkey? No cranberries?
No, we did that last year.
What? No yams? No pumpkin pie?
Pumpkin pie, yes.
Whoever it is,
don't buy anything.
Dr. Elizabeth Corday? Uh, yes.
Happy Thanksgiving.
What is it?
Some sort of letter.
It says, "Notice
to the defendant..."
Oh, my God.
I'm being sued for malpractice.
I'll keep taking my medication.
I... I won't be a burden.
Come on. At least let me
stay through the weekend.
I can't go back. I lost my
job at the department store.
Your brother's not
even talking to me.
You can't throw me
out. I'm your mother.
I put the bus ticket and
some money in your purse.
And you'll have to find a
job as soon as you get there.
I've been here for a week.
I know how hard
things are for you.
I know what you're
going through.
We've been through this.
I just want to be here for you.
I have to go. Excuse me.
Honey, please.
Here. Take my coat.
Okay?
I love you.
Morning, guys.
Hey.
Good morning.
You're getting pretty
good at that, huh?
I've been practicing.
Are we still on for tonight?
Yeah. Actually, I'm looking
forward to meeting your parents.
You'll like them.
Their flight get in okay?
Picked them up this morning.
Hope you don't mind
going out to my cousin's.
No. No.
How's Jackie?
She's okay with you
not being home tonight?
Ah. She doesn't want me around.
Mm. I'm sorry.
I, uh, gotta get
him up to Daycare.
Chen and Carter are late.
It's pouring outside.
You know, when I was a resident,
I left early during
inclement weather.
Whoo. Boy, it's
a mess out there!
Finally. Sorry I'm late.
John, got a drunk with
a hand lac in Sutures.
Chen, a breast abscess in 4.
If you need an
Attending, Kovac is here.
Greene is due in an hour.
Happy Thanksgiving.
Taking Mr. Morgan
up? He's a bit anxious.
They were gonna
murder Bernadine.
He's delusional.
Threatened to blow
up his neighbor's house.
Did you do something
with your hair?
Oh, no. Not really.
You look different somehow.
Contacts. I broke my glasses.
Oh, suits you. Thank you.
Abby.
How's your mother doing?
Better. She left for
Florida this morning.
I'm really sorry about what
happened the other day.
Don't apologize.
She has a disease.
Nothing to be ashamed of.
Hi. Hey.
Did you put her on the bus?
Yep.
Uh, are you free...?
Would you like to go...?
Dinner?
Think anything'll be open?
I think Doc Magoo's.
I think that's kinda
depressing on Thanksgiving.
I could cook at my place.
Rescue's pulling up. A
guy got hit riding his bike.
Call her! She's waiting for me!
30-year-old. Bicycle
versus minivan.
Bent the bike and
pinned him against a pole.
Vitals? BP's 100/60.
Gave him two liters.
Cut off as much of
the bike as we could,
but his leg started bleeding.
I can get it. Four-by-fours.
Looks like the femoral artery.
Abby? Abby?
Abby. What are you doing here?
Come on, Abby!
Okay, let's go! Let's go!
Get four units of O-neg.
I need a thigh cuff
and a Doppler scope.
Ask for dry clothes at the desk
and wait. I tried
to get on the bus.
I can't leave you, Abby.
Pulse is 124 and thready.
Abby? Set me up
for a central line...
Slow down, damn it!
Oh! Oh! Oh!
Set me up for a central line,
and prime the rapid infuser.
We need X-ray to clear the neck.
I'll get the Foley.
Call Maintenance for a hacksaw.
Here we go. On my count.
One, two, three.
Want a second line?
Yes. Set a trauma panel,
and type and cross for six.
Ugh. That smarts
like a son of a bitch.
I gave you
lidocaine, Mr. Florea.
It should be pretty numb.
I can give you some more.
Yeah, please.
It hurts like hell.
So does my knee.
What's the matter
with your knee?
I twisted it when
I fell off the curb.
Dropped my turkey. Cut my hand.
You cut yourself on a turkey?
Wild Turkey. Wild Turkey.
I was drinking it on
account of it's Thanksgiving.
Don't think the Pilgrims
envisioned the liquid kind
when they
established the holiday.
How about something for my pain?
What would you like this
time? Percocet or Demerol?
I'm allergic to Percocet.
This is Mr. Florea's
third time in here
this week complaining of pain.
Really? Oh, I see.
I didn't realize it
was that serious.
In that case, I'll refer you to
a clinic to help you manage it.
I don't need no damn clinic. I
need something for my knee.
Well, we'll get you some x-rays.
Then I'll give you some Motrin.
You think I'm an addict?
I think you have a problem
with drug dependency.
What do you know about my pain?
Ooh, I'll be back
in a couple minutes.
You want to finish him up?
Sure.
Randi? Randi, excuse me.
Do you have a bag I could
put these wet things in?
Did they just bring in a
man from a bike accident?
You'll have to sit in
Chairs. I'll be right back.
He's in the Trauma Room.
Where is that?
Well, I'll show
you. Right this way.
I saw them bring him in.
Was he badly hurt?
I know they're doing absolutely
everything they can for him.
I got two units
of type-specific.
Okay. Neck is clear.
Pulse ox is down to 88.
Okay, bag him while
we set up for intubation.
Twenty of etomidate, 100 of sux.
Got a quart of melted
strawberry ice cream.
His name is Jim Peakins.
He is relaxed.
Take off the collar.
Abby, give me some
cricoid pressure.
Whoa! Big neck lac.
It's hard to see the cords.
Direct your
pressure to the right.
How's that?
Better. Looks like a foreign
body down there. McGills.
Sats are 82 and falling.
Hold on.
There.
Holy crap, you pulled my gauze
right through his neck wound.
Open up some lap pads.
I'm in. Bag him.
Abby, call for a vent.
Sats are still low.
Decreased breath
sounds to the right.
Chest-tube tray.
Okay, start chest compressions.
We're out. I'll get one.
Clear. Clear.
What are you doing here?
The gentleman's wife showed up,
and there was
no one to help her.
I'm not his wife. I hit
him. It was an accident.
I didn't even see him.
Randi, can you sit this woman
down in the hall, please?
Is he gonna be all right?
Ma'am, ma'am, this way.
Abby. Abby, I need
to talk with you.
Not now. It's important.
I'm not going anywhere,
Abby. I'm staying here.
No good deed goes unpunished.
I step in, I clean up your mess,
and I end up named
in your lawsuit.
I'm so sorry.
Yeah, well, sorry isn't
gonna save your ass, or mine.
I take full responsibility
for what happened.
How noble of you.
The guy's a gimp. He walks
in with a little bit of a backache.
He'll be wheeled
out in a wheelchair.
Do you have any idea
how that'll play for a jury?
Not well. Not well?
When his lawyers get
through, you'll be lucky
if you're slinging fish
and chips back in England.
Robert, I thought the
procedure had gone smoothly.
Oh, well, it was a
screaming success
if your desired
outcome was paralysis.
I'll talk to Risk Management
so you're not implicated.
Rocket, are you almost through?
One minute, love.
Do not talk to Risk Management.
Do not discuss this case
with anyone. Am I clear?
Yes.
Surfer.
Couldn't be just some
fat-assed couch potato, no.
And don't even think about
paging me during the weekend.
Ready, Nikki?
Let's go.
Still in V-fib. How
long has it been?
Twenty-five minutes.
Two liters out
of the chest tube.
Okay. Shock once
more, and then we'll call it.
How about a thoracotomy?
Not with blunt trauma.
Charged.
Clear.
Asystole.
Okay, that's it.
Time of death, 10:57.
Any family here?
No. Just the woman who hit
him. She's waiting out in the hall.
Ma'am? Yes?
The man on the bicycle
was, uh, profoundly injured.
We did everything we could,
but he didn't respond
to the treatment.
Oh, God.
He died a few minutes ago.
My baby was crying and I
turned around. I didn't see him.
I'm sorry.
Sweetie, it's all right. It's
all right. It wasn't your fault.
I didn't see him.
It was raining.
It wasn't your fault.
It's gonna be all right.
My God!
It's all right.
You didn't see him. Oh, my God.
It was raining.
You didn't see him.
I thought you quit. I did.
Then my mother showed up.
Is she going back? Yeah.
Think it'll ever stop?
What?
The rain.
Has to stop eventually.
I hope so.
I'm telling you, my knee
still hurts like a son of a bitch.
Yeah, that's why you're
going to X-ray, Mr. Florea.
Hey, Conni, can you take him up?
Call Transport.
They're short-staffed.
I'm suffering.
Stop torturing me.
Yeah, yeah. Catch you later
when you get back with your films.
Excuse me. I'm looking for
Dr. Chen. Is she working today?
She's with a patient.
Just take a seat in Chairs.
Thanks.
Hello. Hi.
Do you work here?
Oh, n... Oh, these? No,
I got caught in the rain.
Oh. My daughter works here.
Ah, so does mine.
Really? Mm-hm. Jing-Mei Chen.
Oh, the cute one. Pregnant.
What? Ah, ha.
You must be thrilled.
I tell you, I would be so
excited if one of my children
made me a grandmother.
Actually, I don't think
of myself as old enough
to be a grandmother.
But I am.
You must be thinking
of someone else.
Jing-Mei!
Mommy. Ji... Jing-Mei...
Oh, my God!
What are you doing here?
I wanted to invite you
for Thanksgiving dinner.
Why didn't you tell us?
Because I didn't know how.
Come home tonight.
Is everyone coming?
Yes.
No, Mommy. Not with all
those people there. Please.
They're your family. I can't.
Please? No, I just can't.
No, please! I need
a hand in Exam 1.
I gotta go. Don't tell Ba-Ba.
We miss you. I know.
You looked like you
needed some help.
Ooh. Thank you,
Carter. No problem.
Did you page me? I've
got an appy in 10 minutes.
Old patient of yours
is here. Debby Marlin.
You operated on her
last year for breast cancer.
What's she doing back?
She's in terrible pain.
Mets to the spine.
Ah. Thought you'd like to know.
All right.
Hi, Dr. Benton. Hey.
How are you doing?
Terrible. I went to my
pharmacy this morning.
They told me they couldn't
refill my morphine prescription.
Why not?
Well, they don't carry narcotics
anymore. Too many robberies.
I gave her a shot of morphine
but it's barely
taken the edge off.
All right. Come on. Let me
see. How much did you give her?
Ten.
You contacted your oncologist?
Mm-hm. I just got the service.
He's away for the
holiday weekend.
All right. Come on. All
right. Give her another 10.
If she's feeling better, send
her home with Percocet.
You mean I have to
come all the way back here
tomorrow for my medicine?
I'm sorry, but the outpatient
pharmacy's closed today.
Can we admit her
for pain control?
Yeah. Yeah, all right.
Let's admit her to Medicine.
Thank you, Dr. Benton.
You're welcome.
The little weasel warned
me not to speak to anyone.
Are you gonna listen?
Do I have a choice?
You're being sued.
You must respond.
Romano insisted he'd handle it.
Yeah, sure. Cover his ass,
and hang you out to dry.
Let me talk to my buddy Dave
Medler. He's in Risk Management.
Off the record.
See what he thinks.
Thanks.
You look tired. So do you.
I shouldn't be
dragging you into this.
We're getting married, okay?
Your problems are my problems.
Mark, Ortho's waiting in 2.
See you later.
♪ It's now or never ♪
♪ Come hold me tight ♪
♪ Kiss me my darling ♪
What's the score? Texas up by 6.
I see Judy's back for
a return engagement.
Elvis' greatest hits. Conni's
serving turkey in the lounge.
I'll wait for dinner. Is there
any ETA yet on my x-rays?
No. I got three
patients waiting.
There's only one file clerk.
Well, you don't look that busy.
You want to cover the
phones? I'll get the x-rays myself.
You all right?
Look at her sitting there. How
long will you make her wait?
She should be on a
bus. Will you talk to her?
I've talked to her all my life.
There's nothing left to say.
Randi, would you call
Security to move her out?
Security? What?
Oh.
Abby. Abby. Abby, listen.
No! What are you
trying to prove?
You're my daughter.
I care about you.
Do you mind?
I'll take my medicine.
I'll get a job. Whatever.
We both know that's
not gonna happen.
I'm not going anywhere
until you talk with me.
Damn it, Abby, I'm your mother.
Deal with me. Go
back to Florida.
I need a monitored bed.
Trauma 1's open.
Lie still. We're trying to
help. Put him on the dynamap.
Get an ultrasound.
What have you got?
25-year-old pharmacy tech
found down in Central Supply.
BP's 260/140. He's combative,
not moving his right side.
And he's vomiting.
Increased intracranial
pressure. Probably a brain bleed.
He needs intubation, a
Nipride drip and a stat head CT.
Go away! We
need hard restraints.
How about we
paralyze and intubate?
Six of Versed, 100 of sux.
Oh. Now I know why
his pressure's so high.
Want a tox screen?
It's probably coke
or crystal meth.
Paralytics are on
board. 80 ET tube.
Damn it!
That's all right. I'll
get another one.
You all right? Uh.
Yeah. Just a little dizzy.
You wanna sit down?
No. Okay.
I'm gonna be sick.
Get an emesis basin.
Pulse ox down to 86. Bag him.
That's okay. Sit
down. I'm sorry.
Put your head down.
His sats are still dropping.
Chuny, can you get some help?
Go ahead. You have to intubate.
Randi, find a doctor! We need
some help in Trauma 1 now!
I can't see the cords. I need
suction. There's a lot of vomit.
Try a straight blade.
Lydia, we need a vent.
How's that Nipride drip coming?
Working on it.
What do you need?
It's a difficult intubation.
Dr. Corday is sick.
Go lie down. I've got it.
Take one more look.
If you can't get it, I'm here.
Can I have a cords tube? Okay.
Bag him. Good.
Knee film on Mr. Florea
looks normal. I knew it.
Take a look at his ultrasound.
I didn't order an ultrasound.
He was in a lot of pain.
Oh, man!
He's got a clot from
the popliteal fossa
to the femoral vein?
Uh-huh.
I thought he was
drug-seeking. Where is he?
Guy was a pain in the ass.
He tried to bum an El
token from the desk clerk.
When the guy wouldn't
cough it up, he got pissed off.
You just let him leave?
I'm not a hall monitor. Damn it!
Mr. Florea!
Excuse me.
Mr. Florea...
Out of my way.
Move away from him.
Mr. Florea?
Randi, it's Carter.
I'm at the El station.
Send a gurney
up here right away.
What happened?
Found him down at the El.
He was drinking
again? No, he left AMA.
He's got a leg clot. It must
have traveled to his lung.
Sats are only 78.
Just keep the TPA box ready.
Mix up the TPA,
run 100 milligrams
over the next two hours.
I've got to do
the checklist first.
No, no. There's
no time for that.
He's altered, a
contraindication.
He's altered because of the PE.
Not enough oxygen to his brain.
I won't give it.
He may be bleeding
internally. I'll give it to him.
I'm not signing my
name to this. Then don't!
You know the pharmacy dude that
Corday and Abby were working on?
The one with the
crack pipe? Yeah?
Cop said he was cooking
crystal meth in the basement.
Had a whole lab set up.
You're kidding. Bad news.
Debby Marlin's HMO
wouldn't authorize admission.
Who? Breast cancer
with spine mets.
HMO said she should be
managed as an outpatient.
Well, if she's in pain, have
her contact her HMO tomorrow.
Oh, should she do that
before or after she takes the bus
across town to refill
her prescription?
Cleo, Cleo, we've
done all we can.
She's got end-stage breast
cancer, Peter. She's in pain.
I know. But she's gonna
have to take it up with her HMO.
She'd be better off
without insurance.
Then we'd have to admit her
and County would pay for it.
Doesn't make a
damn bit of sense.
How's your sister doing, Peter?
Ah, you know. As well
as can be expected.
Randi, how long is Abby's
mother gonna be sitting in Chairs?
I bet three days.
Wanna join the pool?
No, thanks.
You were giving TPA? He's
got a pulmonary embolus.
Are you sure? He's got a DVT,
he's hypoxic and he's
got a right ventricular
strain pattern on the 12-lead.
What are his coags?
What's his head CT
show? I don't know.
Stop the TPA. He could
bleed. Pulse ox is down to 72.
This is his only chance.
You know nothing
about this man's history.
You could kill
him with this drug.
He's hypoxic on 100% oxygen.
He'll never make
it! We must try.
Hey! He'll arrest!
I'm the attending.
Pulse ox is going up to
80. Heart rate's steady at 72.
I just pray he didn't
bleed in his brain.
Thanks.
I feel like such a klutz.
These things happen.
My husband likes
celery in his stuffing,
so I'm chopping away, and whack!
Next thing I know,
there's blood everywhere.
Oh, I should've stuck
to my oyster recipe.
But Sam likes a
traditional stuffing.
You know, you can tell a lot
about people by their stuffing.
My mother hates sage.
And I'm not too fond
of nuts or raisins.
Heh-heh, to tell you the
truth, I don't like a lot of that
fancy stuff thrown in
like eggs or dried fruit.
Oh, how about you, doctor?
What kind of
stuffing do you like?
Dr. Greene?
What do you prefer?
Dr. Greene, lab needs
another red top on Caine.
Dr. Greene, can I run
my asthma patient by you?
Mark, we've got a
lady with syncope in 4.
Mark, do you have a minute?
I got into a thing
with Cart... Not now.
Are you going anywhere tonight?
I don't think so.
Stop by. I'm making
Thanksgiving dinner for 30.
Thirty people? How do you do it?
Takeout from Chicago Chicken
served on my good china.
Abby. Abby, please
talk with me. Please.
Please don't do
this to me again.
All right. All right.
I lost my apartment.
I've been evicted.
I have no place to go.
I don't wanna hear it.
Why are you so damn stubborn?
It's called self-protection.
I did the best I could.
I took care of you
and Eric all by myself.
Excuse me, Mom.
We took care of you.
You always had a place to
stay, food to eat, and clothes.
I worked hard for that.
When you were on your meds.
I tried hard to be
a good mother.
I tried every day.
Abby. Abby, now
you listen to me.
There is a lot of
me in you. I see it.
Please. Do you know that
every night before I went to sleep
I used to pray that you
would take your lithium
and just... Just act normal?
Do you think it was easy for
me? But it was exciting for us.
We never knew what to expect.
Would you bring home some
loser you picked up in a bar?
Or maybe you would
run down our street naked,
screaming your head off.
You can hate me.
It's okay to hate me. Then
there was that Thanksgiving
when I was 10.
You remember that one?
Oh, God, here we go. Here we
go. You were cooking potatoes.
Here we go. Here
we go. I walked in.
Okay. You asked where I'd been.
I said I'd been to visit Dad.
I'll never forget your face.
You threw the food on the
floor. You chased me with a knife.
I would never hurt you, Abby.
I'd never, ever hurt you. I
locked myself in the closet.
I remember sitting with
my feet It was the disease.
Against the door to keep
you out. It was the disease.
You have to see me.
I'm not just a disease!
Then that night you
made me sleep beside you
to prove you were sorry.
I couldn't sleep.
I had to watch you.
I'm your mother.
You might flip out again.
I'm the only mother you have.
I was 10 years old!
I didn't choose to be sick.
You never tried to get better!
I can't make things
different. That's right!
You can't. So now just go home.
♪ Rescue me ♪
♪ I need your tender charms ♪
♪ 'Cause I'm lonely ♪
♪ And I'm blue ♪
♪ I need you ♪
♪ And your love too ♪
♪ Come on and rescue me ♪
♪ Come on, baby And rescue me ♪
I couldn't talk. The words
just wouldn't come out.
Have you had any other symptoms?
Change in vision?
Headaches? Syncope?
Nothing significant.
Neck's a little
sore from hockey.
Headache, on and off.
Could be an atypical
migraine, maybe cerebritis.
You under a lot
of stress lately?
Who isn't?
Right. Let's take a look.
You ready? Yeah, I guess.
This is ridiculous.
I-I'm actually
feeling much better.
It's probably hypoglycemia
from skipping breakfast and lunch.
Well, when I was dizzy and
vomited I took a pregnancy test.
I'm not pregnant. I
had a period last month.
Hmm.
That was breakthrough bleeding.
What?
You're pregnant.
Well, that's impossible.
Really?
Technically, it's possible.
You know, maybe we
should run a serum test
just to make sure.
It's okay. Why
don't you lie down?
I'll do an ultrasound and
see how far along you are.
What's the word?
There appears to be a 3.5
cm mass in the frontal cortex.
A brain tumor.
How bad is it?
I wanna discuss it with
a neurosurgeon first.
You're a radiologist.
How bad is it?
I really can't say.
What's my prognosis?
Phil?
You need to talk to a
neurosurgeon right away.
It's not like he
swallowed one nail.
We're talking
pounds of hardware.
There's nails and screws
and one of those metric
socket sets, and a plier.
I mean, I'm palpating
this guy's belly.
And there's a crescent
wrench outlined in bas-relief.
I mean, just smashed
up against the skin.
So my husband says to me,
"You've gotta go in there
and consent this guy."
You were married?
Yes. And, um...
He was a surgical Resident.
So I go in there and I say:
"Mr. Jebson, how did
you get all this stuff down?"
And he says, um... He
says, "A good Chablis."
He says, "A good
Chablis." Oh, my gosh.
Oh, my gosh. I'm so sorry.
It's fine. I can't believe...
No, you missed most of me.
I'll pay for the dry-cleaning.
Sorry. Kerry, it's all right.
Did you bring the guacamole?
Yeah, and onion dip.
Hey, Dr. Greene. Hey.
Are you okay?
I was just heading
out. Good night.
We need dessert. I can grab
something from Doc Magoo's.
We don't need it that bad.
Good night. Happy Thanksgiving.
Have a good one.
I'm starving.
Those are my favorite, girl.
Hey, what happened? Hmm?
Your...? Oh. I went for a walk.
In the rain? How's Mr. Florea?
He, uh... He threw a
clot. I had to give him TPA.
Oxygen levels are
up, vitals are stable.
Can I give you a hand?
Help you with anything?
I'm just starting an IV.
With your mom, I mean.
No. Every time she
goes off her meds
she says she's not
gonna do it again.
Why should this
time be any different?
I don't know. My
patient's smoking again.
Excuse me.
Mr. Thal, I told you.
If you wanna smoke,
you have to go outside.
In the rain?
I've got pneumonia.
Man, this is smelling weird.
I need an ashtray.
Anything else I can get you?
An extra pillow would be nice.
Dr. Carter, could
I speak with you?
Sure.
I know you're a friend
of my daughter's.
Oh, this is awkward for me.
I don't know what else to do.
Could you talk to her for me?
I'm not sure what...
Abby's in there!
Stay here! Stay here!
Are you okay? Yeah.
Oh, my God! Abby!
Everyone, stay outside!
Abby! Stay out here!
Abby! MAGGIE: Abby!
Abby! MAGGIE: Abby! God, Abby!
Abby! MAGGIE: Oh, my God, Abby!
Please wait outside.
Abby? MAGGIE: Is she all right?
- Is your neck okay?
- Is she all right?
Is her airway clear?
I think she's okay.
Let's go! Let's go!
Down the hall to the right.
Carter, you need help?
I don't think so.
I'll be in Curtain 2.
Get me an intubation
kit, lactated Ringer's
and lots of burn
dressings. Look out, please!
Excuse me. Excuse me.
Is she all right?
Is she badly hurt?
Can you please wait outside? No.
Stethoscope. Do you
have any chest pain?
Yeah. You do? Where's it hurt?
Uh, right there. Right here?
Okay, take a deep breath for me.
All right, give me the oxygen.
Hello, Mommy.
Jing-Mei.
Oh, I'm so glad you came.
Who's here?
Everybody.
Great.
I'll go get your father.
You didn't tell Ba-Ba yet?
You asked me not to.
He'll be okay.
Shocked, but okay.
You underestimate us, Jing-Mei.
You've always underestimated us.
Mommy, will you love the
baby if the father is black?
He's black.
That's what I thought.
Jing-Mei?
It's okay, Mommy.
That's why I didn't tell you.
Any idea what started it?
Ether. Ether?
A couple of guys in the pharmacy
were cooking crystal meth.
Transported the
ether in IV bags.
One of theirs got mixed in.
Damn.
Everybody out?
All but two patients.
Well, move it. We're
evacuating this whole department.
They're critical.
I'll give you 10 minutes.
Just take a deep breath.
Chest still hurt? A
little bit. Can I get up?
I'm okay, and I could help.
Not until I get a chest x-ray.
I don't need a chest x-ray.
Abby, come on. Let him help you.
How are you? I'm a little sore.
I think she cracked
a rib. How's Mr. Thal?
He's going up to the Burn
Unit. But I think he'll be okay.
How much Ringer's do you
want? Ten liters over eight hours.
How's your guy with the PE?
CT was normal.
No brain bleeding.
Good.
Let's get you up to Radiology.
He was staring up at
me from the pavement.
And with every breath
I could see frosted cloud
from his mouth
get smaller.
I just talked to him.
Tried to reassure him.
And I held his
hand, until he died.
The ambulance never came?
He was gone by the
time they got there.
Oh, my God.
Well, what happened
to the driver who hit him?
Not enough.
He was drunk, but
this was 19 years ago.
They revoked his
license for a while
and had him pick up trash
on Saturday or something.
Well...
I certainly got us off on a very
depressing tangent, didn't I?
I think we're gonna
close this place down.
I'm sorry. We haven't
taken care of this.
No, no, no. Let me.
No, you paid last time. Come on.
You know what? Why
don't we just split it?
I got it.
Thank you.
You know, this is our
second meal together.
Some people might consider
a second dinner a date.
A date?
You do know I'm
gay? Of course I do.
I don't have a
problem with that.
I have gay friends.
Oh.
Oh, I'm sorry,
Kerry. I misread this.
No. I mean, I didn't...
I'm so sorry if I gave
you the wrong impression.
It's just that you called me
for eight psych consults
in the past week.
We work well together.
My instincts are usually
a lot more reliable.
You know what? I'm... Thank you.
You know, I'm really very
flattered. It's just that I'm...
Gosh, you're such
a beautiful woman.
You're so beautiful. But I'm...
I... I'm straight.
I mean, I don't... I'm straight.
Okay. Oh, God...
Oh, my God. I don't
know... I don't know what...
I mean, I'm sorry.
I just, I don't...
I feel very...
I'm...
You know what? I'm... I just...
I mean, I-I guess I never
even really considered this.
You haven't said a word
since we left the hospital.
We can talk to each other.
That's what people
do in relationships.
All right.
I'm pissed that Romano's docking
my pay for punching Malucci.
That better?
You should be furious.
Malucci was way out of line.
Not that I'm surprised.
What's that supposed to mean?
You get docked because
Malucci's a jackass.
Your nephew gets crappy care
because they
assume he's a banger.
And today our patient
couldn't get her meds.
Okay, I'm so tired of
hearing you go off on this.
You need to stop trying to
teach everybody how to be black.
And you need to face reality.
Debby Marlin couldn't get pain
medication because her pharmacy
was in a black neighborhood.
You grew up in the suburbs.
What do you know
about her problems?
What, I can't relate
because I wasn't poor?
No. I'm just saying,
I know who I am.
I don't have anything to prove.
And I do because
my mother's white?
I didn't say that.
Where are you
going? I'm getting off.
This isn't our stop.
It's mine. I don't
wanna see you tonight.
Cleo, we're supposed to
be going to your cousin's...
Good news. Your
lungs look clear.
But you cracked
a rib on the right.
I'll write your
discharge orders.
You don't have to do that.
Fine. You did have a
concussion, loss of consciousness.
So I'm gonna call
you later. Thank you.
"Doctor." Doctor.
I borrowed an umbrella. Okay.
Happy Thanksgiving, Dr. Carter.
Hey. GREENE: Hey.
Ooh.
That steak smells fantastic.
Mwah.
How'd you get the
charcoal going in the rain?
I just pulled the grill
in under the overhang.
I've never had a
deck to grill on before.
Makes me feel very American.
Yeah? Yeah.
Shall I help you
with the salad? Sure.
Okay.
Mark...
I have something to tell
you. It's not going to be easy.
Go ahead.
Well, I know it's not
exactly the best time, but...
What the hell? I'm pregnant.
Uh, Chen did an ultrasound.
What are you thinking?
I think it's wonderful.
Oh, I love you.
I love you too.