I'm a horrible person,
aren't I?
No. You're human.
After inseminating the eggs,
none of them fertilized.
You can start
another cycle in
as little as six weeks.
I'll do it.
It must've been
an agonizing decision,
turning in Hannah.
I think you did
the right thing.
Hannah, I was
just trying to...
Go and don't
come back again.
Go! Go! Go!
You're officially
in remission.
If you had one
wish right now,
what would it be?
To spend the rest
of my life with you.
You better not be playing
with me, because
I'd marry you tomorrow.
Finally.
What's the big emergency?
I'm late for work.
Sorry to inconvenience
you, Dan,
but your daughter
was sent home from school.
Suspended.
What?
For vaping.
God, Suzie...
Uh-uh-uh. No, no, no.
This one's your fault.
How's it my fault?
Because you've been
neglecting her.
I'm not the one who
moved to Milwaukee.
Okay, whatever you say.
Look, the point is,
we've been back in Chicago
almost a year,
and the past six months,
you found excuses not to
see her on the weekends.
You beg out of picking
her up after school.
Yeah. Look, I...
I've been
a little distracted,
you know, with CeCe
and everything...
I'm sorry your wife died, Dan.
I am.
But you have
a 13-year-old daughter
who's very much alive.
Is she in her room?
Where else?
It's Dad. Can I come in?
I'm coming in.
She took my phone.
Vaping? Really?
You know that's
gonna kill you, right?
You know I don't
care, right?
Get your schoolwork.
You're coming with me.
Where?
Work.
The hospital?
Yeah.
It's Father-Daughter Day,
and we're late.
Come on, get your stuff.
This is so stupid.
Yeah. You can
say that again.
The Opal Room
will let us start
setting up at noon.
No problem.
I can be there then.
No, you're gonna be
at the tailor's
trying on your tux.
I can't believe
you got all this
done in two weeks.
It's handled.
Maggie, I am
your maid of honor.
I should do something.
Well...
What?
Nothing.
The DJ will start
setting up at 5:00.
Okay...
Mags, I'm sorry
I gotta run.
Okay.
Bride's dressing room
at 6:00, okay?
Yes, ma'am.
All right.
What'd you think
about my playlist?
You won't mind
if I make changes, right?
Ms. Remus,
hi, I'm Dr. Manning.
And you must be Mindi.
Hi.
So, according to our chart,
you're no stranger to the ED.
Mindi was premature.
She's had a lot
of health issues.
I see. Respiratory
distress syndrome.
She has trouble breathing,
so, I keep her on oxygen.
Mmm. Well,
she's satting well.
100%. What brought
you in today?
She isn't sleeping.
It's even harder
for her to breathe.
And this morning,
she was just staring
at a wall,
which always happens
when she has a seizure.
All right, well, why don't
we take a look?
I'm gonna listen
to your lungs, okay?
Okay.
Can you sit up
a little bit for me?
All right, now take
a deep breath in.
Good. How about
one more.
Great.
All right. Well,
her lungs sound good.
She's alert.
I'm not seeing any
sign of seizures now.
But we'll run some tests
to see what's going on.
Let's get a chest X-ray,
CBC, BMP, and let's
check her Keppra level.
I just wanna make sure
she's on
the appropriate dose.
I'll be back when we have
some answers, okay?
Dr. Manning. Do you
know Dr. Strauss?
I don't think
we've actually met yet.
You're in peds, right?
I specialize in
medical child abuse.
When Ms. Remus brought
her daughter in this morning,
it set off an alert.
An alert?
She's been red-flagged
at several hospitals
in the city.
Why?
We have every
reason to believe
she's been abusing
her daughter.
I gotta stop by
the cleaners after work,
pick up my suit for
Maggie's wedding tonight.
That's right.
Oh. Hey, you okay?
Yeah I just got a little
light-headed. I'm fine.
Are you sure?
Yeah, I'm sure.
I'm sure.
Okay.
You can sit at my desk
and do your homework. Okay?
Don't I get to see
any crazy people?
Anna, how many
times have we
talked about your use
of that word?
And no, you don't get
to see my patients.
What's the point of me
being here, Dad?
What's the point?
The point is, you've been
suspended and you gotta
do your homework.
That's the point.
I bet it's not even
Father-Daughter Day, is it?
You just said that,
so you could
keep me in jail.
Wow.
You are so smart.
So, do your homework.
Look, I gotta go.
But I will be back.
And you and I
are gonna have
a little talk, okay?
Later.
Dr. Choi, Dr. Marcel,
GSW coming in. A cop.
Going to Baghdad.
John Bell, early 20s.
GSW, lower
right quadrant.
Stripped his body
armor in the ambo.
Hang in there, Johnny.
BP, 110 over 82,
heart rate 104.
Sats 100.
Doris, with me.
Yep.
Mike, gonna
need an X-ray.
KUB and chest.
Let's transfer
on my count.
Johnny's a hero.
He drew fire away
from a 10-year-old girl.
We got it, Rosado.
Everybody ready?
One, two, three.
That hurts!
Single lateral
gunshot wound.
No exit wound,
likely retained
the bullet.
All right,
bilateral breath sounds.
Sorry about that,
focused lower
right quadrant pain.
Let's get that lateral
X-ray first.
Clear.
Retained bullet
in the posterior lateral,
definitely transabdominal.
That's enough
for me.
Okay, Officer Bell,
we're gonna take you
up for surgery, okay?
Okay.
All right. Doris,
let them know
we're coming up.
Yep.
How is he?
He is one of mine.
Do not give me any
of that HIPAA crap.
Trudy, Officer Bell's
vitals are good.
But the bullet's
in a dangerous spot.
We gotta get him
to surgery.
Do we need
Father Dan?
We're hoping no.
Hey. Keep me
in the loop on this one?
Why don't you
scrub in with me?
I understand you
know your way
around a gunshot wound.
Come on.
Dr. Charles?
We have a possible case
of Munchausen by proxy.
I believe Ms. Remus
is either faking her
daughter's symptoms,
or causing them to gain
attention for herself.
I just don't think
that's the case.
I spent time with her.
She seemed like a normal,
concerned parent.
This little girl Mindi
certainly has been
hospitalized a lot.
Based on vague symptoms,
which somehow health care
professionals don't see.
Just hold on a second.
I mean,
Mindi was diagnosed
with bronchopulmonary
dysplasia.
When she was an infant.
She's four, now.
Her mom's still
bringing her in for
nebulizer treatments.
Yeah, she's on a tremendous
amount of medication,
I will say that.
Which could be necessary,
given her history.
Let's not argue the case
until we have
more information.
Dr. Manning, let us know
if her test results
support the symptoms
her mother is describing.
And, Dr. Charles,
you'll need to
evaluate Ms. Remus.
If my suspicions
are correct,
then for Mindi's well-being,
we're gonna need
to get DCFS involved.
What you getting?
Look who's back.
I wouldn't want her
operating on me.
Nobody asked you.
Between Afghanistan
and Chicago,
I'm guessing
you've seen
all kinds of GSWs.
Mostly high-velocity
overseas handguns here.
Either way,
a world of loss.
Bullet went
through the cecum.
Need to repair.
2-0 Silk to me.
Whoa. Hold on.
Ethan, you see
that bulge?
Yeah. Large mass.
Hematoma?
No, too far
from the bullet track
to be related.
Okay, well, let's have
a look-see. Scalpel.
It's an abscess.
What the hell from?
Something foreign
must've caused
the abscess.
Ethan, what do
you make of this?
See if he's got scars
on his flank.
Yep.
And right next to it?
Entrance
and exit wounds.
Today wasn't
the first time
this patient was shot.
How can you be so sure?
Seen this before.
He was sitting in a car
when it happened.
So, this...
This is foam
from a car seat.
Hi.
The test results
come back?
Yes.
Everything was negative.
Nothing abnormal.
That's great.
What's wrong
with her?
I'm not sure.
Does she have
a fever?
No, ma'am.
Something is wrong
with her.
She's just not herself.
Mommy?
It's okay, baby.
Mommy's okay.
I'm sorry. It's just...
Trying to take
care of her...
Let's order an EEG,
see if she's having
subclinical seizures.
Thank you.
Whoa!
You all right?
All right, all right.
We got you.
Two milligrams
morphine IV.
Right.
April, what do
I need to know?
I'm doing IVF.
Okay. So, you're
on hormones?
Uh-huh.
I'm gonna palpate
your belly.
Sorry.
BP and heart rate
are normal.
Okay. Diffuse tenderness,
worse on the left side.
CBC, BMP and HCG.
April, this could
be ovarian
torsion or a cyst.
I'm gonna send you
to gynae for
an ultrasound. Hank?
Let's go.
I'll call gyne.
Hold up.
Page Dr. Asher,
tell her
I want her to personally
do this ultrasound
on a colleague.
Right.
Honey, I'm so sorry.
I gotta dash right
back out of here.
There's something
going on.
That's an antique.
I'm doing geography.
Yeah, you're funny.
So, look,
very limited selection.
But they did have
your favorite
barbecue potato chips,
which are gonna
go great with this
delicious tuna sandwich.
Gee, Dad, what do
you think would go
best with this?
What, you went
through my desk?
I finished all my homework.
What else was
I supposed to do?
Honey, my desk is private.
I mean, how would
you feel if I went
through your backpack?
You wouldn't find
any alcohol in there.
And you get on
my case about vaping?
That's pretty hypocritical.
Look, that was a gift.
Right.
Hey, look.
I'm an adult
of legal drinking age,
and you...
You're a kid.
So, let's talk about
vaping, shall we?
Oh, my God.
Every week,
into this hospital,
we have kids your
age coming with
their lungs destroyed.
Here we go.
I'm trying to have
a serious talk with you,
young lady.
And if you're gonna
sass back
everything I say...
We're not talking.
You're lecturing me.
Well, maybe there's
a reason for that.
Look, just...
Read a book,
or something.
Please.
Your ultrasound showed
bilateral enlarged
ovaries with good flow.
There's no indication
of torsion
or a hemorrhagic cyst.
Then what?
You do have some
fluid in your abdomen.
That, coupled with
the pain and nausea,
point to a mild
case of OHSS,
ovarian hyperstimulation
syndrome.
That's consistent
with IVF,
from the hormones.
I'm going to start you
on some IV fluids
and albumin.
Continue the pain meds.
Usually, this resolves
with time.
So, we'll wait and watch.
Thank you.
Okay.
Hannah?
Glad to see you back.
I know rehab
wasn't easy...
Let's just focus
on your patient.
So, you didn't find
any other bullet
or shrapnel?
Nothing metallic
on this X-ray?
No, ma'am,
just today's GSW.
But you're sure
he was shot before?
I don't see any
other explanation.
Well, any firearm injury
is a mandatory report.
It's not in his history.
And his partner doesn't
know anything about it.
Look, he did save
a little girl's life.
I mean, the man's a hero.
I say we leave it alone.
We can't leave it alone.
We have a legal obligation.
But I agree, we don't
wanna raise any red flags
if we don't have to.
So, when the patient
wakes up,
talk to him.
Hopefully, there's...
Yes?
Sorry to interrupt,
but, Dr. Choi,
you should know
April's not well.
What?
Dr. Halstead's
treating her.
It's okay.
Go, I got this.
She's tachycardic,
sats down to 94.
I can't breathe.
Doris, cannula.
Okay. Abdomen's distended.
Bedside ultrasound.
April.
Ethan.
What's going on?
OHSS.
Okay.
Ascitic fluid's irritating
the diaphragm.
That's why you're having
a hard time breathing.
She needs
paracentesis.
And a dose of albumin.
Excuse me.
I'm treating
this patient.
You?
Yes. Dr. Asher
is treating her,
and she's already
given April the albumin.
Okay, April,
I am going
to numb the area.
Baby, we're going to
drain the fluid
from your belly, okay?
Okay, you're not
going to do anything.
Please go.
I'm not going
anywhere.
Ethan, you know
you shouldn't be
here for this.
Ethan, go. It's okay.
No, no, no, no.
I'll be okay.
We got it.
Okay,
April, ready?
Okay.
You're doing great.
All right.
We've got 10 ccs.
That's it.
Keep breathing.
We've got 35, almost at 40.
Okay.
Good job, Dr. Asher.
Breathing's easier.
Doris, keep pressure.
Mmm-hmm.
April, I'll come
check on you
in a bit, okay?
Dr. Asher performed
the paracentesis
and it went well.
April's stable.
You can go in now.
Hannah.
You understand,
I couldn't let you
keep treating patients.
I had to make
your addiction known.
Publicly?
So everyone knew?
You have any idea
how humiliating it's been?
There was no other way.
If I just turned
you in, you'd deny it.
I had to make sure
they had evidence.
No. What you did
was a betrayal.
You're an excellent doctor.
I believe in you.
I wasn't about to let you
throw your life away.
And if I had to do it over,
I'd do the same thing.
Hey, guys. The sheers
don't go there.
They have to be
at the head of the aisle
so, I can walk through them.
Hey, sweetie.
Hey.
How you doing, babe?
What are you doing here?
You're supposed
to be at the tailor's.
Already been.
They're letting
out the slacks.
Oh.
So, what can
I do to help?
Nothing.
Ah, Palacio.
I got your orchids.
There's a problem.
What?
They were left
on the tarmac at O'Hare.
Frost damage.
They're ruined.
Yeah.
We can deal with this.
How about you pick out
a replacement, on us.
Here, daisies.
Very popular
wedding flower.
Daisies.
How about...
Babe, I've got this.
So, I just reviewed
the EEG on Mindi Remus.
I see no evidence she
had subclinical seizures
or any eleptiform
activity.
Are you sure?
Am I sure?
Only an incompetent would
prescribe anti-seizure
medication for her.
Anything else?
No. Thank you,
Dr. Abrams.
Okay, so, are we ready
to turn this over to DCFS?
You know,
I'm not quite.
Well, I am.
What do you suggest?
If we're accusing
Ms. Remus of faking
her daughter's symptoms,
why don't we just take
Mindi off of oxygen
and see how she does?
What do we have
to lose, really?
Are we in agreement?
All right, then.
Hey. He's awake?
Yeah.
How's April?
She's okay.
Glad to hear it, man.
Hey, John.
Hey, man.
Operation went well.
How're you feeling?
Okay...
Good.
So, we need to ask
you some questions.
You up to it?
Before today,
have you ever been shot?
Shot? No.
We found two
scars on your side.
How'd you get those?
Yeah, when I was a kid,
I was, you know,
play sword fighting.
I got jabbed.
Officer Bell, I'm sorry,
but that's just
not consistent
with what we found.
There was a piece of car
seat foam in your abdomen.
So, what?
We see that in people
who've been shot
while sitting in a car.
That didn't happen.
Then, can you
help us understand
how that foam
could've gotten in there?
Look, I don't care
what you think you found.
I've never been shot.
Right.
Excuse us a moment.
Ms. Remus,
this is Sharon Goodwin,
our Executive Director
of Patient Services,
and Dr. Strauss,
a pediatrician.
Is something wrong?
Please have a seat.
So, Mindi's EEG
came back normal,
which is a good thing.
Problem is,
it leaves us no closer
to a diagnosis.
Which is why
it would be
helpful for us
to take Mindi off oxygen
and see how she does.
But she needs it.
And that's what
we're going to find out.
And if she has any
trouble breathing,
we will immediately
put her back on it.
But we need
your permission.
You do wanna help
your daughter,
don't you?
Of course I do.
Okay.
Mindi, honey,
the doctors just
need to test
something, okay?
All right. We're gonna
take this out of
your nose, okay?
All right, you ready?
Here you go.
You're gonna
be all right.
There you go.
You okay?
Is it hard to breathe?
Sats are still
at 100%.
I don't understand.
This is like a miracle.
How could this happen?
Do you mind,
could we step outside
and chat for a bit?
Mindi, Mommy'll be
right back, okay?
Ms. Remus,
are you familiar
with a condition
called Munchausen
by proxy?
You think I'm crazy.
You think I'm making
my daughter sick?
Other hospitals reported
that Mindi's symptoms
don't seem to present
when she's
in the emergency room.
Other hospitals?
Yes.
You've known about
this all day, and you
didn't say anything?
I'm sorry.
Oh, my God.
You're trying to take
my child away from me.
Ms. Remus,
our main interest
is Mindi's welfare.
No, no,
you can't take her.
You cannot take
my little girl from me!
Ms. Remus.
No, no, no...
We really should
have this
conversation outside.
You can't take her!
No, Ms. Remus,
it's very...
You can't take her!
I am not crazy!
Dad?
No, you can't
take her from me.
Dad!
Anna.
No.
She has been sick...
Give me a minute.
...her entire life
and I am
the only person
that she has.
Could that really happen?
Could they really take
her daughter away?
Honey,
what are you doing here?
You're not supposed
to be here, sweetie.
I love her.
I know you love her,
but we're not...
You are not taking
her away from me!
Honey, I am so sorry
that you had to see that.
But what was
going on there
was that that woman,
she may have an illness
that causes her
to not be a very good mom.
Dad, are they gonna
separate you from me?
What? Who?
Those people,
like downstairs.
No. No, nobody's
gonna separate us.
Why would you
ask that?
Because you haven't
been a very good dad.
I mean, it's like
you just forgot about me.
No. No, no, no.
Not for a second. I didn't...
You did,
but I'm not mad.
I don't care.
I don't want you
to go away.
No, sweetie,
I'm not going anywhere.
It's not gonna happen.
You promise?
I promise.
What?
It's just that
you know I do,
I love you so much,
and I feel so bad.
It's okay.
No, it's not okay.
You're right.
I have not been
a very good dad.
I haven't been around.
Well, that's
because CeCe died.
Yeah, but you know what?
That's not an excuse.
You're my daughter.
You're my little baby girl.
And...
I'm really sorry.
And I promise
I'm gonna...
I'm gonna do better.
Okay?
Okay.
Your fellow officers
would like to come in.
Did you say
something to them?
No. No,
we haven't.
Look, John, I'm in the Navy.
And it's been
my experience
that cops and military,
we're a lot alike.
Profound sense of duty.
But I gotta
tell you, man.
If something did
happen in your past,
you need
to own up to it.
I'm not a military man,
but my pops used to say,
a lie can poison
a man's life.
What do you think
about the pants?
What's that smell?
What's going on?
The sewer's
backed up.
Can you fix it?
We've got raw sewage
coming up from the drains.
Kitchen's not usable.
We have to close.
Close?
I'm very sorry.
We can reschedule,
help you find
another venue...
Ben...
It'll be okay.
But it's always
been my dream
to get married here.
We'll figure
something out.
I'm not gonna give up.
I can do this.
Where else
can we have it?
The Riverwalk,
we could rent
a tent...
It's March. Maggie,
let me help you out here.
Ben, don't distract me.
Stop it, all right? Stop.
You're acting like
someone in remission.
What?
Cancer, that's what
this is about.
You just went
through something
that made you feel helpless.
And you never wanna
feel that way again.
Believe me, I know.
But no matter
how hard you try,
you can't
control everything.
But it's all ruined.
Mmm-mmm.
You have
a partner now.
What's called in marriage
a helpmate.
And that helpmate is gonna
do his job and help you.
Sorry about that.
Is everything okay?
Yeah. Yes,
it is, thanks.
Good.
Once you're finished
evaluating her,
we're supposed to meet
in Goodwin's office.
I so wanted
to believe her.
When I was pregnant,
they told me that
I would lose her
if I didn't stay in bed,
so, I did for two months.
But still, she came
at 24 weeks.
Would you mind
telling me a bit
about what
Mindi's birth
was like for you?
Terrible.
I was so scared.
And there was
so much blood.
And then
she wasn't breathing.
They took her away
from me and they put
all these tubes in her.
I see the faces
of the doctors,
and I hear the machines.
And I think
my baby is dying.
Even now, she sleeps
next to me in bed.
And I listen all
night to make sure
she's still breathing.
But you're getting
some rest, aren't you?
When do you sleep?
I don't.
Okay. Everything
is looking
great, April,
but you will need to
follow up with your
REI about continuing IVF.
I will, thank you.
I'm glad you're back.
I'll go get your
discharge started.
You're gonna be okay,
but we need
to change your meds.
When the last
harvest failed,
I wanted to make sure
that the next one didn't.
So, I doubled up
on my hormone meds.
I did it to myself.
April...
You want a baby.
We both want a baby.
But not at the expense
of your health. Never.
Look, it's okay.
It's okay.
I just wanted
to make up for...
You have nothing
to make up for.
I do.
What are you
talking about?
Crockett.
Crockett?
The night that you
left on deployment...
I kissed him.
I'm sorry.
Wait. It wasn't his fault.
It was mine.
He had nothing
to do with it.
Nothing? Nothing
to do with it...
Ethan? Ethan...
April? Really?
Huh? All this time,
acting like
friends. Huh?
Come on! Come on, friend!
Let's be friends! Come on!
Hey! Hey!
Come on!
Back up.
Dr. Marcel!
The patient
wants to see you.
Go.
Officer, what
do you need?
They think I'm a hero.
I'm not.
You were right.
I can't go on
living a lie.
I was 17.
A real knucklehead.
Friend had a gun,
thought it'd be cool
to knock off
a liquor store.
Trouble was,
the owner also
had a gun.
Shot my friend,
shot me when
I was in the car,
trying to get away.
My friend died.
But I lived.
I had to believe
it was for a reason.
Turn my life around,
make amends.
Appreciate what it took
for you to tell us this.
Since the gunshot wound
was never reported,
you know that
we have to...
No.
Let me.
I will.
Officer Bell would
like to see you.
So, are we agreed?
DCFS will take
custody of Mindi Remus?
No, we're not.
We are not agreed.
What?
Why not?
Carol Remus is suffering
from a mental illness,
which happens to be
easily misinterpreted
as Munchausen by proxy,
but it's not.
I think she's suffering
from PTSD.
Post-traumatic
stress disorder.
Oh, come on. From what?
From the experience
of giving birth to
an extremely premature baby.
And of watching that
baby almost die.
No. Mindi is clearly not
suffering from any of the
conditions that Mom claims.
PTSD leads
to hyper-vigilance,
in this case,
a mother's constant
worry about her
daughter's health.
This would cause
Ms. Remus to misinterpret
Mindi's symptoms,
even blow them wildly
out of proportion.
What about
the little girl?
what she needs?
What's best for Mindi
is to remain with
a mother who loves her.
You're wrong.
Ms. Goodwin?
I'm going to stand
with Dr. Charles.
When that little
girl comes back in here
severely injured,
and she will,
that's on all of you.
Hey, Will!
You were right.
I would've denied it,
just talked
my way out of it.
Yeah, I was in too deep.
Just total self-denial.
Every day had just
become about
getting my next fix.
You know, if I'm honest
with myself,
what you did
was what I needed.
It has not been easy,
but you gave me
my life back.
You got plans tonight?
No.
How about a wedding?
Dr. Choi?
I understand we had
some trouble upstairs.
Yes, ma'am.
I can't have my doctors
coming to blows
in the ICU.
Understood.
Ms. Goodwin,
it was my fault.
I take full
responsibility
for what happened.
What do you mean?
April and I,
we've been trying
to have a baby.
And I guess
I got obsessed
with that.
Didn't see there
were problems.
I can understand
your wanting to have
a baby, Dr. Choi.
You've seen
a lot of death.
It's only natural
you'd wanna bring
life into the world.
But don't be
too hard on yourself.
I'll see you
at the wedding?
You can open
your eyes now.
Oh, Nat.
You know
my Wednesday
night league.
They helped me
put this together.
We brought
The Opal Room here.
It's beautiful, Ben.
No...
You're beautiful.
Should we do this?
We're gathered tonight
in this bowling alley
to join my friends,
Ben and Maggie,
in holy matrimony.
In a moment, they will
say their vows...
You hit on April?
And I was beginning
to think you were
a good guy.
Whatever gave
you that idea?
With this ring,
I, Ben Campbell,
take you,
Maggie Lockwood,
to be no other
than yourself.
With this ring,
I, Maggie Lockwood,
take you,
Ben Campbell,
to be no other
than yourself.
Brave, loving...
And your
indispensable helpmate.
And my
I promise to love
and respect you,
throughout all of our years...
Throughout
our shared life.
And in all that life
may bring us.
By the power
vested in me
by the State of Illinois...
I pronounce you
husband and wife.
Whoo!
All right, everyone,
let's roll!
Now that we found love,
what are we gonna do...
with it?
One two, tell me what you
got
Let me slip my quarters
inside your slot to
hit the jackpot
Rev me up, rev me up,
my little buttercup
We can tug sheets snuggle up
and get stuck
Great job.
A strugglin', bubblin'
overweight lover hurt
prone
So what's it gonna be?
Me or the TV
Now let me take time to set
your mind and your body
free
Oh, yeah...
Come on, do the right
thing, baby Kitty,
kitty
Now that we found love,
what are we gonna do...
with it?