What have we got?
Kayla Wayne, 32,
hypotensive and tachycardic.
Hypoxic even after intubation.
Severe open wound to
the mid and lower abdomen.
We're with her.
She's part of our act.
I said, "Titanic"! I said it!
Well, I didn't hear you!
There's no such
thing as magic...
As far as we know.
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
Okay, slow down and
tell me what happened.
She's my wife and assistant.
Please don't let her die. We
were performing at a trade show.
Yeah, we weren't ready.
And while, as surgeons,
we study the secrets behind
the human body's
intricate network of cells,
tissues, and organs,
when things go wrong...
Performing what?
It was saw the lady in half.
No way.
Horribly, horribly wrong...
And he really did
with a chain saw!
There are only so many
tricks we have up our sleeves
to put a body back together.
Page Bailey!
Here you go.
But there is a kind of
power, more of a spell, really.
I'm Lauren.
And when we get it right...
Um, okay. Hi, Lauren.
It can be pretty damn magical.
No, I'm the Lauren as in "Lauren" on
the coffee you're way over-sugaring.
Oh, yikes. I am so sorry.
You know what? I
didn't even look up there.
It's okay. I just
grabbed it, so...
Really, it's not a big problem.
This you?
Yeah, that's me.
Mmm. Well, now it's me.
See you around, I hope.
Grey, uh, whoa.
Yeah.
It looks like the
pelvis is involved.
We'll get more X-rays in the OR.
Yeah, no, no. Clearly,
you have bigger fish to fry.
I couldn't hear
"Titanic." The song?
No, it's our safe word. And I
yelled it, like, a hundred times
when the spring
flap wouldn't open.
Shut up, Cherise. You
don't reveal the secrets.
Someone get them outta here.
Brooks is on my moyamoya
case, but if you need her here...
Well, I have Ross, and I paged
Bailey, so you can take her.
What? But she's cut in half.
This is gonna be amazing.
You know what else is
amazing? A moyamoya.
I got paged.
Chain saw to the abdomen. Yeah?
I paged Bailey.
Yeah, I have Bailey's patients.
What? Still?
But she's infection-free.
Uh, clear to operate.
Okay, well, page me when
she's stable enough for X-rays.
How is she still alive?
I have no idea.
He spent the entire night? Yeah.
He heard you say eight days.
He wants to be here
when his dad wakes up.
You understand that
might not happen.
Well, of course I do.
But Ethan's just a little boy.
Nancy, you need to talk to him.
Prepare him for
the possibility...
I can't be the one
to add to his burden.
You talk to him, please.
Did I miss it? Is he awake?
Just because a family
overhears you say eight days,
it's not like, magically on day
eight, the guy's gonna wake up.
I mean, it could be
day four or day 10.
Oh, what is that?
The soundtrack of
your broken heart?
You gotta get
over that hairball.
I'm trying, but I
keep running into her.
Out of order, hairball.
Take the stairs.
Hi Kim, I'm Dr. Kepner. I hear
you're having some stomach pain.
She was over-served.
Or roofied.
The bartender
was a total skeeve.
He tried to grab my ass.
No, he caught your ass.
You threw it at him.
Bam! Aah!
Ow!
Is she gonna boot?
She should. Good call.
You only turn 21 once,
Kimmy. Boot and rally.
Can you guys focus for a second?
Can you remember
when the pain started?
At Kappa Sig.
No, she was making out
with Eric at Kappa Sig.
I think it was at brunch.
Oh, you're right.
It's probably just food
poisoning or something.
Can't you just pump her stomach?
No. Can you...
Smile, beeyotch.
Uh, I need to run some tests.
You'll wait for her?
How long?
'Cause my econ study
group starts in, like, an hour.
Who's Lauren?
Huh?
Oh, God. It's actually
a funny story. I was...
Did you know that Webber is
still taking all of Bailey's patients?
Oh, yeah. She's probably
holed up in the genome lab
because of that CDC thing.
Well, we're not the
ones who called them.
If she's gonna be pissed
at anyone, it should be him.
Who's pissed at me now?
Well, you called the CDC,
and now Bailey hates all of us.
We all called the CDC.
I didn't. We should,
uh, go talk to her.
Oh, no. I have a consult.
How can you go work when
you know Bailey is mad at you?
Hey. Oh, God. I totally
forgot about last night.
We were supposed
to have dinner and sex.
Dinner. Or just the dinner.
Maybe the sex
was all in my head.
Or it could've been
in your mind, too,
but it doesn't matter
because it didn't happen.
I forgot. But I
remember right now.
And I feel terrible. Okay.
I'm gonna make
it up to you tonight.
Yes. Tonight.
I...
Dr. Rymoff, call 566...
Miranda?
Oh.
Miranda, it's Callie.
How you doing? Can I come in?
Bailey.
I just thought you should know that
it was Jackson who called the CDC.
I mean, we all, you
know, we all approved it,
but I never thought
you did anything wrong.
I never thought you did anything
wrong. It was to clear your name.
And which is now clear, so yay!
I feel better. Do
you feel better?
Bailey.
Bailey, seriously?
I'm standing right here.
You're not really gonna
ignore me, are you?
Bailey.
Bailey?
All right.
Take the goal.
No, not again!
4-0.
3-0.
The first one didn't
count. I wasn't ready.
What if he never wakes up?
We're not there yet. Okay?
Hey. 5-0.
I wasn't ready.
Ethan.
Let's go, dear.
We're going to go back to
the hotel, just for a few hours.
I need a nap.
I'd rather stay here with you.
I think it's a good
idea, buddy, okay?
You can go get a
snack, watch some TV.
I promise I will call you if
anything changes, okay?
The kidney's shredded.
There's nothing to salvage here.
And here is part of
the large intestine.
I don't know where this
bleeding is coming from.
I mean, there's too much.
Where is it all coming from?
Ross, ligaclip.
Good God.
There are even chain
saw cuts on her vertebrae.
Ross, get your hands in there if
you have to and scoop out the clots.
PH is 6.9 and temp is 96.7.
It's too much. We
have to pack her.
I just took a look
at the films you did.
I'll need to plate the fracture
as soon as she's stable.
Oh, if she's ever stable.
Okay, we're doing
damage control. Got it.
Um, oh, I went to see Bailey,
and she didn't say a word.
Dr. Webber, has
she spoken to you?
Right now my attention
is on this patient,
who's headed for a
metabolic collapse.
Okay. Just let me know
when you need me.
Ross, faster.
The sooner we get her to ICU,
the better a chance she'll have.
That's okay, Iris. Yeah, her
arm is still weak from the TIAs,
but we'll take care of that.
Brooks, please.
Iris Kane, seven years old,
here for an omental flap that
will treat her moyamoya disease.
Moyamoya.
Boring! Hey, David.
Hospital behavior,
okay? Let me go!
No, no, no, honey. Mommy
and Daddy need to hear
how the doctors
are going to fix Iris.
Buddy, here. Look what
I brought from home.
I'm sorry. He just feels
left out. I'm sorry. Go on.
Karev.
Some of the blood vessels in Iris'
brain have narrowed and been choked off.
So I'll take tissue with healthy
vessels from Iris' abdomen.
And I will take that
tissue, place it in her brain,
where it'll absorb the vessels
and get the blood
supply it needs.
And this will help
with her arm strength.
David, buddy, come here.
Just sit still, okay?
Um, hey. David, I'll
play army men with you...
David!
I want to go! I want to go!
What did we talk about?
I'm so sorry.
Hands are for hugging!
We'll be right back.
David! Honey! DAVID: I
want to go! I want to go!
Go ahead. You
could just tell me.
They're gonna be a while.
Dr. Robbins, we were
just getting started.
Arizona.
You guys know each other?
Yeah. No.
We met briefly.
We had coffee.
Dr. Boswell is the
craniofacial specialist
we flew in to help
with Tyler's case.
You're Dr. Boswell? Mmm-hmm.
Yeah, how about this little guy?
Brain on the outside. That
can't be comfortable, huh?
Well, uh, welcome.
We're glad to have you.
Oh, are you kidding?
I mean, the combination of
encephalocele and facial cleft,
surgeons go their whole career without seeing
one of these. So I'm thrilled to be here.
Um, what's your approach?
Um, I'd like to get a couple more
scans before I commit to anything.
Okay, go ahead. Yeah.
We can talk strategy later.
I'll look forward to that.
Can't believe we got her,
huh? She's a rock star.
Yeah, she seems, um, competent.
She's too unstable.
We want to let her body rest
before we take her back to surgery.
But we're not gonna
lose her? I can't lose her.
You should've thought
of that before you added
a chain saw to
the trick. Illusions!
And I only added the chain
saw to try to get us better gigs.
Your chain saw drowned us
out when the trap door got stuck.
Ba-ba-ba-ba-ba. Magician's code.
Oh, my God. Really?
Okay, well, we'll let you know when
she's ready to go back into surgery.
So let's say I pursued a
different course of therapy.
Okay. Don't speak.
Patient suffered aortic transection,
miraculously repaired by me,
and then had a post-op inferior
MI that led to cardiac arrest.
So I induced hypothermia.
Let's say, hypothetically,
that I did not.
What else could I have done?
Don't answer that.
I could've taken him
straight to the cath lab.
But, no, I could not have
because had he had heparin
after his surgery, that would've
caused his aorta to blow.
And then I'd have to tell the kid
that Daddy's a goner 'cause I blew it?
No. So I was right. Right?
Right. I'm not asking you.
Girls, I really, really need
your help here, okay?
I need to know everything
that she ingested last night.
Every single thing that
went into her mouth.
Everything?
Kim's studies show that she
has a rupture in her abdomen,
which is bad. It
is very, very bad.
Hello? Okay.
Who is that?
Holy panty dropper. Can
he be our doctor instead?
Uh, Doctor. Excuse me.
Hi. Can you help me?
Please.
What's up?
Yeah, they're
drunk... No, we're not.
And don't care that their friend
has a serious abdominal injury.
Just ignore them.
No, my breasts are sick.
And I was wondering if you
had time to give me an exam.
I need one, too.
All right. Enough.
Your friend could die if
you don't start cooperating.
Do you understand that?
Fine. Jeez.
Chillax.
We pre-partied with
lemon drops at O'Briens.
Then cosmos at Bar Nouveau,
tequila shots at Kappa Sig.
Smoking nipples at Brunch.
What? What was that?
Smoking nipple.
Sweet, lots of rum,
comes out all smoky.
Hold on. Like, actual
smoke or dry ice?
Kimmy! Oh, God.
Let's get her down.
So his wife goes in the box.
But at some point,
there's another girl. Where?
That's what I can't figure out.
She's already in the box.
I know, but where?
There's no room.
Like my new apartment.
Living with Peckwell not
everything you hoped it'd be?
Oh, my God. Here
comes the chain saw.
No, no, no, no, no!
I can't watch that.
Oh, my God. That's amazing.
I can't unsee that.
I can't watch it.
That was amazing.
Someone's got his
bummer face on.
Everywhere I turn, she's there.
Oh, so we'll walk this way.
Oh, but I have to go that way.
Yeah, but Alex's little broken
heart needs to go the long way.
Oh, okay. Well, if it's for
Alex's little broken heart.
Alex's little broken heart
wishes you both would shut up.
So I'm worried about Bailey.
You know she's mad at all of us.
Why is she mad at
us? The CDC thing.
She's locked herself in that lab and will
not come out and will not talk to anyone,
and that's weird for her.
I'll talk to Bailey.
Yeah, see if you can
get through to her.
Where was I going?
Oh, no.
What happened?
Abdominal compartment
syndrome. Ross?
She's distended
and hemorrhaging,
causing her intra-abdominal
pressure to skyrocket.
We have to get her
back to the OR, stat.
Kayla, honey, I'm
sorry. I'm so, so sorry.
Ma'am, I'm gonna need the
two of you to please step out now.
Cherise, come on.
Please don't let her die.
Please save her. Ma'am.
Please step outside. Please.
Cherise, now. I
really need you to...
Come on, Cherise. Get
your hands off of me, Danny!
Cherise, I'm her husband,
okay? I know. I get it! I get it!
You don't know anything,
Danny. We're in love.
Which you would've figured out
by now if you paid her any attention.
She wanted to leave
you, but I told her to stay
till you got your freakin' dream
of having a show in Vegas.
I didn't listen to Kayla when she
said she was dying in the marriage,
dying in the stupid costume, dying every
time you made her get into that stupid box.
Okay. We're on the move.
No, I know what
you're thinking. EEG.
I've already done one, and he's not
having seizures. So why hasn't he woken up?
Yeah. I've asked every
doctor in the hospital
for their opinion, and
no one has any ideas.
Oh, my God. You're
right. Go global.
Bailey, you are a genius.
Oh, Cristina. How'd
it go with Bailey?
So great. Did you
get her to talk?
No. Why?
Okay, just remember,
bright and sunshiny.
Hi, Bailey. It's Arizona.
Listen, I understand
that you're mad.
But you know, there's no
reason for you to be mad alone.
You can be mad at us.
You can yell and scream and
throw things, 'cause we can take it.
She's a grown woman
giving us the silent
treatment. It's a cry for help.
Or it's her way of
saying "Leave me alone."
Fine. You want to give
me the silent treatment?
Well, I can give it right back.
Oh, come on,
Bailey. Just talk to me.
So? What'd you find
on smoking nipple?
The restaurant said the drink
is made with liquid nitrogen.
Damn.
Well, it blew out her stomach,
so happy birthday, Kimmy.
There's hardly any
gastric remnant.
What's your plan
here? A Roux-en-Y.
I'm gonna remove
the stomach completely
and then reattach the
intestine to the esophagus.
I need another surgeon,
so I paged Bailey.
Bailey's not operating.
Webber's taking her cases.
And he's with Dr. Grey
on that chain saw lady.
That's okay. I'll
just get an intern.
You're not doing
this with an intern.
I'll do it with you.
Really?
I don't get to see a
torched-out stomach that often.
I want to scrub in.
Jackson.
I am so sorry
about the other day.
Just blaming you for
everything, my whole crappy life.
I'm just...
You know, I'm crazy.
I know.
I know you are.
But you're about
to do a Roux-en-Y.
I'd say your life's
pretty good right now.
Hey, I heard you guys are
going back in. What happened?
Abdominal compartment syndrome.
We need to decompress
her abdomen.
Okay, obviously,
you don't need me.
By the way, it's not just
me. Bailey hates all of us.
Not now, Torres.
She won't even turn around
when someone comes to the door.
I mean, you'd probably
get her to open it
if it were you, Richard.
That's probably true.
I said not now. Scissors.
No, I'm just saying, you're probably
the one person who'd get through to her.
No! I am the one person Bailey
does not want to see right now.
I hurt her, deeply, and I'm
not sure I'll be able to repair it.
So let's leave it alone. And let's focus,
please, on saving this woman's life.
Sorry, Richard. I'll come back
for the pelvis when you're done.
Are you still on the phone
with France about the coma fix?
No, I'm booking us
a vacation in Nice.
You want a facial the first day?
Their trial was specific to
coma patients with head trauma.
Um, Mexico City's
trial focused on
comas triggered by
diabetic ketoacidosis, so...
So you have nothing.
Oh, good. You're
here. Come on in.
Uh, don't you think it's a
little packed in here already?
Moyamoya's rare.
Everybody's gonna want
to see an omental graft.
Come on a little closer.
Make room.
Wilson, step forward. You
can't learn from back there.
Thank you, Dr. Shepherd.
At what point do you
lay down the omentum?
That's a good question.
Uh, well, after you expose
enough of the brain to check
the blood supply with a doppler.
Which is good. Nice work, Karev.
Okay, show time. Here we go.
Wow. Look at that. Where?
Right there. In the
field. Do you see it?
The brain is just
so starved for blood.
If all goes well, in several
weeks, it'll suck the vessels dry.
It's like a vampire.
Okay. Show's over.
Anyone who's not
needed can head on out.
So if we're lucky,
in several weeks,
something may or may not happen.
Well, I'm sorry I am
boring you, Brooks.
Wilson, you interested?
Yes. Scrub in. You
can help me close up.
Nobody likes a dumb trixie,
but this surgery is so much fun,
I kind of love her for
burning a hole in her stomach.
Metzenbaum, please.
I know.
I know you're thinking
I'm an awful person.
I was actually
admiring your technique.
Do not get a big head about it.
You should talk.
Fancy plastics fellow who
also happens to own a hospital.
Which means I spend half my
time in meetings and not the OR.
You know, I just flew out a facial
reconstruction specialist that...
I don't know.
She gets to fly around the
world and perform miracles.
You're holding this
place together, Jackson.
That's pretty miraculous.
Thank you. You're welcome.
So the good news is,
the ultrasound revealed
the encephalocele itself contains
only fluid, no actual brain matter.
So I will resect it,
and hopefully, this little guy's
looking at no developmental defects.
Amazing.
It's just luck.
Hi, sorry.
Arizona, when you have a
second, I need help with Bailey.
Yeah. Hey. Hold on. No.
This is Dr. Boswell.
She's consulting
on the sims baby.
Uh, hi. Dr. Callie
Torres. Ortho.
Do you mind if I sit in?
You see these, like, never.
No, yeah. Yeah. Please come in.
The more, the
merrier. Yeah. Yay.
So then I will take a calvarial
bone graft from the parietal skull
and then use it to form
the base of the skull.
I mean, you can use synthetics,
but where I can
use his own bone,
farm local, right, Dr. Torres?
Yeah.
After that, it's really just
a standard cleft lip repair,
which I'm sure you and
Dr. Avery can do in your sleep.
Uh, well...
Yeah, but since you're here,
we could watch and learn.
All right, then.
In that case, I'll try
to show off a little.
I'm a little bit
in love with her.
Oh, good. I didn't miss it.
Nope. Just in time. I think.
Well, it was her idea.
No, you won't come out of the
lab. You gave us no other choice.
Bailey, just hear us out.
Yeah, Avery wants to apologize.
We all want to apologize.
Yes, he screwed up. He knows
that. He should've had your back more.
Derek, go. Yeah, you know,
I would be just as
mad as you are.
You've seen me mad.
I hang out in the woods
and I drink myself
into a stupor.
But the thing I've learned from
hiding out is, it doesn't work.
And, Bailey, we need you.
This hospital does
not work without you.
Ugh.
9-1-1 in the ER. Gotta go.
Guess what, lady?
This isn't even your lab.
Okay? We bought it for you.
Was it too much?
Yeah.
What's going on?
He got into his grandma's sleeping
pills. Unresponsive. BP 74 systolic.
Okay, let's get him to trauma room
one. Let's prep for a gastric lavage.
No! You're too
close to this. I got it.
All right, let's start a
flumazenil drip, now.
When I woke up from my nap,
he was on the floor.
I couldn't wake him.
You know what happens now? She is legally
obligated to contact social services.
It was an accident. He took an
overdose, Nancy. What were you thinking?
Were you thinking?
Please, he can't die. Oh, God.
He can't die, too. He can't.
Dr. Meadow to
labor and delivery.
Dr. Meadow, labor and delivery.
Is he stable?
I think so.
We're still monitoring him.
But we got him in time to
administer the flumazenil
to reverse the effects
of the zolpidem.
So hopefully,
he'll wake up soon.
Okay. Listen, about
the social services...
I already called them. The
social worker's on her way.
It's a GABA agonist. Yeah.
Owen, zolpidem is a GABA
agonist. We can reverse the effects.
Wait. We want him to wake up.
So why are we giving
him sleeping pills?
Zolpidem triggers the GABA pathway,
causing drowsiness in normal brains.
Where the chemical
balance has been disturbed,
studies have shown that the
drug can reverse the effect.
This could actually wake him up?
So how long before we...
All the cases said
it took only minutes.
Is she gonna be okay?
Um, the next 24 hours
is gonna be critical.
I'm hoping to see her liver
and kidney function improve.
So she's out of the woods?
He didn't say that, Danny.
Okay, you two, stop it.
Stop fighting.
Whatever happened, whatever
the history, you need to get over it.
It's not important.
She needs you.
You know, I...
I saw how unhappy she
was, and I just ignored it.
She tried to talk to me a
couple of times, and I just...
I just shut it down.
You know, I thought if I could get us
better gigs and make some more money
and become more famous that...
maybe she'd love me again.
Danny, right now we need
to be thinking about Kayla.
I am.
She doesn't need
me. She needs you.
You...
You see her. You love her.
You're the one who can help her.
Alex, come on.
Can we at least try
and talk to each other?
I'd like to feel like I don't
have to avoid pediatrics,
that we could
still work together.
So that's what you're worried
about, not being on my service? Nice.
No. That's not...
I've done nothing but
try and help you. Really?
Because every time you say
anything, my life gets worse.
Things with Jason
were perfect...
I'm sorry if your boyfriend's an
idiot and can't deal with your past.
But that's on you. Obviously,
you like them like that.
As for me, I'm sick of
crazy chicks with problems.
Stay out of my business, okay?
Don't worry. I'm out.
Give it a good
squeeze. Squeeze tight.
There you go. There you go.
That's amazing. Her hand's
already stronger. I can't believe it.
Yeah, and no more TIAs?
Well, ideally, her brain will learn to
soak up the blood she's been missing.
Not right away. In a few weeks.
I want to go. Now! Now! Now!
No. No, no, love. Just a
few more minutes, okay?
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey.
We're almost done here.
Hey, listen. Hey, listen to me.
Your sister needs rest
today. You want to know why?
'Cause we opened up her
head and we put magic inside.
So I'd be nice to her if I were
you, 'cause she has special powers.
You understand?
That's what I'm talking about.
He put a vampire in her
head. I'd watch out, kid.
What do we do
about spring break?
Maybe she'll be better.
I mean, if she can eat without a
stomach, she can probably still drink.
Plus she'll be super thin.
No.
No, she can't drink.
Why don't you skip spring break
and help your friend get better?
But we already put the
deposit down on the condo.
Yeah.
Then go to the condo and
bring your books. Study.
You could be a doctor
or a CEO of a company...
or a senator one day.
Help each other get good
grades and become awesome.
Don't you want to
be awesome? Um.
Totally. I guess. Yeah.
Good! Yes. Aspire to greatness.
Nice work.
You think you got through to
Dr. Dumbass and senator Skank?
Not even a little bit.
Is it weird that all I want to
do right now is go for a drink?
Hey, you want to go to Joe's?
No, actually, thanks. I have
something. I have plans.
So...
You know what? I
just remembered,
I'm supposed to meet up with Matthew
anyway, so maybe another time?
Yeah. Good night.
Damn it.
Give it another minute.
Some patients woke up
after five minutes. Others...
Cristina, it's been an hour.
And there's a social worker
downstairs waiting to take Ethan away.
Dr. Bailey.
I put a woman back
together today, Bailey.
She was split in
two, and I fixed her.
Dr. Webber and I, we fixed her.
You know, I don't know what's going
on with you two, but you need to stop it.
It's childish and selfish.
You need to stop.
Dr. Bailey.
It's an unusually
aggressive infection.
Do you have my results?
The infection came from one
doctor, and one doctor alone.
She's been isolated and the
infection has been contained.
This is going to be a nightmare.
First patient, Joyce
Basche. She didn't make it.
Dr. Miranda Bailey is a
carrier of MRSA USA600.
The only doctor who
touched all three patients...
Did you scrub? Was you.
For how long did you scrub?
It's an unusually
aggressive infection.
And one doctor only.
But we're gonna
take care of her.
- Did you scrub?
- It's a third one.
You have my results. Can
you get me my results, please?
For how long did
you scrub? I did.
One doctor alone.
She's been isolated.
Dr. Miranda Bailey...
I have the strain of staph?
5:30 p.m.
Did I do this?
Hey.
You want to tell
me what happened?
I just wanted to go to sleep.
Ethan, you know how dangerous it
is to take medicine that isn't yours?
You could've died. Never take any
pills without a parent's permission.
I don't think I have
any parents anymore.
Hey. Hey, that's...
That is not true.
Your dad is...
Can't you try something else?
Why aren't you trying anything?
We are.
We're trying everything we can
think of to wake him up, Ethan.
We haven't given up on him.
Neither should you.
Hey. Hey. Come on.
It's gonna be okay. Okay?
Hey, you want to go
split a few dozen pitchers?
Yes. Yes, I do.
What is up with that?
I don't know and I don't care.
I told her the guy was a
douche. Whatever. Let's go.
What did the social worker say?
Uh, she said these were
extraordinary circumstances,
which is why she wouldn't
take Ethan into custody.
But I think maybe she should.
Nancy, he is okay.
You can do this.
No. That boy needs his mother.
A mother or father. I mean, he needs
a home, a place to run, and a school.
I can't even drive
anymore. I have cataracts.
I take the bus to see
my husband at the facility.
Is there anyone?
Anyone in the family?
A cousin, a distant
relative, that...
No, no. Rachel lost
her parents young, and...
No. No.
It's just me.
What am I gonna do?
Nancy, take a breath.
Let's just focus on finding
a solution for right now.
But it's not just for right now.
You know it as much as I do.
Paul...
is gone.
My God, how could we have
lost both of them all at once?
He Needs someone
to look after him,
and I can't.
I just can't.
Oh, crap.
Good luck.
I know. I know.
I have not been...
No, shut up. Shut up.
The most available
or attentive... Shut up.
I know. I'm just... Shut
the hell up. Shut up.
Right now I need for
you to not talk, okay?
It's 'cause you're head
of the hospital now, right?
That's why you haven't
called me in 11 days.
Because I hate myself. I hate
that I know how many days it's been
since we hung out.
And I hate myself even
more for asking you about it,
like some needy, boring,
boy-obsessed little girl.
Who I'm not. Let's
be clear about that.
But I do need to know
why it's been 11 days.
Now you can talk.
Because I'm the
head of the hospital.
Come on. That's no
excuse for standing me up.
You just said... I don't care.
I deserve to be treated better.
So...
You know, do that.
'Cause I just...
Hey.
I was hoping I'd run
into you again today.
Has there been a
change in Tyler's surgery?
No.
People tell you all the time
you have really pretty eyes?
What are they, hazel?
Blue?
They're blue.
I'm married.
I'm happily married.
Um, you met her earlier today.
Dr. Torres. Ortho.
Hot. Brunette.
And wow, talk about eyes.
Pretty eyes. Hers are just
magical. And I'm married.
Also, I have one leg.
I know.
Do you know how many Arizona
Robbins there are on the Internet?
One.
See you tomorrow.
You put a chain-sawed lady back together
while I suffered through a moyamoya.
The moyamoya fix is amazing.
Using the omentum
for revascularization...
You still trying to figure
out how the trick worked?
I think I figured out
where the trapdoor is,
but I still don't understand
when the switch happens.
You don't want to know,
kid. Trust me. It'll ruin it.
Hey.
You made the flight?
Yeah, just barely.
Thanks for the call. Sure.
She needs you.
As surgeons, we are no stranger
to the breaks and
tears in the human body.
In fact, we sacrifice the
better part of our 20s...
learning every possible
way to make it whole again.
Miranda. Open the door.
But there are some wounds
a surgeon can't repair.
Not on our own. It takes a
kind of power we just don't have.
I got on a plane
as soon as I heard.
Who called you?
It doesn't matter.
Yeah, it does.
Your intern exams
are coming up soon.
And I'm your husband. Being
there for you is my main job now.
There's no need to keep doing
things by yourself anymore.
Come here.
This wasn't your fault.
Yeah. Yeah, it was my fault.
No, you were cleared.
No, it was my infection.
I put my hands in those
patients, and they died.
I operated on
them, and they died.
A son, and a mother
and a teacher.
I knew their families.
And they all died because of me.
Now they want me
to go back in an OR.
I mean, they say that it...
It doesn't happen again,
but nobody knows that.
I've been testing myself
and testing myself
and testing myself.
But it doesn't go
away, the feeling.
I feel so...
dirty.
Just all the time.
So dirty.
No.
They all died
because of me.
No.
They died.
No. No.
You've changed.
You want a kid.
Don't you?
I want you.
Owen...
There's no such thing as magic.
Yeah!
Not in the traditional... Hi.
Abracadabra,
genie-in-a-bottle kind of way.
So good.
Thank you. Thank you. Cheers.
Mmm. Oh, my God.
She's so perfect.
Yep.
What if he's a monster?
He's not gonna be a monster.
What if he hates her?
What if he steals her toys?
Well, he is gonna steal her
toys because that's what kids do.
Can I have some more?
Lookit. She's just so happy.
You don't have any idea
what's gonna happen, do you?
I think she will
handle him just fine.
You're wearing a
princess crown. I am.
She's very good at getting
people to submit to her will.
Mmm. Good pinkie action.
Won't you give me some
more tea, sweetness?
Delicious.
Oh, man. You're killing me here.
I'm trying to leave you alone.
I'm trying to get out of your
freakin' life, but you're everywhere.
And now you show up
to tell me the same thing?
Well, guess what.
But there is a magic in knowing
that while not everything
can be repaired...
Can I stay here?
Please.
Most everything can be survived.