Damn it, Zach. This is the
last time I'm turning around.
The next time you forget something,
you're gonna be on your own.
I can't play without a stick.
Then I guess you won't play.
I don't care. I suck anyway.
Don't say that.
I'm the worst guy
on the whole team.
No, you're not.
Then who's worse?
Don't worry about anyone
else, just do your best.
See? You can't name anyone.
Zach, stop it.
Then name someone.
You can't, can you?
Donny, Mark, Navid...
You really think I'm
better than those guys?
Yes.
Hurry up and get your stick.
Zach, get back in the car.
I need an ambulance
at 860 Oakwood Avenue.
Why is Dad's car on?
Get back in the car, Zach!
Come on.
Don't do this to me,
Jeff. Don't do this!
I'm sorry. I just... I couldn't
take the pain any more.
Either I need a new watch or Mowgli
is cutting into your beauty sleep.
I was up all night
looking at finance reports,
and Rachel is doing
great, thanks for asking.
Proving that you're a better foster
mom than a homeless drug addict.
Departmental budgets
are due this week.
I'm gonna need an extension.
I've got some
time next decade...
Cameron already turned yours in.
That's nice of her.
Two questions, why did she,
and why are you telling me?
Same answer. Now
you owe her a favor.
I'm gonna need an
extension. I've got some time...
House, I've got a DYFS
home visit on Friday.
And I've got a
W-H-O-R-E visit on...
Mama's busy. You two are gonna
have to go play outside for a while.
32-year-old male with
chronic pain all over.
This is the favor?
I was expecting something involving
whipped cream and tongue depressors.
He's seen seven different specialists over
three years, no diagnosis and no relief.
Oh, I am fascinated already.
It's like I'm treating myself.
He gets cured, and I get
to learn a valuable lesson
about the milk of
human kindness.
If I thought you learned
lessons, I never would have quit.
So you're wasting
a favor because...
I think you can help this guy.
Drug-seeking patients...
Don't attempt suicide with
medicine cabinets full of narcotics.
Sounds like fibromyalgia.
Sounds like you
don't work for House.
A diagnosis that provides
neither an explanation nor a cure
is, by definition,
not a diagnosis.
The American College of
Rheumatology would disagree.
There're specific
diagnostic criteria...
Which this guy doesn't meet.
Putting pressure on his pain
helps, doesn't make it worse.
He's got abdominal pain, severe
headaches, muscle cramps that come and go.
And he tried to off himself.
He's, obviously, mentally ill.
The pain's probably psychological.
It's not a sign of mental
illness to wanna be pain-free.
It is if your solution
is sucking on a
tailpipe. Sane people
don't attempt suicide.
Not ever?
So, if you were being burnt at the
stake and someone handed you a gun...
I'd shoot the guys
with the torches.
Not one doctor this guy's
seen in the past three years
has been able to find a
single thing wrong with him.
What does that tell you?
It means they're idiots.
It means we got to
start from the beginning.
And do a pain profile to
rule out psychosomatic pain.
Search the home. Go home.
Get a refill. And a donut.
I'll help with the home.
"Choose the
statement in each group
"that best describes how you've
been feeling lately, including today."
I'm not depressed. I
know what I did was stupid.
"I usually sleep well. I have
some trouble with sleep.
"I have a lot of
trouble with sleep."
I have a lot of trouble.
It's up and down.
Between the pain and the meds,
his sleep pattern's pretty erratic.
"He's a calm person. He's
more nervous than most people.
"He's so nervous
he's miserable."
He's definitely calm.
Sometimes calmer
the worse the pain gets.
I think talking, interacting with
other people, actually makes it worse.
Interesting.
Why, does that mean something?
No, it's just...
We've seen that
in other patients.
"He can do chores
around the house.
"With help he can do chores.
He no longer can do chores."
He helps all the time.
He's really strong. He used to
play hockey. He was really good, too.
"I believe there's hope. Hoping for
things to get better is a struggle for me.
"Most of the time I feel
completely hopeless."
He still laughs, all the time.
He was always optimistic.
Still is. It's just, it's harder now.
I guess I pray for
strength more than hope.
There's nothing in there but a
pharmacy's worth of pain meds.
This guy makes House
look like a Christian Scientist.
He's also more compliant
than House. Kept all the inserts.
Had daily pill dispensers to
make sure he didn't mix them up.
Guess if you're gonna go out in a
car, this ain't a bad one to choose.
If I ever did it, it definitely
wouldn't be like that.
Don't worry, I'm not
making any plans.
I certainly wouldn't know.
Ever since we kissed,
you've been avoiding me.
No, I haven't. I've
just been busy.
Metal polish could cause nerve
damage, if he inhaled enough of it.
And judging by the shine on
that car, he used a fair amount.
And judging by the fact that he
owns a body shop, and one of these,
I'd say he knew not to inhale.
Busy tonight? We
could get some dinner.
I don't think so.
So, making out, okay,
meals, too intimate?
I don't wanna kiss
you again, either.
Why? Because we work together?
No. Because I like you.
That makes a lot of sense.
What doesn't make sense is
me getting involved with anyone.
I thought you'd gotten past that.
That's why you agreed to the drug trial.
You can't give up
on life because...
I'm not giving up on life,
I'm just giving up on you.
I finally feel like I have a grip
on things, I can handle this.
What I can't handle is dragging
anyone else down with me.
Does this look
like quail to you?
You think he's had food poisoning
every day for the last three years?
Wild quail can be toxic,
cause rhabdomyolysis,
which would explain his pain
as well as the elevated CK levels.
So would the carbon monoxide
he sucked out of his car.
It's not a toxic reaction, it's
a psychosomatic reaction.
The pain profile showed an excessive
concern about his physical health,
difficulty sleeping,
getting out of bed...
He's not in pain
because he's depressed,
he's depressed
because he's in pain.
Not according to the pain profile
you ordered. It's not a diet issue.
We should start him on antidepressants,
for his sake as well as his family's.
We're not diagnosing his family.
We're not
diagnosing you, either.
It's rhabdo.
Push IV fluids, check his
urine, do a muscle biopsy.
What muscle? He
says it hurts all over.
Then she'll biopsy all over.
Where are you going?
If Cuddy can come in
late, I can leave early.
If you need anything while I'm
gone, just ask Cameron to do it.
So if he just stops eating
quail, the pain will go away?
If we're right, it's
definitely treatable.
My arm, it's starting to...
- He needs more medicine.
- BP's down.
We need to get him in
Trendelenburg position.
- Jeff, can you hear me?
- He's arresting.
We need a crash cart in here!
He's not answering
his cell, either.
V-Q scan showed a
pulmonary embolism.
Means the pain's
not psychosomatic.
Also means it's
not rhabdomyolysis.
Up till now his heart and lungs were
the only places he didn't have pain.
Means it's getting worse.
You gotta let the phone ring more than
four times when you're calling a cripple.
Chronic pain and
pulmonary embolism, go.
How'd you know he had
a... Call after midnight,
it's gotta be a heart problem. Heart
only would be consistent with rhabdo,
which means Thirteen and
Foreman would be singing in the rain,
which means it has
to be lungs as well.
Hypercoagulable state
could cause pain and a PE.
You think the blood clot was caused
by a clotting problem. That's helpful.
What if it's a cancer
syndrome, like Trousseau's?
Explains blood clots, multi-focal
pain, lack of obvious physical signs...
And why he's gone three
years without anyone seeing it.
Check his chest, abdomen,
and pelvis for tumors.
Why did he think only you
two would be singing in the rain?
Bone windows are normal.
Checking for cancerous
masses in the lungs.
So, who do you know
who committed suicide?
Hemingway, Goebbels,
Romeo and Juliet...
Your mom, dad?
Saying I wouldn't do it
under any circumstances
means my whole
family was suicidal?
No. But categorically insisting
there are no circumstances
means you've got baggage,
personal betrayal, abandonment...
Just because you grew up
in a Charles Dickens novel...
It's people like
me who don't do it.
When your life sucks from the
beginning, nowhere to go but up.
Thorax is clear, no
tumors in the lungs.
The only betrayal comes
from father of the year in there.
He has a wife, a kid, people
who count on him to have a pulse.
Okay.
Switching to high-res
cuts of the abdomen.
My parents live very
happily in Queens.
They never attempted, thought about,
or attempted to think about committing...
What?
There, along his diaphragm.
That's not cancer.
No hurry. I already bathed once
this week. I wouldn't want to look elitist.
Can't do anything till
I write up an estimate.
Fine. Pad it all you want.
Here's a check for the deductible.
Don't touch the piano,
and lock up when you leave.
Sorry, deductible
doesn't apply here.
I'm no architect, but I'm
pretty sure the master bedroom
is part of the home, which
means the home warranty...
Doesn't cover negligence.
This pipe goes through the ceiling,
over that wall and into your shower.
It didn't burst, it
was pulled apart.
Yeah, 'cause I'm clearly a guy who
likes to knock out a few naked pull-ups
before I greet the day.
You hang laundry in there?
I'm about to hang
a plumber in there.
Look, there's no rust,
there's no corrosion.
I don't know how it happened,
but I know what happened,
and it's not covered.
So, whenever you're ready to spend
the $2,200, give somebody else a call.
I promise, I'm only holding your
hand to check for choreiform movement.
I'm getting absolutely
no intimacy from it.
I told you, it has
nothing to do with you.
I know. That's the problem.
There's 80 reasons we shouldn't
date. But you can't shut everyone out.
You're gonna need help, support.
Look at our patient. Thirty-two
years old, not dead yet,
and already he's
traumatized his wife, his son...
And I'll bet they're cherishing
every traumatic minute he has left,
wouldn't trade him for the
healthiest guy in the world.
True. And they're stuck suffering
with him, hating every day,
only their pain has
no prospect of relief.
This a bad time?
No. Yes.
No trace of cancer
in the patient.
But we did find
edema in his intestines,
air in the intestinal blood vessels,
and House won't answer his phone.
His intestine must be damaged,
the air's leaking into his body.
If there's a blockage in the
superior mesenteric artery,
it could be choking off
blood flow to his intestine.
Blockages all over his
body would explain his pain,
why the cramps come and go.
Do an angioplasty on
the superior mesenteric,
and find the other blockages,
before he has another cardiac arrest.
I'll help.
Good thing we don't
have a suicidal patient
with a horrific,
undiagnosed pain disorder.
We did, till we diagnosed it.
We found intestinal edema and air in
the blood vessels. The pain was vascular.
If it was vascular, we
would've seen uneven pulses.
His blood pressure was uneven.
Thirteen and Kutner are doing an angio.
He'd have hemorrhages
in his fingers.
There's air in the intestine, it has
to have come from somewhere.
Yes, it does.
After we thread the catheter
through his groin and into position,
the blood will start
flowing freely again.
Will that take away the pain?
It will be completely ineffective,
and the pain will completely go away.
Cancel the angio. He
has air in his blood vessels.
If we don't open the
artery to his intestine...
Where can air come from?
Hmm.
Air can either come from a breach
of the lumen in the small intestine,
or, in rare instances,
air can come from the air.
Teeth marks.
I'm guessing from when
he blew into his IV tube.
Air bubble caused the
PE and cardiac arrest.
You tried to finish the job
that you started at home.
Jeff, why? You said that...
I lied.
I want to die.
Please just let me die.
No.
He's in a hyperbaric chamber.
A dose of high pressure ought
to chase the air out of his blood.
Is anyone keeping an eye on him?
You know, because the
whole idea of suicide watch
was specifically created
for suicidal patients.
I realize how you might have thought
the name was just a coincidence...
Are there any
visuals in this room
that are key to us learning our
lesson? Because the telephone...
I'm inconveniencing you
because you inconvenienced me.
When was the last
time you showered?
Scent of a man.
I realize you haven't
experienced it sober.
If anyone should be able to
handle a depressed pain patient...
He insisted he was no longer...
Apparently, he lied.
Didn't think I'd have to remind
you of that remote possibility.
I have a DYFS inspection in less
than 24 hours, so if you can't control...
Non-motor seizures.
Sorry, I was thinking about the
patient. What were you saying?
Go on. The pain
started in his abdomen,
near his intestine. The first
symptom's got to be key.
He's had multiple EEGs,
all of them cleaner and squeakier
than Cuddy's rubber nipples.
What about a glycogen-storage
disease, like McArdle's.
Explains the pain, plus there's plenty of
muscle cells in the wall of the intestine.
Fourteen is right. Go run
an ischemic forearm test.
Take the garbage
out on your way out.
If you want a man to take your
crap, you have to marry him first.
Or employ him.
Good girl.
I don't think I'm ready
to run a decathlon yet.
If we can get you managing your
life a bit better, that'll be plenty.
Dr. Hadley,
whenever you're ready.
Janice.
You look better.
Yeah, they said my basal
ganglian volume's improved.
All I know is, for the
first time in two years,
I can drink a cup of water
without spilling it all over myself.
Thank you for getting
me back in the study.
I haven't even
seen you in weeks,
I didn't even know our appointments
were back-to-back again.
Well, they weren't. Mine
got switched this morning.
We're gonna take
your blood repeatedly.
If the increased strain makes your arm
hurt more, you have a muscle abnormality.
If you're right about this McArdle's
disease, can you take away the pain?
With gene replacement therapy,
with lifestyle changes, we can reduce it.
Keep squeezing the ball.
How long does he have to... Maybe
you and Zach should eat something.
Honey, don't worry about us.
I'm not.
Please, get out of here.
These tests are all I can handle.
They're trying to help you.
They can't.
Then how about helping
them? You know, by not being...
An ass? You have no
idea what I'm going through.
I know it's better than
what you tried to go through.
Sure, no baggage at all.
Where's the pain worst
right now? In my left arm.
Does it hurt more? Couldn't.
And lactate level's steady.
It's not any kind of glycogen...
Oh, God! Pain jumped to my
leg. This never happened before.
Your chest, your abdomen,
you feel anything there?
My leg feels like
it's being sawed off.
Nice. What?
Switching Janice's appointment
time, so I can see the skies brighten
like a Lifetime TV movie.
I don't know what you're...
Sticking your most improved
study participant in my face.
Is that your way of
getting into my pants?
I don't make the schedule, and if I did,
I wouldn't use it as a social lubricant.
And this is the first I've heard
of Janice improving at all.
So, hey, thanks
for the good news.
Pain started in his abdomen.
Now it's hopped from his left arm to
his left leg, skipping the trunk entirely.
I need the name of a good
lawyer. We're getting sued?
Probably. That's
Cuddy's problem.
Hopping pain. Means it's
something in his brain, not his body.
Except the pain's in two places that
connect two separate regions of the brain,
which means you're
not using yours.
Come on, you're from
one of the Twelve Tribes,
you must know a ton of shysters.
What type of lawyer do you need?
I'll bring it up at the next world
domination subcommittee meeting.
I didn't say I needed a lawyer, I
said I needed the name of a lawyer.
Pain hopped to another limb on
the same side, it's gotta be central...
Could still be peripheral. If
multiple areas of disc disease...
Were consistent with a
completely spotless MRI.
Who represented the hospital
when you set that patient on fire?
Chris Carrick.
Chris.
That doesn't sound
like a very good lawyer.
If we can't even resolve body versus
brain, we're never gonna diagnose the guy.
What was the name of the firm?
Caddell and Carrick.
It's not like we can chop off his
head to see if the pain goes away.
Why not?
Need to cut off a guy's head.
Gotta figure out if his pain's
coming from his brain or his body.
Stiff shot of Lidocaine
below the brain stem
should numb him all the
way down to his tippy-toes.
And hearing me say "no" over
the phone wasn't good enough?
I'm inconveniencing you
because you inconvenienced me.
You know that foster care
official is coming in the morning...
If they weren't there'd
be no inconvenience.
Do not try and force me to
choose between my child and this...
I'm forcing you to do your job.
If you can't also... Fine.
You want to separate a
patient's central nervous system
from the rest of his body.
If the pain stays,
it's in his brain.
If it vanishes... What about
options three, four and five?
His respiratory system
freezes, or he dies of infection,
or he leaks CNS fluid like a fire hydrant,
which would make him wish he were dead.
Scratch option five,
he's already there.
You preach objectivity, but as
soon as a patient comes in, in pain,
all you want to do is
look under the hood.
You don't care if there's a
one-in-three chance you'll kill him.
If I don't diagnose him, there's a
one-in-one chance he'll kill himself.
I gotta go.
Do whatever it is
you think is right.
Tammy. You said you
were gonna be a little late.
DYFS is gonna be here in an
hour, and this place is a disaster.
Never mind.
This should numb everything
from your shoulders down.
Any pain that's
peripheral should be gone.
What are you doing here?
Just stretching my leg. Carry on.
Bad pain day today?
About to get better.
Don't worry, he's
making yours a double.
I remember when the drugs
still made things tolerable,
when I still thought
I had good days left.
Turns out you have
to live to find out.
You don't have a family, do you?
Left them all back on Krypton.
You're alone. That's why
you can handle your pain.
No need to put up a front, to be
what anyone else wants you to be.
You're having more bad
days lately, aren't you?
Yes.
Take a look at your future. Let's
hope the drugs work this time.
I really wasn't
expecting you till later.
Had a cancellation, so I thought
I'd knock you off the docket.
Well, I'm sorry this place is such a mess,
it's been a bit of a difficult work week.
Any guns in the house? No.
Pets? Besides the ants? No.
Nice bag. Pricey way
to ditch the diapers.
That's not what I
usually... I sort of panicked.
Mr. Carlton, if you'll just
give me a minute to explain...
Everything looks fine.
Really?
Dr. Cuddy, you've
got sufficient income,
a high degree of personal
and professional stability,
and you care enough to be
embarrassed by what a mess this place is.
Believe me, that puts
you head and shoulders
above most of the
foster moms I visit.
See you next year, if you
haven't adopted her by then.
My legs, they're
different, better.
No pain at all? No, but less.
Four out of 10, maybe five.
Can't be.
If whatever's causing the
pain's in your brain, it's still a 10.
In your periphery, a zero.
It is. Some of the pain
is gone, but not all of it.
What does this mean?
Maybe Taub was right,
it's psychosomatic after all.
Which one of you is House?
The big black guy.
Chris Carrick. Next time you use
my name in a threatening e-mail,
it won't be just a
bill, it'll be a lawsuit.
Can you blame me? Last time
that happened, the guy shot me.
What if the spinal block triggered
some sort of placebo effect?
Guy's taken the finest
opiates Blue Cross can buy,
how come they didn't
trigger a placebo effect?
What happened? LYNNE: He just
started screaming. Do something!
Please, God, do not let
it be what his father has.
I think he's faking.
How dare you? What
makes you think...
House, the kid's
in excruciating...
Where is it? Where's what?
His idiot son
distracted the orderlies
so that Daddy Deathwish here
could down a bottle of isopropyl.
Put him on dialysis or in
half an hour he'll be a corpse.
You're hurting me.
Remember the feeling.
Maybe next time you wanna help
Pops, you'll do a better acting job.
You can't help him.
Zach, why did you do this?
Because he's not Dad any more.
He just wants it
to be over with.
Please, please,
just let him die.
Fabry disease might be able to
cause central and peripheral pain.
No angiokeratomata.
Lightning pain from syphilis.
All the syph tests
were negative.
Why aren't you
guys still talking?
Because we ran out of ideas.
Nothing explains this.
Something has to.
Unless nothing does.
So now you think it's...
Mine's a more interesting
version of nothing.
It used to be something.
We can't find anything
because whatever injury caused the
original pain healed a long time ago.
The only thing
left is the drugs.
Opioid-induced pain.
Pain and the drugs that treat pain
work by changing brain chemistry.
Sometimes to the point where pain
receptors read painkillers as killer pain.
Take him off the drugs.
We can't cure him, so
we're gonna torture him?
Torture is the cure. Eventually
his body will recalibrate itself.
Assuming you're right.
Yes, I find it confusing
to assume otherwise.
How would you like
to stop taking Vicodin?
Good thing I'm not the patient.
It's open.
Thank you. Is it too big?
She'll grow into
it. Put it there.
I take it the home
inspection was pushed back?
I passed.
You do realize
that's a good thing?
This place was a disaster.
I had to stash a dirty
diaper in my briefcase.
So you buy another briefcase.
I let House supervise himself.
That's like handing a 12-year-old
the keys to the liquor
cabinet and the car.
You passed the inspection.
The patient lived. The
car is still in the driveway.
And the next time my nanny gets sick?
When House wants to saw someone in half?
Did I mention you
passed the inspection?
I passed by their meager
standard, I failed by mine.
Why do women always do that?
Fail? Create
ridiculous standards
that no human could meet.
With your careers, with your kids.
You gotta be more like us men.
Be lazy? Blame others?
Get help. Most men in your position
have a deputy and two assistants at work,
and a wife and two nannies at home.
You're not Superwoman, don't be a martyr.
We'll be injecting
you with naloxone,
which will knock the opioids
out of your pain receptors.
If we're right, your system will
recalibrate within a few hours,
and most of the pain
will be gone. Hours?
I need those drugs.
Not if they're
causing your pain.
Then knock me out,
sedate me while you...
That takes drugs, too. We need to
clear everything out of your system.
Please, I'll try anything else.
That's what we're
trying to stop.
So it's not your parents, then it's
your wife, someone you were close...
A colleague. We were
residents together.
I should've done more to stop it. He
had the mother of all God complexes.
So busy treating everyone's
problems, he was blind to his own.
Helped himself to a vial of
insulin. It's a miracle he survived.
His friends and family almost
didn't. He was a selfish ass.
It'll be over soon.
This is lunacy. You're
torturing this guy on a hunch.
It's the only hunch we've got.
If I really wanted to torture
him, I'd manipulate a clinical trial
in the hopes that
he'd sleep with you.
Are you suggesting I got Thirteen in
that trial because of some personal...
I think you got her in because
of your usual messiah complex.
I think you messed with
the appointment schedule
because of your I-like-to-have-sex
complex. I checked the logs.
You moved your most
promising patient right before her.
False hope being
quite the aphrodisiac.
How's it false if the
trials are showing results?
If it were that promising, you
wouldn't have to change the schedule.
But, hey, hope springs eternal.
This was a cooking accident?
First time making
Cherries Jubilee.
Awfully big fire.
If you ask me, some of the
portions in that recipe were off.
I sure hope it happens to be
covered, under, say, section three,
subsection 2.2, paragraph
one. "Accidental fire damage."
In which case you'd have to replace the
entire water line to fix the sagging pipe.
I guess so.
I'd hate to have your next-door
neighbors end up with no hot water.
Lucky the fire skipped
your pipes entirely.
It's not working.
I know. I've started him
back on the pain meds.
Which means you can leave.
My son was right.
I've tried for so long
to protect him from...
But I'm the one
who's been selfish.
This is no way for him to live.
Until we get an
answer, it's the only way.
There is no answer.
There's always an answer.
Then what is it? He's
been here for four days.
Three suicide attempts.
You don't have an answer.
When I saw you,
when I saw the cane,
I thought, "Thank God, a
doctor who will understand."
Because I sure as hell don't.
My husband thinks it's over.
So look me in the eye, tell
me you'd want to live like that.
Then stabilize him,
get him in decent enough
shape for the drive home,
so he can finally...
Okay.
There's gotta be something we can
do. We can't just let the patient leave.
We didn't, House did.
Because he realized
there's nothing he could do.
There's always something we
can do, something else we can try.
You're insane. You
know that, right?
Because I have principles?
Because you paid
more to bribe me
to lie on your claim than
the entire cost of the repair.
I don't care if I pay,
as long as the people
who pocketed my premiums
for the last nine
years also pay.
I didn't break the pipe.
Whatever.
You wanna stick it to
the man, that's fine by me.
You happy? No. But I'm right.
Lock up on your way out,
and don't touch the piano.
Testicles. What do
they make you think of?
STDs, testosterone issues,
that summer on Fire Island.
Oh, so close. The
correct answer is epilepsy.
Epilepsy doesn't
cause chronic pain.
It does if it spreads to the
sensory region of the brain,
then rewires the pain neurons.
Would've shown up on an EEG.
Not if the seizures are in a
place you can't see on an EEG,
a place too deep in the brain,
like the area that controls
the muscles supporting the...
Testicles.
Feels like you got kicked
in the nads, doesn't it?
The abdominal pain, how it all started.
It wasn't the stomach. It was lower, right?
It's everywhere.
But when it first started.
It started in the
stomach, cramps.
Like bad gas or a
permeating pain?
Like your kidneys were being
pulled out through your scrotum?
Why?
Because epilepsy is treatable.
Looks like we shot the
guys with the torches.
Yeah. Pays to hang around.
That selfish ass
with the God complex
who almost made the
stupidest decision of his life,
it wasn't your colleague,
was it? It was you.
No.
See you tomorrow.
You're here early.
I'm feeling better.
What's wrong?
IV's leaking a little.
It's no big deal.
I'll be right back.
Foreman.
You busy tonight?
No.
Rita, the spike on Dr. Hadley's IV
bag wasn't pushed in all the way.
I don't want any dosing errors.
Sorry. It won't happen again.
Stinks, doesn't it?
What?
The medication. When we switch out
the bags you can smell it. It's disgusting.
I didn't smell anything.
She must be on
the placebo, then.
You offered to do House's budget
because you wanted him to owe you,
wanted him to take
that case. Why?
I thought it would help House,
seeing someone worse off than him,
possibly curing a guy with
even less to look forward to.
Can I ask you something?
How would you like my job?