Carter.
Morning, Dr. Benton.
Did you pick up my labs?
Right here.
Where's Deb?
She's sick.
Who said she could
be sick? What is that?
Two feet of necrotic bowel.
And what are you doing with it?
I am taking it to the desk.
Research is picking it up.
Soon, I hope.
Guy infarcted. Needed
a crash hemicolectomy.
When?
Couple of hours ago.
Who did the procedure?
Jagman.
Jagman? Damn!
Why didn't you admit the
woman with pressure sores?
Because her problem
isn't surgical. Carter!
She needs to be debrided.
If we don't admit her,
she's not going to heal.
Look, she's diabetic. Maybe
medicine will take her home,
but she's not coming
on my service.
Hey, Peter, those
Dale Carnegie classes
are really starting to show.
He's been on for 48
hours straight. Really?
Traded a couple of shifts
with people last week
so he could be with
his mom, and now it's...
Payback time. Yeah.
Carter, there's a
code brown in two.
Find a nurse. Clean
it up now. Move.
Unfortunately,
payback rolls downhill.
Did I miss her breakfast?
We're just starting.
The family development
person came by
and stayed for three hours.
Ms. Brown called.
She said you passed
with flying colors. Really?
They're expediting
your application.
Oh, Helen, I can't
thank you enough.
How's she been?
Fever's gone, but I
think she's homesick.
Dobreya utro.
Ti okay?
Botchemu.
Ya skuchayu za Inga.
Ah.
She misses the nurse
she was close to in Russia.
Can I ask her if she
wants to come live with me?
Sure.
Tatiana, ti hochyesh
zcheet samnoy?
Ew tayba doma?
Da, ew meenya.
Ew teyba est VCR?
Yes, I have a VCR.
Hey, Doug.
Hey, is that Mark Greene,
the future E.R. attending?
You found out?
Not from you, schmuck.
I didn't want it to
get out, you know,
till Morgenstern made
the announcement.
Word's out. Congratulations.
Thanks.
What did Jen say?
She signed on for
another year with the judge.
In Milwaukee? Oh, no.
It's been awful, but
if I can make this shot
there's still hope
for my marriage.
There's hope.
When did the rash appear?
Two days ago with a fever.
It started on your chest?
Yeah. Then it spread.
I think I'm allergic
to one of the
medications I'm taking.
What are you taking?
Here.
"P-43B, ZX-7."
I've never heard of these.
They're experimental.
I'm a test subject.
You know, answer those
ads in the school paper:
If you suffer from asthma
nicotine addiction,
panic attacks,
call this number,
earn extra cash.
They pay you?
Oh, yeah.
I'm doing this one
where they inject...
radioactive isotopes
into my brain.
That one pays real well.
Well, I guess we call the
numbers on these vials
to see which drug is
causing your reaction,
but for now, your test
subject days are over.
Oh.
How much you make a year?
Did you stick Mr. Penny
for his blood gases?
Stuck him. Well, all right.
Discharge the abscess.
Just need your signature.
Dr. Hicks, a bowel infarction
came in this morning.
I wasn't called.
You've been
trading shifts again.
That's irrelevant. I
was the resident on call.
And as a result, you've
been on for 48 hours straight.
I don't see what
that has to do with it.
Have you slept at all, Peter?
Look, I require
very little sleep.
I am perfectly capable
of handling my patients.
I didn't think so.
You shouldn't be treating
patients in your condition,
much less doing surgery.
I've never done
a bowel infarction.
Jagman has done two.
Oh, for God's sakes,
Peter, this isn't a competition.
Oh, no? Then why are
we required to keep logs
of every procedure that we do?
As a record, not a scorecard.
Oh, yeah. Right. You're
keeping score, and you know it.
That's enough.
I'm concerned that
your fatigue is
impairing your judgment.
Find a room. Lie down two hours.
That won't be necessary.
This isn't a suggestion.
You will not see another
patient until you've slept.
Got it?
Captioning sponsored
by WARNER BROS.
Are you kidding, Susan?
We don't have time to
sort through these drugs.
Turf the kid to medicine.
I tried.
Got into a screaming
match with Warner.
She won't even come
down for a consult.
Screaming doesn't
work with Warner.
You have to use
the soft sell. Observe.
Morning, Jer. What do you got?
Uh. Full house. Take your pick.
Dr. Ross, Diane Leeds
in risk management
just called for you.
Oh, yeah? What'd she want?
She said she wants
to go out with you.
What?
Just kidding.
I think it was
something about that guy
you decked the other day.
Jerry, did I ever I tell you
you're my least favorite clerk?
I am not a clerk.
I'm an emergency
service coordinator.
Doug, we've got a
burn in one. Mm-hmm.
Carter, here. Write these labs.
I'll take the knee lac in five.
You know, I noticed
exam four is open.
What?
In case you wanted to lie down
and take a nap or something.
It was a great catch, Joyce.
I never would have
thought of sickle-cell...
Yes, you do.
Anyway, I do have a favor.
This kid on experimental
meds is getting worse.
Susan Lewis can't
make heads or tails of it.
Could you please come
down here and bail her out?
Ah. Thank you.
Here you go. She's
on her way down.
Thanks.
Ow! Ow!
It's okay. How'd this happen?
It's my fault.
The plastic knob came off
the radiator in the kitchen
and she grabbed the metal part.
Bonnie, can you wiggle
your fingers for me?
Just wiggle them.
Are you okay?
It's my fault. Ow! Ow!
She's got a second-degree
burn, Mrs. Howe.
I don't think it's going to
affect the use of her hand.
We're going to clean
it up with some saline.
Okay, Bonnie, you
hang in there, okay?
I've never seen
a star-shaped
radiator knob before.
Nope. I'm going to call
around to other hospitals,
see if she's been
seen anywhere else.
Excuse me. Can you help me?
Excuse me.
Malik, get a gurney.
What happened?
He was sitting
in the restaurant.
Just finished breakfast
when he keels over,
starts shaking and shivering.
His eyes roll back in his head.
What is it?
Sounds like a seizure,
grand mal type.
Curtain two's open.
No tongue abrasions.
No signs of incontinence.
Are you related?
No, no. I manage the restaurant.
Thank you for bringing him in.
We'll take it from here.
Just a second.
Look, if he's okay,
have him call me, okay?
Well, I know this sounds bad,
but he didn't pay the check.
He had the champagne brunch...
Steak and eggs.
It was a $35 meal.
Neighbor heard a crash,
found him at the bottom
of the stairs.
Vitals?
80/60. Heart's racing at 128.
Did you get any I.V. in?
No. I couldn't find a vein.
All right. Haleh,
prep for a central line.
Okay, people.
Let's get him in.
Let's get him
across on my counts.
Now, listen, we're going
to do this nice and gentle.
Do you hear me?
One, two, three, go.
Here we go. Here we go.
Watch the line.
Here we go.
Capillary...
Betadine.
All right, the old
guy's got a G tube.
Does anybody know his name?
Joseph Klein.
Hypotensive, B.P.'s 50 palp.
Pedal edema.
Congestive heart failure.
No breath sounds.
Trachial shift.
Lung's collapsed.
Must have broken a rib.
This guy's a train wreck.
Let's get a chest tube tray now.
Can I have more? Yeah.
Can you understand
me? Talk to me.
Carter, he can't.
Look at his neck.
No voice box.
He's in pain.
Can we give him something?
Stand by with morphine.
Here we go. All right,
Carter, 28 French. Move.
Start lasix.
80 milligrams I.V. push.
Let's get some
restraints in here.
He wants the morphine now.
Come on. Over here, now. Move!
Line's in.
Load the dopamine
400 milligrams. 250, D5w.
We're going to take care of you.
Everything's going to be okay.
Pressure's 120/80. Not bad.
Reflexes are normal.
I don't see any signs
of a seizure, do you?
No. He has an
irregular heartbeat.
Hey, he just opened his eye.
Really?
Yeah.
Hello in there.
I know you're busy
having a coma.
Do you want to
tell us why, Mr...
Do we have a name?
Actually, we have several.
Art Moss, Sam Hart
and Gene Finch.
Hello. Me again.
I just want to let you know
that you actually do
have a medical problem.
We're going to have to go in.
Rib spreader.
Hell of a way to
get a free meal.
Okay, can you get bloods?
B.P.?
Still low. 60 palp.
Increase the dopamine
ten mics per minute.
You got a number ten blade?
Hang in there, Mr. Klein.
Let's have it.
He came in with
congestive heart failure,
tension pneumo.
He's on high-dose dopamine.
Peter's putting in a chest tube.
Okay, I'll take it from here.
I got it.
I'll take it from here.
Either get some
sleep or go home.
I won't tell you again.
Mr. Klein's old chart came up.
Can I see it?
Check to see what meds he's on.
Chest tube's in.
We got breath sounds.
Pulse ox up to 90 from 82.
Train is back on the tracks.
Nice job, everybody.
Mr. Klein has terminal cancer
and the last time he was here,
he signed a paper requesting
that no heroic measures
be taken to prolong his life.
You and Jen are going to
go another year like this?
I guess we're going to have to.
Hey, Dr. Greene, congrats
on that new attending gig.
Thanks. Jen is adamant about
keeping her job in Milwaukee?
She wants me to move there.
I can't give up this
job as attending...
Can I help you?
Dr. Greene, right?
Yes. John Koch, M.I.T.
Sloan school of management.
What can I do for you?
They didn't call you?
No.
I made arrangements
to observe your department.
I'm doing research
for the Andover project,
which you may have heard of.
Uh... White House
press conference,
profile on CNN?
Must have missed it.
In a nutshell, we're
building a new hospital
for the 21st century,
scrapping the old model
with its competing factions
in favor of a more
collaborative paradigm.
Like a team approach?
Yes, but on a
comprehensive scale.
We're re-conceptualizing
the hospital...
Architecturally,
organizationally, ergonomically.
We hope to build the model
on which all future
hospitals will be based.
So you'd like to watch us to
see how it shouldn't be done?
On the contrary. This place
has a superior reputation.
I want to keep what works
and change what doesn't.
Well, feel free to look around.
Great. Oh, uh,
I couldn't help overhearing.
I may have a solution
to you and your wife's
uh, geographic
impasse. Excuse me?
Kenosha. Midway between
Chicago and Milwaukee.
Commute's less than
an hour each way.
You can live under one roof,
both keep your jobs.
Huh.
Mr. Klein.
Mr. Klein, I'm John Carter.
You might remember
me from earlier.
I brought a pad and pen
in case you want
to say something.
I'll just put them here on
the end of the table here.
Mr. Klein, I'm sorry about
what happened earlier.
Your blood pressure's
still pretty low
so I contacted your H.M.O.
and they're going to
send an ambulance over
to take you to their hospital
once you've stabilized,
but that might be a while.
So... there's no next of
kin listed in your chart.
Is there anyone I can call?
Can you understand
me, Mr. Klein?
Okay.
Mr. Klein?
I'm sorry, I didn't under...
Roger.
Roger. Roger, that's a...
is he a family member?
I-is it your son?
Do you know his
telephone number?
Blooming... B-Bloomington?
He lives in Bloomington?
He lives in Bloomington
and his name is Roger Klein?
Okay. Okay, great.
I will be back in a little bit.
Hey, Lydia, any interest
in becoming charge nurse?
Me? Yeah.
Not on your life.
Oh.
Why do you ask?
Because Tag and I are
going to be foster parents
to that little Russian girl.
The one with AIDS?
Tatiana. I want to spend
as much time as I can with her,
so I'm cutting
back on my shifts.
Really.
What?
Well, it just seems
like a tough way
to start off a marriage.
You think it's a bad idea?
No, I, uh...
Oh, look, Carol,
it doesn't matter what I think.
I'm certainly no
expert on marriage.
Forget I said anything, okay?
Carol, Mercy General's
calling you back.
Something about a
kid with a burned hand.
Okay. I'll be right back.
Sorry. I didn't
mean to wake you.
You didn't.
Came for a blood gas kit.
Any traumas come in?
Yeah. Two-car
accident, lacerated liver,
went up to the O.R.
Who's doing it?
Jackie. Never
mind, don't tell me.
Uh, half hour to go.
Carter, uh, keep
an eye on the charts.
Anything surgical,
bring it to me.
Can I do that?
I thought we were
just supposed to wait
until we were
called for a consult.
Carter...
just do it, all right?
Okay.
Mrs. Howe, can we
see you outside, please?
I will be right back.
Okay.
What? What is it?
Your daughter was
seen at another hospital
with a star-shaped burn,
and we'd like to know
what's going on.
She touched the radiator.
This is not a
radiator burn, ma'am.
Now, what really happened?
It's personal.
Maybe I can talk
with Mrs. Howe alone.
Sure.
Mrs. Howe, I'm sure there's
a reasonable explanation
for what's happening,
but if you want me
to help Bonnie, you
have to let me know
what's going on.
It's okay to tell me the truth.
Most people don't understand.
I'm pretty understanding.
You promise you
won't tell the doctor?
Yes.
She touches
herself... down there.
I tell her not to.
I give her three chances
and then I use the paperweight.
The paperweight?
I put it on the stove.
I didn't mean to hurt her.
I guess I just
left it on too long.
It's not as bad as it
sounds, you know?
My mother did the
same thing to me.
Okay. The doctor is going
to want a plastic surgeon
to see Bonnie's hand,
so you need to stay here
a little longer.
All right.
K-l-e-i-n, first name Roger.
I don't know the street.
Jerry, I need a $20 taxi voucher
to send Mrs. Von Avery home.
I'm out of vouchers,
but I have petty cash.
Hey, Carter, when is
somebody going to come
and pick up this bowel?
I don't know, Jer.
Uh, let's see...
twenty.
Thank you.
Excuse me, could you change a 20
for the vending machine?
Sure, sure.
One, two, three, four, five
five is ten, 15 and 20.
Actually, could I have a
ten for two of the fives?
Uh, okay.
Right there.
Here you are.
Uh... you gave me 19.
19? You're an honest man.
You want to get that? I got it.
Actually, I have ones here.
Why don't I give you a buck?
That'll make 20.
You can give me the
20 back that I gave you
and that'll
make us even.
Okay.
Thanks, boy.
Jerry, when did
this one come in?
Uh, couple of minutes ago.
Great.
Patient's a 52-year-old
male with a history
of calcium oxalate stones.
Intravenous pyelogram showed
a six millimeter kidney stone
in the calyx, consistent
with obstructive uropathy.
Lithotripsy unsuccessful,
urology's been paged.
We started an I.V.
for hydration, and gave him
five milligrams of
morphine for the pain.
And it ain't working!
Mr. Furst, I'm Dr. Benton.
When did the pain increase?
Been getting worse
for two days. Ah!
My internist, Dr. Feldman, said
if the stone didn't
pass this morning
I should get it cut out.
All right, well, I
couldn't agree more.
Let's move him. Let's get
him up there. Here we go.
Oh!
Oh, boy! Oh..!
Peter, hold up.
That's my patient.
Where are you taking him?
Up to the O.R.
He's got an obstructed stone.
Wait a minute. What?!
I haven't examined him yet.
Yeah, well, I have.
You're supposed to wait
until I call for a consult.
Please, doc, let him
go! I'm dying here.
All right, you want
to examine him?
Here, go ahead, examine him.
Don't pull this crap again, huh?
It's all so unnecessary.
Excuse me?
This territorialism...
The friction between
departments.
It's all part of an outdated
patriarchal system
based on confrontation
where he who yells
the loudest wins
even though he
may be totally wrong.
Yep. That's
how it is, all right.
Doesn't have to be.
Picture this: a hospital
without departments
where every floor
is staffed by a team
comprising their
various specialties.
No time wasted on battles
about your service, my service.
They've been replaced by
a more evolved, harmonious
if you will, feminine model
in which the patient
belongs to us.
Sounds good, but does it exist?
It will.
I'm building it.
And you are again...?
John Koch, M.I.T., Sloan
School of Management.
We have a problem.
She doesn't want to wait
for the plastic surgeon.
She wants to take her home.
Where's the social worker?
I paged her three times.
What about the police?
They're supposed
to be on their way.
Okay, you follow my lead.
Mrs. Howe, we
apologize for the delay.
The plastic surgeon wants to do
some more tests
on Bonnie's hand.
Nurse Hathaway is going
to take her up to radiology.
Can I go with her?
I'm sorry, hospital policy.
I want to stay with my mommy.
It's okay, honey.
It's okay, sweetheart.
Come on.
I want my mommy!
Wait, I don't want her to go.
This is her.
No! No! You liar!
Give me back my baby!
Mommy! Mommy!
You lying bitch!
All right, people, let's move.
Let's get him prepped.
Oh, God, please, Doc,
knock me out, will you?
Okay, Mr. Furst,
Mr. Furst, just take it easy.
Help is on the way, okay?
Yeah. All right, here we go.
Oh!
Cripes, Peter, I
haven't put him out yet.
I didn't cut him.
What's going on?
Well, folks, we
can all scrub out.
The stone hath passed.
Oh, thank God!
How are you feeling?
You know, I saw
in the social
history in your chart
that you used to teach
high school English.
Was that here in Chicago?
You know, the hospital
has a pretty good library.
I could bring you
some books if you'd like.
Maybe some Conrad.
I, uh, I spoke to three
Roger Kleins in the
Bloomington area.
None of them...
were your son.
And I, I had the phone company
check all the unlisted numbers.
I couldn't find him.
Is there anyone
else I could call?
How long has it been
since you spoke to your son?
Ten years.
O-oh, 20, 20, 20 years.
I'm sorry.
Oh! Sorry.
Excuse me.
My fault. You're okay?
Yeah, fine.
Six lousy bucks.
I've got it.
Where's the vial?
Here.
Quick, he's coming.
What?
You people have too
much time on your hands.
You should have
heard that little girl.
She cried for her
mother for 45 minutes.
When the social worker
took her, she was still crying.
She's better off.
What? Growing up
without a mother?
Her mother's a monster.
I don't believe that.
I think she was
damaged a long time ago.
I hope, with some therapy,
she can straighten out
and get her kid back.
Well, you're more hopeful
than I am, thank God.
So I hear you're
fostering Tatiana.
You going to try
and talk me out of it
like everybody else?
No, I think it's a wonderful
thing, what you're doing.
Really?
Absolutely.
I always said you'd
make a great mother.
Doug?
Yeah?
A 16-year-old
G.S.W. to the neck.
E.T.A. seven minutes.
Okay.
Thanks.
Please, no dead kids today.
How is he?
B.P.'S falling,
respiration's down.
I don't think he'll
make it till morning.
Thanks.
Hi.
I didn't know what you'd
like, so I brought a few.
Not a fan of Melville, I see.
Mm-hmm.
Oh, God.
Excuse me for a second.
Did you do the
history and physical
on the leg pain in two?
Not yet. I was about to,
but I thought I'd spend
a little bit more
time with Mr. Klein.
Well, that woman's
been waiting half an hour.
Why are you wasting
time on a D.N.R.?
Because he's dying
and he has no family.
Mm-hmm. Carter, this
is your surgical rotation,
not pastoral care.
It's not your job to
become this man's family.
Dr. Benton, I think
there's more to patient care
than just cutting them open.
Mm-hmm, and that's
what nurses are for, so...
do the H & P on the leg pain
and renew everyone's meds.
I've got a drunk to stitch up.
Better go stitch him up.
It's interesting how
modern medicine
systematically dismantles
the rituals of death.
We do everything we can to
make it routine, a non-event.
People don't die
here, they code.
We can do better.
I can't believe I
didn't think of it before.
Kenosha!
Kenosha?
Kenosha. We can live there,
be a family and commute.
Never actually been to Kenosha.
Oh, it's great.
It's right on the lake,
they've got great schools,
the birthplace of Don Ameche.
Well, there it is.
Looks like our next
lucky contestant.
Who is this Diane
Leeds who keeps calling?
A very desirable woman
who will never go out with me.
Why not?
One of her friends
is one of my exes.
Oh, turned you down?
No, I never bothered
asking her out.
You telling me you're
afraid to ask her out?
Nobody likes rejection.
What've you got?
A .38 Caliber clipped
him in the neck.
He's bleeding profusely,
the B.P.'s 60/40.
How'd it happen?
He was robbing a store.
A cop shot him.
Turn him over to me.
I got it. Here we go. Let's go!
What's his story?
He's the cop.
We need to intubate him now.
Get me a blood on pressure bag.
Cross and type for six
and get me an intubation tray.
The bag's dry.
Hang another liter of saline.
Squeeze it fast,
he's bleeding out.
He's bleeding like crazy.
Load up on the O-negative.
No breath sounds.
I have to clamp this bleeder.
Where's Benton?
Anybody seen Benton?
Hey.
Hey, hey.
Hey!
I'll be back.
I'm not getting a pulse.
Blood-Y tubing.
Oh, God. He took it straight
to the heart... thoracotomy tray.
I thought they were
supposed to wear vests.
Yep, they're supposed to.
I need some help in here.
Coming. Susan, you got this?
Yeah, I got it. Where's Benton?
Go get the one in
there with towels.
Got a lot of blood
coming out of his mouth.
Bullet holes in his chest?
Tube's in.
No, just the neck.
He's bleeding in his lungs.
How you doing, Carol?
If I press any harder,
he's going to stroke out.
All right, what have we got?
16-year-old, bullet
to the carotid artery
thready pulse,
blood in his lungs.
We're going to
need to clamp him.
All right, and what's
going on over there?
Cop took a bullet
into his heart.
Susan's cracking his chest.
Dr. Benton?
Wait a second. Get
somebody else down.
I'm going to go help Susan.
Okay. Suction.
I need some elbow
room. Scalpel. Thank you.
His lungs are full of blood.
Suction, right now. Here we go.
All right, retractor here.
This kid's not getting
any blood to the brain.
Yeah, well, he's young.
He's got enough collaterals
to keep him perfused.
Okay, vascular clamp.
Right now. Come
on, Carol, right now.
Thank you.
Okay, lungs are clear.
Okay. And he is clamped.
Move him right now.
Get him out.
Rib spreader.
Hanging more O-neg.
Okay, now let's see.
What do we have in here?
A hole in the ventricle.
Give me suction,
three-o proline on
an atraumatic needle.
Now.
Call the O.R.
We might have a save here.
Where the hell is Carter?
He's missing out on a
valuable education here.
Okay, I'm going to do
a horizontal mattress,
take two bites, twice
go into the coronary artery
both times so I
don't obstruct it.
You want to do it quick,
Peter. His pressure's dropping.
I hear that.
Okay, now listen
up, boys and girls.
The trick here is
to plug up the hole
without closing
off the artery...
which...
is what I've just done.
Peter?
A bullet through the
ventricle, I stitched it.
Who clamped the kid who went up?
I did.
I'm getting a pulse.
Nice job, Peter.
Looks like that rest
did you some good.
Take him up.
Well, what a way
to end the day, huh?
You taking off?
Yeah.
See you tomorrow.
All right, I'll see you.
I don't believe you.
Me?
I just finished
the file on the guy
you attacked last week
and then I get a call
that you've had
another altercation,
this time with a woman.
This time, I was the attackee.
Are you all right?
It's not the first time
I've been clawed
by a hostile female.
You're finally
paying for bad karma.
You have no idea.
I don't know what
legal's going to say
about the fact that I have
to defend you a second time.
You defended me the first time?
That's my job.
I need you to write
out a statement again.
Huh. Don't take so long getting
it back to me
this time, all right?
Listen, Diane?
Can we get some dinner sometime?
I don't think
that's a good idea.
I guess you were right.
I'm...
I'm right.
You got a minute?
Dr. Greene,
endocrinology on six.
I'll take it at the
nurses station.
I won't keep you.
I just want to make
sure that bleeding varices
gets presented next week.
You won't be there?
Nope. I'll be in
Boston. Oh, yeah?
I'm taking over the residency
program at the Brigham.
It's Greene here.
Can you hold on?
Harvard?
Always an ambition of mine.
Well, congratulations.
Thanks. I couldn't be happier.
As far as your becoming
an attending next year
I took care of it.
I gave my recommendation
to the chief of staff.
You're the guy... no
need to look any further.
Thank you. Appreciate it.
It's almost a lock.
Oh.
Of course, you know,
the new guy is going
to have approve it,
but don't worry about it.
Listen, I'm in my office
another two weeks.
Come by. We'll have a drink.
"Sailing these
seas or on the hills,
"or waking in the night,
"thoughts, silent
thoughts of time and space
"and death, like waters flowing,
"bear me indeed as
through the regions infinite
"whose air I breathe,
"whose ripples hear,
"lave me all over.
"Bathe me, o God, in thee,
"mounting to thee, I and my
soul to range in range of thee.
Oh, thou transcendent,
nameless..."
Carter, did you do notes
on all your patients?
I'm doing them now.
They're supposed to
be in by end of shift.
Looks like you've just begun.
I'll have them first
thing in the morning.
You'll be up all night.
That's what happens
when you spend
too much time with one patient.
I consider it time well-spent.
He, um...
he died ten minutes ago.
Carter, why did you put in
for a surgical sub-internship?
Because I want to be a surgeon.
You're wasting your time.
You don't think like a surgeon.
Why? Because I
don't think like you?
I'd like those notes
first thing in the morning.
Cat. "C."
Da. "C" is for "cat"
and "Carol."
Carol, Ms. Brown from
family development
is here for you.
Oh, okay.
Ya viernoose.
Okay.
Hi.
Carol, something came up
in your background check.
You attempted suicide last year.
Uh-huh.
I wish you had told us sooner.
I'm afraid we can't
place Tatiana with you.
There's no way the
state would approve it.
But I'm fully recovered.
If it had happened
three years ago, maybe.
But one year... we just can't.
I'm sorry.
Hi.
I'm working on
it, uh, right now.
How about next Friday?
You're asking me out?
No, I'm responding
to you asking me out.
That was three hours ago.
You change your mind?
No, I don't think so.
So, we're on?
If it means that
much to you, okay.
I don't think
I like the way this
date is starting out.
It'll get better.
We'll see.
Hey, my man's on time.
Hey.
Where's everybody at, Walt?
Jackie and the kids
went up to the lake early
and mom went to bed.
Oh, Jackie said to remind you
that your mother wakes up
bright and early, 6:00 a.m.,
and she'll be
wanting her medicine.
All right, I'll set the alarm.
So, uh, you really
going down on the ice?
Well, it's that or spend the
day in a three-room cabin
with your sister,
the kids and no TV?
Hell, yeah, I'm
going out on the ice.
What time y'all coming back?
About 8:00 tomorrow night.
Look, man, thanks a lot.
I really appreciate this.
Yeah, yeah. Yeah, sure.
There's some leftover
meat loaf in the fridge.
Mm-hmm.
Hey, Walt.
Catch me a walleye, huh?
Yeah, right.
Later, man.
Yeah.
All right.
Hi.
Carol.
Can I?
Yeah.
Yeah, come on in.
What is it?
I lost her.
I've been in therapy.
I've worked hard for nine months
and it doesn't matter.
All they care about is
that I took some pills.
Who?
Ms. Brown...
foster care.
Tatiana?
They won't let me have her.
Oh, Carol.
It's like I'm defective
or something.
No, no, no.
I'm so...
I mean, God...
I'm kidding myself, you
know, that I could do this.
It's so stupid.
You're ice cold.
You should have seen her, Doug.
I mean, she's seven years old.
I tried to explain it to her...
Carol, listen to me.
It's not your fault.
You hear me?
But I promised her I'd be there
and now I'm not
going to be there.
How could you have known?
God...
Maybe...
Maybe I...
I shouldn't have
thought about doing this.
No. You were exactly
what she needed.
You're the only
person who thinks that.
Well, I know you.
Can I stay here?
Has Tag heard yet?
He never wanted her.
Carol, no.
Please.
Why don't I drive you home?
I know.
Oh... oh, God.
The design's been approved.
We've set a construction
start date for June
and we've recruited
world-class physicians
like Borges and Folkman
to our advisory board.
That's impressive.
Well, they know
we're onto something.
The high profile's
attracting resources
and I'm approached daily
by exceptional doctors
about joining the staff.
Are you interested?
Me?
From what I've observed
your expertise, your temperament
auger a very promising
medical career.
Well, I'm flattered.
And, yes, I am interested.
Excellent.
There he is.
Marty, we were
worried about you.
Why do you got to do this?
Do I know you people?
Marty, please, be good.
I brought the restraints.
Don't make me use them.
This is almost amusing.
This is a mistake.
This is Dr. Koch
from M.I.T., Sloan...
Sloan School of Management.
Yeah, I know.
It's his latest thing.
Mm-hmm. A few months
ago, he passed as an O.B.
and delivered two babies
before we caught him.
He's real smart. Reads a lot.
Wait a minute. You're
telling me you're not...?
Susan, it'll get sorted
out, it'll get sorted out.
I just...
was planning to observe
the psych ward anyway.
Come on.
Come on, Marty.
Ho!
Hey.
I didn't expect you.
Where's Rach?
I didn't bring her.
We need to talk.
Yeah.
Yeah, we do.
I can't do this anymore, Mark...
Not living together and
never seeing each other.
I know, so let's stop it.
You're willing to
leave the hospital?
A compromise.
We can live
between Chicago and
Milwaukee... Kenosha.
It's just an hour
in each direction.
We can be a
family again. Mark...
What? It can work.
You want me to commute
two hours a day so
you can take a job?
So we can all be together again.
That's two hours
less for Rachel.
My God, it's bad enough she's
not growing up with her father.
Whose fault is that, huh?
It was your idea
to go to Milwaukee.
Would you rather
I leave her here
with you?
Do you know that, in seven years
you've never given
anything up for me?
Why are you so intent
on making me give up a job
I've spent years trying to get?
You do what you
want, when you want
and you just expect
me and Rachel
to be there for you
when you have time for us.
Jen, come on.
I don't think
we're going to make it, Mark.
We're going to make it.
No, this isn't working.
So, we'll make it work.
We went a year.
We can go another year.
Mark...
I'll do better, okay?
I'll come up more often.
Rachel, she can come down here.
You're not listening.
I am. I'm listening.
I'm leaving you.
I'm sorry.
Freezing rain West of us at
this hour yesterday morning
but that really didn't
amount to much of a problem.
Skywatch 5, our live camera,
we'll take a look outdoors...
Jackie? I need my medicine.
Peter?!
Peter!
Petey...
Oh...
Mom?!
Okay.
Dr. Benton.
Dr. Benton's mother.
75 years old, history of CVA.
She fell down the stairs.
Possible hip fracture.
B.P.'S 90/60.
Heart rate 110.
Legs shortened and
externally rotated.
I got an I.V. of
normal saline going.
O-2 by nasal cannula,
ten liters, C.C.S. 354.
L.O.C. at the scene.
Got her I.V. Okay.
She's waking up now.
All right...
let's move her.
Careful of her hip.
On three. One, two, three.
Call radiology and
get neuro down here.
Carter, check her pupils
and response to pain.
Dr. Benton, what happened?
What happened?
Mrs. Benton?
Can you hear me?
If you can hear me,
squeeze my hand.
Carter, you try.
Mrs. Benton?
I'm John Carter.
We're going to take care of you.
Can you understand me?
Peter, what happened?
Mrs. Benton?
Can you understand
me? Talk to me?
Peter?