Hannah, you okay?
Still can't sleep? I'm fine.
Can I do anything to help you?
Just go back to sleep. I'm
going to go get a glass of wine.
I can keep you company.
You have work in the morning.
Are you sure you
don't want me to?
I'll be right back. Just sleep.
Hannah?
What did you do?
I just wanted to sleep.
I'm calling an ambulance.
You've seen one patient
in the last two hours.
Complicated case.
I'm a night owl.
Wilson's an early bird.
We're different species.
Move him into his own cage.
Who'll clean the
droppings from mine?
Twenty-five-year-old
female with sleep issues.
I'm guessing she's...
What's the medical term?
Upset!
These 25-year-old females,
they're usually completely rational.
They're rocks, really.
My theory seems to
be supported by the fact
that she swallowed a
bottle of sleeping pills.
Get her a shrink. I
need some shut-eye.
She's a little bit more than
upset. She hasn't slept in 10 days.
She's lying.
Without REM sleep, your
neurons start regenerating.
Your brain shuts
down lobe by lobe.
She'd be insane after
five days, dead by 10.
Give me a little credit. I
know what gets you off.
She took the pills to
sleep, not to kill herself.
Clever alibi. They didn't work.
She stayed awake, even though
she downed the whole bottle.
And the longest anyone's ever
survived without sleep is 11 days.
Which gives you about 22 hours.
You stole my article.
I wouldn't do that.
I wrote up the case where we
induced hypothermic cardiac arrest
in the terminal cancer girl.
I wrote my own. I
didn't steal yours.
You knew I was writing
one. You gave me notes!
Got a case.
It can wait. You two finish.
Five bucks says
someone loses an eye.
Fine, you're only
putting off the inevitable.
Twenty-five-year-old female
hasn't slept for 10 days.
I assume the ER tried
giving her some sedatives.
We should up the dosage.
Sedation isn't the same as
sleep. Thanks for your insight.
For someone who hasn't slept in
10 days, sedation is a great start.
Sleep is an active process. Reboots
the system, restores the brain.
Sedatives don't... The
brain is being stressed.
We need to relieve that.
You've had my article on your
desk for the last four months.
I'm a very slow reader.
No fever, no white
count, means no infection.
Schizophrenia?
No delusions. You read his.
Signed it. Didn't read it.
Aside from the sleeping
pills, tox screen was clean.
No cocaine,
methamphetamines or diet pills.
The only medication
she's had recently
are steroids for poison ivy and
ibuprofen for a knee she hurt skiing.
Nothing that would
cause sleep disturbances.
When did you get his
article? About three weeks ago.
Let's go back to the
beginning. How far back?
Genesis.
God said, "Let there be light."
Sleep is initially controlled
by external light cues.
And if her brain can't
interpret those cues...
Optic nerve disease.
I'm sensing another article.
I'll go run the tests.
I'm injecting a dye which will
allow us to take a look at your retina
and your optic nerve.
Everything's kind of blurry.
Normal, because of the dye.
It's going to be that
way the next few hours.
Need a hand? No.
Are we never going
to work together again?
I just don't see the need to make
you feel better by forgiving you.
I wasn't asking for forgiveness.
I was asking if you needed help.
It's unprofessional to be talking
about this in front of the patient.
Maybe that doesn't
matter to you, but...
It doesn't matter.
She's not listening.
She's asleep.
Normal stage-one brain waves.
Maybe she's better?
Still blurry.
You fell asleep. No, I didn't.
Negative for optic nerve
disease. But she sleeps.
For, like, 10 seconds,
maximum one minute.
We also checked the
ocular pressure. It's normal.
And she doesn't know she sleeps.
The brain is often
unaware of stage one sleep.
The CT showed no tumors,
no clots, no seizure disorder.
So she sleeps. She
just can't stay asleep.
You going somewhere with this?
You know what keeps
me awake at night?
Monsters in the closet.
There's no monster in
the closet. We looked.
Well, it's certainly not
showing up on the scans.
Where's Cameron?
She felt I could deliver
the news on my own.
Oh, this is going
to work out great.
Come on.
If you two guys can't play nice
together, I'm taking away your toys.
I don't care
whose fault this is.
If you hadn't... I especially
don't care if it was my fault.
Whatever this woman has,
it's not showing up on our tests.
Which means she's sick, just
not sick enough for us to see it.
You want us to make her sicker?
- Yes.
I want to stress her body.
Specifically her brain.
Keep her awake.
Depriving her of even the few minutes
of sleep she does have, it's torture.
So is cutting
people with knives,
but you can totally get away with
that if you have a doctor coat on.
Those few seconds of sleep are
maybe the only reason she's still alive.
The more symptoms we can force
out of her, the more tests we can do.
The more tests we do the
more information we get,
the quicker we make a diagnosis.
See how much more fun it
is when you guys get along?
You two take the
first four hours.
Hannah?
Hannah!
You fell asleep.
No, I didn't.
Your brain doesn't remember.
It was just a few seconds.
Is this really necessary?
The sooner we find out what's wrong,
the sooner she can get a real night's rest.
Hannah?
Hannah? Hannah.
Ow.
- What did you do that for?
- You fell asleep again.
- No, I didn't.
- We're sorry.
We have to do this.
We don't have to be cruel.
You know what happens
when you're nice? Nothing.
That's how you define
nice? Not stealing?
Doctors!
Did she fall asleep again?
We've got rectal
bleeding. What, all of you?
So the monster is peeking
out from under the bed.
Which either means
she has a clotting disorder
or she has a tumor in her colon.
I'll do a colonoscopy.
Who's keeping her awake now?
I figured once we found another
symptom, it really didn't matter.
Yeah, he's got all the ideas.
Who is with her?
Her partner's donating
blood, so she's with a nurse.
Probably singing her
lullabies. I want her awake.
You have to sedate a
patient to do a colonoscopy.
Why? Just because of the pain?
If you find a tumor in her
colon, you can knock her out.
If you don't, she stays awake.
Oh! God, it hurts.
Can't you hurry? Trust me,
you don't want me to hurry.
God, you're killing me!
Hold my hand.
Keep breathing, nice and steady.
How am I supposed
to work with him?
Maybe we shouldn't be
talking about this right now?
Think I'm overreacting?
I need you to relax your anus.
We're not here. We're skiing.
It's Thanksgiving at Vail.
You want me to think about nearly
killing myself on a snowboard?
Come on, you never fell.
You were awesome.
Is that what you told him? I'm
hysterical and I need to relax my anus?
I told him... How many
cases do we work up in a year?
They're all weird. He could
have written up any one of them.
She's bleeding.
I can't breathe.
Hold on.
We packed her nose
to control the bleed
and started transfusing
two units of whole blood.
The pathology from the rectal bleed
showed traces of nasal epithelium.
So the butt bleed's
just a nose bleed.
That much blood is
not a "just a" anything.
When two people fight this
much, you know what it means.
It's gotta be a massive
sinus hemorrhage
that was draining down
her throat and out the back.
The question
isn't what, it's why.
Oh, get a room.
Rat poison mixed with
some sort of neurogenic toxin
could cause bleeding
and sleep disturbances.
Do you have a specific type
of neurogenic toxin in mind,
or should we just start running
a thousand different tox screens?
Just pretend I'm not
here, I'll be reading.
It could also be some
type of coagulopathy.
Or it could be us. Do you
have any idea what it feels like
to have a six-foot-long hose
shoved into your large intestine?
No, but I now have a much greater
respect for whichever basketball player
you dated in college.
We've basically been torturing
this girl for the last eight hours.
We've been poking her
foot, not punching her face.
Extreme stress can
cause high blood pressure,
which can cause bleeding.
Wouldn't keep her awake for 10 days.
What if the poison
ivy wasn't poison ivy?
She got the rash
that was diagnosed as poison ivy
around the same time
the insomnia started.
Rash plus nose bleed
plus sleep disturbance
equals Wegener's granulomatosis.
Start corticosteroid treatment.
The poison ivy treatment was
steroids. Much lower dosage.
Get her back on the
juice and triple the dose.
Get a cANCA and an upper airway
biopsy to confirm the Wegener's.
She has menstrual problems.
They're really bad. The
pain keeps her in bed all day,
plus she's super depressed.
She said, "Super depressed"?
She heard that birth control
pills can make her feel better.
She wants birth control
pills for her PMS. I guess.
Judging by the redness
around your mom's nostrils
and the tissue she's got
conveniently stashed in her wristband,
I'd say her problem is more
likely a URI than a PMS.
A URI? Upper respiratory
infection. A cold.
I don't think so.
I also think she's got
a problem with a SAC.
SAC?
Thanks for playing.
Stupid American Child.
If you want the pill,
all you have to do
is to walk into any health clinic
in Jersey, alone, and ask for it.
What exactly was your plan?
You're going to exchange
the birth control pills
for some over-the-counter
decongestants
and hope that your mom's
cold lasts another six years?
No.
Is that for a cold? No,
that's for your ovaries.
I assume you
haven't had a stroke.
Have you ever had
a blood clot? No.
Super.
In three months when you need
a refill, take a bus to a free clinic.
Don't wait around hoping
for Mom to get another sniffle.
Not the sharpest chopstick
in the drawer, is she?
Was this just one
of your experiments?
You just wanted to see how I'd react
to being screwed over by Foreman?
Nice idea, but no. This was
just good old-fashioned laziness.
I gotta hand it to
Foreman, though.
He knew that you're a
suck-up and I don't give a crap.
He successfully
exploited us both.
Right, we're both victims. A
simple heads up. That's all I needed.
Maybe between your
incredibly witty remarks
about anal sex and Cuddy's
breasts, you could have tipped me off.
Yeah, but then I'd have
Foreman pissed at me.
And as annoying as you could be,
at least I know you're not
gonna pop a cap in my ass.
Witty, huh?
You, on the other hand,
continue to be flabbergasted
every time someone actually
acts like a human being.
Foreman did what he did because
it worked out best that way for him.
That's what everyone does.
That is not the
definition of being human.
It's the definition
of being an ass.
This will numb you up.
And this will keep your
tongue out of the way.
Don't worry. You shouldn't feel
anything except for a slight pulling.
So do you think
I was out of line?
That article would have sat on
House's desk for the next six years.
I could've told her.
You could have
written it for her, too.
She knows House
as well as any of us.
She should've known
she was waiting for him
to do something he
was never gonna do.
Chase?
Hannah? You still with us?
What's wrong with her
eyes? It looks like REM.
What's that? Rapid
Eye Movements.
It's what your eyes do
when you're sleeping.
But she's awake. Hannah!
Hannah, can you hear me?
Yeah, of course.
Was she sitting up or
lying down? Sitting up.
Then it wasn't REM.
Chase says her eyes
were moving the exact way...
You start her on the steroids?
Not yet. We were still doing...
Then she wasn't sleeping.
How do you know? Because
we haven't done anything yet.
She may be able to sleep with her
eyes open, but unless you also discover
she's got two extra
teats and hooves for feet,
there's no way she'd be able to
maintain enough muscle tensity
during REM sleep to sit upright.
It's a movement disorder,
which rules out Wegener's.
Where's Foreman?
Keeping her awake. Good.
Rabies could cause muscle spasms,
malaise, anxiety and wakefulness.
Pretty unlikely she'd forget
being bitten by a crazed animal.
She could've been exposed
through an open wound.
Does she have a dog?
For less than a week.
She had an allergic reaction,
so they had to give it away.
Allergies.
Animal allergies seems
unlikely, but it's possible that...
When? When what?
When did she get rid of
the dog? About a month ago.
Her girlfriend gave it
to her for her birthday.
Well, then, it's not allergies.
She's just leaving
her girlfriend.
You spoke to the dog?
If her birthday was a month ago,
she would have still been
on steroids for the poison ivy.
Those meds would have
suppressed any reaction
she might have had to the dog,
which means she lied about being
allergic. A dog's a commitment.
You pretend to be allergic
because you don't
want to tell your girlfriend
that you're not planning
on being around that long.
So, I think we can move on
to options other than allergies.
We should still
do a scratch test.
If she's allergic
to one thing...
She is not allergic.
Okay. Well, we could
either base our diagnosis
on your admittedly keen
understanding of lesbian relationships,
or we could do a scratch test.
Do a scratch test.
Are you still feeling a
lot of blood in your throat?
No, it's actually
getting a little better.
Good, maybe things are just
starting to improve on their own.
Just a few more.
Want some water to wash
out your mouth? No, I'm okay.
Come on, that can't taste
good. I'm gonna get you a soda.
It's okay, isn't it?
You and Max seem to have
a really nice relationship.
Yeah. She's very supportive.
When Max got you the dog,
did you lie about having
an allergic reaction?
No.
Why? If you have
preexisting conditions,
it's important we know, but if
you don't, it's just as important.
If I'm wasting my
time doing this...
You're not going
to tell her, are you?
It's none of my business.
She's a good person, and we've
just been together so long, I...
I'm tired of her.
It sounds terrible, doesn't it?
I guess it happens sometimes.
My back hurts.
Hannah, can you turn over?
What's wrong? I'm not sure.
Oh, my God.
She has massive
internal bleeding.
Did she have access to aspirin?
She'd have to
take a hell of a lot.
Why not? Considering
her current mental state.
What about her mental state?
You were right about
her wanting to break up.
That just means I was right.
Doesn't mean she's suicidal.
A bottle of pills is what landed
her here in the first place.
Sleeping pills. God knows
why she'd want them.
What else could cause sleep
disorder and internal bleeding?
Drugs or alcohol could
mess with the sleeping
and compromise the liver.
What are you doing here?
Who's keeping her awake?
Doesn't matter. Liver function
tests are through the sky.
Liver's not
compromised. It's dead.
She doesn't need a diagnosis.
She needs a new liver.
Well, she's not
getting a new liver
unless we can figure
out what's wrong with her.
Test for cirrhosis, 12 hours.
Test for hepatitis, eight.
Her liver's not gonna
last another six.
So your advice
is we just give up?
My advice is that we narrow our
focus to conditions that we can diagnose,
treat and cure in
less than six hours.
And there's
nothing on that list.
The girlfriend
donated blood, right?
Yeah, so?
It means they're the same type.
You can't ask the person she's
about to dump to donate half her liver.
It does seem tacky, doesn't it?
I'm Dr. House.
I'm in charge of your case.
What's going on?
How come no one is
keeping her awake anymore?
You're in acute liver failure.
We can continue the
transfusions and the lactulose,
but it's only a stopgap.
There's really nothing we
can do to stop the toxins
from building up in
your bloodstream,
which means
that, in a few hours,
you will lapse into a coma
and you won't wake up.
I'm sorry.
That's it? You're giving up?
You're not going to try to figure
out what's doing this to her?
Well, even with
the right diagnosis,
any treatment's gonna take
longer than the time she has left.
If it's her liver, can't
she get a transplant?
Wouldn't work
without a diagnosis.
Whatever killed the first liver
would do the same to the second.
But it would give you more time
to make the diagnosis
to get her better.
Well, it might give
us an extra day or two,
but no procurement agency is
gonna let a liver go to a patient
with an undiagnosed,
preexisting...
Hannah and I have
the same blood type.
Couldn't I be the donor?
Well, it is medically possible
for us to take a part of your...
Please, I don't
care about the risks.
You're very lucky to have
such a devoted partner.
I just bought us 36 hours.
Differential diagnosis.
Which monster eats your liver,
screws up your sleep
and causes bleeding?
Does Max know Hannah
plans to leave her?
Didn't come up, so I guess no.
If she knew, there's no way
she'd go through with this.
And if you didn't have
a pathological need
to create a close, personal relationship
with every dying person you meet,
we would be blissfully
ignorant of any ethical dilemmas
and might actually be able to
concentrate on the differential.
The scratch test was negative.
It's rare, but any of the hepatitis
viruses could cause sleep disturbances
and liver failure. No,
PCRs were normal.
We have an ethical
dilemma. No, we don't.
Continue.
What about splenic cancer
or Non-Hodgkin's lymphoma?
She's the right age.
It could explain the bleeding,
maybe the liver failure.
We're withholding information
relevant to her decision to risk her life.
How is that not an ethical
dilemma? It's not medical information.
Who cares? The AMA.
Wilson's disease could explain
the liver and neurological symptoms.
It also causes
bleeding disorders.
No Kayser-Fleischer
rings in her eyes.
Rings don't have to be there if
there's neurological symptoms.
This is immoral. Look,
let's say you're right!
We tell, she changes her mind,
our patient dies. How is that moral?
What else?
Poisoned mushrooms
can cause liver failure,
sleep disturbances
and internal bleeding.
She's not shrooming.
She's a sports nut.
Right, skiers never party.
She's doing this out of
love, and Max doesn't know...
It's only moral to save a
person if they love you?
That's kind of a selfish
way of looking at life.
I like Wilson's disease,
like cancer, love mushrooms.
Yeah, but we don't have
the time to test for any of it.
Before she can get the transplant,
we need to do about 80 procedures.
So, do those tests and
my tests at the same time.
Use the PET to look
for cancer and Wilson's.
While you endoscope
her bile ducts,
scrape her stomach
for mushroom spores.
One of you CT her liver,
while the other two check
protein CA 125 d CA 19.5.
Oh, yeah, anyone says
anything to Max, they're fired.
We have to.
We have to not, because
she's not our patient.
She's getting surgery.
She's someone's patient.
I think that's it.
Great, thank you.
I need a little help.
Inexplicable rash on a patient's
scrotum you need me to look at?
Twenty-seven-year-old
female wants to donate
half her liver to
her dying girlfriend.
That's very generous.
This the sleepless girl?
What's she got? Liver failure.
Sort of figured that out when
you said she needed a new liver.
You don't have a diagnosis?
The transplant buys me time.
Let's just skip the part
where I say this is insane.
It was her idea. If she wants
to be an idiot, it's her call.
You don't need me.
Have one of your team
walk her through the process.
The donor and the donee sort
of have opposing interests, right?
We can't really
advise them both.
You're concerned
about the ethics of this?
What's going on?
What do you know?
Nothing medically relevant.
But you know something,
and it is relevant.
If I can't tell her, I can't
really tell you, can I?
I mean, if you're advising her.
I assume this information
is in the medical file.
In my patient's confidential
file. This hospital's file.
You can either satisfy your
curiosity, or you can remain ignorant,
do nothing ethically wrong, and
my patient doesn't die in three hours.
These tests and the counseling
normally happen over
weeks, sometimes months.
It's okay.
Well, the most important
part we're skipping is time.
Time for you to
change your mind.
I don't wanna change my mind.
Not now, but,
with time and perspective,
maybe we learn things...
If we had the time, we'd
take the time, but we don't.
So can you get this over with?
Either I sign off on this,
or it doesn't happen.
So I need you to listen to me,
because there's a chance
that you will die on that table.
I just want me and Hannah
to be able to lie in bed together
as old ladies,
compare scars.
I need you to lie on your
side and hold your knees.
I'm going to check for
vascular abnormalities
that might prevent us
from doing the transplant.
At the same time, I'm also
checking for mushroom spores
to see if that's the underlying...
I don't do mushrooms.
If you lie about your love life,
maybe you lie about drugs. Open.
Aren't you at all concerned about
what Max is going through right now?
They're shoving a
tube up her rectum,
then they're going to swab
her stomach just like I'm doing.
It's going to hurt
just like this hurts.
Which is nothing at all like the
risk she's taking on the table.
And you don't love her, do you?
I'm not leaving her
because I don't...
I'm not talking about the
leaving. I'm talking about this.
If you care for her at all,
you won't let her do this blind.
You'd really tell? Yeah.
You'd die?
I take it you've seen that.
Seen it, digested it, watched it
blow up my entire department.
Did you read Cameron's
version? I didn't read either.
It was good.
Better than Foreman's? Maybe.
He was more analytical about
the diagnostic procedures.
She concentrated more on the
ethical dilemmas of informed consent.
How any patient can really be
informed without a medical degree.
Same old party lines.
Foreman should have told her.
Oh, shoulda, woulda, coulda.
If you allow this sort of
thing in your department,
you're basically
saying it's okay.
No, I'm saying that I
don't care what they do
as long as my life isn't interrupted by
pointless conversations like this one.
They won't trust each other,
and they won't trust you.
They shouldn't.
Deception like this is
just one step removed
from actively
sabotaging one another.
Then what would you do?
I could be the kindest,
gentlest boss in the world,
and Foreman would still have done
what he did, because that's who he is.
We can only hope that
Cameron has learned something.
Right, because you're
all about the teaching.
Our children are the future.
Hey.
Cuddy cleared Max for
surgery. She's okay to go.
How's our patient?
She's also cleared.
I don't care about the prep. I
care about the diagnostic tests.
Looks negative for Wilson's
disease. We'll know for sure in an hour.
Blood proteins are
normal. It's not...
Where's Cameron? Taking
a sample of the bile duct.
Surgeries are supposed
to start in about 15 minutes.
She had a chance
to get one last...
Hannah and Max will
be in the same room.
You wanted us to do as
much as we can before...
They're both awake with Cameron.
Maybe we should give these two a
minute together before the surgery.
You ready, honey?
Max. It's okay, I'm right here.
I need you to know
something. I know.
I love you, too.
I don't know how to say this.
Good Lord!
You can tell me anything.
She hasn't slept in 11 days!
You people trying
to torture her?
Ding, ding, let's go.
I told you... I didn't
say a word to Max.
This is exactly why you
got screwed with Foreman.
You're looking for people
to do the right thing.
She hasn't slept. Her
judgment is compromised
due to inactivity in
her prefrontal cortex.
Oh, she could have the best prefrontal
cortex in the history of mankind,
but given the choice
of life versus death,
those bad, bad people
are going to choose life.
Then why'd you sedate her?
If she wasn't going to tell,
if she was never going to do the right
thing, why bother knocking her out?
This isn't about them.
If she talks, if she
does the decent thing,
then you don't get to solve your
puzzle, your game's over, you lose.
Yeah, I wanna save
her. I'm morally bankrupt.
How's it going? They're
about to remove Hannah's liver.
All right, I'm good to go.
You can start
removing Max's liver.
You wanna let me in on what the
big secret is between these two?
You read Foreman's article?
It was good.
He basically stole it from me.
So?
You're on his side?
Sides? No, this
isn't dodge ball.
What am I supposed to
do, just sit back and take it?
No, write another article.
Kick ass until you're sitting
behind some big, expensive desk,
and someone from Johns
Hopkins calls and says,
"We're thinking about hiring Eric
Foreman as our head of Neurology."
And you can say
whatever you want.
Lovely. Revenge as
motive for success.
Well, it doesn't have to be the
motive, but it sure tastes good.
She's in VF. I've got no
pulse. She's arresting.
I am so relieved
you two are here.
'Cause without you looking out,
they'd be playing foosball down there.
Max's heart stopped.
Your patient is
on the other side.
Now get yourself upstairs
and figure out what Hannah has,
or Max has risked
her life for nothing.
Charging.
Clear.
We're okay.
Max's cardiac arrest was caused
by hypoxia from hypoventilation.
They restarted her heart,
and the right lobe of her liver was
successfully transplanted into Hannah.
Now, where were we
before we were so rudely
interrupted by the liver transplant?
Dopa decarboxylase
was processed normally,
and the ceruloplasmin and
copper levels were normal.
So, no Wilson's disease.
Gastric content was negative for
spores, so no mushroom toxicity.
And initial tests were
negative for cancer.
Which cancer were you
looking for? Any of them.
We ran blood tests for
ovarian, lung and lymphomas.
Not gonna tell you much.
Her blood was taken after she
was given immunosuppressants.
They fight rejection.
They also mess up our
ability to get any clear readings.
Great battles
kick up a lot of dirt,
obscure the battlefield so
generals can't see what's going on.
So, what are your
orders, General House?
Sound the retreat.
How you feeling?
Is Max okay?
She's still unconscious,
but her vitals look good.
We need to stop all the
immunosuppressant drugs
which are protecting
your new liver.
But if you stop
the drugs, I'll die.
You're dead anyway if we don't
figure out what caused all this.
By removing any
outside influences,
it'll help us see what's really
going on with your body.
So you did all this to
buy me a couple of days,
and now you're taking one back?
Will it hurt?
As your body goes into
acute organ rejection,
your liver will begin to swell,
and that'll put pressure on...
Yeah, it'll hurt.
But we can knock you out.
No, if Max wakes up,
I want to talk to her.
She's been taking the decongestants,
but she's not getting better.
She also says...
What?
Her boobs are bigger.
How could you get them mixed up?
They come in a little wheel.
They don't look anything
like decongestants.
Oh, God. The cashier put
them both in the same bag.
I thought I gave
her the right ones.
No, you gave her
the wrong pills.
You speak Mandarin?
I can count to 10, ask to
go to the bathroom and...
I'm not pregnant. We
haven't even done it yet!
Okay, I'm going to leave you two alone
now. I'm sure you got a lot to talk about.
Fever is 106. She's
in full rejection mode.
Is that supposed to surprise me?
Her white count is normal.
Normal is not normal.
She's been on steroids.
The transplant team gave her a
cocktail of immunosuppressants.
She hasn't slept in over a week.
Her white count
should be in the tank.
Looks like the problem
is some sort of infection.
Probably caused the
hypotension, shocked the liver.
We should start
broad-spectrum antibiotics.
Yeah, you might want to
add some chicken soup.
It'd be just as useless,
but it's got chicken.
We need to know exactly what
kind of infection we're dealing with.
What infection causes sleep
disturbance, bleeding, a movement disorder,
organ failure and an
abnormally normal white count.
What about tularemia?
Chest was clear.
Tularemia doesn't cause
movement disorders.
It would if she
developed meningitis.
There was no
ulcerations on the skin.
With the bleeding, it looks
more like leptospirosis.
Without conjunctivitis
and elevated creatinine?
What about typhoid or
some kind of relapsing fever?
Makes sense, if we
were in the Sudan.
Are you sure she hasn't
been out of the country?
She hasn't even been out of the
state in at least a year. Neither has Max.
Maybe she lied.
You talk to her friends,
neighbors? You don't know?
Come on, if you don't stay
up-to-date on my notes,
where's your next
article gonna come from?
Talked to the dog?
We're not as up on foreign
languages as you are.
Has the dog been traveling?
It came from a breeder.
Where? I don't know.
Place called Blue
Barrel Kennels.
They only had the
thing for, like, two days.
Blue barrel is a kind of cactus.
You see many cacti in Jersey?
Wanna see a magic trick?
Oh, no. Where'd it
go? Where'd it go?
Is it here?
No. What about here?
There it is.
Oh, that doesn't look
anything like a nose.
That wasn't there this morning.
Get that to the lab
and call the CDC.
Tell them what? That we
have a patient with the plague.
The black plague?
Looks that way.
Plague's carried by
rodents, not dogs.
Where there's
dogs, there's fleas.
If they hail from the Southwest,
then those fleas can't tell the difference
between prairie dogs and puppy dogs.
A small percentage of plague
cases present with sleep disturbance.
Imagine an idyllic
river of bacteria.
Okay, it's not idyllic for her,
but it serves my purposes.
The steroids and
immunosuppressants
acted like a big honking
dam across the river.
Physics 101.
Put a dam up in front of a
raging river, the river rises.
By stopping the immunosuppressants,
we blew up the dam,
and a 100-foot wall of bacteria
flooded her lymph nodes.
We better find out
where that dog is now.
After you restart the
immunosuppressants,
and fill her up to the eyeballs
with streptomycin sulfate,
gentamicin and tetracycline.
Use a garden hose
if we've got one.
Get yourselves some
prophylactic treatments as well.
I've got the plague?
Don't worry. It's treatable.
Being a bitch, though,
nothing we can do about that.
You weren't in your room.
The surgeon said
I'd heal faster if I walk.
I got this far, needed a rest.
What you did was crazy,
but it was pretty amazing, too.
Yeah. I'm a hero.
She's been planning to leave me.
Really?
She told a friend.
The friend let it slip.
You knew, and you gave
up half your liver anyway?
She can't leave me now.
You really want her to stay out of guilt?
That's not gonna make either of you happy.
You don't know that.
I love her.
I just want her to stay.
I don't own House's cases.
You had just as much
right as I did to write it up.
You should have told me, but I
should have handled it better, too.
If we want this not to get
in the way of our friendship,
I think we both have to
apologize and put it behind us.
I like you, really.
We have a good
time working together.
But 10 years from now,
we're not gonna be hanging
out and having dinners.
Maybe we'll exchange
Christmas cards, say hi,
give a hug if we're at
the same conference.
We're not friends.
We're colleagues.
And I don't have
anything to apologize for.