Okay, modern art movement
characterized
by strong colors
and fierce brush strokes,
seven letters,
begins with an "F."
Ask the Art History major.
Fauvism.
Painters were called fauves.
It's French for "wild beasts."
Hmm.
Always were
smarter than me.
Yeah, but it only
took you 20 years
to figure it out,
though, right?
You're gonna
have to eat fast,
because we're due
at the hospital
in a half hour
for your clinical
trial eval.
You know, speaking of which,
I had some time open up
in my schedule this morning,
so I was just thinking,
you know...
Okay, you can come,
but no doctoring.
No doctoring.
Danny.
I promise.
No doctoring.
Saw Robin and her mother
in the atrium.
Okay.
You must be happy
to have her back in town.
Look, Ava, we have to
share the same space,
so how about we just try
and keep it professional,
okay?
Still taking
the antiretrovirals,
by the way.
You know I've loved
having you crash with me.
The laundry, I know.
It won't happen again.
It's the third time
this week you left
wet clothes overnight.
What kind of grown man
can't follow a timer?
What kind of grown man buys
a sofa secondhand?
My back's killing me.
Honestly, dude,
don't you think
it's about time
you started thinking about
pulling the trigger
on an apartment?
Yeah, when I find one
I like, sure.
All right,
just level with me.
Are you holding out hope
that there's gonna be
a reunion with Natalie?
What? No.
She's done with me.
She's made that
perfectly clear.
What is it, Kol?
What do you see, huh?
What the...
Oh, my God, it's a body.
Frozen solid, no pulse.
I'm calling it in.
Jay, hang on.
I feel something.
She's alive.
Will, Baghdad's open.
What do you have?
Jane Doe, found her frozen in
the snow in
Jay's neighborhood.
Miss, can you tell me
your name?
Any idea how
she got there?
No overt signs of trauma,
did smell alcohol
on her breath.
CPD's working the scene.
Hey, you know the drill.
One, two, three...
Let's swap these blankets out
for warmer ones
and get these
wet clothes off her.
Whoa, whoa!
No wonder she's frozen,
got down to 10 degrees
last night.
Shawn, get a temperature.
Lucy, warm saline, two liters.
On it.
Frostbite to
her extremities.
Temp's only
31 degrees Celsius.
Miss?
My hands...
You're at Chicago Med.
Can you tell me your name?
My ring... Where's
my wedding ring?
Get new hot packs behind
her neck and in her armpits,
CBC, BMP, coags
and a urine tox screen,
specifically for
flunitrazepam.
On it.
Date rape drug? You think
she was sexually assaulted?
And probably robbed.
No cell phone or purse,
could have taken her
wedding ring, too.
And dumped her in the snow.
I'm gonna call Jay,
see what they turned up.
All right, wait a minute.
Do you remember when
you had that party,
that kind of New Orleans
style... What kind of party...
Fourth of July party.
Well, I always threw
the best parties, but that
was one for the books.
Pretty sure I ate
half my weight
in crawfish that day.
You did.
I did, yes.
And you had on that
really beautiful red sundress
that you made.
I did.
Made?
Looked pretty damn good
in that dress, too.
I looked good in that dress.
You looked good in red, right?
Hate to break up
the party, folks,
but I come
bearing good news.
Oh, Dr. Singh,
we love good news.
Caroline, your blood
and urine samples were normal.
Just need to do
a quick physical exam,
and then the last step
is to send you for scans.
If you follow me...
Okay, okay. Wanna come?
Yep.
All right.
It's nice of you to
clear your morning.
I'm sure
CeCe appreciates it.
Just trying to keep
everybody's spirits up.
Yeah, well,
I'll check in later.
Thanks for stopping by.
Okay.
She's hearing my murmur.
Had it since
she was a little girl.
No, I'm actually hearing
a double gallop.
A double gallop? Isn't that
usually from a valve issue?
We'll need an echo
to confirm,
but that tends to be
the cause, yes.
I'm sorry. I'll have to
hold the clinical trial
evaluation for now.
I'll page cardiology.
Can you page Dr. Rhodes?
Tell him it's for
Caroline Charles.
Morning.
How's Owen?
He's doing well.
Everything good with you?
Yeah.
Therapy's been going well.
That's great, Will.
I'm really glad
to hear that.
Oh, uh, I almost forgot...
What's up?
Your mail.
Sorry about that.
No, don't be.
Should change my address.
What? I didn't say that.
I...
Have a good day, Natalie.
Dr. Halstead,
Jane Doe's test results.
Did you hear? CPD stopped by
and dropped this off.
Her wedding ring.
Where'd they find it?
In the snow
where she passed out.
Her car was parked
nearby, too.
Purse and ID were inside.
Her name is Emma Patterson.
So she wasn't robbed.
Mmm-mmm.
What'd her labs turn up?
No roofie in her system,
but her blood alcohol
was.300.
Whoa!
So maybe
she just got wasted
and passed out.
Then what happened
to her clothes?
Right.
Let me know as soon
as she wakes up.
Hmm.
Hey.
Hey, Ethan...
Um, Shirley and Elijah
and I are going to check out
a band at the
Hideout tonight.
Since you haven't
accused me of murdering
any patients lately...
April, again, I'm sorry...
You should come.
I'd like to reset,
try being friends again.
I'd love to go.
It's just I have
plans already.
Vicki? What?
We're friends, right?
I mean, we should be able to
talk about our dating lives.
Okay, yeah, with Vicki.
I'm actually meeting
the parents tonight.
Wow.
It's a big step.
Some help over here!
Hey. I'm Dr. Choi,
what's going on?
We were driving when
Tommy started complaining
of a headache.
We thought
it was a migraine.
A few minutes later,
he started vomiting.
Okay. Hey, Thomas...
Thomas, can you open
your eyes for me?
The light, it hurts.
All right, he's burning up.
He has acute
lymphocytic leukemia.
All right. Thomas...
Thomas, can you touch
your chin to your chest?
Stiff neck.
Could be meningitis.
Let's have a look at him
in the ED.
I'll let Maggie know
we're coming.
Grade 4 plus
mitral regurgitation?
I mean, what does that
even mean?
In addition
to your lymphoma,
you are, unfortunately,
in heart failure.
It was that chemo,
wasn't it?
I knew we shouldn't have
done the second round.
Some anti-cancer agents
can have cardio toxic effect.
What are the treatments?
Is it valve replacement?
Normally, yes, but given the
progression of your cancer,
the surgery is just too risky.
So I recommend
that we treat
with medication.
And how long
will it take to
show improvement
in her cardiac function?
There's no way
to know for sure,
but a couple of months,
at least.
But the clinical trial
starts in two weeks.
There's no way
she'll be accepted
if she's still being treated
for heart failure.
It's okay. There'll be
other trials.
Honey, there are new trials
being presented all the time.
All the time.
I'm gonna give you guys
some time.
Connor...
This clinical trial,
it's my mom's last hope.
Without it, she won't live
more than a few months.
If my mom agrees
to the surgery,
I want you to do it.
Look, Robin, I understand
how overwhelming
all of this is,
but I... I can't do that.
What do you mean,
you can't?
Oh, you mean you won't.
Look, there is
a 30 to 50% chance
of operative mortality.
Since when have you shied away
from a challenging surgery?
It is because
it's your mother
that I'm not willing
to chance it.
Robin, take the time
that you have with her.
Months are better than hours.
We could lose her
on the table.
And if it goes well,
you could give her years.
Please, Connor,
if anyone can
bring her through,
it is you.
I'm sorry, but no.
Wow.
I thought I could rely on you.
Robin, you have to
trust me, okay?
I am looking out for
both you and your mother.
Thomas's lumbar puncture
confirmed he has
viral meningitis,
most likely because
he's immunosuppressed.
I thought he was
finally out of the woods.
Kid can't catch a break.
Unfortunately, it appears
Thomas's leukemia
has progressed, as well.
His white blood
cell count is 48,000,
much higher than I'd expect
from viral meningitis alone.
You're saying... You're saying
the chemo isn't working?
I'm sorry.
We're gonna start him on
antivirals to help treat
the infection.
And then what?
A bone marrow transplant?
That's the next step.
It may give him time.
Our younger son, Gavin,
will donate to his brother.
Transplants from minors
are extremely rare.
Your oncologist will evaluate
all potential donors first...
No, you don't understand.
We conceived Gavin in vitro,
so he would be the perfect
genetic match to Thomas.
He's already donated
cord blood and a kidney.
Gavin was conceived to save
his brother's life?
I know how it sounds,
but we've been battling this
since Thomas was a toddler.
Without him...
Thomas wouldn't have made it
past his fifth birthday.
Ms. Patterson, do you know
how you ended up in the snow?
Call me Emma.
Um, couple of us
were at the office
working late.
We opened
a few bottles of wine,
had too much to drink.
So I ubered home
and left my keys.
Last thing I remember
is trying to get into
my house.
You ubered home?
Mmm-hmm.
'Cause they found
your car nearby with your
phone and keys in it.
Okay, truthfully,
I was hammered,
and I didn't want
you to know that I drove.
I know how irresponsible
that was.
Any idea what happened
to your clothes?
You were only wearing a slip
under your coat.
Right. Uh...
I spilled red wine
on my dress.
I left it at the office.
God, my hands are killing me.
Lucy, four of morphine.
You mentioned
your wedding ring
earlier...
Yeah, did you find it?
We did.
We got it in a safe place
for you.
Thank God.
If you want,
we can call
your spouse for you.
No, no, no, no, no.
I don't wanna worry Shelly.
Okay, but you are
gonna be here overnight.
We need to monitor the
severity of your frostbite
for at least 24 hours.
Well, my wife is
on a business trip.
If you call her, she'll just
hop on the first flight back.
There's really nothing
she can do, right?
Just let us know
if you change your mind.
Okay.
A bit shifty, no?
Mmm-hmm.
I mean, we all
have our nights,
but they don't end up
passed out in the snow.
Yeah, I wouldn't be surprised
if she's trying to hide
a substance abuse
problem from her wife.
Do me a favor,
look in her records for
past hospitalizations,
anything related to drug
or alcohol abuse.
Yeah.
Hey, why'd you take on
Caroline's case if you're not
gonna see it through?
The last thing she needs
right now is to be passed off
on another doctor.
Whoa, wait a second,
what are you talking about?
We all agreed
that the surgery's
too dangerous, right?
Mortality rate's too high.
Now, all of a sudden,
Dr. Bekker's giving her
the green light?
Dr. Bekker advocated
for the surgery?
Advocated?
She agreed to do it.
I'm gonna take care of this.
Hey, Maggie, I have to
take off for a bit.
Dr. Peters is gonna
stay and cover for me.
Is everything okay?
Is Owen all right?
No, he's fine. It's Sophie.
Wasn't she discharged
a few days ago?
Yeah, but Phillip
just called.
Apparently, she's been
crying for hours.
He can't get her to stop.
Why doesn't he
just bring her in?
The last thing Sophie needs
is a trip in the cold,
especially if it's nothing.
Call me if you
need anything.
Thanks.
Oh, Will, good.
I've been doing
some digging.
I can't find any sign
of substance abuse in
Emma Patterson's records.
Huh.
Usually my gut doesn't lie.
Well, hold on, didn't you say
you found her
in Jay's neighborhood?
Yeah.
And she told us
that was her neighborhood,
but look at this.
Her current address
is Wilmette.
Okay, so she passed out
on someone else's lawn,
in her lingerie...
And didn't want us
to call her wife.
She's having an affair.
Certainly looks that way.
Oh, man.
Mags.
Mmm-hmm.
You know where
Natalie was off to?
I thought she was
working today.
She took some personal time.
With her medical bag?
She's making a house call.
Okay, Gavin, can you
make a fist for me?
Tight, tight, tight.
Okay, just gonna feel
a little prick.
It's not too bad, right?
No, but...
What's up, buddy?
When they take my bone marrow,
is it gonna hurt?
Last time, with the kidney,
I was so sore after.
I missed a lot of school.
I had to quit hockey.
Oh, sorry, bud.
That doesn't sound
too fun.
This time it shouldn't be
as rough, though.
The doctor will just take
some stem cells
out of your hip bone.
And it won't take long.
You'll be asleep
the whole time.
Asleep?
Yeah.
They'll give you
anesthesia.
No, I can't.
I don't want that again.
Gavin, did you have
a bad reaction last time?
It was so scary.
I couldn't breathe.
I couldn't scream.
When you were waking up?
It felt like there was
a pillow over my face.
I was gonna die.
Hey, hey, hey.
Take a deep breath,
Gavin, okay?
There you go.
Will it happen again?
Hopefully not.
No, no, no, no,
no, no, no, no, no.
Hey, hey, hey...
Gavin,
Gavin, look at me.
Look in my eyes.
Let's take some
deep breaths slowly.
In and out.
Slower, slow down.
Let me see your chest
fill up big, and relax.
She went behind my back
and tried to poach my patient.
Is this true, Dr. Bekker?
Hardly. I was offering
a second opinion.
You gotta be kidding me.
The patient's daughter
had already requested
the surgery directly.
You had no right
to insert yourself.
And honor
the family's wishes
when you'd refused?
Admit it, you're gun shy
because it's your
ex-girlfriend's mother.
Oh, come on, that is absurd.
I am acting in my patient's
best interest.
That's enough.
You mean my patient.
Really?
You two may think
I'm fascinated
by your little soap opera,
but I couldn't care less.
When you clock into
this hospital, you leave
that mess at the door.
Dr. Bekker, your lack
of professional etiquette
is glaring.
But Caroline Charles
has the right
to determine her own care.
Dr. Rhodes,
if you won't perform
the surgery,
Dr. Bekker will.
Thank you.
Not so fast.
Now, Caroline is
still my patient,
so if this surgery
is gonna happen,
I'm gonna do it.
What do you mean,
he doesn't wanna donate?
What did you say to him?
You have no business
scaring him.
I wasn't trying
to scare him.
Gavin had questions.
I answered him honestly,
because ultimately,
it's his decision.
We're his parents.
I still need his assent.
We won't put him under
anesthesia without it.
Dr. Choi.
My head. God, it hurts.
Oh, God.
He's tachycardic.
BP's 88 over 50.
Pressure's low.
What's happening?
Bolus a liter of saline
and give him 30 milligrams
ketorolac IV.
I thought you said
the antivirals would help
his infection.
They take time, but I'm
not convinced this is all
from the infection.
Pain is a stimulant.
I would expect
his blood pressure
to be high, not low.
Meds are in.
So then what is going on?
He's getting worse.
I'm not sure yet,
but I'm gonna find out.
April, let's get
a random cortisol
and a head CT.
Gavin, honey,
your brother is
really sick.
He needs you.
You wanna help him,
don't you, son?
Yeah.
I'll do it.
I wanna donate, Dr. Choi.
Oh, sweetie.
Hey.
You know
if Natalie's back yet?
Mmm-mmm. I don't think so.
Did she say who she was
going to see?
Will...
It's Phillip, isn't it?
Will, stop.
You know I'm friends
with both of you.
Just let sleeping dogs lie...
For now.
Hey, Nat, it's me.
I guess you're busy.
Uh, call me
when you get this.
How's everybody doing?
Good, Dad.
Honey, do you mind if I grab
a quick moment with your mom?
Sure.
Okay.
I'm fine, go.
All right.
Thanks, Dad.
Oh, God,
there's that look.
What look?
That look you always get
when you're about to
shrink me.
Me? Shrink you? Never.
Mmm-hmm. Mmm-hmm.
So, um, how you feeling?
Terrified.
Honey, you know that
up until the moment
they wheel you into that OR,
you can change your mind.
You know that, right?
I can't.
I can't because
Robin begged me.
She begged me, Danny.
She begged me to do this.
And when your little baby
begs you to fight, you fight.
Right?
Of course, of course,
of course.
You know what?
It's cold in here.
Are you cold? Let me get you
another blanket.
Get you another
blanket? Okay.
Thank you.
Better?
Yeah, thank you.
Hey...
You know, I just, um...
I just wanted to
tell you how much, um...
How much I...
What?
I just wanna tell you that I
think you're gonna do great.
And I'm gonna see you
in a little while, okay?
Okay.
Where's Emma Patterson's room?
May I have your name, please?
I'm sorry, ma'am,
you cannot just walk in there.
Shelly,
how did you know
I was here?
The insurance called me.
Oh, my God, look at you.
I'm gonna be okay, honey.
Thank you for checking on me.
I saw your car outside
of Ann's house, Emma.
Let's all take
a breath, okay?
I know how this looks.
This isn't the first time!
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
I swear, I wasn't planning
on doing anything.
What the hell
were you doing there?
Okay, that's it, outside now.
Your wife's still recovering.
Wife? You mean ex-wife.
Shelly, I'm so sorry.
Emma, I'm serious.
Leave me
and my girlfriend alone.
If you come near us again,
I'm calling the cops.
Okay.
Okay, that's enough.
Let's go, here we go.
It's nothing serious.
Okay, but the crying,
it's not gonna affect
her heart condition, right?
No, no. It's just colic.
So she'll be crying like this
for hours each day
for how long?
A week or two?
Probably a little bit longer.
Most babies stop
around three or four months.
But the best thing
you can do
is just try and soothe her,
just like this.
Okay, right. Yeah.
Wow, I love the little clouds.
My wife painted them.
And I nearly
had a heart attack
when I came in here,
and I saw her standing alone
up on that ladder.
But she insisted we get
the nursery done before
Sophie arrived.
Aww.
I... I haven't had time
to unpack the rest
of the house.
It's so strange,
it's like,
each day gets
better and worse
at the same time.
Hmm. Grief isn't linear,
at least not in my experience.
Can I ask you something?
Sure.
When did you know
that it was time
to take your ring off?
I noticed you were
still wearing it
a few weeks ago.
Oh, um, that wasn't
my wedding ring.
That was my engagement ring.
Oh, I didn't know.
That's okay.
Uh, we're not...
He and I aren't in
a great place, so...
I'm sorry.
No.
Did you hear that?
What?
Sophie fell asleep.
Oh, that's amazing.
Yeah.
Okay, I can put her down.
No, no, no, no, no.
It takes a while for them
to get into deep sleep.
I got it.
Okay.
Yeah.
Thank you.
Well?
I asked Gavin
if he wanted to donate.
He very clearly said yes.
The kid's scared
out of his mind,
I'm telling you.
He agreed under duress,
Ms. Goodwin.
April, duress is nearly
impossible to prove.
He's 11 years old.
He's already given
a kidney.
At some point,
we have to take into account
what Gavin wants.
He can't just be
a means to an end.
I get it, Dr. Choi.
Trust me, I do.
But the Kramers
don't want to hurt Gavin.
They want to
keep Thomas alive.
It's an impossible situation.
And if he doesn't voice
his reservations directly,
my hands are tied.
I can't stop the transplant
from moving forward.
What do you think
you're doing?
What does it look like
I'm doing?
I'm scrubbing in.
Oh, come on, you didn't think
you were going to perform
a surgery without me?
This is my floor.
You don't take on
cases this risky.
You're too worried
about your stats.
You know, I would say
that you were doing this
to get under my skin,
but even you wouldn't
stoop that low.
Or... Or would you?
Wow.
Your egotism
is truly boundless,
isn't it?
All right,
you want it straight?
I agreed to do the surgery
because I'm the
best CT surgeon
in this hospital.
I'm confident I can pull
Caroline through.
And if you're not, then stay
the hell out of my OR.
Hey, your temperature's up,
kidneys are making urine,
all good signs.
You think I'm insane,
don't you?
I'm not judging.
Breakups are tough.
I didn't intend to
go over there, I swear.
I'd just been drinking
and I couldn't sleep.
So I throw on my coat
and the next thing I knew,
I was parked outside
her girlfriend's house.
Listen, we all
make mistakes.
I get it.
I just mean you shouldn't be
too hard on yourself.
Thank you for saying that.
Everybody says
I should let it go.
But... Mmm.
I know that Shelly
still loves me.
She came to the
hospital, right?
She wanted to see me.
Don't you think
that's a good sign?
How are your hands feeling?
Mmm. Okay.
My right one's still
really throbbing.
But my left one, I actually
don't feel anything at all.
Nothing?
Mmm-mmm.
Maggie.
Yeah?
Oh, God, why does it
look like that?
The tissue's dead.
Page burn service right away.
Yeah.
Retractor's in place.
I can see the entire valve.
Scissors.
Starting with the
anterior leaflets...
Hold on.
Those, uh...
Those cords aren't as diseased
as I would have imagined.
I think you can
just repair them,
avoid replacing the valve.
If I do that
and the repair fails,
she's gonna be back
on the table in six months.
That's if it fails.
I'm not taking that risk.
And if it doesn't, she'll be
in better shape long-term.
She won't have to take
blood thinners...
I'm not gonna do it.
Like I said, starting
on the anterior leaflets.
Thomas's latest
test results
just came in.
Wait, his head CT's negative.
His random cortisol
is really low.
He didn't drop
his blood pressure
because of the infection.
He's in adrenal crisis,
but that would only happen
if he'd stopped
taking his prednisone.
Isn't that part
of his chemo regimen?
Please don't tell my parents.
Why'd you stop taking
your prednisone?
If it's making you sick,
the oncologist can
adjust the dose.
Thomas.
Not just the prednisone.
I stopped taking
all of my chemo drugs.
I just... I don't
wanna do it anymore.
Any of it.
I...
The chemo, the operations,
the doctors' appointments...
I'm in pain all the time,
and my little brother's
suffering, too.
What's going on here?
Nothing.
What were you
talking to him about?
Hey.
I know you're scared
of disappointing your parents,
but you need
to tell them
how you feel.
Disappoint us?
What is she
talking about?
I don't want the transplant.
Honey...
I'm sorry...
I don't wanna
fight anymore.
Do you know
what you're saying?
I'll donate.
I'm not scared anymore,
I promise.
I know, but I don't
want you to.
You're really brave,
but I'm ready to go.
I'm ready. I'm so sorry.
It's okay, son.
You're not
disappointing us.
I promise.
You could never
disappoint us.
Hey, Nat, it's me.
I guess you're busy,
but call me when you get this.
I'd really like to talk.
How about dinner tonight?
Thanks.
Here you go.
Sophie should be
down for the count,
but if you need anything,
feel free to call.
Why don't you
stay for dinner?
Oh, no, I shouldn't.
But thank you.
Nothing fancy, I promise.
I was gonna order
Chinese food.
And you've been so good
at reminding me to eat,
I figured the least I could do
is return the favor.
Well, I do love
a good egg drop soup.
Fantastic.
The place down
the street makes
an excellent egg drop soup.
Really?
I'm hoping.
They're gonna amputate
all five fingers.
Man, the cost
of living in denial.
She just couldn't accept that
that chapter of her life
was over.
Yeah.
If nothing else,
hopefully this wakes her up.
Finishing the
left atrial suture line.
Let's get ready to take off
the cross-clamp.
Start warm blood
and stop cardioplegia.
Got it.
She's fibrillating.
Paddles.
Let's charge to 20.
Charging.
Charged.
Clear.
Still fibrillating.
Charge to 30.
Charged.
Clear.
No change.
Dammit. Charge to 50.
If we can't get her
into a sustainable rhythm,
she won't make it
off the table...
You think I don't
know that? Clear.
Maximum charge.
Clear.
Connor, we can't just
keep defibrillating.
We need to re-arrest her.
Her heart's too sick.
She'll never come off
the pump.
We don't have a choice.
I'm gonna remove
the cross-clamp.
Are you insane?
Do that and she'll
still be fibrillating,
but without
coronary perfusion.
You'll kill her.
When I was in my fellowship,
we had a patient like this.
He wouldn't convert.
This is the only thing
that worked.
It's your show.
Cross-camp off.
Clamp off, 3:42.
Wow, she's back
in sinus rhythm.
Amazing call, Dr. Rhodes.
Hey, have fun tonight.
Will do.
Um, an orchid
and a bottle of whiskey.
What?
For Vicki's parents.
Guys always bring flowers
for mom and forget about dad.
Good tip, thanks.
Caroline is doing well.
Oh, my God.
We hit a bit of
a rough patch...
But we pulled her through.
She's absolutely fine.
Your mother's
a fighter, Robin.
Oh, thank you.
Thank you so much.
Yeah.
I'm gonna go meet
my mom in recovery.
Dad?
Right behind you, honey.
Thank you.
That was a lucky move
with the cross-clamp.
Don't you ever put me
in that position again.
Oh, there you are.
I was just about
to text you.
Sorry, I was running
a little late.
No worries.
Uh, so, heads up
for tonight,
my dad loves sharing
his travel photography.
So, apologies in advance
for the extended slideshow.
Oh, and my mom is
probably also gonna...
Vicki, uh...
What's wrong?
This isn't right.
What are you trying to say?
I'm not being fair to you.
Introducing me
to your parents,
I know it's something
you don't take lightly.
So I shouldn't go tonight.
It's about April, isn't it?
It's not good.
No, no.
Uh-huh. It was really bad.
I had a fanny pack
every day of eighth grade.
And it wasn't a subtle
fanny pack, it was like...
It was like, neon green.
Well, full disclosure...
Hmm?
The fanny pack was there
to house the inhaler.
No.
It was an aggressive
fanny pack.
All right,
well, you know what?
I am not one to judge,
because rainbow braces,
right here.
Woof! Really?
Yeah.
How did you
make it out alive?
I have no clue.
This is so good. I have not
laughed in a long time.
Me neither.
I'm sorry, I shouldn't
have done that.
I'm sorry.
I heard the surgery
was a success.
How's CeCe doing?
Already requested a cocktail.
That's my girl.
So, what's next?
Well, they still
need to do
the examination,
but I expect
she'll get accepted
into the clinical trial.
That's not what I meant.
What's next for
the two of you?
Sharon, come on.
Look, maybe I've
always been a bit of
a puppy dog around CeCe,
but she moved on
a long time ago, trust me.
Mmm-hmm.
I wouldn't be too sure.
Nice view.
Well, lots of privacy.
Plus brand-new floors,
fresh paint on the walls.
You have an in-unit
washer and dryer,
and the kitchen was just
recently remodeled.
And the building allows pets?
Yep. There's even a dog park
around the corner.
Look, if you want it, I would
put down a deposit tonight.
Rentals in this area
are going fast.
It'll be gone by tomorrow.
What do you think?
Should we mingle?
All right.
Hold, hold on. Whoa.
Kol, come back here.
Sorry. Don't worry,
he's friendly.
Sorry, thank you.
It's okay.
Kol, come on, bud.
He all right?
Agent Lee.
Uh, Dr. Halstead.
Didn't know you live
in this area.
Oh, I don't.
Well, actually,
I guess I do now.
Huh.
Well, welcome
to the neighborhood.
Thanks.
Yeah.