Every action has an
equal and opposite reaction.
Emergency rooms
are kept in business
by people who've learned
that lesson the hard way.
You made waffles in our kitchen.
No, not me.
Your sister, in between weepy
phone calls with the fiance.
Skydivers, bull riders...
People whose bold
ideas can often result
in broken bones and
smushed spleens.
Well, being away
from home is hard.
I've been in DC for so
long. I know how she feels.
You're the one who
brought her here.
She doesn't need your sympathy.
She needs you to send her home.
Now, did she say that?
I'm sure she's telling James all
about how we're holding her hostage.
Well, we can negotiate
the terms of her release
when I get home later tonight.
Tonight? You and
I have a surgery
scheduled this
afternoon together.
Another meeting popped up.
I'm gonna have Amy cover for me.
Sorry.
No. Not you. The
waffles are amazing.
I'm gonna miss having a hostage.
Surgeons are trained to deal
with the fallout of bold ideas.
We pick up the pieces
and do our best to
fit them back together.
Guys, Jo's dying.
They're stress hives.
I've been a mess since I
heard Hunt and Webber
talk about firing one of us.
You're a mess? I've gained
eight pounds this week.
You could stop eating.
Where do you even
get these at 7:00 a.m.?
Drop it before I drop you.
You know who's
not getting fired? Me.
I'm gonna keep my head
down and stay out of trouble.
No, we should be
impressing them,
showing them they need
us. Wait. I'm confused.
Should I keep my head down,
or should I put on a show?
You just need to go one week
without having a nervous breakdown.
Why does everything
keep coming back to that?
It happened once!
Relax. Hey, I'm the
one who's in trouble.
Last one in, first one out.
Please, even if you
weren't Dr. Bailey's husband,
you're still Webber's favorite.
Okay, I need two
of you for rounds.
Warren, Murphy, let's go.
Nice knowing you.
Braden Morris' ALC and
T cell counts are fantastic.
Do you think it
might actually be time
for the boy to come
out of the bubble?
It would appear so.
So why do you look like
I just punched a kitten?
We can't send him
home until I tell his parents
the truth about
how I treated him.
And before I do that, I
need to inform the board.
Yang. - Mmm?
I gave a patient a
stem cell transplant
using deactivated
HIV as a viral vector
in order to cure his SCID.
I did so against
his parents' wishes.
Whoa!
Did it work?
Damn right, it did.
Up top! Hey!
I've just informed the board.
Now, let's go see his folks.
Look at this cute, little fetus.
I want to send this to my mom.
Of course, right after
the first trimester.
Two more weeks.
Come on, that's so far.
Look, if we start telling
people, we gotta tell my mom.
She already tried to
torpedo our relationship once
over a hypothetical child.
What do you think she's
gonna do with a real one?
Oh, hey, guys.
Hey.
Hi! Hey!
Just having a checkup
with the old OB-GYN,
making sure all the
parts are in order.
Yeah.
Both of you?
Callie Torres?
Hi. Yes. That's me.
Uh, I think I can
handle this on my own.
Okay.
That was terrible!
And what's up with
this? I don't know!
Mmm! Hey! The
first candidate's here
and waiting in the
conference room.
I'm on my way now. Okay.
So, I still can't believe
he's making you
pick your replacement.
Mmm.
I'm interviewing Dr. Russell's
replacement, not mine.
Which I volunteered
to do, by the way.
It's a punishment.
It's like making you clean
the apartment you're vacating.
No, Owen knows this
is the right move for me.
He's been nothing but
supportive. Mmm-mmm.
Something's coming. I
can feel it in my bones.
Ew. I hate his face.
Okay, now look me in the eye
and tell me this isn't a punishment.
Thank you for this waffle.
All right, Miss Campbell.
I'm just gonna grab you...
Non-adherent gauze, Dr. Kepner.
Do you prefer tape or Coban?
Where did you come from?
Just trying to be
useful, proactive.
Finding needs and filling them.
That's my business.
30-year-old male,
motorcycle versus SUV.
Complex scalp lac and
bilateral hip dislocations.
Vitals are stable.
Wilson, you want to be useful?
Yeah. Take him to trauma one.
Start the ABCs, get him off the
board, and get him his trauma X-rays.
And I will join you as soon as I
finish up with Ms. Campbell over there.
Absolutely. Of
course, Dr. Kepner.
Thank you for the opportunity.
You're welcome!
I don't believe it.
We can take him home?
Absolutely.
Oh!
This is just wonderful.
Thank you, Dr. Bailey.
Thank you so much for hearing us
and just letting him
get better on his own.
Mr. Morris.
Braden did not get
better on his own.
What do you mean?
I gave him the treatment.
They did not react as I
had hoped they would.
Legal action never
crossed your mind?
I had hoped that they
would see the bigger picture.
Dr. Edwards should be excused.
She wasn't involved.
Did she know what you
were doing and fail to report it?
She was involved.
Okay, um...
I'm gonna get someone
on the phone from legal,
and till I come back,
don't go anywhere.
Don't speak to
anyone. Don't move.
Okay.
Parents authorized
your treatment
with signed consent. Yes.
Then they told Dr. Edwards
that they changed their mind.
Yes.
Dr. Edwards informed
you, Dr. Bailey,
of the parents'
withdrawal of consent.
Yes. Yes.
And then you gave the patient
the stem cell transplant anyway.
Have you told anyone
else about this?
I informed Dr. Yang this morning
as a representative
of the board.
What did she say?
She gave me a high five.
And did you apologize?
To Dr. Yang?
To the parents.
An apology could go a long
way in circumstances like this.
An apology is only effective
when a mistake's been made.
I chose not to
honor their wishes.
It wasn't a mistake.
All right, Dr. Ross.
Tell us what's so special
about little Jacob here.
Jacob has an omphalocele.
He was born with his abdominal
organs outside of his body.
We've been managing
him with daily application of
silver-sulfadiazine ointment
as a bridge to delayed closure.
And that's your job. And to keep
an eye on the other tiny humans.
It should be a quiet
and adorable day.
Whoa!
Look at you, all grown up.
How's the private
sector? Couldn't be better.
I just came by to check
on my inguinal hernia kid.
Oh, great. Well,
don't be a stranger.
Yeah, you too.
Hey, Ross, hold up.
I'm not gonna hit you.
I just want you to check
up on an old patient of mine.
Kevin Platt, short gut kid.
Did he get his
STEP procedure yet?
Robbins has it
scheduled for Wednesday.
He's here for TPN till then.
Cool. Got it.
That's my tablet.
Monica Zarr, 27, in
remission from rectal cancer.
Okay.
Monica now suffers
from poor sphincter control
due to her low
anterior resection.
She's here today
for the implantation
of the permanent
rectal pacemaker.
Gosh, when you say
it, it sounds so sexy.
Sorry.
Honey, there's no
need to apologize.
They're doctors.
Um, Monica, I asked
you to keep records
of your movements
after your last surgery.
Right. The log log.
Paul, give him the poop diary.
Sure.
Every four hours and 26 minutes.
The sacral nerve
stimulator lead we implanted
should have cut your
frequencies down far below this.
I'm sorry. I'm gonna recommend
that we not implant the
permanent pacemaker.
In fact, I think we
should use the OR time
to remove the lead wire.
But I'm pooping way less.
But it's not enough to
consider the device effective.
We should explore
some other options.
Such as?
Antidiarrheals, high-fiber
diet, smaller meals.
I'm a professional dancer.
My diet's pretty much
leaves and twigs already.
There has to be something else.
Sweetie, we made it
through your cancer.
We'll make it through this.
I am so sorry. I
couldn't help it.
But also, she farted like 80
times, and I did not laugh once.
No, you just belched
to rattle the windows.
And Dr. Warren did neither,
so he's gonna take the
lead on the lap chole.
You prep Monica
for surgery. Yes, sir.
And take an antacid
before you go back in there.
No, you need to
bend the knee first.
Did you get those
X-rays, Wilson?
Think I'd be in
here if she hadn't?
Well, somebody's
sure a grumpus today.
Wilson, fill me in.
Hey, what the hell?
I'll be with you in two shakes
of a lamb's tail, Dr. Torres.
Vitals have been stable.
Trauma lab's done.
Primary survey revealed a
large, briskly bleeding scalp lac.
I put a pressure dressing
on for you to assess.
CT negative for abdominal
or intracranial hemorrhage,
but did show bilateral
hip dislocations,
one anterior and one posterior,
with an acetabular wall fracture,
but both have been reduced.
Wilson, this traction pin's
not gonna place itself. Let's go.
Oh, yes. Sure. Of course.
Such a grumpus!
Do you see this pin, Kepner?
You call me that nonsense
word one more time,
you won't like where I stick it.
So, you'll access the spine
through the retroperitoneum,
and I will perform the
fusion with bone graft
between L5 and S1.
Do you need to take that?
Nope.
So, Derek usually does the...
You can take the
call. It's okay. It's fine.
I'm sorry.
Just because Derek
and I are having
a hard time juggling our lives,
that doesn't mean that we
should keep you from yours.
You know what? I
liked you a lot better
when you were the sister-in-law
who didn't give a crap.
Could we just go back to
that? That would be great.
Am I qualified to
run the department?
Yikes. You know, not my call.
What I do know is that
for some strange reason,
since I was a resident,
I keep getting thrown
the riskiest, high-profile
cardiothoracic surgeries.
I mean, why me, you know?
Uh-huh.
So, you did your fellowship
in Philadelphia under
Jack Alexander?
Do you know Dr. Alexander?
Such a great guy.
Really, sweet as pie.
Which is why it was
always a little embarrassing
when our chief of surgery
would come to me for consults
instead of Dr. Alexander.
I took it as a compliment,
but still, awkward.
Hmm.
Knock, knock. Who's there?
Interrupting jellyfish.
Interrupting...
That's my favorite one!
Hey, Dr. Ross.
Kevin doesn't need
the TPN this afternoon.
Dr. Karev said he could
do his surgery today.
Oh, that's... But Dr. Robbins...
Ross, let me explain short
bowel syndrome to you.
Kevin here is missing a
big chunk of his small bowel,
which means he needs
surgery to lengthen it.
The sooner we operate,
the sooner he goes home.
Sound good to you? Yeah.
We just need to transfer
you onto my service.
Dr. Ross will pick up
the paperwork for you.
Hey, I should let
Dr. Robbins know.
He's my patient.
Or he will be, as soon as
they sign the transfer papers.
I don't feel good about this.
You got two choices.
You can feel good about
it and scrub in with me,
or you can rat me out to Robbins
and I tell her you didn't check
placement of some kid's feeding tube
and he nearly died from
aspiration pneumonia.
But that's not true.
Yeah, but I worked
with her for years.
You went nuts and killed my dad.
Who's she gonna believe?
You've already been the head of
your own department for two years.
You think I look too young.
I finished high school early.
Also med school.
It's pretty annoying, right?
Yeah, it's pretty annoying.
Excuse me. Sorry to interrupt.
Can I borrow
Dr. Yang for a moment?
Excuse me.
Hope you saved
the big guns for last.
They're all solid
candidates on paper,
but between the humble-bragger
and the girl who rode
in on the big wheel...
Cristina, I need to know
exactly what Bailey
said to you this morning.
About?
Her patient, the
deactivated HIV.
Drawing a blank.
Really?
Well, I've been
interviewing all day.
I'm surprised I
remember my own name.
You know what? It's
probably for the best.
Oh, and... Go
easy on these guys.
You know, they can't all be you.
Dr. Avery, I haven't
held my son in months,
and I want him to come
out, but for all we know,
she could be making up
numbers to cover her own ass.
Yeah, we can't
trust that it's safe.
I mean, what if we get him
home and something happens?
You know what? I
understand your concerns.
What I'm saying
is if the labs show...
Are you a parent, Dr. Avery?
My wife and I are expecting.
Well, if someone
did this to you,
your child, how would you react?
I'll go ahead and run some
new labs for you myself.
All right, that might
be enough weight.
All right. Ready for that X-ray?
Right away. Whoops!
Looks like I need
more irrigation.
Uh, Wilson, can you take over?
Yes, absolutely, Dr. Kepner.
"Absolutely, Dr. Kepner."
Who are you? I
thought you had grit.
I do! I do have grit!
Okay, well, all I see is some
"yes, ma'am, no ma'am" sissy girl,
and there's no place
in ortho for sissy girls.
Do you hear me?
Check yourself before
you wreck yourself.
Sweetie, look.
This says yoga might
help. You love yoga.
Are you crazy? I can't
do downward dog.
In a hot room?
A bunch of yoga won't
get me my job back.
You lost your job over this?
They can't fire you over
something you can't control.
After the cancer,
I was supposed to have
my big return to the stage.
I was able to make
it through rehearsals,
running back and
forth to the bathroom,
but then, the first
full run-through,
no breaks...
Oh, no.
Blastoff, in the
middle of a pirouette.
The fact that it didn't
happen in front of an audience
is the only thing that kept me
from shooting myself in the face.
She's exaggerating.
Paul, it was like
frickin' spin art.
Hey, where's Kevin Platt?
Dr. Karev took
him up to surgery.
Hey, what, are you
poaching patients now?
I didn't poach anything.
You stole my short gut kid.
All right. Up until
a few weeks ago,
he was our short gut kid.
Look, his parents know
me. They're fine with this.
Consents are signed, and
he's just about prepped.
Ross?
Really?
The kid's on the operating
table. What do you want me to do?
This was a jerk-ass move, Karev,
and you know it.
So, no one's qualified?
No, I mean,
they're all qualified...
But Owen's right.
I need to accept that none
of them are gonna be me.
That's his plan.
What's his plan?
Owen. Didn't make sense before.
A fellow interviewing
potential department heads,
showing you a bunch
of people you won't like
to get you to stay. He
wants to offer you the job.
Mer, you're thinking
about this way too hard.
You don't offer a
first-year attending
head of cardiothoracic
surgery. It's just not done.
You just got hired to run
an entire research facility.
You're perfect for the job.
Wait, two seconds ago,
I wasn't qualified to
interview the candidates,
and now you're saying
that I'm perfect for the job?
Yeah, because you're you.
Okay, I'm lost.
Is Owen the one plotting
to keep me here, or are you?
Now you're the one
thinking about it too hard.
She's a dancer.
This isn't just a job.
This is who she is.
And we're just
gonna send her home
farting and pooping
uncontrollably
for the rest of her life? And
we're done with the chili.
Webber told you
to take an antacid.
I did. I drank half a bottle,
and it didn't do anything,
and then I got all
anxious about that,
and the next thing you know,
I'm on the train to pizza town.
You know what you need? A
magnetic esophageal sphincter.
Bailey put one in
an old lady last week.
A ring of little magnets
at the end of the esophagus,
just above the stomach.
Lets food in, stays
closed so you don't keep...
Doing that. Yes. Yes.
Please get that thing.
It's a magnetic sphincter? Yeah.
So, if it closes the opening
for the food on the way in,
wouldn't it work on the way out?
What, for our cancer dancer?
It's actually pretty good. Yeah.
You should pitch it to Webber.
Hey, Edwards, you've been
working with Bailey, right?
She was supposed
to meet me for lunch,
but she hasn't returned any
of my calls. Something up?
What the hell's the matter with
you? How could you be so reckless?
How did you... I had
to hear it from Edwards!
I sure as hell didn't
hear it from you!
I couldn't tell you.
I didn't want you
to have to lie for me.
Dr. Warren, I'd appreciate
it if you stepped outside.
Look, she is my wife.
Okay, um...
The lawyers are meeting now.
We're discharging Braden soon,
but it does not look like the
Morrises are going to let this go.
So it looks like a
malpractice suit?
Worse.
Assault and battery charges.
Tuck's soccer practice
is gonna be over soon.
I was supposed to
pick him up. Can you?
There's nothing you
can do for me here.
Braden's coming
out of the bubble?
Yeah.
I wish I could have seen that.
Suction, please.
You can go, Ross.
I've got it from here.
Come on. We're in the
middle of a surgery here.
I know. You stole my patient,
but you can't steal Ross.
He works for us.
He's my resource,
and I need him in the NICU
doing what he was told to do.
You need an assist?
You've got one.
How can I be of help to you?
Sorry, I'm having
a little bit of trouble
dividing these
branching vessels.
I can retract the iliac vein
medially to help with exposure.
Thanks.
Derek's coming
home tonight. Yup.
Which means you can go home.
I understand.
I'm sorry.
You were just trying to be
nice, and I bit your head off.
I will be out of your
hair first thing tomorrow.
Oh, that? No. This
is not about that.
I've already forgotten
you said that.
So, this isn't you kicking
me out for being a bitch?
No. No, we love having you here,
but we don't want to
keep you from your life
any more than we have to, so...
What's so funny?
I'm sorry. It's just...
If I had spoken to anyone
at Seaside Wellness
the way I spoke to you,
I would have to have
a conversation for
six hours about it.
I love it here.
James and I have
not been fighting
about the fact
that I'm still here.
We have been fighting about
the fact that I never want to leave.
So, you want to give
me a bionic butthole?
It's magnetic.
Yeah, it was Dr. Murphy's idea.
Well, it's commonly used
as the esophageal sphincter
to reduce reflux
and prevent food
from coming back up the throat,
but we think, with
a bit of modification,
that it might work just
as well for your stool.
Have you done this before?
No, but it wouldn't
be the first time
a medical device was adapted
to something other
than its original intention.
But we're willing to
give it a shot if you are.
What do you think, honey?
Yes. Please.
Thank you.
Oh, my God. Thank you.
Paul, you okay?
I am ecstatic. My
heart broke when
Dr. Webber said the
pacemaker wouldn't work,
but now you can
have a normal life.
I mean, you can be comfortable.
This can all end here.
Baby, I love you so much,
and, I mean, that
cancer was one thing,
but I don't know how much
more of this I could take.
I... The smell...
Okay, yeah.
We'll take one magnetic
butthole, please.
Twenty pounds. Let's see
if it's fully reduced this time.
All right, you ready to shoot?
Uh, wait. I'm almost finished.
Okay, well, I need to
make sure that his hip
isn't grinding on broken
bone pieces. Yeah. Hold on...
Just give me a second.
Just put on a lead apron!
Please give me a second! Kepner.
Dr. Kepner, put
on the damn apron!
Torres, I can't be in here
while you do the X-ray.
Um...
Wilson, take over
for Dr. Kepner.
God, you're so weird today.
I'm sorry. I... Shut it.
Just shut it.
I'm telling you, kid,
this is the place to be.
It's quiet.
The company's great.
You and me, we
got a lot in common.
My intestines are
on the inside, but still,
I know what it's
like to feel exposed.
If we stick together,
I think we'll be okay.
In fact...
What the hell, man! I
thought we were friends!
His omphalocele's ruptured!
Get me saline,
sterile dressings,
and VICRYL mesh, now!
Reload stapler.
You're not gonna
oversew the staple lines?
Staples alone should do it.
You don't want to take the time?
I mean, I would, but, you
know, I don't like leaks, so...
This isn't my first
STEP procedure.
Oh, I know. I taught
you how to do your first
STEP procedure, which is why
it blows my mind that you
would try and poach my patient.
Why are you making
such a big deal?
Because it's
freaking rude, Alex,
and I don't deserve
to be treated like that.
I taught you better than this.
You're out in the world now...
But what you do reflects on
me, and I do not approve of this,
and neither will Lebackes.
So, what, you're
gonna tattle on me?
Dr. Robbins, you're
needed in NICU. 911.
And I spearheaded a hybrid OR
that offered more flexibility
between non-invasive
and invasive techniques,
gamma cameras, the whole works.
I definitely want
to bring that here.
Wow, impressive.
Well, do you have
any questions for me?
One.
There's a rumor
that working here
means giving up hope of
ever winning the Harper Avery.
That's...
That would make a
difference for you?
Of course it would.
I mean, it's the goal, right?
I assume it's why
you're leaving.
No.
You'll probably never
win a Harper Avery.
I've known people who
have deserved Harper Averys,
and people who have won them,
and the thing they all have
in common was the work.
They are focused on
the work and the patient,
on making someone better or
someone whole or someone live.
That's their goal.
So... No.
I mean, you, specifically,
will never win a Harper Avery.
Not if that's what you're after.
So, that's... You know,
I wouldn't give this place another
thought. You'd be a terrible fit.
Thank you so much
for coming in, though.
I don't know what happened.
It burst, Ross. That's
what happened. Move.
Fran, get me a
larger VICRYL mesh.
I need to protect his
organs. Can I do anything?
You can step outside. Go.
We ran the labs twice, and
his immune system values
are within the normal range.
Let's do it.
Okay.
Come on.
Oh!
Oh, baby!
She went about it the wrong way,
but Bailey's treatment did work.
Are you looking for a
"thank you," Dr. Hunt?
She's lucky he's alive, because
we're only gonna take her license.
When we're done, she won't
practice medicine ever again.
And if we'd lost him,
I wouldn't stop until
she was behind bars.
It wasn't Dr. Bailey's fault.
She didn't do anything wrong.
It's my fault he got the treatment.
It's mine.
I forgot to tell her you
wanted to withdraw consent,
so she just went ahead,
and when I told her the truth,
she covered for
me. It was a mistake.
You forgot? You just forgot?
Hold on. David, please.
Look, Dr. Edwards is
a resident, a trainee...
And if you want to
yell at someone, then...
In what world does
that make it okay?
My son could have died,
and you're just gonna
stand there and tell me
that it's okay because
it would have been
a mistake? David.
Honey. David, come here.
Come here.
Sit down.
David, he's alive,
and he's healthy,
and we can take him home.
Maybe we should just go home?
Can we, Dad? Can we go home?
Yeah?
Okay.
You're gonna want
to position the ring
in apposition at the level of
the anorectal junction. Good.
Careful.
Okay, once it's aligned,
we'll use the attached
sutures to tie the ends together.
Like this? No.
Now, you need to provide
passive reinforcement to the canal.
That's better.
Now, don't add tension
when you throw your knots.
When it's connected, we will
confirm placement with the fluoro.
How far along are you?
Ten weeks, today. Mmm.
I know it's still early.
We're not really
supposed to be
telling anyone, but...
Wow.
But we're happy about it?
Yeah.
Yeah, we are. We're really...
Really happy.
Oh, hey.
Thanks.
Those tears aren't
for me, are they?
There's a reason you
were such a grumpus today?
That is not a word!
Sorry. I know. My mom
says it. It sounds so stupid
that once you hear it,
it's hard to stay angry.
Note to self. Does
not work on Callie.
We're trying to
have another baby.
And I had an
appointment this morning,
you know, just to
get the lay of the land.
But I guess since
the car accident,
I've developed all
these adhesions,
and so I can't
carry another baby.
Oh, Callie, I'm so sorry.
No, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, too.
Wilson, we need
to put a bell on you.
I owe you both an
apology for snapping.
We overheard that one of the
residents isn't coming back next year,
and I've just been so
afraid that it might be me.
Could be. Totally possible.
It's not that James
isn't amazing. He is.
I mean, he really helped
me through something.
But I'm through
it now, you know?
I mean, I'm on the
other side, you know?
And now, when I stop
and look around, I just...
I don't think I need him
anymore, which is terrible, right?
I don't know.
When we're done here,
I am gonna go and meet
with our patient's family,
and then I'm gonna go home
and bake a cake with
your kids and read them
a really long bedtime story.
And then, when I have absolutely
no more ways of
avoiding breaking the heart
of this man who deserves
better, I'm gonna call James,
and I'm gonna tell
him that I love him...
But I can't do this anymore.
She's lying!
Bailey, that is enough.
I understand you
wanting to protect
our residents,
but you should not
have let it go this far.
Well, you're taking
her word over mine!
It is over, Bailey.
The Morrises have agreed
to drop the charges in exchange
for Edwards receiving one week's
disciplinary suspension.
They have gone home.
You should both do the same.
What the hell is wrong with you?
If you got fired over
this, no one would benefit
from this treatment
the way Braden did.
You were gonna go
down for this, Dr. Bailey.
You knew it could happen, but
you were willing to risk everything
to save that little boy.
What kind of surgeon would I be
if I wasn't willing
to do the same?
Plus, there's a chance I
won't even be here next year,
so I was just rolling the dice.
I was looking at
the bigger picture.
You're not going anywhere
without a fight from me.
If it's all right with you, sir,
I'd like to stay
on Monica's case.
I want to be there when she
comes back for a follow-up.
Come over here.
Let's, um... Let's have a seat.
That was a good
move today, Murphy.
You're very bright, and you have
what it takes to be
a very good doctor.
But you're not a surgeon.
What?
Standing next to you in
surgery today only confirmed it.
You make five moves
where a second-year
resident should make two.
Your knots aren't square. You
can't see the planes of dissection.
Next year, you'd
only fall farther behind.
I can work harder.
I can do better.
A surgical residency just
isn't the right fit for you.
Is...
Is this because I filed
that harassment complaint?
No, Murphy. No.
Letting you go
isn't a punishment.
It's a kindness.
And you deserve
every opportunity
to figure out what your
next steps might be.
In the meantime, Dr. Miller
at the University of
Washington runs a research lab,
and I think you would
do very well there.
She owes me a favor.
I'd be more than happy
to make a phone call.
Thank you, sir.
So, observe him
carefully overnight,
and in a few weeks, we'll do
a double-thickness skin graft.
Okay.
What, did you come
to steal more babies?
Don't tell Lebackes.
Oh, God. That makes it worse.
Get out. Look, I'm
sorry. I screwed up.
Kind of...
I'm drowning over there.
Here, cases come in all
the time. I can prove myself.
Over there, if you're
not bringing in the cases,
you're not bringing in the
money, and you're a nobody.
I don't want to lose this gig.
I didn't know what else to do.
I'm in trouble, and I need help.
What do you mean?
When something
like this happens,
you call me, and you say, "Arizona,
I'm in trouble, and I need help."
And I help you.
Do you understand? Right.
I couldn't tell
you. So you said.
I need to know.
This risk, was it
absolutely necessary?
He was dying.
And I created
something out of thin air.
I took a virus that kills
into something that heals,
and I saved his life.
I saved his life.
You know, I've thought about it,
and if you want to send
the ultrasound to your mom,
that wouldn't be
the worst thing.
You've told!
I kind of...
Who did you tell?
Stephanie?
Oh, wow! So, after all the
crap you gave me this morning,
you went and told
your ex-girlfriend?
It was an accident,
okay? I'm sorry. Uh-huh.
I forgive you.
Thanks. Mmm-hmm.
Still don't know how
we're gonna tell my mom.
What do you mean, "we"?
That is all you, Talky Tina.
How are your hives?
Oh, my back looks
like a political map
of the United States, big
mess of red down the middle,
plus Alaska. Bad day?
Bad day.
Did you pop a baby?
I popped a baby.
I don't even know what that
could mean. And do not elaborate.
You guys are gonna be fine.
That's easy for you to say.
Your big victory in
the OR. You're fine.
One of us is
definitely going down.
Come on, let's
go drink about it.
You really think
I'm gonna be okay?
I really do.
Go, go, go. I'll meet you there.
Well, I...
I could do it. No.
I could.
I could carry the baby.
I won't ask you to.
But I'm offering.
Because we want this.
I want this.
And I can do it.
We just got good again.
Now we're too fragile.
And something like this, if it
goes badly, we won't make it.
I'm not gonna put
us in that position.
Okay.
We have a beautiful life.
We have a beautiful daughter.
And that can be enough, right?
Yes.
That can be enough.
I love you, Calliope.
I love you, too.
Hey. How'd it go? Do we
have a new head of cardio?
I don't know.
I did screen all these applicants
before they came to you.
They couldn't have
been all that bad.
No, they're mostly
fine. No, not fine. Good.
Any one of them
could do the job.
Except humble-bragger.
What?
The Harper Avery Foundation's
been looking for ways
to mend fences with us
after what happened to you.
A large cash infusion
into our cardio department
could allow us to attract
higher caliber of talent,
and then... Owen, don't.
The worst they can do is say no.
Please don't offer me this job.
I...
I wanted to.
For a week.
But I know you have to go.
And I know nothing good
can come of me
asking you to stay.
So I'm not.
And I won't.
Thank you.
But I will ask you
something else.
What?
Owen... Just until you go.
Don't leave me until
you're leaving me.
Just until you go.
Hey, stranger! Hey!
What are you drinking?
You know what? Doesn't
matter. You can dump it out.
This is better.
Champagne is perfect, because...
I was wrong about
the Amelia situation.
She doesn't want to
leave. She wants to stay.
She can take over your service.
She can help out with the kids.
You can brain map
to your heart's content.
I don't have to
pull my hair out.
It is the answer
we've been looking for.
This is great! It is, right?
Yeah. Amy can move to
Seattle, and we can move to DC.
That wasn't the
point of my story.
I met him, Meredith.
I met the president.
He came to us.
We walked him through
everything we've been working on.
And then, at the end of it,
he said that he wanted to
make this a weekly thing.
They offered me a
position at the NIH.
It's the job. I'll
be right there,
on the ground, doing the actual
brain-mapping work myself.
They've given me everything.
Well, we can't just
pack up and move
across the country.
They have promised to
have an attending position
waiting for you at
James Madison hospital.
The thing about
the bold moves...
They're terrifying.
Could end in nothing but
tears and broken bones.
If Amy wants to move to Seattle,
she can take over my practice
without me hovering over
her, and she will thrive.
Alex is leaving,
Cristina's moving on.
They all have their next step.
This could be our next step.
This should be our next step.
And that's exactly what
makes them so damned exciting.