You jeopardized a man's life.
Am I gonna get fired?
I don't know if I'll be allowed
to practice medicine again.
It's not up to me.
You're supposed to
be her supervisor.
That never should have happened.
- Get out of my house!
- Daniel!
Why are you speaking
this way to my brother?
Because your brother
is suing Ripley
and the hospital
for malpractice.
I didn't think it
would happen so fast.
Alzheimer's is just a
very tricky diagnosis.
I'm sorry about this afternoon.
I didn't have the bandwidth
for worlds colliding.
Of course not.
It wasn't the time or the place.
- Thank you.
- Mm-hmm. You too.
Medium black coffee for
me, and I got her today.
What are you doing?
Because it's her birthday.
Oh, happy birthday.
Thank you.
I gotta say, I'm so pumped
for the big bash tonight.
I mean, pretty cool.
You have the same birthday
as your grandbaby?
I mean, come on.
Well, here's hoping
that my birthday twin
doesn't pass out before cake.
So is tonight really
the first night
that Bert and the kids
are meeting Dennis?
Well, just two of them.
David was gonna fly in,
but work got too hectic.
So how are you feeling?
Introducing the
boyfriend to the family.
Well, let's just say I only
got about three hours of sleep
last night, so...
- Oh, come on.
Dennis is gonna charm
their socks off.
Yeah, well, I better get going.
I got a meeting on the
Pawel suit in five.
Sharon, I'm so sorry you
gotta deal with that crap.
No worries.
How are things at home?
Honestly, it's a
little strained.
Yeah, I can imagine.
So let me know how
the meeting goes?
- Will do.
- All right.
Happy birthday.
- Thank you.
- That's right.
- Okay.
All right, so
these are my girls.
That is Melissa. That's Alice.
And Melissa is 24,
and Alice is 26?
- Yes, good memory.
- Oh.
And where are they?
That's Playa Del Carmen.
Melissa was actually supposed
to go with her girlfriend,
but the girlfriend
broke up with her
the night before the trip.
- Oh, poor kid.
- Mm-hmm.
I almost canceled my whole week
and hopped on the
next flight to Mexico.
You are a good mom.
Well, my girls mean
everything to me.
Isn't it just awful
watching your kids
go through their
first heartbreak?
Do you remember Sean's?
Sean's first serious breakup?
- Yes.
- Yeah.
Uh, well, actually,
Sean was the one doing
the heartbreaking back then.
Yeah, that does line up.
No one doubts the
suit is merit less,
but given the nature
of the injury...
It's gonna be your
word against Pawel's.
The bottom line is that
juries are unpredictable,
not to mention that
it could end up
costing the hospital
more to defend the claim
than to just settle it.
So trust me, the cost-benefit
analysis is clear.
It's to settle.
Sorry, I gotta get
back to the ED.
We got two helicopters inbound.
- Of course.
Listen, I'll draft
the settlement.
I'll get it over
to Pawel's lawyer.
And then there'll
be some documents
I'll need you to
sign, Dr. Ripley.
Now, hold on a second.
Listen, Dr. Ripley, this is
ultimately your decision.
If you wanna fight the suit,
the hospital will defend you.
- Reluctantly.
- Vigorously.
- Can I think it over?
- Absolutely.
- What's there to think about?
- That's not a problem.
Take the day.
Thank you, Ms. Goodwin.
Sharon, we are
settling this case.
Oh, hey, I hear the renegade
resident Dr. Ahmad got canned.
That true?
Try not to look so broken
up about it, okay, Peter?
And no, she was not canned.
She's suspended pending an
investigation of the incident.
Shayna Ellis,
28-year-old female.
She and a companion were
driving a UTV on the freeway
and got rear-ended.
Took a side-by-side
on the freeway?
Shocking it didn't
end well, right?
She was pretty
combative at the scene,
wouldn't let us treat her.
Gave her two of Versed,
four of morphine.
She's sedated but rousable.
Shayna, can you hear me?
You're at Chicago Med.
We're gonna take good
care of you, okay?
It's a good thing she was
wearing her seat belt.
The driver was not.
She got ejected
from the vehicle.
Yikes.
Clear breath sounds bilaterally.
She's tachycardic.
I'm gonna ultrasound.
Cycle her blood pressure cuff.
- Mm-hmm.
Dr. Ripley, I'm
bringing a second victim
into Baghdad right now.
- Zach.
- On it.
BP 150/100.
I'm not seeing any free fluid.
No.
Her right kidney look a
little abnormal to you?
Yeah, it does.
Nancy, let's get chest
and pelvis X-rays,
as well as an abdominal CT.
Yep. On it.
We did everything we could
for her at the scene,
but I don't know if
she's gonna make it.
Like her friend here, she
wasn't wearing a helmet.
- Get back!
- What's going on?
- Hey!
- I see them!
There they are! Look!
Back off right now!
They do not consent
to treatment!
We're taking them out of here!
- Like hell you are!
Get your hands off her!
You good?
Yeah.
Ow.
Maggie, who the hell
are these people?
Apparently, they're
members of a cult.
They've all been removed?
Yep, and we've
got extra security
posted outside in
case any of them
try to get back in.
Thanks, Kev.
What did you find
out about them?
Well, they call themselves
HTS, Heal Thyself.
The woman was driving
the UTV, Dakota Andrews.
AKA Cea, short for
Panacea, is the leader.
But wasn't Panacea
some kind of God?
The Greek goddess of healing.
She carried with her a potion
that could cure any
illness or injury.
I minored in
classical mythology.
Mm-hmm.
They're deeply anti-government.
They believe the medical
industrial complex
is a tool used to
control society,
that big pharma is incentivized
by the federal government
to actually keep people sick.
It appears to be mostly
an online community,
but the top brass live together
on a commune in Indiana.
Yeah, we picked them up
right along the border.
And how did they all
get here so fast?
Well, Shayna called
someone from the scene
before we sedated her.
We had to circle the
choppers a couple times
because of strong winds.
Shayna's labs just posted.
She's coming down from CT now,
and then I'll send Dakota up.
Great. Thanks, Zach.
Excuse me.
- Yeah.
Well, I guess I'll
be hitting the road,
unless you wanna put me to work.
Coming off a night
shift. I'm free.
I appreciate how much
you've helped us,
but you've been way too
generous with your time.
Why don't you go home
and get some sleep?
You know, I may have an
ulterior motive why I've been
hanging around the ED so much.
Oh, yeah? What's that?
Oh.
So sorry.
Trisha, are you okay?
No, I'm good.
See you around, Mags.
Yeah.
Are you two...
Oh, no. We're just friends.
In that case, you mind
putting in a good word for me?
I think I got a little crush.
Oh, yeah. I'd be happy to.
Thank you, Maggie.
You're the best.
Oh, Daniel, good.
Thank you for meeting me.
What's going on?
Will you give this to Sharon?
I'm afraid I'm not
going to be able
to make the party after all.
Oh, bummer. What's... what's up?
Pawel, he needs my help.
Well, what does he... what
does he need your help with?
Grocery shopping, a
few other errands.
Daniel, please.
- I didn't say anything.
I did not say anything.
He can't drive.
I am not going to have
him walk to the store.
He's my brother.
Sweetie, do you really
believe that he can't drive?
Dr. Ripley, I'm sure, did
not mean to harm Pawel.
But mistakes happen.
Dr. Ripley didn't make
a mistake, Liliana.
You were in the room.
You were right there.
I have to go to him.
I really do not want
to continue this.
But if we must, at home.
Okay.
Shayna.
Shayna, hi. I'm Dr. Ripley.
Cea.
Where is Cea?
You and your companion
were in an accident.
Where is she? Where
did you take her?
Your friend is in
critical condition,
but we're doing everything
we can to help her.
She doesn't need your help.
I beg to differ,
but right now, we
need to focus on you.
What is this?
What are you putting inside me?
It's just some medication to
control your blood pressure.
- I want it out. Now.
- I wouldn't advise that.
Shayna, your CT revealed a
mass on your adrenal gland.
It's likely a pheochromocytoma.
It's a rare tumor that
releases epinephrine
into your bloodstream, causing
the blood pressure to spike.
Have you found
yourself experiencing
panic attack-like
symptoms lately?
Rapid heartbeat, shortness of
breath, that kind of thing?
Okay, well, this appears
to have gone untreated
for some time.
Where is the adrenal gland?
We have two of them.
They're located on
top of your kidneys.
The crash caused you to
bleed in and around the mass,
which makes it even
more imperative
that we surgically remove
the pheo as soon as possible
to prevent life-threatening
complications
like heart attack and stroke.
I appreciate your
time and your concern
for my well-being, Doctor...
Ripley.
Dr. Ripley.
But I have come to the
realization on my own
and without coercion
that I don't want surgery
or any medical intervention.
I don't think you understand.
This could kill
you at any moment.
I understand completely the
potential risks of my choice.
I take full responsibility
for any negative consequences
that may result from
my informed decision.
And I would be happy
to put that in writing
or repeat my wishes
to a supervisor.
Okay?
No, no, I got it.
Crockett?
- Yeah?
Ambo just landed.
Pedestrian struck by a
vehicle while out jogging.
Dr. Tanaka-Reed is with you.
All right, uh, keep an eye
on your residents
today, Dr. Marcel.
Try not to let them
declare anyone dead
before they've actually croaked.
Hey.
Have you spoken to Zola?
How's she holding up?
- I don't know.
You haven't been
in touch at all?
No. I'm her attending, Maggie.
I'm not her buddy.
Mr. Acosta, I'm Dr. Tanaka-Reed.
We're gonna take good
care of you, okay?
Everyone watch the wires.
On my count. One, two, three.
I need to go home.
Emily is waiting.
- Patient's perseverating.
Let's give two of Versed.
- Got it.
Oh, no, wait a second.
BP's soft.
Yeah, but he's clearly agitated.
How do you know the
change of mental status
isn't from hypoxia?
Resuscitate before you sedate.
Let's give two units of blood,
two of plasma, and TXA, please.
Lungs are equal bilaterally.
Put your hands by
your side for me.
There you go.
Pelvis is loose.
Let's get X-ray in here.
Let's get a binder on
him in the meantime.
Why don't we wait
for X-ray to confirm?
Because I know a busted
pelvis when I feel one.
Dr. Marcel, the ICU just called.
Carson Miller's labs are back.
Okay, one second.
I'll be right there.
I can bind a pelvis
without supervision.
All right. I'll be back.
What is his deal today?
Hey.
Hi, you.
I just wanted to apologize
again for the other night.
Oh, my gosh, you have
to stop apologizing.
I get it.
You'd just been served. I'd
need a night to myself too.
Speaking of, what's going
on with the lawsuit?
I think we're gonna settle.
You seem thrilled.
Yeah, I've just never been
one to walk away from a fight.
Doesn't feel great.
- Mm-hmm.
Especially considering this
is the dude who messed up our,
you know, tea,
which I was really looking
forward to, by the way.
As was I.
Rain check?
I think we can make that happen.
I see we had the same idea
combating the mid-morning slump.
I'm trying to, but
the pickings are slim.
Ugh.
Isn't that Sam Abrams' wife?
Yeah, it is.
Trini, why don't you
get a treatment room
with a crib ready?
- Got it.
Michelle, hey.
- Oh, Hannah, thank God.
- Hey. What's going on?
Mason had a fall.
I've never heard
him cry like this.
He won't stop.
- Okay.
I'm scared something's
really wrong.
Yeah, okay. Let's
get him checked out.
Come on.
- Okay.
So how'd this happen?
He was in his stroller
seat, and he just fell out.
He wasn't buckled in?
I had just unbuckled him.
How far was the
drop, would you say?
About two, three feet?
Yeah.
Yeah, exactly. Not very far.
Well, he seems to be a little
fussy when I move his left arm.
He's clearly favoring his right.
I'd like to get an X-ray.
Is that safe for
a baby of his age,
the radiation exposure?
Absolutely. The
radiation is minute.
Michelle, I was in surgery.
I just got your text.
- Honey.
- Okay.
All right.
Did he lose consciousness?
Has he been crying
appropriately the whole time?
- Mm-hmm.
- Did he vomit at all?
Is he taking his bottle?
Sam, you can take a deep breath.
We're not seeing
any cause for alarm.
Yeah, Hannah's right.
He's awake and alert.
He was crying, but he's
consolable now, obviously.
And Mason's gonna be just fine.
How much Levophed is he on?
- Five mics.
- Okay.
Keep titrating him down.
He's doing a good job
clearing his sepsis.
It's the perfect window
to transplant him.
It's gonna close.
Just a matter of time
before he gets sick again.
I have to imagine he's top on
the transplant list, right?
Hopefully a pair of lungs
will come through soon.
Yeah.
Their founder, a woman
named Dakota Andrews,
claims that all illness is a
manifestation of stored trauma.
Hmm. Not a completely
baseless idea.
We do know that excess
adrenaline, cortisol,
can cause all kinds
of health issues.
Agreed, except that
her proposed remedy
is a combination of
energy work, meditation,
and herbal teas she
makes containing.
God knows what... no
medicine, no surgery,
no diagnostic tests.
How did she start to
attract a following?
After she claimed to have cured
her own malignant meningioma.
Started going by
the name Panacea
and posting her ideas online.
Happy to have a
chat with Shayna,
but needless to say,
just because she has
a belief system at odds
with our treatment plan...
No, I know.
I don't think she lacks
decisional capacity.
And even if she does,
she's been heavily coached
to pass the test.
I was actually
hoping you might know
something about deprogramming.
What?
- Well, just, you know,
in practice, historically
speaking, anyway,
pretty horrifying tactic.
Usually starts off
with kidnapping,
and then there's
illegal imprisonment.
Yeah, no, I wasn't
suggesting we kidnap her.
Look, getting
somebody to abandon
a deeply held belief system
is not typically a
one-and-done idea,
but let me see where she's at.
Appreciate it.
The results of Dakota
Andrews' head CT.
Subdural hematoma with
brainstem herniation.
Neurosurgery saw her,
said her exam is congruent
with brain death and supported
by the confirmatory testing.
They just moved her to the ICU.
Any family to notify?
An older brother
who lives in Ohio.
He's on his way
here to say goodbye,
and he's expressed a desire
to possibly donate
his sister's organs.
Hey, uh... sorry.
Y'all mind keeping me
posted if the family decides
to go with organ donation?
I've got a patient up in the
ICU in dire need of new lungs.
- Sure thing.
- Yeah. Of course.
Great, thank you.
Hey, Zach?
Let me see Dakota's
head CT again.
I just wanna look at something.
They're ready.
Hey. What's going on?
We're heading up to
interventional radiology
to angio his pelvis.
- FAST was negative?
Have you been transfusing him?
Obviously.
BP 90 systolic.
His pressure's dropped before.
We just need to
give him more blood.
No, change of plans.
We're taking him up to the OR.
We'll pack his pelvis,
get him resuscitated,
then we can go to IR.
I'll call upstairs.
Isn't the OR an
unnecessary delay?
Mr. Acosta's been responding
well to blood and plasma.
Let's continue to
resuscitate him in IR.
You don't wanna take an
unstable patient to IR.
Things start going south,
you're much better off
being in the operating room.
Trust me.
Good judgment comes
from experience.
Experience comes
from bad judgment.
You should put that
on a bumper sticker.
Let's go.
Hey.
Just got Mason's X-ray back.
Mm, good.
Greenstick fracture
of the left humerus.
It need to be splinted, but
looks like it should heal
just fine on its own, right?
Correct.
Okay, then.
Why do you look like
the sky is falling?
It's highly suspect to
see a humerus fracture
from a short fall.
What are you saying?
These types of fractures,
especially in babies,
typically come from
direct blunt-force trauma.
What?
We should loop in Ms. Goodwin.
Hospital policy, not
to mention the law,
mandates that we notify
DCFS in these situations.
But this is Sam and Michelle.
There's just... there's no
way that this is child abuse.
You can't say that with
100% certainty, Hannah.
None of us were there.
- And if we turn a blind eye
because it's
Dr. Abram's family...
Look, I know how it looks.
It looks like
preferential treatment
because he's the
chief of neurosurgery.
And frankly, that's
exactly what it would be.
We all know how quickly
these investigations
can go off the rails.
They could lose their baby.
- I agree.
It seems highly implausible
that Mrs. Abrams
did something
intentional to Mason.
But she is also
a sleep-deprived,
terrified new mother.
We have no idea what's
going on in her head.
We have to err on
the side of caution.
Look, if you'd like,
I'll speak to the Abrams.
No, no, no. It
should come from us.
We'll talk to them.
Thank you.
Went about as well
as I expected,
so, you know, not great.
I mean, she thinks that Dakota
is this omnipotent being,
and everything she
says is the truth,
and everything else is a lie.
Well, I think I might have
a way to break the spell,
prove to her that Dakota isn't
an all-powerful celestial being.
She didn't cure her
malignant meningioma
with meditation and herbs.
She never had brain cancer.
You see Dakota's
head CT from today?
No scar gliosis, no
evidence of past tumor.
Okay, just curious about
what this might have to do
with Shayna's care
right now, if anything.
If Shayna knew...
- Mitch, come on.
- Hey, I'll say it.
If there was ever an
instance to break HIPAA...
Because you might
get away with it?
Because Dakota is gonna die,
and the truth is
gonna die with her.
I dug deeper into this group,
and a lot of the
people who follow HTS
have completely
treatable illnesses
but are refusing care
because of this woman's
dangerous brainwashing.
If we can get Shayna to
see that Dakota built HTS
on nothing more than a lie...
- Need some help in here.
She tried to stand up
and had a dizzy spell.
Her blood pressure is
through the roof, 200/130.
And she won't allow us to
restart the phentolamine drip.
Shayna, you're having
a hypertensive crisis.
The pheo is releasing massive
amounts of epinephrine
into your bloodstream.
We need to give you
something to bring
your blood pressure down, or
you're gonna have a stroke.
I don't want your poison.
After the incision, you're gonna
make a nick in the fascia.
Then you're gonna
put down the knife
and grab the electrocautery.
Elevate the fascia, pull
out the hematoma, and pack.
I know the steps.
Scalpel.
Make sure you stay
out of the peritoneum.
Go on.
There you go.
Mr. Andrews?
Yes.
- I'm Dr. Charles.
- Hi.
First of all, I wanna offer
my very sincere condolences.
Thank you.
And I also understand that
you've agreed to organ donation.
That's an incredibly
generous act.
At Dakota's core, I think
all she really wanted
was to help people.
She just went about
it in the wrong way.
Kind of what I was hoping
to talk to you about today.
Do you mind if we sit?
I've been treating a young
woman who was in the crash
with your sister today.
One of her followers?
Yeah, very entrenched in
your sister's philosophy,
and as a consequence,
she's been refusing
life-saving treatment.
Oh, God.
When I first heard
the story that Dakota
was peddling that she'd
cured her own brain cancer,
I thought it'd be obvious
that that couldn't be true.
I knew what she was
saying was dangerous,
that it could hurt people,
but our relationship
was already so tenuous.
I was afraid that if
I confronted her...
You might lose your sister.
That's a really difficult
position to be in.
She had a lot of demons.
But I loved...
I loved her very much.
And now here I am,
losing her forever.
I'm so sorry that it's too
late to help your sister.
But if you're willing, I
think that it might not be
too late to help
this young woman.
You can't be serious.
Look, we're not accusing
you of anything.
This is just protocol...
- What a load of
yes, you are.
Get Mason. We're leaving now.
You know we can't let you leave.
It's gotta be cleared
by DCFS first.
Is that everything?
Let's go.
Move aside, or I will move you.
Sam.
Come on. Don't do this.
Please, don't make
us call security.
Honey, I don't know.
I can't believe you're
doing this to my family.
Mr. Acosta's wife is
asking for an update.
What should I tell her?
Soon as Kai finishes packing,
we'll close and take him to IR,
so hopefully any day now.
Gentlemen, temp's down to 96.8.
Gotta move faster, Kai.
Yeah, I'm trying.
Pressure's down.
How much blood has he had?
Four pack cells, four plasma.
- Any platelets?
- Not yet.
All right, give him
a dose of platelets
and start him on pressors.
Come on, Kai! Hurry up!
If I'm not moving fast
enough, do it yourself.
Step away from the
table right now.
Gladly.
All right, come on. Focus, guys.
We're not done yet.
Shayna?
There's somebody here who
would like to talk to you.
This is Josh, Dakota's brother.
Why are you here?
I'm afraid.
My sister's not gonna make it.
No.
Unfortunately, Shayna,
Dakota suffered
a catastrophic brain
injury in the crash.
She can heal herself.
She's done it before.
I really wish that were true.
Smart move, pulling in someone
who isn't bound by HIPAA.
I figured the last thing you
needed was another lawsuit.
You think he'll be able
to get through to her?
I don't know. I mean,
I certainly hope so.
Checking to see if
there's anything you need.
Can we talk somewhere private?
Yeah, of course. Come here.
Hannah...
I lied.
Okay.
I was just so scared that if
I said what actually happened
please, they cannot take
Mason away from Sam.
He hasn't done anything wrong.
This is all my fault.
- Okay, okay.
- It's all my fault.
- Just take a deep breath.
We're gonna figure
this out, okay?
Just, just...
- What have I done?
Tell me what really happened.
I was... oh, God.
I was doing work in bed
on my laptop this morning.
You know, I've been
working from home
since Mason was born, and
he woke up from his nap
early, and he was crying,
so I brought him
into bed with me.
And he was on my chest.
I swear to God, I don't even
remember my eyes closing,
and the next thing
I know, he's crying.
And he's just not
on my chest anymore,
and I'm on my side,
and Mason is on
the hardwood floor,
and my laptop is on top of him.
Michelle, Michelle, hey.
Hey, that was an accident.
Hey, what's going on?
Hey, honey. What...
- I'm sorry.
- Sweetheart.
Honey, what is it?
- It's my fault.
What is it? No, no, no.
Talk to me.
It's my fault.
Oh, baby, no, no, no.
It's gonna be okay.
- Crockett.
- Hey.
Hey. Mr. Acosta's doing well.
He's on his way to IR now.
Great. Hey, what
was that back there?
What do you mean?
Were you trying to
break Kai's confidence?
Come on, Maggie.
The patient was crashing,
and Kai's got confidence
to spare, all right?
- I was there.
It wasn't a crisis point.
- Yet.
I needed to gain control
of the situation,
and quickly, all right?
Well, maybe Kai was having
problems picking up his pace
because he couldn't concentrate.
You were breathing
down his neck.
Is this even about Kai?
What's that supposed to mean?
You think that you
were too lax with Zola?
Clearly, I was
too lax with Zola.
I gave her an inch,
and she took a mile.
I'm gonna make sure that
doesn't happen again.
Whoa.
I really like Zola, but
this wasn't her first rodeo.
This was her third residency.
And I don't think the
problem was your supervision
or your lack thereof.
You're not responsible
for her poor decisions.
And neither is Kai.
So don't take it out on him.
- How's it going in there?
- Good.
I mean, good given where
it could have gone.
Gastern agrees it
was an accident,
but DCFS need to do a home visit
before they can close
the investigation,
and Michelle has to attend
a mandatory parenting class.
Yeah.
Man, if Michelle had
just told the truth
from the beginning, she could
have avoided all of this.
Mm.
Lies always catch up to you.
I told one today to Margo.
It was a lie of
omission, really.
Okay. Why do you
think you did that?
Well, same as Michelle.
I didn't want her to
think I was a bad parent.
So she asked me if I remembered
Sean's first heartbreak.
And I made some glib
remark, you know.
But the truth is...
I had no idea. I wasn't there.
My advice?
If you must.
You're gonna have to show
her who you are eventually.
Mm.
It's called being vulnerable.
You can't have a real
relationship without it.
Let her see you, Dean,
your warts and all.
Dr. Charles.
Hey, I just wanted
to let you know
that Shayna agreed
to be admitted
and put back on a
phentolamine drip.
Oh, excellent news.
Yeah, that should keep
her in the hospital
for at least a couple of
days, hopefully enough time
to get her stabilized and
on board with surgery.
I'll make sure somebody
from inpatient psych's
assigned to her case.
- Yeah, great.
I wonder if the rest
of the followers
will ever figure it out.
Who knows?
See you later.
Oh, what did you, um
what did you decide
about the lawsuit?
Sharon said that you were taking
the rest of the day
to figure it out
if you don't mind me asking.
Look, I think settling
is all but inevitable.
Kalmick said it'd be my
word against Pawel, so...
Of course, right?
A respected physician's
word against a con man's?
Apparently, juries
are unpredictable.
Sure, but I mean, a
grifter like Pawel?
I mean, it shouldn't be
that hard to poke holes
in this guy's credibility,
I'm telling you.
I mean, for instance, he's
got a major gambling problem.
There's your motive right there.
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah.
Last year, Lili lost the
down payment to a house
paying off his gambling debts.
- Really?
- Really.
I mean, the guy's
a fricking menace.
And he's gonna
continue to be a menace
until he gets a
message that, you know,
you just can't use
other people as pawns.
Well, then, it sounds like
it's time he got that message.
That is one sparkly
birthday girl sweater.
You look fabulous.
- Thank you.
Oh, I wonder who that could be.
You better get it quick.
- Leave me alone.
Leave me alone.
Hey.
- Hey.
Ready to meet everyone?
You bet.
Everyone, this is Dennis.
Hey there.
Hi, Michael.
- And Tara.
- Hi.
I'm a hugger. Is that okay?
Oh, please.
Hi.
Hey, Bert. Nice to meet you.
You too.
Sorry, remind me...
- Dennis.
Okay, got it now.
And who's that for?
Well, actually, it's something
for you and the birthday boy.
Oh!
Yeah, it's something
that Sharon told me
that Isaiah liked to
do with his grandpa.
Wow.
Where is the birthday boy?
Oh, he partied a
little too hard,
so he's already
knocked out upstairs.
You wanna open?
- Go ahead. Go ahead.
- Okay.
Tear it open.
Aww.
He loves blocks.
Thank you.
- Oh, wow.
Grandpa loves to
build him tall towers.
And Isaiah likes
to knock them down.
And so does Grandpa.
Thank you.
I told you so.
- Oh, hey.
- Trisha, um...
I'm sorry, but I actually can't
put in a good word with Loren.
Um, okay.
Oh, I see.
Mm-hmm.
So when are you
gonna make your move?
Oh, I hadn't really
thought about it.
You should, because
Loren is a catch, Maggie.
And if not me, it'll be
someone else who snaps him up.
Don't do that.
Don't time yourself.
Why not?
Because your pace is just fine.
Really.
If you rush, you'll get
sloppy, start to make mistakes.
All right.
- Dr. Marcel?
- Yeah?
I wanted to let you know,
unfortunately, Dakota wasn't a
donor match for Carson Miller.
I'm assuming he's your patient.
Yeah, he is.
Well, good news is,
he's top of the transplant list.
Hopefully there'll
be a match soon.
- Yeah.
- Thanks, Zach.
Mm-hmm.
By the way, does Sean know
that we're seeing each other?
I haven't said
anything, and I just...
I didn't know if he knew yet.
He does, and he's very
much in favor of it.
Okay, okay, good.
That is a relief, 'cause I
know how close you guys are.
Yeah, Sean and I are
we're close, at least now.
There was a period of
time, almost 15 years,
where we weren't.
And actually, we
didn't talk at all.
Yeah.
Wow, I mean, Sean, he
never said anything.
He's probably trying to
protect me, your opinion of me.
So what happened?
I tried for years
his mother and I both tried
for years to get him off drugs,
and he wouldn't quit using.
And I finally cut him off,
told him to get back in
touch when he was clean.
And 15 years goes by.
What are you thinking about?
Honestly?
Yeah.
I just... I can't
imagine anything else
Melissa could do that would
make me stop speaking to them.
Single greatest
regret of my life.
I know, that's a
red flag. I get it.
Well...
Hold on a second.
I was going to say
that I have never dealt
with addiction as a parent.
So I... I don't
know what I would do
if there were to ever
come a point where...
To give up on your kid?
There's no excuse
for what I did.
And I'm not making any.
I see the way you show up
for Sean, and it's beautiful.
And it's one of the
reasons I was so
drawn to you.
And now?
Yeah, I'm not seeing
any red flags here.
- I do okay?
- Better than okay.
Tara's already pulled me
aside to gush over you.
Good to see you.
You get home safe now.
Oh, you too, Bert. I hope
to see you again soon.
Yeah. Hon, look, I'm tired.
I'm gonna go to bed.
I'll leave the light on for you.
Hey, Dad.
If you're tired, let's
just get you home, okay?
Yeah, I'll pull up the car.
Get me home? I am home.
Dad, this is Mom's house.
Best not to contradict.
Wait a minute. Wait, wait, wait.
What are you talking
about, this is Mom's house?
She's my wife. This
is my house too.
Why don't we go sit down
on the couch for a moment?
I don't wanna have
a seat on the couch.
I'm tired! I wanna go to bed!
Is everything okay, Bert?
I don't know what they're saying
that this isn't my house.
They're trying to
steal it from me!
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
Bert. Come on, now.
I want all of you
out of my house, now!
I think if we just
go sit down...
Okay.
Can you...
- Yes, yes, of course.
- Get your hands off me.
- You're okay, Bert.
You're okay.
- It's okay.
Let go! Let go of me!
You're okay, Dad. You're okay.
Come on. Come on.
All right, just sit down.
It's okay.
Bert
let's sing your
favorite song, huh?
Each day through my window
I watch her as she passes by
I say to myself
You're such a lucky guy
Sing with me, baby.
Both:  To have a girl like her
Is truly a dream come true
Out of all the
fellas in the world
She belongs to you
You remember this song.
Both:  But it was
just my imagination
Once again
both:  Running away with me
There you go.
It was
all:  Just my imagination
Running away with me
Hmm?
Yeah?
This isn't my house.
No.
We're not married?
No, but it's okay.
- Uh-huh.
- It's okay.
It's okay.