She's smart. She's tough.
She'll fight for ya.
I've been impressed
with her every time.
How many times
have you been sued?
Twice, just twice.
But when you run a hospital,
it's good to know a good lawyer.
Aaron!
Janet, hi.
Oh, my gosh. Did it happen?
Did you play Pebble Beach?
I did, and it was the
worst mistake of my life.
Hello.
I am Dr. Shaun Murphy
of San Jose St.
Bonaventure Hospital.
- Your client.
- Yes.
Aaron has told me
a lot about you.
Congratulations on all you...
Is this billable time?
It is.
But it will be paid for
by your insurance company.
And I have good news.
$300,000 that will be paid by
your malpractice insurance.
All you have to do is
sign some documents
and agree to a six-month
supervisory period.
You can still practice medicine.
It just means another doctor
would have to sign off
on all your decisions.
Excuse me.
That is not good news.
Can it be anyone?
Anyone qualified.
So Park, M-Morgan.
It could be anyone you
trust. Could be me.
I have worked very
hard to be an attending
to prove that I don't
need anyone's approval
to do what I think
should be done.
Which is often different from
what Dr. Park, or Morgan,
or you think should be done.
Also... it is
very humiliating.
- What if he says no?
- We go to trial.
And if he loses at trial?
The money will still be paid
by the insurance company.
But the bigger issue is that a
report, and the court's decision,
will be sent to the
California Medical Board,
and they will make a
decision about whether...
you have a future as a doctor.
I'll settle.
I need to go to the bathroom.
Excuse me, excuse me, excuse me.
You're Dr. Shaun Murphy,
- Miss Stewart's 10:00 a.m.?
- Yes, hello.
My name is Joni DeGroot.
Um... I'm curious
about cancer patients
whose exposure came
from formaldehyde
in pressed wood
office furniture.
Have you had a case like that?
No. Nor have I
read about that.
If you have a case
where that is alleged,
- I would not be a good consultant.
- It's not for a case.
It's...
Thank you. Thank you,
thank you, Dr. Murphy.
Tell Miss Stewart
to review my update
on Carter v. Willis before
finalizing your NDA.
The Idaho District Court made
the stare decisis vulnerable.
Are you working on my case?
You should not be in here.
This is my office.
No one is supposed to
come into my office.
Okay.
I'm not officially on your case.
But I read the file.
It was amazing how you
created arterial clamps
out of pieces of
an aluminum can.
Yes. Why is everything
covered in plastic?
They're getting ready to paint.
Oh, I thought it was because
of your obsessive-compulsive
disorder.
I used to have a
closet for an office.
Did you choose this instead
of sharing an office?
- It's not a closet. It's an office.
- It is very small.
Even smaller than my closet.
This is all I need. I
don't meet with clients.
And it's very private,
so I'm not disturbed
while I'm doing my research...
Or your rituals.
Nice to meet you, Joni DeGroot.
You're settling your case?
Yes.
Miss Stewart and Dr. Glassman
say it is for the best.
Your settlement includes
a supervisory period?
Mm... yes. Six months.
Hmm.
It doesn't seem
right. Does it?
That... That you
should be punished
for saving a man's life?
You've overcome a lot.
To have that kind of
mark on your record...
seems very humiliating.
- I see you're still in the big office.
- Ah.
The partner uprising wasn't
as bad as you feared, huh?
It's an ongoing battle.
Joni, I'm with a client.
No, she is.
Joni is my lawyer now.
She will be representing
me at trial.
Resync By M_I_S
www.opensubtitles.org
I have a new lawyer.
I have a new client.
How did you get the partners
to change their minds?
The client insisted
that I represent him
instead of Janet Stewart.
What?
♪♪ If I felt this way before ♪♪
♪♪ Now I do not recall ♪♪
You stole your boss's client?
♪♪ If we go ♪♪
And what does Glassman
think about this?
He said it was my decision.
Did he say that in a
neutral way or an angry way?
♪♪ Then I am gonna fall down ♪♪
Angry.
He is worried about
Joni's lack of experience.
But she's smart, and
because of her OCD,
she is very thorough and
understands my situation.
OCD.
You mean she's really
neat and organized?
No, that is not OCD.
She has repetitive
intrusive thoughts
that cause excessive anxiety
which she manages
with ritual behavior.
And when you say
lack of experience?
This will be her first trial.
♪♪ Really and truly, maybe ♪♪
I get to go to court. I
get to be a real lawyer.
Which is great, very exciting,
but it's also... court.
All those people... the judge,
the jury, the other lawyers,
and everyone looking at you...
watching while you do that.
I'm practicing exposure to
contaminants and noises.
I can adapt. I can hide it.
But that's the upside
of your current setup.
You don't have to hide it.
Because they're hiding me.
Mm.
♪♪ Really and truly, maybe ♪♪
♪♪ Really and truly,
it might be ♪♪
Pockets.
Your outfits for court
will need pockets.
When you need to tap,
put your hand in there,
no one will know.
Just... don't be late.
You're late.
I thought you had
this worked out.
I know, I know, I know. Sorry.
The... The bus stalled right
in the middle of Hastings.
Do you want me to call the
VTA and check if that's true?
No.
Sorry. It won't happen again.
The night of the accident,
you were coming from where?
I was giving Shaun a lift home.
We had grabbed dinner
together after work.
Did either of you have
alcohol with dinner?
I, uh... had a beer,
and, um, Shaun didn't.
Joni, your tapping is
distracting Dr. Park.
I'm okay.
Tap three times or bad
things will happen.
Your shift that day,
how long was it?
Did you or Dr. Murphy have
any difficult surgeries?
Uh, nothing unusual.
I had an appendectomy,
22-year-old patient, no issues.
Tap three times or bad
things will happen.
Shaun performed a
bowel resection.
Tap three times or bad
things will happen.
Joni...
Tap three times or bad
things will happen.
Joni.
I'm sure you have more
questions for Dr. Park.
You and Dr. Murphy left the
restaurant around what time?
Uh, a little after 10:30 p.m.
We were on Hellyer,
coming through the wooded
section of the park...
and between the
rain and the turns,
I was driving pretty slowly.
Good thing... There
was a car in the road.
I'm a doctor. My
name is Alex Park.
- I need to examine...
- Where is Bob?
I need you to hold
still. Scalp laceration.
Was there anyone
else in the car?
Yes. My brother, Bob.
He was driving.
Hello?
He was thrown out.
Bob?
Bob!
I found Bob!
He is bleeding from
his radial artery.
We need to move him!
I can't leave her!
Okay, Bob.
That's wrong.
What?
You didn't bring him that way.
Oh. Yes, I did.
No, you didn't.
Yes, he did.
No, he didn't. You couldn't
have. There was a log there.
Most people's brains
prioritize details,
weed out what seems unimportant.
My brain doesn't.
Why does it matter what route
Shaun took out of the woods?
- The case is ab...
- It matters
because if that way was blocked,
I must have taken him this way.
I would've had to
angle the spinal board,
which could've caused
neurological injury,
which could mean my neuro exam
was off, which could mean...
I didn't need to
amputate his hand.
This seems like a
good time for a break.
Tell me about your decision to
amputate the plaintiff's hand.
His breathing became labored,
and his pulse was thready.
He had no capillary refill.
His hand was irreversibly
damaged from lack of blood flow.
It was leaking toxins
that would stop his heart
before he reached the hospital.
I need to amputate his hand.
The ambulance is
two minutes away.
But ambulances do not
carry amputation kits.
There is no time.
Once I removed the hand...
we traveled safely
to the hospital.
That's... not quite
how I remember it.
The ambulance is
two minutes away!
I need to amputate his hand.
There's no time.
Shaun! It could
be a vasospasm!
The ambulance is here!
They'll have a calcium
channel blocker
that might restore
the blood flow!
Shaun, are you sure?
Interesting.
This is a disaster.
He has to settle.
You have to talk him into
accepting the settlement.
No, it doesn't change
the underlying merits...
It changes the testimony.
It changes our testimony.
One of our witnesses is going to
testify that our client screwed up.
His view of the accident is almost
exactly what their expert...
What are you doing?
I'll talk to Dr. Park
and counsel him...
No. I mean to my books.
I straightened one. Or two.
Listen to me.
Taking this case to
trial, with that client
and you as counsel,
is a terrible idea.
Fix this or bad
things will happen.
You cannot win a case if
the jury doesn't like you...
if you make them uncomfortable.
- Fix this or bad things will happen.
- Cases are stories.
Fix this or bad
things will happen.
And we write it all.
Except the ending.
Fix this or bad
things will happen.
You can't control
yourself in my office.
How are you gonna control
yourself in court?
Texas v. Marquez.
What?
425 Federal Digest, page 734.
Um, you're gonna have to
give me a little more...
Owen Marquez was caught entering his
high school carrying a Swiss army knife.
He was charged with being on
school property with a weapon.
But they'd set up
the metal detectors
outside the front door.
The case was dismissed.
Interesting.
But different state, different
court, different law.
- Same principle.
- I don't think I can convince a judge that that is...
Let me try.
Oh, I have to go.
Stop. Stop. Stop.
I'm about to test the
lactate levels in Bob's hand.
This will prove definitively
if I was right to amputate.
No. This will
tell you nothing.
Medically, it will.
Legally, morally,
this'll tell you nothing.
This test will
tell me the truth.
Was... that a laugh?
It was a scoff.
Why would you
scoff at the truth?
What truth?
There's only one.
There's a single correct
answer to any question.
But there are a
lot of questions.
You're asking, "What was
the right thing to do then,
given what you know now?"
Which is a stupid question.
I don't like to use
the word "stupid."
"Desperate" then.
For an answer.
But whatever that test says,
we have to share it
with the other side.
If it goes the way you want, we
will definitely win your case.
If it goes the other way, we
will definitely lose your case.
But neither result will tell
you if you did the right thing,
given what you knew at the time.
So the real question here is...
Do you believe in that test
more than you believe in me?
Why?
Why am I doing what you
just asked me to do?
Why do you have so
much confidence in me?
I'm a lawyer with OCD.
I work out of a closet.
I was late to the only
meeting you had with me.
Why do you trust me
more than the test?
Because the test doesn't care.
That's a good answer.
Hm.
We're gonna have a motion to
dismiss tomorrow at 10:00 a.m.
Don't be late.
One, two, three.
One, two...
We'll be okay.
Only if I do this right.
Now I have to start over.
One, two, three.
Mom will be okay.
Joni DeGroot for the
defense, Your Honor.
Yes, I can see your name right
here on top of your brief.
Excellent. May I say
what a privilege it is...
No. No, you may not.
You are just here to
argue this motion,
which... is a novel argument.
Thank you, Your Honor.
It wasn't completely
a compliment.
Dr. Murphy cannot
be held liable
for professional misconduct
because Dr. Murphy
was not acting in a
professional capacity.
He was a Good Samaritan.
And you're taking the position
that The Good Samaritan
exception stayed in effect
even after the
ambulance arrived?
Yes, because he didn't do the
amputation in the ambulance.
He was outside the ambulance.
He chose not to do the
amputation in the ambulance.
To save your client's
life. He had no time.
The ambulance was right there.
Right there? What
does that mean?
Would it have been "right
there" if he was 10 feet away?
100 feet? Or a half a mile?
All interesting questions
for another case.
He was five feet away.
Outside is outside.
The statute specifies
protection if the care happens
at the scene of an emergency.
Counsel is using a technical
distinction that...
Counsel is using the law.
Statutory interpretation
rules require, Your Honor,
to "give effect, if
possible, to every clause
and word of a statute,
avoiding, if it may be,
any construction which implies
that the legislature..."
Two more squeaks.
You just stopped?
I lost my train of thought.
You said you didn't think
you could win this motion...
I would've finished it.
I...
I heard a squeak.
I needed two more squeaks
to complete the set.
They pulled the
settlement offer.
And... the partners met.
You're off the case.
- They told you...
- Mm. The vote was unanimous.
You are a good researcher.
You are a database that thinks.
But you need to accept
that you are not,
and you are never going
to be, a good lawyer.
No, no, no.
Joni is my lawyer.
It is my case, my choice.
And your career
that's riding on this.
Joni's deficits are
more significant
than you think they are.
Everybody said that about
me. Everybody was wr...
Do you know why her
office is a closet?
Joni has had issues
since she started here.
She was late a lot.
Her first assignment, her
first motion, she missed it.
She must have had a good reason.
She saw someone drowning.
Oh.
She was on her way to court,
driving by the bay,
and she saw something.
She stopped, called the police.
They shut down the road,
searched the water.
Joni knew she saw...
a log, a wave... nothing.
But her mind wouldn't let her
accept that it was nothing.
We found out this had
happened twice before.
Why didn't you fire her?
Because she
threatened to sue us,
arguing that firing her
would be a violation
of the American's
With Disabilities Act.
- Was it?
- I'm not sure. I don't think so.
But this brief that she wrote...
most impressive
thing I've ever read.
So she doesn't need an office,
because she doesn't need to meet with
clients because she does research.
Just research.
She cannot be your
trial attorney.
- I hate her.
- I don't.
She stuffed you in a
closet. Set you up to fail.
You know she's done more.
She hired me. She saved...
She sent you to
court on your own.
What was she expecting?
She expected me to
do the job. So did I.
She could've been there...
It was my idea, my
argument, my case...
my failure.
Why do you want to be a lawyer?
Why did you threaten to sue?
Why do you want to be there?
They're a very good firm...
I-interesting files,
important cases,
and it's not like I
have huge options...
No. I meant...
why do you want to be a lawyer?
A lawyer saved our family.
Our father died in a car
accident when I was 8.
That's when my OCD started.
I was very worried that
my mother would die, too.
So you developed rituals
meant to prevent it?
Mm.
And she didn't die.
But she did drink.
Bad things happened.
A lot of people made
a lot of mistakes...
Our mother, some
overworked social workers,
some foster parents, a judge.
But one person made
it all right again...
A lawyer.
Joni...
I still want you as my lawyer.
Dr. Murphy, I made
a huge mistake.
Because...
I have a problem.
We all have problems.
I'll talk to Janet.
Dr. Murphy wants you as first
chair. So you're first chair.
- I'm first chair?
- You are not first chair.
I'm not first chair.
You are a figurehead.
You will sit in your first chair
and you will not say a word.
You will not stand up.
You will not object.
If you have to tap,
you will tap quietly...
on your leg.
Now wish me luck.
Good luck.
In your expert opinion,
when Dr. Murphy
concluded that my client's hand
was irreversibly damaged and
needed to be amputated...
He was wrong.
The lack of blood
flow was caused
by a temporary condition
known as vasospasm,
which can occur after a
trauma such as a car accident.
Vessels temporarily clamp down,
cutting off the flow of blood.
In this case, Mr. Patton's
ulnar artery spasmed.
And this condition is treatable?
Yes... with an injection
of calcium channel blocker,
which was available in
the ambulance that night.
Hm.
Thank you.
Your witness.
Any last minute ideas?
Anything we can challenge
him on medically?
It wasn't vasospasm.
Anything we could prove?
No.
Dr. Rutenberg,
are you being paid
- by the Plaintiff's attorney for your testimony today?
- I am.
Then you can hardly consider
yourself unbiased, can you?
It's routine for
experts to be paid.
You're being paid.
And I admit, I am biased...
Excuse me, excuse me, excuse me.
Traumatic vasospasm doesn't
occur in isolated vessels,
but rather the entire
affected limb, right?
Yes, of course.
Can you visually identify
a damaged or occluded vessel
versus one in vasospasm?
Yes.
So...
this one?
Occluded.
Vasospasm.
Not vasospasm?
- No.
- Objection, Your Honor.
Is this testimony or the MCAT?
Goes to the witness' expertise.
Oh, he's definitely an expert.
That last photo, which
did not show vasospasm,
that was a pathology image of
Mr. Patton's radial artery.
And if his radial
artery didn't vasospasm,
then according to
your expert testimony,
his ulnar artery didn't either.
Is that correct?
It's possible.
But we'd only know for sure if Dr. Murphy
had given the calcium channel blocker.
- I'm sorry.
- You're not great at taking direction, are you?
- No, I shouldn't...
- And you only still have a job
- because you threatened to sue us.
- I'm sorry!
I'm not wanted in
a lot of places.
I make people feel
uncomfortable.
If I let that stop me,
I wouldn't be anywhere.
At my first job, I was
the only female associate.
Tomorrow...
you're first chair.
Actual first chair.
Good luck.
Nice work. This is good stuff.
- Thank you.
- The carpal tunnel research is really interesting.
A pre-existing condition
mitigates our client's respon...
I'm not gonna use that.
It could help reduce damages.
If damages are even $1, it
means Dr. Murphy was negligent,
which means his medical
license would be at risk.
We need total victory.
Okay. So what's
your theory on this?
How are you going to
approach this witness?
I'm going to establish
that he's a dick.
I can't do my job.
I can't even hold my niece.
Thank you.
No more questions, Your Honor.
Dr. Murphy saved your life.
Is that a question?
Not really. Seems
pretty obvious.
- I meant...
- I know what you meant. I'll rephrase.
What kind of person sues a
person who saved their life?
Do you sue people who buy
you Christmas presents
you don't want, or
only the weird ones
you figure the jury won't like?
Objection... compound
and argumentative.
Sustained.
I'm the victim here.
You were driving, right?
- Yes.
- Over the speed limit?
I'm not sure.
According to police analysis
of your skid marks...
- Yes. A little.
- You were going at least 70 in 40 zone.
- You were ejected out the car window?
- Yes.
So you weren't
wearing a seat belt?
- I'm not sure.
- It was fastened behind you.
Yes.
So all things considered,
maybe a better adjective than
"victim" would be "lucky".
Withdrawn.
Do you feel any guilt
over any of this?
You're asking me
if I feel guilty
- about wanting to be compensated for losing...
- No.
I am asking you
if you feel guilty
about driving recklessly,
flipping your car,
and almost killing
your sister...
the mother of your niece?
Yeah, a little.
Is she suing you f...
Two more squeaks.
Counsel, do we have a problem?
Again?
Uh, one moment.
Don't win cheap. You're
better than this...
I am fighting for my client.
If she can't handle
a little adversity,
then she shouldn't be here.
Don't let that dick prove
people like me right.
Hey, hey, hey.
Miss Stewart, I will
hold you in contempt.
If Dr. Murphy had
been a not nice person
and just driven
on, you'd be dead.
And his career wouldn't
hang in the balance.
Uh, objection.
- Calls for speculation.
- Not a lot.
The objection is sustained.
Miss Stewart, I am
finding you in contempt.
That stunt just cost you $5,000.
You're lucky it's not assault.
Now, Miss DeGroot...
you may continue.
- Thank you, Your Honor.
Mr. Patton, the night
of the accident...
- Hey.
- I'm so sorry.
- I know that it happened again...
- Shut up.
You're doing fantastic.
But you still have
Murphy's testimony.
We need the jury to like him.
They need to think
he did nothing wrong.
Have you given thought to
how you're gonna do that?
Yes. I have.
Did you do anything wrong at
the scene of the accident?
Objection. Leading.
Yes.
Withdrawn.
I did four things wrong.
I applied the tourniquet
at the brachial artery
instead of mid-forearm.
I laid out the clamps after
the makeshift vascular clips.
I only did two wipe downs
of the surgical field,
and I angled the spinal
board as I moved Mr. Patton
out of the woods because
a log was in the way.
Were any of those
mistakes relevant?
They were to me.
But I don't believe they
affected the patient's outcome.
Given where you sit
today, right now,
do you think one of the things that you
and Dr. Park did wrong... was stopping?
No. Then Mr. Patton
would be dead.
And the amputation, was
that the right thing to do?
I don't know.
But I know that if I had
to do it all over again...
I would stop,
I would help,
and I would amputate.
Dr. Murphy, you're different.
Tell me about yourself.
Objection. Vague
and irrelevant.
Your challenges, the
obstacles you've overcome...
Marginally less vague,
still completely irrelevant.
And yet, I will allow.
I have autism spectrum disorder.
I have always had autism
spectrum disorder.
I have also always
wanted to be a doctor.
Many people thought that
couldn't happen, but I saved...
Hi.
I think I'm better at asking
questions than giving speeches.
Closings are tricky.
It helps to actually
say the words,
not just mutter them.
Can I say them now?
You want my feedback?
If I don't like it, I'm going to tell
you, bluntly. You know that, right?
'Cause you've been so
tactful with me up till now?
My mentor told me that
criminal law is about justice,
whereas civil law is about one
thing and one thing only...
Money.
You can't undo what's been done.
The best you can do is
compensate, financially.
But that's wrong.
Everything we do in this
room is about justice.
We can't change what's happened,
but maybe, just maybe, we
can change what will happen.
We can encourage people to care,
to care about strangers, to care...
That's not your closing.
- It's a good closing.
- It's a very good closing.
It was your closing.
A long time ago.
My mentor said that to me.
I developed it into
an effective clos...
Did you believe it?
About justice? That we
can change the future?
I did.
But not anymore?
Maybe if my mentor
gave me advice,
I could turn it into
something effective.
You consider me a mentor?
You did inspire me.
I will give you one
piece of advice.
You're not me.
Not once in this
trial have you done
what I would've done.
Or what I wanted you to do.
So far, it's worked.
I see no reason to change now.
My mentor told me...
that people don't like me.
That I make them uncomfortable.
She's right.
And people don't like
my client either.
We're different.
But we're all different.
You... You've worn purple
every day of this trial.
I assume because you love it.
And 'cause you want
it to be your "thing."
You've got those mutton chops.
They're great. They're fun.
They make you... you.
But when we start to get judged
based on our differences,
it's not fun anymore.
And fair enough,
this is a courtroom.
You are literally here
to judge my client.
But please don't judge him
based on the way that he talks,
or on how he
doesn't look at you,
or on his awkward mannerisms.
Judge him...
on who he is.
At every moment of his life, he
has tried to make a difference,
tried to make things
a little better.
Please don't punish
him for that.
Please...
do what the plaintiff
should've done.
Say thank you.
♪♪ I think it's time we
found a way back home ♪♪
♪♪ You lose so many things
you love as you grow ♪♪
♪♪ I missed the days
when I was just a kid ♪♪
♪♪ My fear became my
shadow, I swear it did ♪♪
♪♪ Wherever is your
heart I call home ♪♪
♪♪ Though your feet may take
you far from me, I know ♪♪
♪♪ Wherever is your
heart I call home ♪♪
♪♪ You made me feel like
I was always falling ♪♪
♪♪ Always falling down
without a place to land ♪♪
♪♪ Somewhere in the distance
I heard you calling ♪♪
♪♪ Oh, it hurts so bad
to let go of your hand ♪♪
♪♪ Though your feet may take
you far from me, I know ♪♪
♪♪ Wherever is your
heart I call home ♪♪
You are a good lawyer.
Thank you.
The jury's back.
♪♪ I'm calling home ♪♪
♪♪ Oh, God, forgive my mind ♪♪
♪♪ When I come home ♪♪
I won, Mom.
She was brilliant.
I think you need to seriously
consider picking a new favorite child.
We gotta go, Mom.
People are buying Joni lots
of drinks. We love you.
♪♪ Though your feet may take
you far from me, I know ♪♪
I never doubted you.
Yeah, you did.
Because you love me.
Shaun!
Oh, Joni. Tequila, stat!
We did good, huh?
We did very well.
We need to celebrate.
We are celebrating.
This is definitely not what
you want to be doing right now.
♪♪ Wherever is your
heart I call home ♪♪
- Don't you want to see this?
- Nope. Not my thing.
♪♪ Wherever is your
heart I call home ♪♪
♪♪ Though your feet may take
you far from me, I know ♪♪
♪♪ Wherever is your
heart I call home ♪♪