[SIREN WAILING] ♪
Little bird, little bird ♪
MEREDITH: When a virus finds
its way into our bodies...
♪ Won't you sing me a song?
...our immune system
unleashes an attack.
♪ I may not know all the words
It puts up a good fight
and then stands down.
♪ But I'll try to sing along
Or at least that's
what it's supposed to do.
♪ My little bird
[WHEEZING]
♪ Let 'em talk,
that's what they do ♪
Sometimes the system
works so hard
that it goes completely
off the rails.
♪ No amount
of saying somethin' ♪
Immune cells start attacking
healthy tissue.
They flood the lungs,
clot the blood,
cause vessels to leak,
and shut down organs.
Our own body
wreaks havoc on itself.
♪ All will be alright
[MONITOR BEEPING]
♪ Hold tight, stay gold
It's called the cytokine storm.
♪ It hurts bad but I know
[GASPS]
♪ Ooh
And it takes a miracle
to stop it.
Subtitles by SilverStark
www.OpenSubtitles.org
[LAUGHING]
DELUCA: Okay, better lung sounds
than yesterday,
and your inflammatory markers
are decreasing.
But, uh, how do you feel?
MEREDITH: Like I've been asleep
for a week or a month.
It's like that
whether you have COVID or not.
You've been mostly asleep
for eight days.
MEREDITH: Oof.
How are the kids?
Have they been a lot?
Be honest.
AMELIA: This week?
Ellis is leaving dishes
all over the house.
Bailey is mad
that he can't fly.
[CHUCKLES]And Zola's teacher has asked
that Zola stop
correcting her.
[MAGGIE CHUCKLES]
When can I leave?
Your oxygen requirements
are decreasing,
so if they continue
in that direction,
we could probably discharge you
within a week.
I'll be back in an hour
to run another ABG, okay?
Take a deep breath for me,
there, Shanice.
Good.
Another one.
SHANICE: I didn't
want anyone to get hurt.
SHARON: Hush, sweetie.
You are brave.
You are a hero.
Rescue someone, did you?
Herself and her friend.
From a fire?
That's incredible.
By startinga fire.
Some animal kidnapped them
and locked them up in his house.
It was the only way
they could get out.
Oh, my God. That's... [
DOOR OPENS, SIREN WAILS]
Oh, my God.
Owen:
Jada Williams. Smoke inhalation,
second degree burns
to the left hand.
SHANICE: Jada! Are you okay?
SHARON: Where's your mother?
JADA: [CRYING] They took her.
They arrested her!
- Wait, why would they...
- Montgomery from 19
said there was an altercation
with police at the scene.
OBVIOUSLY SOME MIX-UP. SHARON: It's okay.
It's a mistake, okay?
They'll let her out.
Where's your father?
Did your mother call him?
JADA: He went to see
my grandma in Nevada.
She wouldn't stop going out
in public without a mask.
Okay.
We'll figure it out.
We'll be okay. Schmitt,
get her a chest X-ray
and page Avery to come
and have a look at this hand.
♪♪
[FACETIME CALL CHIMES]
WINSTON: Hey.
Did we have a date
and I forgot about it?
Maggie:
Mer's awake.[LAUGHS]
Really?
That's incredible!
We weaned her
off of high flow O2.
Her PaO2 is 88.
She even laughed!
She's awake! God!
[CACKLES]
That sounded
a little crazy.
But it's just been so dark
around here.
I hear you.
But you're still shining
on my end.
Aww.
Where are you? Oh, I'm in my car,
in a-a grocery store
parking lot.
Mm-hmm.
Oh, my God.
There is another woman,
isn't there?
You know, I, uh, hate for you
to find out this way,
but, you know,
I'm just not cut out
for the whole
long-distance thing.
Yeah, well, it was nice
while it lasted.
I'm so happy
about Meredith.
[CHUCKLES]
Truly.
[CHUCKLES] Now let me go buy my eggs.
[CALL ENDS]
Okay.
Richard:
Evening rounds was uneventful.
But Ms. Fisher complained of a
tenderness around the incision.
JO: Okay. I'll check on her
as soon as I can.
Uh, Wilson, I know you've
taken on some of Grey's cases,
and now
with Bailey's mother passing...
I'm asking a lot of you.
Well, she's awake now.
But she still needs time
to recover.
Right. Just [CHUCKLES]
wishful thinking.
Yeah. Um... Oh, uh, uh, sir,
w-when you have a minute, I was
wondering if I could talk to you
about something that I am
considering...[TEXT MESSAGE CHIMES]
...um, career-wise.
Oh, damn it.
Oh, well, it doesn't
have to be now.
I'm sure
that you are dying to go home.
[SIGHS]
No one's
leaving here tonight.
♪♪
Pierce.
What? No Magpie?
You said
you hate my nicknames.
Which only seemed to increase
your pleasure in using them.
[MONITOR BEEPING]
Alright.
Deep breath.
[WHEEZING INHALE]
[EXHALES SHAKILY
]Alright. Still diminished,
but decent.
Who slapped you
with the happy stick?
Meredith's awake.
Oh.
Maybe I won't die alone
and forgotten.
I'm basing my chances
of beating this thing
on Grey pulling through.
She's a lot, uh, feistier.
And younger.
Ouch.
[CHUCKLES]
I'm gonna come check on you
in an hour.
Try to get some rest.
I literally
have no choice.
[MONITOR BEEPING]
[DOOR OPENS, CLOSES]
[WHEEZING]
Know any good jokes?
[CHUCKLES]
Me neither.
[SIGHS]
♪♪
[INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS]
JO: Hey.
Great news about Meredith.
TEDDY: Yeah. Great.
RICHARD: Listen up. Seattle Pres
has reached capacity.
Which means we should
expect to receive
about twice the patients
per day.
We are activating
surge capacity protocol.
[ALL MURMURING]Hey, I'm not happy
about it, either.
We need to double up
on every room we can.
We are converting this cafeteria
to COVID overflow tonight.
We need all available hands,
including residents.
You will now take care
of COVID patients.
So, call home,
make arrangements,
check your inboxes
for assignments.
Thank you.
Bailey:
I didn't get an e-mail.
Because you're not supposed to
be here. You should be at home.
I'm not exposing
my kids to COVID
the week
they lost their grandma.
Then go to a hotel.
You told me you couldn't leave
this place when it needed you.
Well, neither can I.
Fine.
Patient transfer.
Bailey, if you need to leave
to go home... I won't.
We want to do a chest X-ray
to make sure the smoke
didn't damage your lungs, okay?
Shouldn't take long.
JACKSON: We're gonna have to do
the same for you, too.
Let me just
finish this hand first.
[SIGHS] I pushedon
the vent thing to get out,
but the fire made it really
hot.[CELLPHONE RINGING]
STUPID. SHARON: Hello?
No, no.
It sounds smart.
SHARON: Sure. Hold on. Let me ask.
This is Jada's father.
Can they talk?
Of course.
I'm almost done here.
I-I'm so sorry.
Daddy, I'm... I'm so sorry.
We didn't mean
to do anything bad.
Any word on the mother?
Can't believe they arrested her.
I CAN. OWEN: Nothing yet,
but we need to get them
transferred upstairs.
What? Now? We've only just
gotten them anywhere near calm.
They're bringing
the kidnapper here,
and Montgomery saidthat he is belligerent.
Absolutely not. We're not
bringing him to this hospital.
I'm as against it
as you are.
But Seattle Pres
has closed their doors,
and he has to go somewhere.
♪♪
DeLuca:
Okay. Sats are incredible.
MEREDITH: Must be able todo
those in your sleep by now.
Sleep? What sleep?
Kidding.
I've been getting sleep.
How are my patients doing?
Okay, Randall, Thompson,
and Patel...
they were all discharged.
They recovered.
Walker?
Did his son get to see him
at least?
He barely made it
in time, but yeah.
Wish I could help.
If it's any consolation,
I've been working here
every single day,
and I don't really feel like
I'm much help, either.
[CELLPHONE CHIMES]
[SIGHS]
Look, I really hate to go,
but...
No. Go. It's okay.
Hey.
It's really good
to hear your voice.
Fire marshal says
no more than 30 beds.
Has Supply brought down
the pulse oxes yet?
Yes, they're being deliveredas we speak.
And we got an additionalfour high flows.
How?
We lost the patientswho were using them.
Helm!
You have just put the monitor
in the wrong place,
and now we're gonna havewires and cords
running along
the patient's bed,
which has created a hazard,
not only for a seriously ill patient,
but also for the staff.
I'm sorry.
I didn't realize...
I guessyou didn't "realize"
that you putthe medical waste bin
too far away fromthe
hand sanitizer dispenser.
So if I'm examining
a patient,
that means that I have to cross the room
to dispose of the
medicalsupplies, recross the room,
sanitize my hands,
which means you
havedoubled my exposure time
and wasted my time.
So fix this station and
fixthe other three stations.
Actually, you know what?
Find someone else to do it,
because you've just proven
why we haven't let
residentsactually do anything.
RICHARD: Dr. Altman.
Can I help you?
Can I send Dr. Helm upstairs
to help out
on the COVID floor?
Bailey's asking
for reinforcements.
I don't care.
♪♪
[FLATLINE]
MAGGIE: Charge to 200.
[PADDLES WHINE]
Clear.
[DEFIBRILLATOR THUMPS]
Charge to 300.
Clear.
[DEFIBRILLATOR THUMPS]
[FLATLINE]
♪♪
Time of death, 2:13.
[CLICK, FLATLINE STOPS]
♪♪
I didn't even know
his whole name.
♪♪
Do you want to?
His wife would call him
every day.
She'd talk his ear off
on the speaker phone.
I don't speak Spanish,
but I could hear kids playing.
Maybe grandkids.
I could hear
his wife crying.
And then she would
force a laugh.
And sometimes
his eyes were open.
And... he would
force a smile,
you know,
when she would force a laugh
'cause he was trying to take
care of her through the phone.
His first name is Hector.
And yes, I'd like to know
his last name
for my prayers, please.
Martinez.
Hector Martinez.
♪♪
Is Grey still awake?
Yes.
Yeah, she's still awake.
Alright.
[CELLPHONE CHIMING]
♪♪
[SIGHS]
[DOOR OPENS]
[DOOR CLOSES]
♪♪
[SIRENS WAILING]
Alright, we got
the girls upstairs,
so the coast is clear down here
for... Satan's arrival.
Do they know
what this guy was doing?
Is he, like, a serial killer?
In a pandemic?
Sex trafficking is more likely.
The house they burned down
could have been a way station
or the destination.
I don't want to be
anywhere near this guy.
♪♪
[BOB COUGHING]
TRAVIS: 45-year-old male
involved in a house fire.
Smoke inhalation,
burns to the left arm.
Vitals are stable.
OWEN: The victims are safe,
Montgomery.
You mean the girls
who broke into my house
and set fire to it?
TRAVIS: They could have
burned alive in there.
He's human garbage. Get these cuffs off me!
I want my lawyer. Now.
He's also gonna say that a lot.
Good luck.
[COUGHS]We've already informed security.
Let's get him
to trauma one.
♪♪
Ma'am? What happened to the guy
who just came out
of the ambulance? Is he okay?
Ma'am, you can't be out here
without a a mask.
Okay, yeah.
Thank you very much.
I just, um...
I'm a little... out of it.
I just was mugged,
and, um,
the guy, he... he shoved me
and took my purse,
and I hit my head,
I think.
You'd think people would
behave better in a pandemic.
Come on. Follow me.
I'll get you checked out.
♪♪
Jackson:
So, I made a few calls,
and my attorney's looking into
your mother's arrest.
We should know more
pretty soon.
WOMAN: Code Blue, Room
5260.MAN: Room 5260 coding. Let's go.
It's okay.
I know it may not
sound like it,
but you're safe here, Jada.
You are, okay?
We are gonna get
your mother out of there.
JADA: She didn't...
She didn't
do anything wrong.
She was just scared...
trying to protect us.
[SIGHS]
We never should have
met up with a stranger.
It was so dumb.
He's the bad guy here,
not you.
You're 13 years old, Jada.
You should be allowed to make
a few mistakes and survive them.
That's kind of what growing up
is all about.
When I was 15 years old,
took my mother's car.
Didn't have
a driver's license yet.
Picked up my buddies, driving
around, trying to show off,
spin the tires,
you know, burn rubber.
Caught a patch of ice.
Crashed sideways.
Could have killed everyone
'cause I did something stupid.
Still ended up
being a doctor.
You made a mistake.
You learned from it, right?
What that guy did,
that was no mistake.
He did that on purpose.
So he's the one
that we're mad at.
You want to be mad
at somebody,
be mad at him,
not yourself.
[INHALES DEEPLY]
Okay.
♪♪
[BOB COUGHS, GRUNTS]
Can you at least loosen
these damn things?
If you would calm down
and stop moving,
it might not
bother you so much,
and it would help me
to work on your arm.
Oh, they burned down my house,
and I got arrested.
Would yoube calm?
Oh, don't tell me
you believe them.
Sir, not only do I believe them,
but I'm amazed by them.
They are resourceful,
powerful, brilliant.
You know, my own sister
was taken hostage
by scumbags like you.
She was held for 10 years.
And these girls, they got
themselves out in one night,
and they risked their lives
to do it.
Now, it is my job to repair
your lungs and your skin,
and I need your cooperation to
do that, but your life, Bob...
your life will be spent
behind bars.
And your soul?
[CHUCKLES]
There is nothing
anyone can do to save that.
You're the devil's barbecue,
Bob,
so get used to the smell
of burning flesh.
[GRUNTS]
Get me another doctor.
I want another doctor!
I've been through enough...
without... hav...
♪♪
Owen:
Okay, dramatic move, Bob.
Let's call a stroke alert
and have CT on standby.
Code stroke, emergency room.
Doesn't look like you sustained
any serious injuries
from your fall.
Code stroke, emergency room.
OPAL: Um, what's...
What's going on in there?
Owen:
Let's get ready to move him.
Ugh.
You don't want to know.
♪♪
Anything else hurting you?
Any soreness or...
Have someone from neuro
meet me in CT.
He has slurred speech
and focal deficits.
Possible stroke.
Let's go.
Ma'am?
Oh. [EXHALES SHARPLY]
Sorry.
Been alone for months.
I'm not used
to all this activity.
Um, can I...
Where is your restroom?
Oh, yeah,
it's just around the corner.
Thanks.
♪♪
[DOOR OPENS]
[SIGHS]
KORACICK: Uh, you can go.
[CLEARS THROAT][DOOR CLOSES]
Meredith:
It got you, too, huh?
KORACICK: Like an 18-wheeler
on a sheet of ice.
But I, uh...
I just wanted
to see for myself
that it's possible
to beat this thing.
Almostbeat it.
You know how many rules
you're breaking right now?
I really just wanted to be in
a room where no one was dying.
♪♪
'Cause everyone's dying.
I won't tell if you don't.
[SIGHS]
♪♪
AMELIA: Whatcha got?
OWEN: I didn't mean
for them to page you.
If you need to be
with Meredith...
I want to be wherever I can help
and save lives,
so it is your guy's
lucky day.
Well, slurred speech,
slight droop in the face,
left-sided weakness
in the arms and legs.
He was also just arrested for
kidnapping two teenage girls,
possibly trafficking.
I'm not sure that this is a life
you're looking to save.
I've already said a few things
to this guy
that could get me fired.
Well, then...
I guess I am his best chance
at living long enough
that he will rot in prison.
[CHUCKLES]Silver lining?
[COMPUTER BEEPS]
Okay, looks like
an ischemic stroke.
Let's start alteplase
and get a CTA.
Okay.
Mm-hmm.
♪♪
DELUCA: Ah, Bailey. Good.
Uh, Abrams and Richardson
are settled,
and I want to wait
on Lottman's ABG results.
Make sure she's stable.
Um, DeLuca, can you
get Mr. Franklin settled?
Dr. Bailey?
Uh, my mom died
in that room last night.
I just need a minute.
♪♪
Dr. Bailey...
Hmm.
...you're super human.
You know that, right?
You got an ability
to cut through crap
unlike anyone
I have ever seen.
You're a world-class surgeon
and an even better boss.
So please don't mistake this
as disrespect
when I say...
go away.
Go home.
At the very least,
go to your office
and scream, break something.
I don't know.
Just take
more than a minute.
Because, yes, even super humans
need more than a minute
to grieve the loss of the person
that made them who they are.
We got this.
♪♪
Go away.
[DOOR OPENS]
DeLuca:
Okay. How we doing here?
♪♪
AMELIA: Fluoro.
[VENTILATOR HISSING,
MONITOR BEEPING]
He's got a clot
in his middle cerebral artery.
♪♪
Are the girls he hurt
okay?
I mean...
okay as they can be?
I hope so,
but I cannot imagine.
Was the world
always this messed up
and we just didn't pay attention
'cause we didn't have kids yet?
Yeah, I notice more now.
I just want to hug Scout
and never let go.
You know, after drenching myself
in sanitizer.
[CHUCKLES]
You know, I can't even go home
to hug Allison and Leo.
They're staying at my mom's,
and I see them on video chat.
It is a special kind
of torture.
[SCOFFS]
Sensory deprivation.
I just...
Ugh. I just want to smell them
and hold them.
Well, at least I have a pandemic
to keep me occupied.
[CHUCKLES]That's dark.
You know,
when all this started,
I treated it like it was a war,
like we were all this together,
but we're not in this together.
Not even close.
I mean, some of us
are risking our lives,
missing our families,
sacrificing everything, and why?
So other people can just keep
finding ways to hurt each other?
I mean, kidnapping teenagers
during a pandemic?
Don't even get me started
on all those people
who are partying without masks.
I think you said those things
in the wrong order.
I'm not so sure.
[SCOFFS]
[BOTH LAUGH]
MEREDITH: It's a fact, huh?
KORACICK: Yes. Neurosurgeons
are the best lovers
of all the surgeons.
It's the attention
to the smallest of details.
We know about, uh,
pleasure centers.
Okay. It's been very nice
having you stop by.
[LAUGHING] You're welcome
to prove me wrong.
Ortho?
Forget about it.
No finesse.
Anesthesiology?
Snooze. Literally.[BOTH LAUGHING]
[COUGHS]
If this thing ever ends,
I am creating a dating app
for women who want to date
a neurosurgeon,
and that would be me.
Woman:
Let's go, let's go, let's go!
MAN: Code Blue, room 4850.
Code Blue, room 4850.
You know, you don't realize how
addicted you are to saving lives
until you can't.
I realized it.
How hilarious is it
that the best and second-best
surgeons in this joint
caught the plague?
You're not the second-best
surgeon here.
[LAUGHING]
You might be top five.
[CHUCKLING]
Wait. Wait, you...
You thought I put you
at number one?
Oh, that is...
That is so sad.
How many Catherine Fox Awards
do you have?
How many Catherine Foxes
have you saved?
[GASPS]
Good one.
WOMAN: I can't believe
we lost another one.
MAN: We did our best.
♪♪
TEDDY: Six more beds,
nine more vital monitors,
and we will meet
protocol standards.
Nice work, Altman.
It'll fill up before we know it,
but I guess it's something.
Well, when I said not everyone
would be needed here,
I meant it.
If you need
to take personal time.
That's a joke, right?
You've been burning the candle
at both ends
trying to save Meredith.
You've earned a break.
Meredith doesn't matter,
Richard.
I'm saying it's great
that she's awake.
But I thought
if I... if I could...
If I could just keep her alive,
that meant something.
And now she's awake,
and nothing has changed.
And we are in
a frickin' cafeteria.
People used to take breaks
in here,
and they would eat ice cream
and French fries,
and we... now we
just converted it
so that they would
die here instead.
So, taking a break
won't save anyone.
And I don't have
anywhere to go anyway.
And that's on you.
♪♪
And you know it's on you.
Feeling sorry for yourself
doesn't save lives.
You aren't gonna get better
until you take the time
to find out
why you did what you did.
You blew up your life
and profoundly hurt
and humiliated
the man that you love.
You need to take inventory.
Name your demons.
Clean up your messes.
You may not be able to get
things back the way they were,
but if you honestly
look at yourself,
maybe you won't repeat
the same pattern again.
♪♪
WOMAN: Nurse Kruger to the OR.
Nurse Kruger to the OR.
[MONITOR BEEPING]
[EXHALES SHAKILY]
MAGGIE: Ma'am, you okay?
I will be.
I just need a minute.
I'm sorry, but you have to
keep your mask on.
Do you want to sit down?
My daughter, she was taken,
and I almost
lost her forever.
Oh, my God.
I heard about that.
I can only imagine what you
must be feeling right now.
You know,
I spend my whole day
just trying to get to end of it
still standing.
And there's
always something,
but I find ways
to deal with the somethings.
I try to get ahead of them.
But you can't
get ahead of everything.
It's too much stress.
It's too much. I'm so sorry.
And you know what's crazy?
I have to get up
and go to work in the morning
and act like nothing happened.
Because we have to eat
and have a roof over our head.
Even in a pandemic.
There's no stopping.
There's no relief.
♪♪
I need to get back
to my girl.
♪♪
Opal:
It's Bob. He's not gonna talk.
No, he's not. I know.
I know.
I just have to figure out
how to get
close enough to him
to find out
what they already know.
No, because
he may have had a stroke.
I will, yes.
WOMAN: Dr. DeLuca,
can you take a look at this?
♪♪
That is my niece!
Arrest this woman
for child trafficking!
Security!
Detain her!
♪♪
DELUCA: I'm still waiting
on the results,
so let me know when they
come in, okay? Thank you.
[CELLPHONE CHIMES]
♪♪
[SIGHS] Okay.
Koracick:
Your sats still look good.
Meredith:
You're a workaholic.
Oh, work is all I have.
That and a... to-do list
of many, many women.
That's not all you have.
[SIGHS]
You miss the kids?
So much it hurts.
I even miss when they say,
"Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom,"
so many times
I want to change my name.
[CHUCKLES]
Used to be so angry at God
for taking David away,
but now I think
it's kind of like a blessing.
He doesn't have to feel this
or worry about me.
I don't have to worry
about him.
[CHUCKLES]
Yeah, that's B.S.
I'd kill for a "Dad, Dad,
Dad, Dad" about now.
Just trying
to silver-line something.
[DOOR OPENS]Oh.
Nurse James:
Are you kidding me?
Okay, arrest me, officer.
No, no, I've been a terrible,
terrible patient. I...
Good luck
with your plague!
Good luck with yours!
[DOOR CLOSES]
♪♪
Woman:
Chaplain to patient services.
Levi:
She's got red hair, and...
Oh, oh, there she is!
Opal:
Uh... Uh, what's going on?
You were mugged. Don't you want
to make a statement?
Yes. Thank you.
O-Of course.
I... Uh...
it's been a crazy night.
Um...
I was walking to my car,
and I actually felt something
from behind.
Policeman:
Okay. And then what?
HAYES: So, both girls are
responding well to the oxygen.
As long as the next X-rays
are looking good,
you can all be on your way.
♪♪
Mom![BOTH CRYING]
I'm so sorry, Mom!
JOYCE: No. Oh, God.
I was so worried about you.
I was so scared. I was so scared.
I'm okay, sweet girl.
I'm okay.
I'm here, baby.
I'm here.
HAYES: You did this?
You got her out?
JACKSON: Money did this.
It's the only language
this country understands.
MAGGIE: No, Mrs. Willett.
[SIGHS]
I don't have better news.
I'm sorry.
Okay.
I will.
[SIREN WAILING IN DISTANCE]
MAGGIE: Hey.
Thought you had surgery.
I did. [SIGHS]
Saving a sex trafficker's life.
So... I needed some air.
How did you manage to not...
stab him in the skull
with a scalpel?
Skin of my teeth.
I easily could have let the
catheter slip by a millimeter,
lacerate his artery,
or I could have accidentally
let him have a bigger stroke,
landing him
in a vegetative state,
sitting in his own filth
for decades, but I didn't.
Because I took an oath.
I saved his life
so amazingly well
that he will live
far longer than he should,
until he dies alone
in prison.
[SIGHS]
I'm so sick of it.
I know. It's infuriating.
How anyone
could kidnap children...
No.
That's not it, Amelia.
That's not it.
You're outraged.
Everyone is outraged
that this monster
kidnapped these girls.
And that is awful.
It's awful.
But what about the monsters
that got us here?
The many reasons that
Black girls are more vulnerable
to being taken
in the first place?
I want outrage for that.
I want outrage for the fact
that we are seen as disposable
and rarely seen as victims.
That Black girls
are less likely
to be as seen as innocent
than white girls,
which makes people think
that we don't need protecting,
and it's okay to
hypersexualize us in the media.
Meanwhile, we are being
physically and sexually abused
at horrific rates,
and not just by sex traffickers.
There are so many things
just waiting
to rob Black women and girls
of our freedom and future
and our joy.
And because none of it
has an evil or obvious face,
it just gets ignored.
And now...
there's a plague
that is killing Black people
at a rate that should
make everyone outraged!
If COVID were killing
white people
at the rate that it is killing
Black people [SCOFFS]
you better believe that everyone
would be wearing masks
because it would be
the damn law.
You're right, Maggie.
And I don't know
how you carry it all.
By the skin of my teeth.
[SIGHS]
Did you quit yet?
It's not quitting.
It's choosing joy.Mm.
I want to choose joy.
I want to bring life
into the world.
It's nothing
to shame me over.
I didn't shame you.
A little bit, you did.
I heard Grey's awake.
Did you tell her?
No.
She would definitely
shame me.
[CHUCKLES]
She was my teacher.
She loves to cut
more than anybody I know.
She would tell me that it's
a reaction to the pandemic
and that it's insane
to quit surgery, and...
on some level,
she'd be right.
But...
Butwhen I think
about quitting,
it brings me
so. Much. Joy.
It's like I have
a dirty little secret.
♪ We will call this place
our home ♪
DeLuca:
27 patients transferred...
in under five hours.
And somehow we're all
still standing.
♪ Though the storms
will push and pull ♪
Whew.
So... did you
break something?
I screamed into a pillow
for a few minutes.
Thank you.
[SIGHS]
♪ We'll tell our stories
on these walls ♪
You know,
when my mom died...
♪ Every year, measure how tall
...I don't even have words
to describe how bad it felt.
Like the pain should just
carry me out of my body
and take me with her.
I feel like
I'm not in my body.
Like I'm watching myself
move around,
but I'm not all there.
I have no idea what to do
about a memorial.
She wanted something joyous.
My father and I following behind
the hearse in a white limo.
Had to be white.
Her church choir singing
"His Eye Is On The Sparrow"
in front of the entire
congregation.
And no crying.
Yeah, said she'd been to
enough sad funerals.
She wanted good food,
good music, and laughter.
You know, working every day
in the COVID ICU,
I have to say, I've seen some...
Some pretty beautiful things.
♪ We are the impact
and the glue ♪
Candlelit drive-by vigils
and video memorials.
Look, I know
none of it's ideal,
but it does provide
a little comfort.
[CELLPHONE CHIMES]
Oh, uh, do... do you mind
if I knock off?
I-I have to take my meds
and get some sleep.
[CHUCKLES] What?
♪ With each year,
our color fades ♪
No, of course.
I'm just so proud of you,
DeLuca.
Managing your mental health,
taking your meds,
getting rest,
setting boundaries.
That's not easy
even when we aren't
in the middle
of a pandemic.
Guess I'm just lucky
I was surrounded by people
that didn't give up on me.
Night, Chief.
♪ And repaint every day
[FLATLINE, ALARM BEEPING
IN DISTANCE]
WOMAN: Code Blue, room 4878.
Code Blue, room 4878.
♪♪
Nurse Linda:
Dr. Grey, get back in bed.
The code team will be here
any minute.
MEREDITH: She doesn't have
that kind of time!
Get me an ET tube.
♪♪
Take over compressions.
Dr. Grey!
Meredith:
Alright, I'm in. Bag her.
[FLATLINE, ALARMS BEEPING]
♪♪
What the hell
are you doing?
[WEAKLY]
Helm, get me a wheelchair.
♪♪
[SIREN WAILING IN DISTANCE]
[OWEN SIGHS]
[EXHALES SHARPLY]
[VEHICLE BACKUP ALERT BEEPING]
Hey.
Teddy, I don't want
to keep punishing you.
We have kids, you know?
Maybe it's time we start to talk
about what we're gonna do.
Allison.
Allison's fine. I talked to Mom
this morning. She said that...
No, Owen.
Not our Allison.
MyAllison.
We weren't just
best friends.
I was in love with her,
and she was in love with me.
We were so deeply in love.
And I don't know what this has
to do with what I did to you.
But I know that is it the only
secret that I kept from you
before Tom
and before this. I...
I know that it's connected.
And I know you well enough
to know that you...
You need the whole story.
I don't know all of it yet,
but I wanted to give you
what I do know.
I don't know
what to do with this.
You don't
have to do anything.
I just want you to know that
I love you and I love our kids
and I loved our family,
even if it's over.
♪♪
♪ Hold the line, aye
[LAUGHING]
♪ Do you fight
for pride or glory? ♪
[LAUGHS LOUDLY]
This makes so much sense.
[LAUGHS, SIGHS]
I mean, ever since
our wedding day...
I've been trying
to piece it together.
Our history.
Searching for when you changed
and became someone
that was capable of doing things
that I couldn't understand.
And it turns out that...
you didn't change.
Turns out...
Turns out I just
never really knew you.
Owen, that's not true.
Do you even know
what true is, Teddy?
We named our daughter
after a lie.
[CELLPHONE CHIMES]♪ I don't know
where you've gone ♪
♪ You used to be
the heart of this town ♪
No, no, no, no,
no, no, no, no, no, no.
[PATIENTS COUGHING]
♪♪
♪ I don't know
where you are now ♪
RICHARD: I have never seen
anything like this.
BAILEY: Everyone really
pulled together today.
It would be beautiful
if it wasn't
full of dying people.
I mean COVID.
We're doing our best, but this
is the first time in my career
I'm not sure that's enough.
Pretty soon, we're gonna
start losing our own.
Not to the disease
but to the toll it's taking.
♪♪
I fear this will hurt us
in a way we can't even
begin to understand.
♪♪
[CELLPHONES CHIME]
♪ Whoa
BAILEY: It's Grey.
Come on.
♪ Whoa
[PATIENTS COUGHING]
♪♪
♪ Yeah, you've got your back
against the wall ♪
[INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS]
[MONITOR BEEPING]
[SIGHS]
Her sats are plummeting.
But she was fine... Yeah,
until she got out of bed
and tried to resuscitate
a coding patient.
The exertion, it just pushed her
over the edge.
TEDDY: Maybe. Or maybe her lungs
already looked that way.
The experimental drug
doesn't reverse damage
that's already occurred.
She might have been
on a COVID high.
What about putting her
on BIPAP?
It won't be enough. If she's not
already responding to high flow.
Where's Pierce?
She went home.
She's not answering her phone.
♪♪
I think it's time.
Dr. Webber...
No. Uh... Mnh-mnh.
She said she didn't want
to be on a vent.
Unless it's a last resort.
Well, Meredith's lungs
are at a breaking point.
I know early results
weren't good,
but more and more patients
are surviving
after they go on a vent.
Richard... It's my call.
♪♪
Do it.
[DOOR CLOSES]
♪♪
No, I'm sorry.
I had to get out.
It's too risky.
♪♪
Open your eyes, people!
She's selling human beings!
♪♪
CARINA: Buon giorno.
DELUCA: Shh, shh, shh, shh.
Carina. What's wrong?
It's the woman
who brought the girl. Cindy.
E-Erin. Erin Banks.
Do you remember her?
Andrea... Carina, I swear it's her.
No, you call the police. I'm following her.
I let her out of the hospital
once. I'm not doing it again.
Va bene.
But... But I'm driving.
Okay? Okay. Come on. Hurry up.
♪♪
[CELLPHONE CHIMES,
KNOCK ON DOOR]
I don't need anything.
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
[SIGHS]
Are you real?
I told you the long-distance
thing wasn't working for me.
[CHUCKLES]
♪♪
[SOBBING]
♪ Hmm, hmm
♪♪
♪ Ooh
♪ Ah, ah
[BIRDS CHIRPING]
♪♪
♪ Ah, ah
[MONITOR BEEPING]
[SEAGULLS SQUAWKING]
♪ So take me to the airport
♪ And put me on a plane
♪ I got no expectations
♪ To pass through here again
♪ Our love was like the water
♪ That splashes on a stone
MEREDITH: Sometimes, when
you think the storm has passed,
you realize you were just
in the eye of it.
♪ Our love is like our music
♪ It's here,
and then it's gone ♪
♪♪
[MONITOR BEEPING]
...Captions by VITAC...
♪♪
Subtitles by SilverStark
www.OpenSubtitles.org