Previously on ER:
- Be with you in a second.
- I found a baby, I think it's dying.
I'll need to appoint someone
from the hospital staff...
to be his protective
custodian while he's in here.
You up for it?
So many times in my life
I've failed to take a chance.
Don't worry, Neela. I'm not
here to convince you to stay.
If you can handle being with a guy who gets
stuck by needles, kicked by patients...
takes an occasional slug
of radiation to his cojones...
well, then, I can certainly
stomach some occasional gunfire.
I got a meeting at 9, maybe
the weekend will be better.
- No. He's getting discharged tomorrow.
- You're about to start a shift.
I can get someone to cover.
Look, it's okay to be nervous.
- We don't know about this baby.
- Most times you don't.
He seems perfect right now.
I'd rather do this when we
can spend time with him.
Let's start with five minutes
and take it from there.
- Good morning.
- Yes, it is.
I will pick you up at 8:30.
- What should I wear?
- Something fancy.
- I hate surprises.
- Okay. Okay.
It involves fine dining
and some other things.
- Archie.
- Gonna be a big night.
Big night? Popping the question?
Are you crazy? We're
in the honeymoon phase.
Year from now, we
could hate each other.
And I thought romance was dead.
Big surprise is I've been studying
an instructional DVD for two weeks.
What happens in your
bedroom stays in your bedroom.
I'm taking her salsa dancing.
She's Puerto Rican, in her
blood. And I have to work on it.
- Yes, you do.
- I do.
You should be dressed
before you start your shift.
I'm not on today. I'm
volunteering at Camp Del Corazon.
- Is that today?
- Camp Del what?
For kids who've had
open-heart surgery.
Kids with heart
disease running around?
We should get
some business here.
It's nothing strenuous.
Arts and crafts, face
painting, a little charades.
Excuse me. Cate, can we...?
I'm gonna go and check on him.
Felix Kirsch, found unconscious in
park. Scalp hematoma, blood from the ear.
- Trauma rooms are full.
- Curtain 2.
Started seizing.
Gave four of Ativan.
- Another two. Did he fall?
- Maybe mugged.
- Police there.
- Gotta consider cardiac...
metabolic and
toxicologic etiologies.
All right. That's more like it.
Um, I'll just start them off.
Ready. One, two, three.
Okay. Felix, open your
eyes, look at me, Felix.
He's postictal. Call parents?
- Didn't have time.
- Here's his ID.
Ruptured his eardrum.
I can come back after work.
Pupils equal and reactive.
You got everything under
control, I'm going to Pediatrics.
All right. Gram
of dilantin over 20.
How are you doing today? Hmm.
Did you get a
good night's sleep?
Did you?
- He likes the rocker.
- Ah.
I want you to meet someone.
I want you to meet my
husband. His name's Russell.
- Hello.
- Wash your hands?
Yes.
Settle down, little man.
Settle down. Settle down.
You know what? He
seemed happier with you.
- Do you wanna take him?
- Oh, no, no, no.
No need to fuss.
- Okay.
- Russell's a good guy.
That's better.
That's better. Yeah.
He's tracking
objects with his eyes.
Mm-hm. And he smiles at people.
Yes, you do.
Yeah, developmental
milestones of a two-month old.
Ah. You're a very advanced
young man. Uh-huh.
My protective custodianship
is over when he's discharged.
Mm-hm.
If we're serious about adopting, we have
to take a state-certified parenting class.
When do we start? Huh?
We gonna start now.
Woo! Woo!
Hey, Archie.
- Archie Morris?
- Yeah.
I'm Vera.
Um, you need to
see the Big Kahuna.
- Okay.
- Kahuna, this is Archie.
Been looking forward
to meeting you.
Hey. Why don't you jump
in and, uh, follow my lead?
On second thought,
see that kid over there?
His name is Logan. See if
you can get him to join us.
- Okay. All right.
- Yeah. Over there.
Hey, Logan.
How's it going?
- Looks like fun out there.
- Lame.
I never cared much for, uh,
dancing when I was a kid either.
You play basketball?
No.
What do you like?
You're wasting your time, I
don't want to be here, okay?
My parents made me come.
Have you been
out of the country?
Uh, two months
ago. Machu Picchu.
I might not need
a scalpel, then.
- Kayson called about a biopsy.
- I'll call him back.
He faxed a report.
Thanks.
Hey, doc?
Do I need a tetanus shot?
If it's been more
than five years, yeah.
Oh, my God.
Bot fly larva. It's, uh,
endemic to South America.
Are...? Are they
taking over my body?
The fly lays eggs on you and
the larva burrows under the skin.
You'd know if there's more.
I'll be back.
Your bookshelves are empty.
- You need some artwork.
NEELA: I'm still in boxes.
Way they're working me, it'll
be a year before I get settled in.
Neela's showing us her office.
Hey, look, Simon's here.
Hey, there. This is my new home.
That's impressive.
Oh, check this out.
Wow, assistant
professor of surgery.
We get residents from Tulane,
so I do have a faculty position.
Well, I'll be sure
to tell Dubenko.
I brought the stuff
you wanted from home.
- Who are you talking to?
- County.
Yeah?
- Hey, guys.
- Hi, Ray.
Ray.
Um, I'm gonna be late for the
OR, I just wanted to check in.
- Call anytime.
- Yeah, we miss you.
Take care.
Bye.
Yeah.
Rule of the friendship bracelet
is you can't keep it for yourself.
You have to give it to
someone really special.
Who are you giving
yours to, Xena?
I haven't decided yet.
You can give it to your husband.
I don't have one of those.
- Do you have a boyfriend?
- Not right now.
You?
A boyfriend? Pfft. Yeah, right.
- Why not?
- Guys tend to avoid me.
What? Come on. You're
pretty and you're smart.
I'm a freak with
scars and a bad heart.
I had a cardiac arrest in class and
the paramedics had to give me CPR.
It's kind of a
buzzkill to the guys.
That and my
internal defibrillator.
- What's your heart defect?
- Tetrology of fallot.
- So you had a BT shunt?
- Mm-hm.
I had hypoplastic
left-heart syndrome.
I needed a Norwood, Glenn
and Fontan before my transplant.
You know, the great thing
about camp is that we all fit in.
You don't have to
worry about your scar.
Just be yourself and go crazy.
Come on. Let's make
those. Let's make those.
Woo! Nice shot, nice shot.
What's up, Xena?
Nothing, just a
little arts and crafts.
Oh, I gotta cool down.
Emily, you wanna
check out the slime slide?
Um, I, uh, have to get
something from my backpack.
- Is she not supposed to exercise?
- She's in good shape.
This is her first time at camp. Her
parents don't let her do very much.
- Thread to 40 centimeters.
- All right, needle's out. OpSite.
We'll titrate to 10 cc's an
hour. You did great, Felix.
This is Dr. Kirsch, Felix's dad.
- Hi, I'm Dr. Gates.
- I'm Dr. Banfield, we spoke.
- Hey, there.
- Hey.
- Are you a physician?
- No, physics professor.
At the world-famous
Enrico Fermi Institute.
Are you okay?
- How'd you hit your head so hard?
- I don't remember.
Trying to figure out if he fell
or something made him faint.
I've heard that, uh, sometimes
sleep deprivation can lead to seizures.
It can.
He was up all last week
burning the midnight oil.
But he aced all his midterms.
Indeed, I did.
You wanna have a seat?
Thank you.
Yeah, it could be a while
before they take him upstairs.
"How much of human
life is lost in waiting?"
Ralph Waldo Emerson.
- We'll be back.
- Okay if I take him to Curtains?
Uh, that'll be fine.
Can you imagine
having a dad like that?
I like him. He's
concerned, devoted.
Think about the
pressure that kid's under.
Fits the profile. Acting
out, doing drugs.
We'll check it
out, but I doubt it.
I'll have Psych come
for an assessment.
Knock yourself out.
Dr. Banfield, there's
someone's here to see you.
Hmm.
That's, uh, Megan.
I dropped off a baby
a couple weeks ago.
I remember.
I can't sleep at night.
The baby's doing fine.
- He is?
- Yes.
He's well taken care of.
Are you all right?
No. No.
I made a mistake. I want
him back. I wanna keep him.
My mom says she can help.
I'll be getting a check from
the state, so we'll be okay.
What about high school?
I can go back.
You know, being a
mom isn't so easy.
I see girls younger
than me doing it.
You're sure about this?
Okay, I'll talk to our social
worker. But, uh, it might be a while.
I'll wait.
Megan, you know...
You just seem confused.
Are you sure you don't
wanna think about this more?
I already have.
I made a bad decision and
I just wanna do what's right.
So there's a tear
in the dura mater.
Outermost, toughest of the
three meninges covering the brain.
- AP Biology.
- Okay.
You're gonna be on bed
rest for five days till it heals.
I canceled my appointments,
but I've got classes.
- Okay if I'm back at 6?
- No problem.
- I'm not going anywhere.
- All right.
Cell phone's on. See you, kiddo.
Okay.
What do you remember
about this morning?
I cut through the park
on my way to school.
Sometimes I jump
over these rocks.
I guess I slipped.
Anything else?
So tell me, how does a
freshman end up in AP Biology?
All my classes are AP.
Sounds like a lot of stress.
Not really.
You been sad lately?
Alex on line two.
Says it's important.
After a concussion, as time
goes by, you start to remember.
Make sure to tell
me if that happens.
- I've got something to tell you.
- All right.
Hello.
What do you mean it doesn't fit?
I specifically ordered
for a '65 dashboard.
How was camp?
Amazing. I wish I
could stay all day.
I'll call for a return
authorization.
No, they were not supposed
to send a six-CD changer.
Okay. Okay, bye.
Getting a new stereo?
No, actually, my...
My car got broken into.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Oh, P.D. has some new info.
Witnesses saw a fight in Lincoln
Park where they found your kid.
At least four teenagers
grabbing and shoving each other.
- Frank.
- Thanks.
- What's Neela doing on your computer?
- A screen shot.
- You missed her video chat.
- Oh, how is she?
Never thought she'd be
happy in Louisiana, I was wrong.
She looks good, she sounds good.
Three new ones to present.
Why am I the only
attending on the floor?
Good afternoon. Hedda
Lanford, 24 weeks pregnant.
Congratulations.
- Left-leg pain and swelling.
- It got so bad, I couldn't walk.
- Any shortness of breath?
- No, just the leg.
- Good vitals.
- Okay. Trauma 2.
Paramedics are five
minutes out with a hot MI.
Call the cath lab and
grab me when they're here.
Has the baby been moving?
- Mm-hm.
Maybe a little less, but I
could be imagining things.
Let's get some fetal heart
tones and prep the SonoSite.
- Simon?
- Yeah?
- Want me to take her upstairs?
- What for?
After 20 weeks, we
like to send them to OB.
Baby's viable, they
get better monitoring.
If she had belly pain.
- They can check her leg.
- We'll do a better job.
Worried about a clot,
Mom comes first, not baby.
Then she needs an NST.
So get a fetal monitor.
- Are you okay?
- Yeah.
You seem a little...
I'm looking after 40
patients by myself.
Set up a duplex scan.
Keep going, man.
Good job.
Wow, this is pretty cool.
It's a baby wall. I've been
up one twice that size.
You wanna race me to the top?
- I'll give you 10 bucks if you win.
- Think you can bribe me?
- That is so pathetic.
- No, I can't.
It's not as hard as it looks.
- I don't want to.
- It's... It's fun.
- Hey. What's going on?
- She's afraid to try.
You know what?
Have you ever have a
dream where you were flying?
What was it like?
Don't look at the
ground. One more step.
Yeah, I'm... Yeah,
I'm coming down, guys.
No. Keep going.
Okay.
I'm gonna keep going.
Oh, no. I don't think
I can do this. Yeah.
- We did it!
- Yeah!
- You got it. MORRIS:
Two, three. Woo-hoo.
Yeah. Good job, Emily.
- You too.
- Hey.
All right, who's next?
- That was awesome.
- Oh.
Hey.
Russ. I got some bad news.
Definite DVT, there's a
large blood clot in the thigh.
How does that happen?
As the uterus grows, it
presses the pelvic veins.
Pregnancy makes the
blood more coagulable.
We need to treat you with a
blood thinner called heparin.
- Is that safe for the baby?
- Yeah.
Sure? Took us
years to get pregnant.
Doesn't cross the placenta.
What if you don't give it to me?
A piece of the clot could break
off and travel to your lungs.
- It's called a pulmonary embolism.
- And you can die.
Um, my brother-in-law's an OB. Do
you mind if we discuss this with him?
- That's a good idea.
- I think we're wasting time.
This is a no-brainer. Heparin's safe. It'll
save your life, save your baby's life.
- So let's prep a 5000-unit bolus, please.
- Excuse me.
Hey. Hey.
- What is their problem?
- They just need a little time.
Banfield can deal with them because
I'm supposed to go to this heart camp.
Oh, they're gonna love
you with that attitude.
Well, maybe I won't go.
Look, I know it's a hard time.
It'll get better.
- What are you talking about?
- Neela.
Neela? Look, Sam, tell your
gossip circle not to worry.
I've moved on
and I'm fine. Okay?
- You really need me here?
- You're my designated runner.
Okay. On my way.
Oh, oh... Oh, no, no...
Okay. Okay.
All right. Two down.
- Bases loaded.
- Bring me home, baby.
Bring me home, Vera.
Yeah.
Make the play. Make
the play. Bring it in.
We could get a grand
slam. Bring it home.
- What happened?
- Vera, are you okay?
Okay. What's going on, honey?
- My defibrillator's firing.
- Let me check the carotid.
I think she's in V-tach.
- Somebody help her.
- What's wrong with her?
Now do a Hennepin
with him sitting up.
Back in the socket.
All right. Immobilizer
and post-reduction film.
When we lived in San Diego, I
saw a surfer throw his shoulder out.
- San Diego's nice.
- We were there for about two years.
- Hmm, how long have you lived here?
- Since September.
Are you having any eye pain?
Archie, I know I volunteered, but
if you've got enough help, then...
We're completely
short-staffed now.
- You need to get over there.
- This is not necessary.
Good, it's not
gonna take very long.
- ICD discharge. TAGGART:
You want a 12 lead?
I gotta grab the programmer,
we're gonna interrogate.
- Who is that?
- The Big Kahuna.
Chief of Pediatric
Cardiology at Rush.
- He runs the camp.
- Normal sinus, 84.
Okay, send lytes and a troponin.
- Hey, I'm Vera.
- Felix.
- What happened?
- I have a defibrillator in my chest.
Cool.
Ha. I think it shocked
me by accident.
- Did it hurt?
- A little, ha. Like a horse kicked me.
Hey, Rojo, Xena. Um, can you
call and tell them I'm all right?
Rojo? Xena?
Vera says she's fine and
she'll be back really soon.
- You ready?
- Okay.
We all have to get from
this side to the other side...
without going through
the same hole twice.
- Can I go first?
- Sure. Go ahead.
Huh, wow.
It's like Cirque du Soleil.
Good job!
Don't touch the web.
Hey.
What?
Well, if everyone goes through
the web, it kind of builds a team.
That's stupid.
He doesn't have to
if he doesn't want to.
It would mean a lot to
the kids if you'd join in.
It wouldn't mean a lot to me.
Why don't you do it for them?
You really want me
to go to the other side?
Yeah.
I did it.
Look at me, I'm
on the other side.
Bingo.
That'll tell you
if it was V-tach?
This will tell us everything.
Oh. Excuse me. KAHUNA: Mm-hm.
Felix is getting a bed at 7.
- How's your headache?
- It's better.
- How'd you get a name like Felix?
- After Felix Bloch.
A physicist who won the Nobel
Prize for nuclear magnetic resonance.
- Like in MRI scans.
- Yeah. His work led to that.
He was a giant. Studied with
Heisenberg and Schrodinger.
Schrodinger had a cat.
- You know about that?
- He didn't actually have a cat.
It was a thought experiment.
Uh, the cat in the box was either alive
or dead depending on a random event.
- Okay, I am completely confused.
- That makes two of us.
Great news, it was
just a sinus attack.
When you ran, your
pulse rate went up to 180.
That means she can go back?
Well, she got shocked six times.
So I think we gotta
keep you in the hospital.
I'm not getting admitted.
Not during camp.
Honey, this thing zapped
you at a heart rate of 160.
- So if you exert yourself at all...
- Why don't you set it higher?
That's a good idea.
We can do that.
Okay.
Okay, no shocks until 200.
But only till after the
dance, all right? Huh?
Two weeks later, she can walk
in the door like nothing happened?
- That's what she did.
- There must be a time limit.
- There isn't.
- She's in high school.
We are in a better position
to care for that baby.
- That isn't the issue.
- We have resources, we have a home...
we have maturity.
Doesn't that count?
She's his mother. That
counts more than anything.
It's not a done deal.
The case worker still has to
talk to the mom and grandmother.
Take a week for
the determination.
- You let me know how that goes.
- Russ. Come on.
You know the system.
There's something else to do.
We keep working, we keep
praying, and we keep going.
I've been doing
that for seven years.
There you go.
They really need me, I
have to cancel tonight.
You could come down here.
You would?
Really? Do you own...?
Do you own a sleeping bag?
It was nice to meet
you. I'll see you around.
Yeah.
You could take
Felix to the dance.
It's only for kids who've
had open-heart surgery.
- Has an open skull fracture.
- That's close.
Not to mention a catheter
in his spinal column.
He has to stay on bed rest.
Let me see what I can do.
So how's it going in here?
Okay.
Doctor Gates, would
you take a seat?
I... I... I get very frustrated, because
I like to get to the bottom of things.
I need to know the truth.
Did you know Felix's parents
have to move every year or two?
Academic careers,
new universities.
Doesn't give you much
chance to put down roots.
- Make friends.
- When you feel like an outsider...
sometimes you fall in with
kids who do dangerous things.
- Like drugs.
- My urine test was negative.
You have Tardieu's spots...
little red dots near your eyes.
Maybe you don't remember...
but it can happen when
someone tries to choke you.
Felix?
Felix.
Did someone grab
you around the neck?
Not the neck.
The chest.
It's called
suffocation roulette.
You hold your breath and
someone squeezes you from behind.
The first one to pass out loses.
Kids die from playing that game.
Or get brain damage.
You're too smart a
kid to be doing that.
They're my friends.
Dr. Banfield, need you
in Trauma 2 right away.
My pregnant DVT lady has
sudden-onset chest pain.
- On heparin?
- For the past hour.
- What's her pressure?
- 110 over 65. Already did an EKG.
- Tell me about your pain.
- It hurts when I take a breath.
- Could a clot have gone to her lung?
- I would say, yes.
There's new right axis
deviation, and an S1, Q3.
- She's on heparin.
- It's not a perfect drug.
- What do we do now?
- We could try TPA.
It's a powerful clot-busting medicine.
If it works, she's back to normal...
with only a 1 percent risk.
- What about the baby? BANFIELD:
There are no good studies.
TPA definitely carries a risk
of miscarriage or fetal death.
- How big a risk?
- Ten percent, maybe more.
Oh, God.
What about a vena cava filter?
If we put a filter in
your main vein here...
we could prevent future clots
from traveling to your lung.
- But it takes time.
- We... We don't want to hurt the baby.
What would you do?
I don't care.
I don't care if we have
to stay here all day.
No, me neither.
They keep bugging me
to play their stupid games.
They don't get it.
They don't understand.
We could flush some
tennis balls down the toilets.
That would back
them up for days.
Or...
I know where there's
spray paint. We could tag...
"camp sucks" all over
the walls of the gym. Huh?
Or we can pull fire alarms and
make them evacuate all the patients.
Or we can... We can just
sit here and do nothing.
You think I'm being a jerk.
No.
I think that you're not letting
yourself have a good time.
It's not a good time.
Because Sean's not here.
Sean?
I met him in September,
we were in for heart caths.
We both had truncus arteriosus.
- You know what that is?
- Yeah.
Since we were babies, we had the same
operations and were on the same meds.
He had never been to camp.
I kept telling him
how great it was.
We made plans, we
talked and texted every day.
He thought he could win
the Kahuna's fart contest.
We were gonna have so much fun.
He had to go to surgery last
week for a conduit replacement.
Died on the table.
Logan, I'm sorry.
Hello.
Yeah, I know. I know. I'll...
I'll... I'll be there as soon as I can.
Not a good week all around.
What?
A good friend of
mine is in the ICU.
Uh...
I tried really hard to get
her a heart transplant...
but now she's back in rejection.
It's pretty bad.
What are you doing here?
Well, I... I stopped
by, but she's in a coma.
I've been intubated
like 10 times.
When I'm deeply sedated,
I can hear everything.
I can even tell
who's in the room.
She'll know if you're there.
Trached a month ago
for myasthenia gravis.
Bleeding this morning,
opened up in Triage.
Tracheo-innominate fistula
from pressure necrosis.
- Four units of O-neg.
- Have Thoracic Surgery hold an OR.
Pouring out faster
than we can transfuse.
Overinflate the trach cuff.
That can tamponade the bleeder.
You want the rapid infuser?
- Absolutely.
This isn't helping. More
air and I'll burst the cuff.
A number four Shiley.
- That's a pediatric size.
- Wait and see.
HemoCue is only eight-point-two.
Now put your finger
in the trach hole...
and compress against
the posterior sternum.
- Like this?
- Well done.
- Now get your ass up to the OR.
- Thank you.
We took her to Radiology for the
filter, crashed before they started.
BP 70 palp, tachy to 120.
You may need to intubate her.
Wait, what's going on?
Likely it's another blood clot.
We need to think about TPA.
We don't want it. Don't
want to hurt the baby.
Things have changed.
No, honey, honey.
Honey, honey, talk to me.
Honey, I need your
help here. Wait.
What are you doing? Wait,
What...? What...? What are you doing?
Baby looks great.
Placenta is perfect.
No sign of bleeding.
Thank you.
And the clot in your lung
has completely dissolved.
I thought I was
gonna lose both of you.
Well, we like it
when things work out.
Dr. Banfield, you gave
TPA without consent.
Yes, I did.
Well, what if there had
been a bad outcome?
She's young and healthy
and was about to die.
Do I need consent to shock her
heart if she has cardiac arrest?
I guess you got lucky.
- You saved that lady?
- Yep. And her baby too.
Uh, I'll get these to the lab.
- You're still here?
- That guy with the bleeding neck?
He's okay after surgery.
Is there someplace
we could talk?
In here.
What's on your mind?
I've been thinking
about it and...
I want him to be proud of me.
Yes.
To do that, though, I'd want
to make something of myself.
You know, be somebody
who did something important.
Like you.
Like me?
Make a difference, you know?
That's a good goal.
I don't know if I'd really be able
to do that if I quit school right now.
Having a kid's
gonna be really hard.
That's true.
The nurses told me you
were the custodian of the baby.
Does that mean you
wanted to adopt him?
My husband and I
were thinking about it.
I'm just scared I'll
never see him again.
That... That doesn't
have to happen.
You can watch him grow up...
get to know him,
be part of his life.
It's called an open adoption.
How do we do that?
I... I... If we all agree,
we can work it out.
- What is taking so long?
- Uh, give us two minutes.
Yeah, I'm timing you.
Tony, we're on next. We
didn't do a sound check.
Just start without us.
- Go on, I'll wait.
- All right.
Archie.
Hey. I'm so glad you're here.
His name is Rojo. Who are you?
Uh, this is my friend Claudia.
- Do you have a scar?
- A big one.
From here to here.
What do you think?
- Hey, beautiful.
- Looking good there, Felix.
- It's good to be the king.
- All right, let's go.
Hello, is this thing on?
All right, hello, Chicago.
Yeah.
Prepare to be blown away.
I have one question.
How are you feeling out there?
- Good!
I can't hear you. I
said, how you feeling?
Good!
Hey, Rojo, how're you feeling?
Wow!
- Doctor Brenner.
- Hey.
What are we stopping here for?
Checking on a patient.
You people have some
very unusual therapies.
Seem quite effective.
All right, shh.
Everybody's sleeping.
Room 209.
- Can I stay for a little while?
- We'll be quiet.
You need to get back to camp.
Visiting hours were
over three hours ago.
Yeah, but you
can say good night.
- Good night.
- Night.
Good luck, Felix.
All right, hey, give
them some privacy.
Quite a day today, huh?
Yeah.
Oh, thank you for coming
out to dinner with my mom.
You're welcome.
It took the heat off
of me. She loves you.
Well...
Wanna go to her colonoscopy
with me next week?
Excuse me? Privacy?
Hey!
Busted.
Back to your tent.
Boys stay on the
boys' side. Got that?
Let me know if you
hear anything out there.
- Yes, sir.
- All right.
- You thirsty?
- No.
- Ah. You hungry?
- Ugh, I had too many s'mores.
Not quite as good as Charlie
Trotter's would have been.
- This was way more fun.
- Really?
Definitely.
You are something else.
You went from a night on the town
to a night in a pup tent without a hitch.
Ah. Life's too short to whine.
It is.
You know, you spend a day
with these kids, you realize...
This... This is
totally random...
but sometimes I
imagine a night...
in the future.
A night where I would take you out,
spend money, make a deal about it.
And it would end like this.
When I ask you to marry me.
What do you think?
I think I'd say yes.
Dr. Morris.
I can't fall asleep.
Yeah, she's never been
to a sleepover before.
She's homesick.
Well, what do you...?
What do you need, Em?
My dad tells me a
bedtime story every night.
Not a problem. All right.
Okay, let me see.
All right, once upon a time...
there was a little blood cell...
who couldn't find
his way to the lungs.
Now, he was... He
was blue all the time...
but he wished that he was red.
He needs a Rastelli operation.
What?
No, no, no. A Blalock-Taussig.
He has tetrology.
Hey, who's telling
this story anyway, huh?
Three ounces down the hatch.
How about a nice
burp for Russell?
Uh-huh.
Oh.
That was a good one.
That was a quick one.
Here we go. High-five. Yes.
Now, tomorrow, we gonna
work on that fist bump, okay?
Aw.
There we go, there
we go. There we go.
There we go.