Rach. Rachel.
Come on, honey. Time to get up.
Rachel.
Uppy, uppy, squeezer.
Daddy, I'm not a squeezer.
Oh, yeah?
Well, I made you
"eggs in the window."
Come on.
Hello?
Hey, Jen.
She slept great.
She read Winnie the Pooh
and did her homework.
Okay, 2:00 will be fine.
Look, I am not signing
anything until my lawyer comes...
There she is. She's up.
Hey, Rach.
Mom wants to talk to you.
Hello.
Okay.
I guess.
No.
Here's Daddy.
Yeah?
Nothing. She just got up.
Look, I am not bad-mouthing you.
Her breakfast is getting cold.
I'll see you at 2.
Your mom's going to come
pick you up later, okay?
How long are you
going to stay here?
A while,
so it would be great
if you could draw some pictures
for the walls.
Window's too big.
It still tastes good.
It's okay.
I don't like eggs.
Since when?
If Mommy said she was sorry,
would you stop being mad at her?
Oh, I'm not mad at Mommy.
Are you going to move
back to Milwaukee?
Um...
maybe.
We'll have to see.
When you move back home
can we put the fish tank
in my room?
Yeah. Sure, we can.
And you'll help
me take care of it
every day?
Let's go to Lou Mitchell's
and get pancakes
and after I drop
some stuff off at work,
we can go ice skating.
You don't know how to
skate very well, Daddy.
Well, then, you can teach me.
Easy, easy.
That's precious cargo.
Honey, it's okay.
Sign here...
and here...
and here.
BP is great.
Hmm.
So you finally got
a normal reading?
Yep. Three.
Good for you.
She's just going
to decompensate.
Maybe, but not here.
The nursing home
is all the way up in Evanston.
All right, let's go.
So Tompkins is the next patient,
and if you remember,
last time we...
Well, you're looking
much better, I see.
Says who?
Why don't you pull
Tompkins' CVP line,
please.
Doctor,
when is she going
to be able to walk?
Mr. Carter is going
to accompany you
downstairs,
and you can address
any further concerns
you have with him.
Please, Carter.
Peter, may I see you
for a minute, please?
Oh, and Carter,
Dr. Benton needs
some coded data sheets
for the Investigation
Review Board.
Peter, I want you to come
to a dinner party
I'm having tonight
for some colleagues.
It's 8:30 sharp.
We have Dean Adelstein-Fields
from Johns Hopkins...
Gaylord Fields?
Sorry about such late notice,
but you see...
what is it, Carter?
Just the transfer authorization.
Bye, Carter.
So that's you and a guest,
and Peter, please,
don't be late.
Well, Mrs. Tompkins...
Hey, we thought
we'd lost you, doc.
No, I'm here. Hey, Jeanie.
Good morning.
She doesn't seem to have
much of an appetite yet.
Well, Mr. Rubadoux, she...
Please. Ruby.
Ruby, she just had
a major surgery.
It takes time to recover.
Stop pestering the young man.
Who's pestering?
He's the only doctor
worth a damn in my book.
Uh-huh. Coughing still.
You know, I think the
pneumonia is back.
She's on powerful,
broad-spectrum antibiotics.
She's fine.
The convalescent home
is too far from the hospital.
Ruby, we've been all over this.
She looks good,
she's responded
well to the medication.
It's time for her to go.
You spoke to Dr. Chung
at the convalescent home,
and he concurs.
Mm. Dr. Chung.
Egg rolls, they
know, but medicine?
Jules, enough.
She just won't have
to stay in bed, will she?
Oh, she's gonna be back on
her feet in no time. I promise.
Are you sure
she shouldn't have
stayed a few more days?
Ruby, she looks great.
She's doing great.
Goodbye, Mrs. Rubadoux.
Well, God bless, Dr. Carter.
What a boy. What a boy.
Yes.
February's Residents' schedule.
ACI is done.
Just needs a
fever control sheet.
Thanks.
Hi, Rach. I love your outfit.
Carol's talking to you, honey.
Aunt Bubble Butt gave it to me.
Rach...
That's what you call her.
That's nice, Mark.
Aunt Bubble Butt.
Hey. Hey.
Hey.
Susie! Can I hold her?
Oh, yeah,
if you're really,
really careful, though.
Use both hands, honey, okay?
Oh...
Hey, Susie-woozie-woozie.
That's the first smile
I've seen all morning.
Oh. Rough couple of days?
You have no idea.
Aren't you supposed
to be on a swing shift?
Yeah, I just came by
to catch up on dictations.
I think you should
go skating instead.
I have so much paperwork.
Susie, she'd love it,
and, uh, you know,
it'd help me out.
I'm really behind.
Oh, what the hell. Okay.
Excellent.
Guess who's coming
skating with us?
Susie. Susie's coming.
Yes, as soon as I
get her all bundled up.
Thank you.
Her too?
Of course, her too.
She's a really good skater.
Yeah, I'll teach you
how to do a spin.
I know how to do a spin.
Do you want to put
little Susie's cap on?
She'll be fine.
Okay.
Just say no to colic.
Doug, your dad's called
three times since last night.
If you don't call him back,
he's gonna keep bugging us.
I don't have anything
I want to say to him.
Well, his number's right there.
He's staying at the Hotel Dupre.
That's one step up
from a refrigerator box.
Carter, where you been?
I've been seeing patients.
Ah. Vucelich's data sheets.
Tomorrow morning before rounds.
Right.
Rubadoux's discharge summary?
Oh, that is in your box.
I finally, finally turfed her.
Husband drove you nuts?
You have no idea.
So...
who are you taking tonight?
What?
To Vucelich's big dinner party?
Nobody.
Nobody? You got
to take somebody.
No, I don't.
Yeah, you do.
He said, "Bring a guest,"
and that sounded like an order.
I don't know.
I was thinking maybe Jackie.
Your sister?
You're kidding, right?
You can't take your sister.
Why not?
Well, it just seems kind of...
Kind of what?
Pathetic.
What about, uh...
Carter,
I can find my own damn dates.
Okay, fine.
It's going to be a
bunch of surgeons
and their trophy
wives and you...
with your sister.
The boy with
inguinal hernia repair
was discharged yesterday.
Kids recover fast.
Yeah.
They seem to be keeping you
pretty busy down here.
Aerobic medicine.
You should see me
crawl home every night.
Yeah, well, um...
if you're not too tired tonight,
Dr. Vucelich,
this vascular surgeon
I've been assisting...
I know who Dr. Vucelich is.
Well, anyway, he's
having some colleagues
over to his house for dinner.
It's not a social thing.
It's mostly surgeons.
Peter, are you
asking me to dinner?
It's a hospital function.
As opposed to a date.
What time do we
need to be there?
It starts at eight.
He lives on North Lake Shore.
I can pick you up at 7:30.
I'll meet you there.
It's not a date.
We need some help lifting.
Wow!
What the hell is that?
Guardrail.
Pinned him to the car seat.
All right, page Benton
and call Engineering
for a metal saw.
These seats are
from a '67 GTO, right?
The car is toast.
Damn! What a waste.
Rollover TC on the Ike,
two fatalities.
Guy's car flipped
and hit the pipe guardrail.
Came through the windshield
and nailed him.
Absent breath
sounds on the left.
Chest tube tray.
BP is 100/60, pulse 120.
O-2 at 10 liters.
1500 cc's saline in.
C-spined the best we could.
A hell of an extrication.
BP 110 palp.
CBC, type and cross 10 units.
Get four units
O-neg, just in case.
How the hell am I
supposed to tube him?
Somebody call for a metal saw?
Ew.
Get up here and cut between
the chair and his back, now.
Gown him! Me?
Wow!
There she goes.
Whoa, whoa. That's a nice one.
Yeah.
I'm going to get sick.
Hey, you want to
show me your spin?
No.
Sorry.
So, how's she taking
you two getting divorced?
We haven't told her yet.
She's still
getting used to the separation.
Yeah, why don't you
Let me take Susie,
so you can skate with her?
You kidding?
This is what's holding me up.
Yes.
Come on, Miss Munchkin.
Oh, you are so funny.
Are you ready?
Here comes Dad!
Whoo!
Why do you stick
your butt out so far?
I just got to tuck it in here.
Is that what... Whoa!
Oh-ho! Nice!
Half a grundoolie.
I give it a 6.5.
Oh, hey, Rachel,
you want me to show you
a special way to tie your skates
really tight
so your ankles stay straight?
I want to tie my skates
like Mommy does.
Rachel... It's okay.
I don't want her
touching my skates.
Sorry.
Maybe this was a bad idea.
Rach.
Rach!
Rachel.
Gown me.
My first medical consult.
O.R.'s ready.
Carter, Vucelich's charts
been done for those data sheets?
Uh, almost.
What do you want me to do?
Throw in a left chest tube.
36 French.
BP's fallen, 50 systolic.
Uh...
10 blade.
Okay, crank up the saline.
Two more units
packed cells on the infuser.
Bullet.
High-speed impalement injury,
hypovolemic shock.
Widened mediastinum.
Maybe a traumatic
rupture of the aorta.
Somebody call Vucelich.
Thora-Seal's filling.
Let's get him upstairs.
We'll do a trans-esophageal
echo before we prep.
Carter, where are you going?
To the O.R.
Uh-uh, not when
you have work to do.
Dr. Benton, I think he
ought to see this case.
Oh, there he is. Dr. Carter.
She said her chest hurt,
then she passed out.
They tried to go
to another hospital,
but I insisted
that they bring her
back here to you.
Okay, people. Let's move.
Carter, tend to your patient.
I want to go to
the O.R. with you.
Not anymore, you're not.
Don't make a career of her.
You've got things to do. Move!
Dr. Carter, please.
Well, day care time.
Say goodbye to Rachel.
Bye-bye, Rachel.
Say bye, Rach.
Dr. Greene,
your wife called.
Her doctor's appointment
got changed.
Why you working behind
the counter, E-Ray?
Jerry got the flu.
I thought I might supplement
my meager nurse trainee stipend
with an occasional
clerking shift.
Does personnel know about this?
Oh, yes.
I'm over-qualified, actually.
120 words per minute,
shorthand, IBM, Mac,
four kinds of word processing,
spreadsheets.
Yeah, did she say
when she was going to get here?
As soon as she can.
Right.
Okay, Rach,
let's get you set
up in the lounge.
Mark, we need you in Trauma 2.
Uh, I'll take her.
Licensed Illinois
day care worker.
All right, easy now.
Tie that bleeder off.
All right. We have exposure.
Finally, we can do some work.
The arch has been grazed.
It could blow.
We're gonna have to bypass him.
Let's take this nice and slow.
Set up the roller pump
and call in the Tech.
We should clamp and run.
No, there's more damage
than the echo showed pre-op.
He's unstable and
this aorta could blow
any second.
If we bypass him,
we've got a safety net.
By the time we
set up for a bypass,
we could clamp
proximally and distally,
pull out the rail,
and sew in a graft.
How long will that take?
I'll be out in 35 minutes.
Get me an ETA on Vucelich.
At least half an hour.
We could be closing
when he gets here.
It's too risky.
I've assisted on
five of these things.
I've done two myself.
I can do this.
You heard the man.
Let's do it.
Statinsky.
Found at Louie's
Ribs, passed out drunk.
Acute respiratory distress.
She won't give us her name.
Is that bourbon or Scotch?
BP 70/50, pulse 120,
GCS, eight.
I gave her glucose, Narcan,
and 40 of Lasix.
Okay, let's move her.
Ready? Set?
Go.
Really cyanotic.
Pulse ox 72.
She's in pulmonary edema.
Intubation tray, ET tube 7.0.
I'm gonna have to put a
tube down your windpipe
to allow you to breathe, okay?
So just try... try
and relax, okay?
Rapid sequence induction?
Oh, definitely bourbon.
Let's try two of Versed first,
and get a blood
gas, CBC, Chem-7,
enzymes,
portable chest,
check for I.D.
BP's 80/50.
Dopamine drip?
Yeah.
All right, I'm in.
Inflate the cuff.
V-fib.
Charging to 200.
Everybody off.
Just a sec.
Okay.
Clear.
Sinus tach. Faint pulse.
Lidocaine, 100 IV Push.
Hang a drip, two
milligrams a minute.
Shoot a chest, get a
gas, and call Respiratory.
Lidocaine 2 grams.
Name's Barbara Dean.
Wow.
Wow what?
Today's her 50th birthday.
No kidding.
Nope.
She looks pretty old for 50.
Looks like she did all
her partying up front.
Sylvie.
I'm getting good returns.
Sylvie?
She needs a Foley.
Come on, honey. I'm
right here, sweetheart.
Sylvie, please...
She's not responding.
She may have had a small stroke.
Stroke?
Can you be careful
of the sterile field?
She had a stroke?
It's really too
early to tell that.
She was fine until I took
her to the nursing home.
Ruby, give us room to work.
What happened, Dr. Carter?
Did she leave the
hospital too soon?
I'll be back in a minute.
Stroke?
We are going to take
very good care of her.
Eww!
E-Ray, what is that?
Skin lesions.
This is nightmare material.
On the contrary, Dr. Greene.
Children greatly benefit
from confronting their fears
in a supportive and
nurturing environment.
It's cool, Daddy.
We're going to go finish
The Little Mermaid, okay?
Yes, Mrs. Hardy, we need
you to sign some papers.
Yes. She was.
Well, she's extremely ill...
I understand, but your
mother's in grave condition.
Old records on Barbara Dean.
She hung up.
Detox twice, D.T.'s,
fractured wrist,
collarbone, seizures,
end-stage liver disease,
and cardiomyopathy.
Well, her daughter
won't come in.
Said she's had enough.
Mrs. Dean seems to
have had enough too.
Dr. Ross, it's
your father again.
Tell him I died.
Beautiful funeral,
everybody cried.
You are not going
to believe this one.
Oh, yeah? Try us.
Guess who's in the suture room.
Come on, guess.
We don't want to guess.
He's wearing a Catholic
schoolgirl's outfit...
Plaid skirt,
ballet slippers, frilly blouse.
David Morgenstern ring a bell?
Our David Morgenstern?
Knee socks too.
Somebody get a camera.
Let's go.
This aorta's shredded.
It's not holding
the sutures. Damn.
He's had 14 units
of blood, two of FFP,
and six of platelets.
He's got to be chewing
up clotting factors.
Retract this way. I can't see.
Where is Vucelich?
He's scrubbing in.
BP's crashing.
If only I could... if I
could just... damn!
Suction! Suction. Let's move.
I've got an angle
on it. Give it here.
Gown me.
Traumatic dissection
of the aorta.
We elected to clamp and
run rather than bypass.
What have you been
débriding with, Benton?
Garden shears?
It's... it's hard to
appreciate the degree of...
I went the wrong way with this.
All right, let me
in there, Benton.
Get out of the way.
Side clamp.
The dissection's high
in the arch and posterior.
2.0 Prolene, 24
inches, retract caudally.
Shall we go on bypass?
No.
No. I think we're okay now, huh?
It's my fault.
I allowed Benton's enthusiasm
to cloud my judgment.
All right, tie it off here.
No, no. It's too long.
Yes. Yes.
Adson.
Bovie there.
Hmm. Good.
Got it.
Okay, Bovie that.
Mosquito. No, tie that off.
Okay, let's dissect this.
Hey, Jeanie.
Uh, is he still hanging around?
Yeah.
Dr. Carter. She's
not responding.
H-how long is she
going to stay down here?
Believe me, nobody
wants to get her admitted
more than I do.
Carter, I need you.
Her heart monitor beeped.
Yeah, that's what
it's supposed to do.
Ruby, I got another patient.
Hey, Ruby, let's go take a look
to make sure everything's okay.
Yeah. Another adolescent
fantasy shot to hell.
Nice knees.
Hey, you guys,
we get an 8 x 10 glossy,
none of us'll ever
work holidays again.
Doug, two boys
playing in the street
hit by a car.
Paramedics are two minutes out.
Man, I miss all the fun
stuff. Come on, Carol.
Why me?
I don't get to see,
you don't get to see.
That's not fair.
Care to join me, Dr. Lewis?
Oh, I'd be delighted,
Dr. Greene.
Mark, Susan, thank God.
I'm feeling a bit foolish.
No doubt.
What seems to be the problem?
Oh, showing off
tossing the caber.
I clunked myself,
the buffet table,
and my Great Aunt Jean Ferguson.
The caber?
Big telephone pole thing.
You pick it up, and you...
and it's not light, mind you,
and you...
flip it upside down,
or you, you try to.
The Highland
Games. Burns' supper.
My leg's killing me.
So...
that's a kilt?
Well, of course it's
a... what else would it..?
I see what you're saying.
Well, that would
be embarrassing.
Russian Jew on my father's side.
Full-blooded Highland
Scot on my mother's.
Ow, ow, ow, ow.
Oh, yeah, it's probably broken.
Oh, damn.
Hey, Jeanie.
Look, I, uh, hope you haven't
gone through a lot
of trouble tonight,
but dinner's off.
Really? They canceled this late?
No, no, no, no.
I, um, I got a post-op
with a lot of complications.
I'm going to be hung
up here all night. Sorry.
Guess I'll cancel my makeover.
That was a joke.
Some other time.
Yeah.
Twofer. Brothers.
Noah's nine, Kenny's
seven. Skitching behind a bus.
Kenny fell off, Noah let
go, and a car hit them.
Kenny's hurt real bad.
All right, hang in there, Noah.
Skitching?
When you grab the
bumper of a moving car,
and it drags you along the ice.
Seven-year-old's
dinged pretty badly.
Head trauma, ALOC. GCS
10, BP 60/40, pulse 144,
probably femur fracture,
and he's got a tire track
across his abdomen.
And what about Noah?
Stable, good vitals,
couple of cuts,
maybe a fractured wrist.
Okay, on my count.
One, two, three.
All right, let's
get X-ray in here.
Portable C-spine, CBC,
type and cross six units.
Babinski's downgoing.
BP's down, 50 palp.
Pulse 150.
Get two of O-negative
down here stat.
Absent bowel
sounds, belly's rigid.
Intubation tray.
Excuse me.
Uncuffed number five ET tube.
Stabilize his neck for me.
Head CT, non-contrast?
Here we go.
I'll order a C-spine,
chest, pelvis, right femur.
Set up for a peritoneal
lavage, please.
Uh-huh. I'll be next door.
Who's on Pediatric surgery?
Kenny! Kenny!
Calm down, Noah.
You're going to be fine.
What about Kenny?
Is he going to be okay?
Is he going to die?
Taking care of him, Noah.
It's my fault.
How is he? He's lucky.
Just a couple lacerations,
road rash, left wrist fracture.
Kenny! Kenny!
Noah, you're going
to have to calm down.
Kenny's going to
have to have surgery,
and we need to know
where your parents are.
He is going to die, isn't he?
Where are your parents?
I don't know where my mom
is, and my dad's not around.
I recognize this kid.
Noah, you've been
in here before, right?
Don't let him die, please, okay?
We're prepped for the DPL.
Listen, Noah, you
need to calm down
and try to remember
where your dad is, okay?
Parents are nowhere to be found.
We got to do this
without their consent.
Here's the blood.
All right, notify O.R.
and the Pediatric
surgeon on call, please.
O-neg at 20 per kilogram.
I figure 500 cc's.
Sounds about right.
Mm-hmm. Okay.
Tap's positive.
Dr. Carter, could you explain
what's going on with my Sylvie
to Dr. Goldstein?
Dr. Goldstein?
Carter?
He's the upstairs neighbor
of my sister in Miami.
Carter.
Uh, just get a number for
me and I'll call him back.
Carter!
Where are Vucelich's
data sheets?
Uh, I'm not quite
done with them yet.
Carter, what the hell
have you been doing?
I've been trying to get
Mrs. Rubadoux readmitted.
Cardiology won't take her
because there's no confirmed MI.
Renal won't take her
because she's in failure.
Carter, she's one patient. One.
Get her admitted and finish
Vucelich's data sheets, okay?
Okay.
Mrs. Dean?
I'm Dr. Lewis.
Lily tells me you took
your intubation tube out.
We don't usually
encourage that here,
but I'll take it as a sign
that you're feeling better?
Like a million bucks.
In your records, there's a
Do Not Resuscitate order.
I'd like to remove it.
No. Leave it.
You're in impending
respiratory failure.
It's treatable,
but we need to put
you on a respirator.
Mrs. Dean, you're
only 50 years old.
Leave it.
Well, it's not an emergency.
I just wanted to tell them,
that I'm not coming
to the dinner tonight.
Dr. Benton, are you ill?
And by that, I mean do
you have a terminal disease
to which you will succumb
before 11:00 tonight?
Then I suggest you
arrive promptly at 8:00
and enjoy your evening.
Well, I'm not sure
he wants me to come.
Of course he wants you.
You're filling in for a
last-minute cancellation.
Marian doesn't like empty chairs
at her dinner parties.
Think of it this way:
his dinners are
like his surgeries.
When your presence is requested,
you don't decline.
Any word from my wife yet?
On her way.
Is someone poking
out a cat's eye in there?
I told him it was
okay to practice.
It looks like you have
a non-displaced fracture
of the distal fibula.
Damn!
You're going to need a cast.
I'm going to miss the haggis.
Boys'll be disappointed.
Uh-huh. I'll call Ortho.
I was supposed to cut it.
Great honor.
Nephews were going to
pipe me in and everything.
Even memorized Robbie
Burns' "To a Haggis."
Uh-huh.
His knife
See rustic labour dight
And cut you up
with ready sight...
Yeah, this is Greene in the ER.
Your burde, like a distant hill,
Your pin wad help to mend a mill
In time of need
While through your pores
The dews distill like amber bead
Dinner's back on.
Excuse me?
I can make it after
all, if it's cool with you.
Uh, sure. Yeah.
I'll see you later.
Hey, Rach. How's it going?
Okay.
Your mom's going
to be here real soon
to pick you up.
So, who's winning?
She is. Good, too.
Thanks for watching her, Malik.
Hey, no problem.
I had four sisters.
Mark, can I steal
you for a consult?
Sure. I'll be back in a sec.
No, you won't.
I'll be back as soon as I can.
I finally remembered him.
The father was in last Fall
with respiratory
and liver problems.
Passed out in his own vomit.
Noah called 911 and saved him.
Father of the Year candidate.
Yup. He's been in six
times in the past two years.
He's a real mess.
The DCFS guy's here.
Dad's a drunk, kids
are playing in the street
in the middle of a school day,
and who says the
American family's in decline?
How are you doing?
So, what's wrong with you guys?
How long's it going to take
for you to get these
kids out of the home?
Dave Donovan.
Nice to meet you too.
Got a long history with
the Krawcyzk family.
Mother's MIA. Dad's been
on a bender for three years,
but he's cleaned
up pretty well now...
AA, job...
How's Kenny?
Uh, ruptured spleen,
concussion,
fracture of the thigh.
He's up in surgery.
He's going to be okay.
And Noah?
We're going to admit him
until you find him a placement.
Not looking for one.
Father's on his way in.
So what?
Father lets his kids run wild.
They're boys. Screwed
up. They played hookey.
No, no, no. The
father screwed up.
Yeah, maybe, maybe not.
So that's it?
That's all you're going to do?
Look, let's just wait and see.
Okay.
John, hold on.
I'm in a hurry.
This will only take a sec.
Rubadoux. You haven't told him
how serious his
wife's condition is.
Yeah, I tried to,
but I couldn't get a
word in edgewise.
He needs to know so
he can say goodbye,
get their affairs in order.
Why does it have to be me?
He trusts you.
I have to go.
Just do it?
Yeah.
Karen Hardy.
She's been there
for about 20 minutes.
Her mother signed a DNR order.
She hasn't budged
from that spot.
I'm afraid she may
challenge the order.
Mrs. Hardy, this is Dr. Greene.
She's been in and
out all afternoon.
This would be a good
time to go and see her.
No, thanks.
This glass between
us is just fine.
Your mother's
condition is very grave.
We can't be sure that
she's going to pull through.
Did she ask to see me?
No.
No, the only thing she's
ever really wanted to see
is the bottom of
a bottle of booze.
Your mother's dying,
and she's asked
that no heroic measures
be taken to save her life.
You understand the implications
of her request?
She wants to die.
She can't face the truth,
that she's an alcoholic.
She'd never admit that.
I don't know why
parents lie to their kids.
Children know.
Always.
If there's a chance
to make peace,
you should talk to her.
I don't want to see her.
I believe you, but you have
been standing
here for 20 minutes.
You said there were some
papers that I should sign?
Yeah. They're at the desk.
Rheumatology,
no. Orthopedics, no.
What are you doing?
Oh, I'm trying to find a study
that'll take Mrs. Rubadoux.
Neurology... bingo.
Dr. Carter?
Yeah, this is Carter in the ER.
I've got a patient for your
nerve stimulation study.
Post-op ischemic myelopathy.
You'll see her?
Well, you're going
to have to hurry,
because Cardiology's
interested too.
All right, I'll save
her for you. Okay.
She's admitted, Ruby. Neurology.
They're on their way
down to see her now.
You'll still be her
doctor too, right?
Oh, I'll visit, but, uh...
I'm assigned to
the surgical service.
B-but the Neurology people,
they're the ones
to help her, right?
That's right.
And... and she's
going to be okay?
They're the people to see.
Neuro. Bye, now. God bless.
A-ha-ha.
Thanks, Malik.
I've got a couple minutes.
Hey, no problem.
Rach, you and
I, we need to talk.
You know... that you will
always have a mom and a dad
who love you very much.
See my fish?
When you move back home,
can we get
another angel fish to
keep Moby company?
Yes. Moby can
have a new friend...
but Daddy's not
moving back home.
The truth is, you are
going to have two homes
from now on...
One with Mommy, one with me.
Mommy and Daddy aren't
going to live together anymore.
I know you're
sad... and angry...
but I want you to talk to
me about anything, okay?
Believe me, Daddy wishes
it could be any
other way than this.
It's just...
Hey, Jen.
Rach and I, we were
just having a talk.
That's good, Mark.
Hey, bananafish,
I'm sorry I'm late.
Mommy got her cast off today.
Come on, let's start
packing up your stuff.
We're going to go.
No!
Come on, honey.
You can do lanyards in the car.
Stop it!
Put your knapsack on.
Get away!
Oh, no. You don't talk
to your mother that way.
That's enough. Come on.
No way. I don't want to go! No!
I don't want to go.
Get away. Get away!
I don't want to go! No!
Let me alone!
Get away!
I don't want to go!
No!
Get away!
Hello.
Hi. I'm Peter Benton.
Peter, I'm Marian Vucelich.
Nice to meet you.
My guest should
be arriving soon.
She is already here.
Will you excuse me for a moment?
Oh, sure.
Thought your plans
changed again.
Yeah. Traffic was bad.
You look nice.
So do you.
Ladies and gentlemen...
it looks like everyone's
finally arrived, huh?
So...
dinner is served.
Mr. Krawcyzk, I'm Dr. Ross.
How's Kenny? When can I see him?
He's still in surgery.
But he's going to be all right.
Yes, he is. Can we have..?
Can I talk to you out here?
Sure.
Excuse us.
Why aren't these kids in school?
I already talked to the
social worker about that.
Indulge me, indulge me.
I usually drop them off,
but I got a new job this week,
and they're supposed
to take the bus.
And how did you
lose your old job?
I quit my old job
when they switched me to
nights, not that it's your business.
It's my business when these
boys are brought to the ER.
They ditched school,
so they'll be punished.
I believe they've
been punished enough.
What do you mean?
Doug...
I don't know what your game
is, doc, but me and my boys...
How many times have
you been in here drunk?
What?
Doug, what the
hell are you doing?
My job.
Look, the last time
this guy was in here,
he was circling the drain.
I think he's trying.
People don't
change. Sure they do.
You want to beat up on
a father, call your own.
This guy's doing the
best he can. All right?
How are you feeling?
Disappointed.
They'll be cutting
the haggis about now.
Do you hear that?
Yeah, I hear that.
My boys!
My nephews!
This is great!
Those are his nephews?
A Scotsman loves a
man who never gives up.
"A man's a man for a' that,"
says Robbie Burns.
Here's to you, Uncle Davey.
The haggis! Oh-ho!
We couldn't do it
without you, Uncle Davey.
You do the cutting.
His knife see rustic labor dight
And cut you up with ready sight
Trenching your
gushing entrails bright
Like onie ditch
And then, oh, what
a glorious sight
Warm, reeking, rich
Let's eat.
Oh, bless you.
L'chaim!
Long may your loom reek.
What is this?
Sheep's blood,
intestines, and testicles
mixed in a gruel.
L'chaim!
Mrs. Hardy?
Hi.
Are you all right?
I used to watch her
like this when I was little.
Passed out on the sofa,
kitchen floor, front steps.
I never waited
around long enough
for her to wake up.
Too afraid when I was a child,
too angry later on.
I just don't seem
to have the energy
for fear or anger.
I can't decide if that's
a good sign or not.
Well, here's to
arteriosclerosis...
without which I could not
be offering you this exquisite
'85 Corton-Charlemagne.
Beware.
The last time Carl
uncorked a bottle,
I bought 5% of his
miracle drug, Lazerol,
by the end of the evening.
To Lazerol!
I'm Anne Adelstein.
I don't believe we've met.
I'm Peter Benton.
I've read your work on dialysis.
It was very impressive.
My husband, Martin.
Troffle d'or?
Are you the visiting
Ortho fellow?
No, darling.
He's Carl's newly anointed.
Ah, yes. The chosen one.
The heir apparent.
Carl has an eye for talent.
To the heir apparent.
Not after this afternoon.
Why, what happened?
I made a fool out
of myself in surgery.
Vucelich was just too polite
to kick me off the
team before dinner.
Ooh, I'm sorry.
Jeanie?
Hmm?
Where's the truffle?
You got me. Maybe there.
Thanks again for
a lovely evening.
Our pleasure.
Bye.
Thank you.
Thanks.
Quite the evening.
Yeah, yeah. I had a good time.
Yeah. Me too.
Well, um...
Peter?
Peter, do you have a moment?
Of course.
Good night.
Dr. Lewis, please...
there's something wrong.
On 100% O2, her
pulse ox is down to 70.
She's in respiratory failure.
What's wrong?
Heart rate's down to 40.
Dobutamine, dopamine, Levofed...
They're all maxed.
Do something.
Your mother signed a
Do Not Resuscitate order.
You have to help her!
Her breathing's agonal,
no BP, pulse down to 30.
Aren't you going to do anything?
We have to respect her wishes.
She was very clear.
Brandy, or should
we have some port?
Uh, no, I don't drink.
Don't drink?
Well, how in the world
are you going to
enjoy your Cohiba?
Castro's favorite.
Rolled on the thighs of virgins.
Um... I don't smoke, either.
Please, Peter,
you're contributing
to the appalling
demise of social ritual.
I'll tell you what.
Let me just put this beside you.
It will make me feel
oh, so much better.
I'm sorry about this
afternoon's surgery.
I... I know it was
disappointing for you.
It was for me.
It was.
Dr. Hicks was absolutely right.
I did overstep my bounds.
You did.
That's exactly
what I expect of you.
Angela Hicks is
a superb surgeon.
I've never known her to
make a significant error.
But the physician
that is useful to me
is the one who has the vision
to keep one eye on the details
while the other eye
roams the horizons.
Peter, to me,
medicine is a challenge.
It's full of highly
skilled drudgery.
There are plenty of
talented surgeons out there,
man and woman alike,
who simply want to
perfect the practice
of what's already
been accomplished.
My interest lies
in what's beyond that...
The puzzles, the
impossibles, the risks.
Well, that's why it's been
an honor to work with you.
Is it? Really?
Hmm. To tell you
the truth, Peter,
I really haven't
been able to tell
whether you like it or not.
No, no, no, believe me,
it's been the best
and hardest work
I've ever done.
Good. Good.
That's music to my ears.
I was beginning
to fear that I saw
something in you
that you didn't see
in yourself.
I want to see it.
I'll drink to that.
Hello? Who is this?
Hey, what are you doing
sitting here in the dark?
Don't ask.
Mind if I join you?
Tough day, guys?
Don't ask. Don't ask.
Would a little single
malt Glendronach help?
I don't know.
We could do a linear
regression analysis.
Well, the regression
part's guaranteed.
Do you have anything to eat?
I think there's some
haggis left over.
What's that?
Don't ask.
Cheers.
Dr. Carter.
I'm buried, Ruby.
I've got all this
data to tabulate.
I've got two pre-op
histories to dictate.
I've got a.m. labs to order...
You lied to me.
What?
The neurologist told me
she'll never leave the hospital.
Well, uh...
he's her doctor now.
You should respect his opinion.
You knew all along, didn't you?
I got to get back to work.
You were our
doctor and our friend!
No, I was a fourth-year
medical student,
who took care of your wife
when she was on
the surgical service.
You gave me hope,
because I thought you cared.
You should've told me the truth.
I tried.
I'm not a kid.
You should've told me.
Did her leaving the hospital
today make her worse?
I don't know.
I trusted you.
I spent two weeks
treating her multiple
medical problems.
I dealt with social services,
I arranged for her
convalescent care,
I fought with Cardiology,
Renal, and Neuro
to get her admitted here.
I did everything that I could.
We're not just old people.
We have lives.
You look at my wife,
and all you see is her problems.
I see a 20-year-old dancer.
27-year-old bride.
30-year-old mother.
What do you want from me?
The truth!
She's dying, Ruby!
Is that what you want to hear?
She's dying, and she's
never going to leave
this hospital.
Thank you!
I'm sorry, Ruby.
Call me Mr. Rubadoux.