Now keep your eyes
looking ahead. Both hands
under the pillow.
Mmm-hmm.
And stop.
Then what?
Then you give the rings
to Mommy and me.
I'm gonna show her.
Mommy, Mommy!
Hey, you guys
aren't supposed to be in here!
You look beautiful.
Aww. Thank you, my love.
Come here.
Give me a kiss.
I love you.
He's right.
Don't you know it's bad luck
to see me before the wedding?
Yeah, sorry.
I'm not superstitious.
It's all right.
Wow.
Oh, don't step on it.
We're okay, right?
Yeah, we're okay.
I got to pick up my tux.
Hey, we're really
doing this, huh?
Absolutely.
Remember to make sure
your sleeves aren't too long.
Bye, Owen!
You're sure the sleeves
are the right length?
Not too long?
They're perfect.
What do you think?
Maybe different cuff links?
Okay.
Yeah.
Will, please.
Tim, I told you
over the phone, I can't.
You don't understand.
Pop fell again.
He's dizzy.
He's not walking right.
You gotta come see him.
You need to bring your dad
to the emergency room.
You know he won't do that.
You know
I'm getting married today.
This won't take long.
I promise.
Please, Will. He needs you.
All right,
let me get changed.
No, we don't have time.
Get the doc's stuff.
Come on, we'll drive you.
It'll be faster.
Come on.
Talk to me.
Knife in the upper chest.
GCS 12.
Passed out on the way in.
All right,
Trauma Two.
Minimal blood loss
in the field. BP 100/60.
86% on four liters.
How did this happen?
He broke into
some lady's house
and she stabbed him.
Ambo behind us is bringing
her in with a hand lac.
Not dressed
like a burglar.
More like a duffer
ready to tee off.
Ready? Let's go inside.
Let's transfer him
on my count.
Ready? One, two, three.
Okay, no breath sounds
on the right.
I need another 18 gauge line
in the chest tube
and let's get an AP
and a lateral chest X-ray
to see how deep
this knife goes.
Got it.
We got an ID on this guy?
No.
No, but we found this
in his pocket.
Can I see if I can get
an emergency contact off that?
Thank you.
Courtney, you're going to
Treatment Five.
The burglar's here,
too, isn't he?
Why was I brought
to the same hospital?
I assure you, ma'am,
you're completely safe.
Now please, walk me through
what happened again.
I was making breakfast
and then there he was
in the living room,
just rifling
through the cabinets.
Wait, where's my bag?
I have to call my husband.
I'll check the ambo.
Ready to transfer
on my count.
One, two, three.
Get it out.
Hello, Mrs. Young,
I'm Dr. Lanik.
How about I take a look
at that hand, hmm?
Please, can you call
my husband?
I have to make sure
he's okay.
His name is James.
James Young.
Calling him right now.
Here's her phone.
I'll take that.
Any luck
finding the husband?
Yeah.
That's him in Trauma Two,
the guy she stabbed.
What is this place?
One of my dad's
businesses.
Come on.
Pop?
The hell's he doing here?
I want him
to take a look at you.
Today? With everything
that's going on?
Yeah, Mr. Burke, I got a few
things going on today myself.
This can't take long.
Well, you're already here.
So okay.
Let's have you sit down.
Got a John Doe.
GCS 3, intubated in the field.
Going to Baghdad.
Okay, BP 90/60,
heart rate 140s,
sats 99%.
Took three bullets. One
to the head, two to the torso.
Looks like some kind of
targeted hit.
Trigger the MTP.
All right.
Let's get him over
on my count.
One, two, three.
There we go.
Roll him.
Got one
through-and-through.
Don't see a second
exit wound. Back?
Bilateral breath sounds.
Let's get a fast scan
for his chest and belly.
And the head shot?
Wound is tangential.
Looks like he caught a break.
There's a lot of fluid
around his heart.
Same in the belly.
I got to open him up.
Tell them to prep
the hybrid OR.
Stapler?
It's not that
I don't want to go.
Of course not.
I'm fond of both
Dr. Manning and Dr. Halstead.
I want them to be happy.
Me, too.
But is it wrong
that I'm just
a little cynical
about the whole
institution?
Sharon,
I'm thrice-divorced.
Remember, you're preaching
to the choir.
How about this?
Hit the reception,
kiss-kiss,
sneak out to a movie.
Sounds like a plan.
Excellent.
Sharon.
Hey.
Weren't you trying
to get out of here
early today?
Yeah, I mean as soon
as all this gets squared away.
Police can't seem
to figure out
who the heck the victim is.
No, no, no, you go do your
maid-of-honor thing.
I'll take care of it.
Okay, thank you so much.
Listen.
I thought this was
a straightforward case
of self-defense.
Nothing straight forward
about it. That woman
is a nut job.
This is your department,
not mine.
I'm telling you, it's not him.
I mean, yes, that man looks
just like my husband, but...
But he's an imposter.
Exactly.
And you can
tell them apart how?
It's all the little things.
Like the way
he buttons his shirt
and the way
he nods his head.
It's not James. It's not
the man I love.
Anything like this
ever happened before?
No? Have you ever been
medicated for your thinking?
For hearing stuff
other people don't?
You think I'm crazy,
don't you?
Ah, it's not
my favorite term.
I'm a particle researcher
at Fermilab.
I do the Times crossword
every Sunday
without any help from Google
and I am well past the age
of onset for schizophrenia.
So how about you stop
trying to figure out
what's wrong with me
and help me figure out
what that imposter did
with my husband.
I told you. I don't want
to press charges.
Well, you have my card
if you change your mind.
Mr. Young?
I'm Dr. Charles
and I just talked
to your wife.
Is she okay?
No one's letting me
see her.
Her hand is fine.
I'm just still...
I'm still trying
to figure out
why she stabbed you
in the first place.
We've been happily married
for 29 years.
I have no idea why
she would do this.
Any changes to her health
recently of any kind?
Yes, Amber was diagnosed
with a pituitary adenoma
a month ago.
It's pushing
against her brain.
I'm very sorry
to hear that.
How is her treatment going?
Is the tumor operable?
Her doctors advised
against the surgery
because of where
it was located.
They're trying to shrink it
using medication.
Would one of those
medications,
by any chance,
be bromocriptine?
How do you know?
Bromocriptine
significantly boosts
the dopamine in the brain,
and that very well
could have something to do
with Amber's delusion.
Delusion?
As strange
as it may sound,
your wife stabbed you
because, well,
she doesn't believe that
you are actually you.
She's under the delusion
that you've been replaced
by an imposter.
It's actually got a name,
too, in fact.
The Capgras delusion
and, well, imposter syndrome.
And this is all
a side effect
of the medication
she's taking?
I'm pretty sure
it is, yeah.
The doctor said her
medication's the only thing
keeping the tumor at bay.
What I want to do is put her
on a very mild antipsychotic
and I'd also like to have
one of our own neurosurgeons
review her scans.
Okay.
The longer a delusion lasts,
the harder it is to break.
Because this one
came on so suddenly,
I'm going to choose
to be optimistic
and I think that
you should, too.
Ethan is bringing
his ex to the wedding.
That doctor from the VA?
That sounds awkward.
That would make me insane.
If I were April, I wouldn't...
Doris, I can hear you.
Hmm?
We're just worried
about you, is all.
Don't be. I'm going
with Noah instead.
Okay.
April?
And we are going to
tear up the dance floor.
Okay.
Fire up the ultrasound,
would you?
So how long have you been
in labor, Lisa?
A couple of hours, maybe?
But the baby's not due
for three more weeks.
We decided to come
to Chicago as a mini-vacation
before the baby came,
but then this happened.
Let's check
how far along you are.
Okay, so you're
really, really far along.
Nine centimeters?
Nope, fully dilated.
Ultrasound ready?
Yeah.
Ooh!
It's okay.
What?
What is it?
Your baby is
in a breech position.
It's upside down.
The baby is going
to be okay though, right?
We want to send you up
for a C-section.
I'll let OB know
we're on our way up.
Thanks.
It's gonna be fine.
I just felt something move!
Just breathe.
Okay, tell OB we need them
down here stat.
Lisa, your baby's coming
bottom first.
I can feel one leg
and not the other.
It's in
a very difficult position.
We don't have time
to go to the OR.
This baby has to be
delivered right here now.
Looks like a bullet
entered and exited
through the apex
of the left ventricle.
Heart's still beating,
but it looks empty.
This guy's a train wreck.
BP's dropping.
He's about to code.
All right, you got
a cross-clamp?
Here, do what I'm doing.
Clamp.
All right.
Pressure's better.
His belly's distended.
It's full of blood.
Give me a knife.
Got to find what's bleeding.
Page Dr. Bekker.
I need an extra set of hands.
Okay.
Extend your arms out
in front of you.
Palms up.
We done now?
You fell again, Pop.
It could be serious.
Joey?
Stop with the shredder.
It's giving me a headache.
How long have
you had the headache, Ray?
Eh, who knows?
Close your eyes.
Okay, relax.
Yeah, you have
some pronator drift.
It means your brain's
balance system is off,
which is consistent with
what we found on your MRI.
So the scans show old
subdural hematomas.
Hi, Tom.
What's he doing here?
I brought him here
to check on Pop.
You know what?
Good, good.
I swept the house.
Found this.
A bug?
How the hell did it get there?
I got a pretty good idea.
Agent Lee,
what the hell's going on?
Have you heard
from your brother?
No, not since
last night.
He wasn't answering his phone,
so we tracked it to here.
Found it
in the changing room.
Tailor said
he left in a hurry
with someone who fits
the description of Tim Burke.
Put out
an investigative alert.
I'm going to their house.
Already done.
Tim's not there.
None of them are.
We're fairly certain
Ray's found out
he's been under surveillance.
Do you know
where they are?
No.
I thought you flipped some guy
in Burke's organization?
We did, Shawn Corcoran.
But we can't reach him either.
Hey, Jay, I'm not sure
what you guys are up to,
but I'm thinking that
maybe Will lost
his phone or something
because he hasn't
returned my calls.
So if you could just
have him call me back,
that would be great.
Okay, thanks.
Honey, Will knows that
the photographer wants us
at St. Ursula's,
4:30, right?
I told you, Mom,
he's going to meet us there.
Okay.
Hey, there.
There she is.
Yeah.
No answer?
No, and if it was
just Will not answering,
it'd be fine,
but Jay, too?
I mean, what if they got into
an accident or something?
Oh, you really need to stop.
Maggie, I...
Look, your mother
just opened
a perfectly good
bottle of champagne.
Don't let it
go to waste. Come.
You know, I just...
I really don't have
a good feeling about this.
I mean, Will has been
so stressed lately.
You know, I'm gonna try him
just one more time.
No, you won't.
Just to be sure.
Natalie,
you're the one that
made a charge nurse
your maid of honor.
So this is what
you're gonna do.
You're gonna stop
freaking out
and you're gonna let
these ladies
turn you into
the most beautiful
bride ever.
Phone.
Yeah, and there's
the other arm.
Okay, Lisa, just give me
one more push.
I can't push any harder.
Yes, you can.
Breathe.
Dr. Patchefsky sent this
delivery tray down in advance.
Said she was on her way.
On her way?
Maybe 20 minutes or so.
Look, I don't have 20 minutes.
Yeah, I'll let her know.
What's happening now?
The head's entrapped.
I can't get it.
It won't flex.
Forceps.
Heart rate's
down in the 90s.
What does that mean?
The baby's just
a little in distress.
Her heart rate's dropping.
Come on, come on, come on.
Decels down to 75.
Okay, okay.
Breathe.
You're doing great.
Decels 63.
I think it's coming.
Yes.
Yes. There.
Okay.
Congratulations.
It's a baby girl.
Her head is so big.
That often happens
in delivery.
It's called molding.
Congratulations.
Nicely done.
You, too.
Dr. Choi,
something's happening.
Why is she shaking like that?
She's having a seizure.
Get me a neonate resuscitation
cart and 0.3 milligrams
of diazepam.
What's wrong with her?
We're going to find out.
I don't like this.
Tell me again,
tell me where
you're taking me?
Well, you took
the medication about
an hour ago, right?
So what are you
expecting to happen
aside from me feeling
a little sleepy?
Let's see, let's just
call it an experiment.
Amber, sweetie.
Oh, my God. I was
so worried about you.
What are you doing here?
What happened to you?
Amber,
you actually
did this to James.
You stabbed him.
You didn't know it was him.
What? No,
I stabbed an intruder.
It was me.
I would never do that.
You know
I would never...
I know. I know. I know.
It's not your fault.
I don't understand.
You experienced
a very rare side effect
from the medication
you're taking to control
the tumor in your brain.
It made you think that James
was somebody else,
an imposter.
He doesn't appear
that way to me now.
Well, that's because
I gave you a very mild
antipsychotic
to control the delusion.
So problem solved?
I told you.
Everything's going to be
all right.
Honey, are you okay?
Amber, what's the matter?
Amber!
Can I get a little help here?
A little help, please?
What's happening with my wife?
I've been racking my brain
as to how this bug got there.
Gotta agree with Tom.
You're the only person
who could've planted it.
That day
you gave me the EKG.
I could tell
you were nervous.
Ray, I swear I have never
seen that thing before.
I can't tell you how
disappointed I am.
I don't know
what to tell you.
Just know that while
I was treating you,
I was the best doctor
I could be.
That sounds like
a confession to me.
I wanted to give you
the MRI results.
You wouldn't answer
my calls.
Stop changing
the subject.
Listen to me, Ray,
you're slurring
your words.
Your balance is off...
That's enough.
We need to get you in
immediately to see
a neurosurgeon.
Stop.
You're not getting
yourself out of this.
Hey, Pop.
Not now, Tommy.
I'm busy.
What do you mean
he's in the hospital?
You said Corcoran
wasn't gonna be a problem.
I just found out myself.
I thought it'd been
taken care of.
We're not done here.
I want answers.
Throwing my last stitch now.
Let me know when I can remove
the cross-clamp.
Give me a second.
I'm still trying to locate
the source of this bleed.
Got it. Left kidney.
Metz?
All right.
There we go.
Clotting is still good.
I think we've got time
to close him up and
move him upstairs.
All right,
Number 1 Vicryl to me
and a looped monofilament
to Dr. Rhodes.
Dr. Rhodes, is your patient
stable at the moment?
I need to speak to you.
He is, but now's
not a good time, Jay.
This really can't wait.
I'll be done in an hour.
We can talk then.
Now, Connor. Right now.
What?
I need to speak
with your patient
as soon as possible.
Jay, you can't just
come in here
and interfere
with my surgery...
He's a material witness
in an ongoing investigation.
I don't care who he is.
Well, you need to.
His name is Shawn Corcoran
and the guys that shot him,
they're going to do
the same thing to Will
if I can't find him.
Will? What are you
talking about?
I can't get into the details,
but Will is missing
and this guy is our only lead
into where he might be.
This guy has just been
through a huge surgery.
I am really
not comfortable
waking him up
before he's ready.
I don't care, Connor.
Look,
even if I stop what I am doing
and lighten his sedation,
there is no guarantee
that he's going to be able
to communicate with you.
I'm sorry.
I get that it's a long shot.
I don't know what else to do.
I need your help.
All right, change of plans.
Let's pack, leave him open,
and get to the ICU.
I thought you wanted
to close and be done.
I reconsidered.
Patient's lost too much blood.
Best to get out and come back
another day.
Let's get
an abdominal VAC.
You guys got this?
Yeah.
So you just
changed your mind?
Yeah.
And that had nothing to do
with the conversation
you just had with Jay.
I don't like being
blind-sided like that
in the middle of the OR
and I really don't like
you shutting me out.
Trust me, it is better
you not knowing.
Why would you say that?
Because, Ava, if...
If something goes wrong,
you're going to want
deniability.
We're supposed to be
a team, Connor.
Fine. Let's talk in here.
Temp 102. Pulse 140s.
BP?
I don't know.
The reading's
all over the map.
160 over 101.
88 over 59.
Maybe I need
a different cuff.
No, it's labile.
What's happening to me?
You're having an adverse
reaction to the antipsychotic.
Okay, start a new IV.
Five liters of O2 bi-mask.
125 of dantrolene.
What? Does that mean that
the antipsychotic
doesn't work?
Based on the way
you're reacting,
I'd say, probably not.
But what about the delusion?
It'll likely return.
Here, I need you to breathe
into this, okay?
Tell the neurosurgeon to do
whatever he has to do
to take out the tumor.
Why don't we discuss this
after you're stabilized?
No, because
I'm clearheaded now.
I want the surgery.
You hereby have my consent.
Amber, your doctors have
advised against it.
It could kill you.
Even if the delusion
never goes away,
you could live
a long life.
We can figure out a way
for you and your husband
to coexist.
I don't want to coexist.
I want to love him.
Is our baby okay?
Did they say
when we'd be able
to bring her home?
I'm sure the doctors can
answer all of your questions.
We decided
to name the baby Esther.
It was Kevin's
grandmother's name.
It's very pretty.
Here she is.
Lisa, Kevin.
This is Dr. Watkins.
She's a neonatologist.
Hello.
How is she?
Mr. and Mrs. Jensen,
we've done some tests
on your daughter.
Your baby has something called
a Vein of Galen malformation.
It's a misconnection between
the arteries and the veins.
And that's why she had
the seizure?
Yes, in this case,
it caused a hemorrhage
that irritated the brain.
So you're saying she's sick.
What can you do
to fix her?
Normally, we could embolize
some of the vessels.
But I'm afraid the specific
anatomy of where they are
doesn't make that possible.
I don't understand.
It's not operable
and the bleeding
will only get worse.
We don't expect she'll survive
more than a day at this rate.
No. No. No!
Our baby's gonna die?
I'm afraid so.
I am so sorry.
There's a private room
next door.
We'll have her transferred
so you can be alone
with your daughter.
Pop! Go get Will!
No!
Get him now!
All right!
I got this!
Come here.
What's going on?
Now.
He just collapsed.
What the hell are we
supposed to do?
Check him out, Will.
Ray, can you
open your eyes?
I need a flashlight.
Your phone.
Oh, God.
His left pupil's sluggish.
Ray, did you hit your head?
He's unconscious.
It's getting worse.
What does that mean?
He's not responding
anymore.
There's a bleed in his head
putting pressure on his brain.
We have to get him
to the hospital now.
Call an ambulance.
Can't you fix him here?
You're kidding me. No.
The pressure in his skull
needs to be released.
Maybe we should take him
to the hospital, Tommy.
Don't be an idiot, okay?
Hospitals mean police.
Look, Pop is lying here.
No, no, no.
I'm making this decision.
Figure something out.
Now.
All right. I'm gonna need
a few things.
Then do it.
Oh...
I don't know
how much longer
I can work around
not having
a groom or best man.
Well, just take pictures
of the bride's family.
I don't have
a bride either.
Okay, we're...
We're working on it.
Hey. Come on.
Let's go get our
picture taken together.
I don't believe this.
Will was supposed
to be here an hour ago.
Is he standing me up?
No, no.
I'm convinced
that there's...
There's a logical
explanation to this.
Like what, Maggie?
I'm sorry.
It's just, for the last month,
he has been so secretive.
Keeping things from me.
I think he's backing out.
Oh, my God.
Oh, my God,
all these people coming.
Breathe.
Am I gonna have to cancel...
No.
Am I gonna have to
cancel the wedding?
No. Give me a second,
and let me see if I can get
to the bottom of this.
It's gonna be fine.
Okay, turn around
and sit down.
Okay.
Go ahead.
Do the same
with the bit.
It'll be okay, Pop.
Now just stay calm.
All right,
pass me the drill.
How... How do you know
where to put the hole?
His MRI, the hematoma
was just about here.
It's just about?
What, are you guessing?
You want certainties?
Let me bring him in.
Will...
You better guess right.
Could you stop
pointing that at me?
It's best if my hands
aren't shaking.
Tim.
I need you to hold his head
as still as you can.
There you go.
If I go too deep, he's dead.
My God.
What did you do to him?
What did you do to him, Will?
You're all right, Pop.
You're going to be all right.
Temp's down to 99
and her BP is normalizing.
Thanks, Tanya.
How long till you think
she's stable enough
for surgery?
A couple hours, but
take a look at these scans.
Tumor's invading
her cavernous sinus.
There's a hell of a lot of
blood vessels and nerves
that pass through there.
If you were to predict
the likelihood of success...
On a scale
of one to 10, it sucks.
Luckily, you're looking at
the one guy in Chicago
who might be able
to pull it off.
I understand your patient
Amber Young wants to have
an inoperable
adenoma removed?
Inoperable according
to her primary surgeons.
Sam here says he can do it.
Ah, not so fast.
No.
I'm not okaying this until
I hear it from her directly.
I don't know
if that's gonna be possible.
She won't recognize you.
If you do this surgery,
she can die.
Nope. I'm not gonna
allow this.
With all due respect
Mr. Young,
legally, it's not
your decision to make.
Just so we understand
each other,
I've already spoken
with my lawyer.
Understood.
She completely
understood the risks.
I can't just unhear that.
Are you absolutely certain
that her Capgras
has not impacted
her decisional capacity?
Look, I've been making
these evaluations
for 30 years.
Sharon, I'm between a rock
and a hard place here.
I completely understand
his point of view,
but I'm legally and morally
bound to honor her wishes.
I'm sorry, Daniel.
I can't open the hospital
to a potential lawsuit.
Without the husband's consent,
it's not gonna happen.
You sure we can't
keep him here?
He has a hole in his head.
He's at risk of infection.
He needs an ICU
and antibiotics.
Easy.
Where do you think
you're going?
To the hospital.
I gotta tell the doctors
what we're looking at.
No.
Tommy, I swear,
I'm not gonna say a word
about this to anyone.
Stay here.
Clean this up.
Wait!
Tell the doctors he has
a history of subdural
hematomas.
If they need to,
they can call Med for the MRI,
and keep him sitting up.
April.
Hello.
Where are Kevin and Lisa?
They left.
But their baby's still alive.
They just left her?
How could they do that?
They said it would be
too painful to watch her die.
So you spoke with them,
and you let them leave?
I would've stopped them
if I could.
How can they just
abandon their child?
They experienced
a tragedy, April,
and they couldn't cope
with it,
and there's no law
to make them stay.
This isn't right.
No.
But there's nothing
we can do.
I'm sorry.
This baby's gonna die alone.
She'll be on the monitors, and
nursing will check in on her.
No, that's not
what I mean.
You know that.
She is alone.
April, do you
want me to stay?
Go.
Dr. Rhodes!
I'm Mary Corcoran,
Shawn's wife.
When can I see him?
I'm sorry,
Mrs. Corcoran,
but your husband's
still in critical condition.
We're certainly
not out of the woods yet.
Then why was he taken
out of surgery?
Um...
We could only keep
your husband on the table
for so long.
We did as much as we could,
and then we had to give
his body some time to recover.
Now, hopefully, tomorrow
we'll take him
back to surgery,
and we'll close him up.
I have to run.
I'm very sorry, but someone
will come out and get you
as soon as he's stable.
We're running out of time.
I gotta talk to this guy.
I'm not sure
how stable he is yet.
You really want
to wake him up?
You got something
he can write on?
Mr. Corcoran, I'm
Detective Jay Halstead.
I gotta ask you
a few questions, okay?
Turn around.
You don't have to
do this, Tim.
You know that.
Yes, I do.
Turn around.
No.
You don't think
I'll do it? I will.
I swear I will.
This isn't who you are.
Shut up!
Shut up.
You don't know me.
I know you.
We grew up together.
Please, don't.
Shut up!
Will, are you all right?
You okay?
Call an ambulance.
This is 21 George. Emergency
shots fired by the police.
Offender down.
Call an ambo
to our location.
We're good.
Let's go.
Clear the building.
Do we know what hospital
Ray was taken to?
Did you get the license
of the car they were driving?
No.
Can this wait?
We can still make it
to the church.
Come on.
What is it that you guys
aren't telling me?
Dr. Rhodes?
Detective Halstead asked me
to forward a message.
He says it's all good.
Said you'd know
what that means.
I do. Thanks.
Dr. Rhodes, your patient...
What happened?
Chest tube started
dumping blood.
Repair must have blown.
He's still asystolic.
Push another round of epi.
He's already had four.
There's nothing
we can do, Connor.
No...
Time of death, 18:43.
Oh, I'm so sorry.
His blood pressure spiked.
He came off the Diprivan
pretty hard.
Hey. Hey.
You didn't really have
a choice, Connor.
How you feeling?
Like I was hit by a truck.
There is somebody outside
who I think might make you
feel a little better.
Your husband.
James.
Hey, hon.
How you feeling?
You okay?
You remember James.
You look good.
That's not my husband.
Honey, please.
I thought you said
my husband was here.
Sweetheart,
don't you see? It's me.
It's not you!
You are not my husband!
No!
Get away from me!
That is not my husband!
You are not my husband!
It's okay. It's okay.
That is not my...
He's gone. He's gone.
It's okay.
James, I'm so sorry
that that...
It didn't go the way
that we wanted it to.
Don't be.
You know how Amber and I met?
It was April of '87.
On a whim, I drove up
by myself to Pontiac
to catch a U2 concert.
Scalped a nosebleed seat.
Amber had done the same.
The moment I saw her,
I knew.
Over 50,000 people,
and I wind up sitting
next to my soulmate.
What are the odds of that?
This won't stop us
from being together.
Maybe her tumor
will go into remission.
We'll find a way.
I thought I was gonna be late.
Oh...
No.
I heard somebody say
the groom got delayed.
Oh...
What you got there?
Rice?
Millet.
They say it's better
for the birdies.
I brought enough
for you, too.
Since when did you get
so sentimental?
Thank you, thank you,
thank you.
Natalie, it's Will!
He's here. He's here.
Will? Where?
Right outside.
Will?
Oh, my God.
Natalie!
I didn't know what to think.
I know. I'm so sorry.
I'm so sorry.
Are you bleeding?
No, it's not mine.
What happened?
Where were you?
There's so much
I need to tell you.
Dr. Halstead,
we really need to go.
"Go"? Go where?
What is she talking about?
They're taking me into
protective custody.
What? No!
Will, come on.
No!
Jay, one minute.
Will... No.
I'll explain everything
as soon as I can.
Will...
I love you, Natalie.
Jay, what is happening?
I'm sorry.