So now the plan is either
find ourselves a new counselor,
stick it out with the old
one, but go more often,
or resign ourselves to the fact
that she's never gonna be happy...
no matter what I do, so
let's take the money we're
wasting and put it towards
a membership at Lakeview.
I'm guessing the last option has
yet to be formally presented. Yeah.
Geez. What's with you? You
usually run half speed to stay with me.
Didn't get a lot
of sleep last night.
How are things
with Elyse? Great.
Great? Yeah.
One-syllable answers. You're either
out of breath, or you're lying to me.
Yeah. We have our moments,
but they usually work out.
Man, you got some water? Yeah.
So how do you work things out?
I don't know. We talk,
someone apologizes.
Man, I shouldn't
have drank last night.
- Hey, you mean you apologize.
- Yeah, I guess.
- How often do you guys have sex?
- Enough.
You do it this morning?
You did. You did
it this morning.
Maybe that's why you can't
stand up, huh? Come on.
Elyse.
Great.
Honey, I'm dehydrated.
Do we have anything
with electrolytes?
Sleeping Beauty, wake up.
This is an emergency.
The fridge is empty.
Come on. It's almost 4:00.
Elyse. Sweetie.
Call Jacques. Tell
him I'm not feeling well.
It's Saturday. You haven't been
to work in three days. Remember?
Just let me sleep.
Come on. You haven't been
out of bed since Wednesday.
- Leave me alone.
- Come on. What's up?
No. Leave me alone.
Honey. I said leave me alone!
Oh. I think there's
something wrong with me.
She's been averaging 18 hours
of sleep a day since her admission.
Clinical depression.
Incredibly contagious.
Every time I'm around one of them,
I get blue. It's not clinical depression.
Great. Got it all figured
out. You don't need me.
Three E.R. doctors,
two neurologists and a
radiologist have all
figured out what it's not.
We need to figure out what it is. If
any of the above-mentioned doctors...
were interested in my opinion,
they would have asked for it.
None of them are willing to
subject themselves to you.
No pain, no gain.
The blood work shows
no signs of inflammation,
and no one can figure out
what's actually the cause— Ah.
What? Husband described her
as being unusually irritable recently.
And? I didn't realize it was possible
for a woman to be unusually irritable.
Nice try, but you're a
misanthrope, not a misogynist.
What's the first thing you ask a
doctor who's referring a patient?
Are you questioning my
ability to take a history?
What's the primary—
Not "what." "Why?"
Diseases don't have
motives. No, but doctors do.
Why this patient?
What interests you?
Give me the chart. Why?
I find your
interest interesting.
She's irritable and
sleeping 18 hours a day.
What's interesting about that?
Hypersomnia's usually accompanied
by irritability in depressed patients.
True, but not relevant.
She's not depressed.
Hello. She's sleeping
18 hours a day. Fever.
Clinical depression
does not cause fever.
- She could be sick and depressed.
- She's sick.
Oh, damn it. Why
didn't I think of that?
- Yeah, that's what I meant.
- Elevated sed rate indicates inflammation.
Hypersomnia and personality
changes point toward the brain.
Not the spleen?
Thank goodness we
hired a neurologist.
Brain symptoms. Hmm.
Could this be a brain problem?
No other systemic signs of
inflammation. Probably not vasculitis.
What about parasites?
Malaria, Chagas.
But the patient's never been outside of
the United States—especially the tropics.
- You mean she claims
she's never been outside the U.S.
- Very good.
Doesn't matter. Blood and C.S. F.
Smears show no sign of parasites.
- Has to be a tumor then.
- A tumor sitting directly
on top of the brain stem...
that three E. R. doctors, two
neurologists and a radiologist missed?
Partridge in a pear
tree missed it too.
Redo the blood work,
and get a new M.R.I. with
two-millimeter cuts through
the mesodiencephalic.
And check for evil stepmothers.
This much sleep usually
indicates poison apples.
Anything else besides
the shortness of breath?
Not really. It's actually
just kind of a tightness.
You smoke? No, never.
- Exercise?
- Eight hours a day.
- I teach preschool.
- Sounds fun.
Any history of heart
disease in your family?
Not that I know of.
Take a deep breath.
Been under a lot of stress
lately? No more than usual.
You're probably
just a little anemic.
I'm gonna do an
E.K.G. just to make sure.
Do I need to take this off? Uh, no.
You can just pull that down in front.
Good Lord.
- Are those real?
- Do they look real?
They look pretty damn good.
They were a present
for my husband's 40th.
I figured he'd enjoy
them more than a sweater.
That's so sweet.
But I'm afraid the cause of your problem
could be staring us right in the face.
Actually, I guess I'm
the one doing the staring.
Of course, I can't be sure.
I'd like to consult a colleague.
He's actually somewhat of
an expert in these matters.
Can I get a page on Dr. Wilson?
A tumor? We don't know.
- We're checking just to be safe.
- Y'all already checked for that.
The previous M.R.I. had a broader
view. Some tumors are almost
impossible to see unless you
know exactly where to look.
- That means it would be small, right?
- Yeah.
Then you'd be able
to operate, take it out?
If it's a tumor, there are a
variety of treatment options,
but there are variables
other than just size.
Don't worry.
Too late.
Try to remain as
still as possible.
The less distortion there is, the
more detail we'll be able to see. Okay.
X-ray tech, report
to Radiology Room 3.
Well. That's what
breasts look like.
Is a lie a lie if everybody
knows it's a lie?
Well, if a tree pretends to fall in a
forest— House, come on. They're breasts.
They're a birthday present, not a
philosophical treatise. Lie number one.
She did not do that for her
husband. She did that for herself.
She thinks if she looks
different, she'll be different.
No. She thinks if she
looks different, she'll
be more attractive,
which I have to say...
Not to her husband. Cosmetic surgery is so
everyone else will look at us differently.
The same reason
you're wearing that tie.
Well, exactly. That was
gonna be my next point.
Last three months,
same five ties.
Thursday should
be that paisley thing.
It's a gift from my
wife. No, it's not.
Julie hates green. You
bought that yourself.
You want to look pretty at work.
Wilson's got a girlfriend.
D—Stop.
Stop. I don't.
It takes two department heads
to treat shortness of breath?
What, do the complications
increase exponentially with cup size?
I want an E.K.G. and blood
tests, including tox screen on Mrs...
- Exam Room One.
- You're ordering tests
to cover your lechery.
- Interesting.
- Very tricky case.
You love everybody.
That's your pathology.
There were no lesions and no
mass effect that we could see.
What does that mean?
It means we're still not sure what's
causing the neurological problems.
I know some things
are hard to cure,
but what I just don't
get is why it's taking
so long to figure out
what's wrong with her.
- I know you're scared. I would be too.
- I don't feel good.
You feeling nauseous?
Honey, are you all right?
She's seizing!
Get her on her side.
- I need some Ativan!
- I'll get it.
- What's happened?
- She's having a seizure.
She's aspirating. Suction.
Come on, Elyse.
The M.R.I. reveals nothing.
- That we were able to detect.
- It's not a tumor.
A small glioma could hide from
contrast. We could do a PET scan.
Yes. That's how a responsible doctor
would waste his time in this situation.
Suddenly tests and radiologists
are incapable of error?
A glioma not presenting
on a contrast M.R.I.
would have to be smaller
than a grain of sand,
which does not a
gravely ill person make.
- It could be just postictal disorientation.
- We would have seen
improvement by now.
- Late-stage Lyme disease
can cause seizures.
- Does the husband care about her?
- He hasn't left her bedside.
- How annoying.
It also means she doesn't
have Lyme disease.
What, love conquers all?
Lyme disease initially
presents with a rash.
- Mr. Clingy would have noticed.
- We've looked at everything else.
Did you look at her breasts?
Men.
It could be paraneoplastic.
She have any family
history of breast cancer?
Her mother died of it.
The brain, but not the brain.
Clever, huh?
How can breast cancer
cause problems in her brain?
There are molecular similarities
between brain cells and tumor cells.
Paraneoplastic syndrome causes the body's
own antibodies to get thrown off track.
They end up attacking the
brain instead of the tumor.
So, if you do find a
tumor, what do you do?
We treat the
underlying malignancy.
Once there's no tumor
to attack, there's nothing
for the antibodies to
get confused about.
- If the tumor's treatable.
- Exactly.
Ow. I'm sorry. I know
it's uncomfortable.
The tighter we go, the
better the image will be.
At least it'll keep me awake.
Don't worry. It's almost over.
I wish people would stop
telling me not to worry.
I'm sorry.
My mom was the same age.
We've been trying to get pregnant for
over a year. Guess we're lucky we didn't.
A lot has changed
since your mom died.
Don't worr...
Don't give up.
No tumor?
The M.R.I. and the mammogram
only showed a few benign calcifications.
It's most likely a
small-cell tumor.
It's no surprise we're
having trouble finding it.
We should do a PET scan. Start
with her lungs, then maybe her bones.
Sometimes it presents
with no tumor at all.
- How can a disease caused by a tumor
present if there's no tumor?
- It happens—12% of cases.
- And how do you treat it
if there's no tumor?
- You don't.
Those 12%, no treatment.
They were too busy
looking for the tumor...
Right till they put the
patient in the ground.
- What choice do we have?
- Treat the symptoms.
- I.V. immunoglobulin.
- So we're just gonna ignore the tumor?
Well, eventually it'll get bigger.
Then it'll be really easy to find.
- One of you needs to check out
where she works.
- Why?
- 'Cause the husband's not sick.
- Meaning?
If it’s not paraneoplastic, and it
is a reaction to some sort of toxin,
it's obviously not
coming from their home.
Foreman, you do it.
Why are you riding
me? It's what I do.
Has it got worse lately?
Yeah. Seems to me.
Really?
Well, that rules out the race thing.
'Cause you were just as black last week.
How long has Elyse worked here?
Oh, three years.
She's my best rôtisseur.
And what's that? The rôtisseur
prepares the roasted meats and gravies.
How do you clean your grill?
You say “elbow grease." Do
you use chemical cleaners?
Ah, non. Absolument. And chefs
don't do the cleaning anyway.
What about pesticides? You must
spray for roaches and that sort of thing.
No. My kitchen is
clean. No roaches.
I need to get back to work.
So the fact that I'm here asking you
these questions, it doesn't worry you?
Look at me. I'm
here 18 hours a day.
That guy practically lives
here. He does live here.
I use the same detergents for 15
years, and everyone is healthy as a horse.
Whatever Elyse has,
she didn't get here.
Tell her I hope
she feels better.
And I had to get
a new rôtisseur.
- Where's Ed?
- He went down to the gift shop
to buy a shirt.
I told him I'd stay up
here in case you woke up.
You must have
better things to do.
I send my laundry out.
- You're not married?
- No.
Waiting for the perfect guy?
Let me guess. You've
already found him.
He threw my towels
out the window.
That's how we met.
Freshman year, Ed came to a
party that my roommate and I threw.
He spent most of the
night on the bathroom floor.
He figured I wouldn't notice the vomit
on the towels if I didn't have any towels.
I'm assuming he came back
the next day to apologize?
No way. I had to track him down.
Conflict resolution has never
been one of Ed's strong points.
Nobody's perfect, right?
I guess.
Oh, my neck hurts.
You've been in this
bed for a really long time.
We're gonna do the same test we did last
night, okay? Do you know what day it is?
My arm itches. It's
probably a mild skin irritation.
I'll get you some
hydrocortisone in a minute.
- Do you know what day it is?
- Tuesday.
It really itches.
How about I get you
that cream right now?
Oh, my God! Get them
off! Get 'em off of me!
- Get 'em off me! Get 'em off me!
- Elyse, calm down.
- Get them off me!
- Elyse, calm down. Calm down.
They're biting me!
Oh! They're biting me!
I'm gonna need some
Haldol, five milligrams.
- Honey, what's wrong?
- Get 'em off!
Get 'em off. Get 'em off.
There's nothing there, Elyse.
They're biting me.
There's nothing there.
Ow!
We had to sedate her.
You gave sedatives to a patient
who's already sleeping 18 hours a day?
It was better than letting her
scratch all the skin off her arms.
- Where's Wilson?
- Creepy-crawlies are consistent
with paraneoplastic syndrome.
Onset immediately
after I.V.I.G. isn't.
There is a simple explanation.
Maybe she really has
bugs under her skin.
- Infection?
- That's what a worsening of symptoms
after immunotherapy would suggest.
Blood cultures and the
timeline rule out most bacteria.
Patient throws up on your
shoes, do you clean up most of it?
The symptoms rule out the
rest. Serology rules out viruses.
C.S.F. smears
rule out parasites.
In the final stage of
African trypanosomiasis...
almost all the parasites
are inside the brain.
It's possible they
wouldn't show on smears.
But it's not possible
for a patient who's never
been to Africa to have
African sleeping sickness.
- I'm just saying it fits the symptoms.
- She could've got it from a transfusion.
- Or I'm just saying she could've
got it from a transfusion.
- Which she never had.
Okay. What about toxins?
No, the kitchen she works in
is cleaner than some hospitals.
But they do serve rabbit.
Rabbit fever fits her symptoms.
Tularemia initially presents with a
rash or ulcer near the infection site.
Not if she inhaled it.
Chopping the meat with
the cleaver could easily
aerosolize the bacteria.
- No. Then she'd have respiratory symptoms.
- Maybe she ignored it,
figured she had a cold.
We rejected Lyme disease because
the couple would have noticed a rash,
but a wet, hacking cough
is just gonna slip right by?
It's either that or she missed her exit
on the turnpike and wound up in Africa.
Okay, two lousy ideas.
Unfortunately, they're
better than all the other ideas.
Tularemia. Bizarre.
Very nice. That's
why I ride you.
Stay tuned— Did he
just turn on the TV?
He needs to think.
So this should tell us whether
or not she's got rabbit fever?
For a diagnosis of tularemia you need a
fourfold increase in serum antibody levels.
To measure an increase you need
a before. All we have is an after.
- A single titer over 160
would be a big clue.
- "That's why I ride you."
What does that mean? When I
have a good idea it's because of him?
Actually, I think he said
your idea was a lousy idea.
It has to be one of these
two conditions. I say we
take our best guess and
start treatment. Or treat both.
The treatment for tularemia
can cause aplastic anemia.
- How come he doesn't ride you guys?
- Got a crush on you.
- He just doesn't know how to show it.
- Get over it. He rides everybody.
- The treatment for sleeping sickness
kills one in 10 patients.
- We start with the safer treatment.
By "safer," you mean the one
that's slightly less likely to kill her.
Foreman got the gang
testing for tularemia?
- Yep.
- Probably inconclusive, but worth doing.
So, what's her name?
When do I get to meet her?
- There's nobody. Give it up.
- Your lips say no.
Your shoes say yes.
Well, they're French.
- You can't trust a word they say.
- Solid, yet stylish.
A professional woman
would be impressed.
I'm thinking accountant.
Actuary maybe.
It's somebody in the hospital.
Patient?
No. Chemo's not sexy.
Daughter of a patient.
She would certainly have
the neediness you need.
I'm not gonna date
a patient's daughter.
Very ethical. Of course, most married
men would say they don't date at all.
There was no date.
I had lunch with
one of the nurses.
It's her first time in an oncology unit.
She's having a tough time— emotionally.
- Perfect.
- I wanted to be nice.
That's all. I mean it.
You always do. It's
part of your charm.
Hi, boys.
Mrs. Campbell's test results.
You remember her. The preschool
teacher with the heart of silicone.
No. Doesn't ring a bell.
They came in yesterday. I
figured you guys would have
been all over them. I know
how concerned you were.
She's all upset 'cause we paid
more attention to the other girl.
You check out her
ass. I've got the chest.
The tests were normal. Of
course, that's just my opinion.
You might wanna call a couple of
guys from maintenance in for a consult.
You check her E.K.G. results
before she left the other day?
- You ordered it.
- You're the responsible one.
- What's wrong? They look normal to me.
- Where is she?
- Waiting downstairs. Why?
- I was right.
Do I have to get
rid of the implants?
Surprisingly, no.
But your E.K.G. shows a
slightly decreased heart rate.
Is that a problem?
You told me you hadn't
changed your diet or
exercise. Were you lying?
Lying? Does your husband
have high blood pressure?
My husband? Yeah, you see,
if you're gonna
repeat everything I say,
this conversation's
gonna take twice as long.
Yes. He was diagnosed
six months ago.
He do a lot of cooking? Not really,
other than oatmeal in the morning.
Did you happen to notice a slightly
odd taste to the oatmeal lately?
Wait. Are you saying that—
That it looks like your husband...
stirred in some of his blood pressure
medication along with the brown sugar.
You think my husband's trying to
poison me? No. Nothing like that.
He just doesn't want
to have sex with you.
Decreased sex drive is
one of the most common side
effects of the beta-blockers
he's been taking.
I'm guessing he figured if you're
both frigid, no harm, no foul.
Should've gotten him the
sweater. That's ridiculous.
Fine. But if you're still
concerned about the shortness
of breath, I'd start
making your own breakfast.
Wait.
What should I do?
If you care about your husband
at all, I'd do the responsible thing.
Buy yourself some
condoms, go to a bar, find...
Huh.
Lab tests inconclusive?
Not surprisingly.
No. But too bad.
Luckily, I have the answer.
- To what?
- Thanks for asking.
To life itself: sex. Anything
that can be transmitted
via the blood can be
transmitted through sex.
- Sleeping sickness from sex?
- It's not without precedent.
I'm pretty sure it is,
unless you're talking about
going to Africa and
having sex with a tsetse fly.
A Portuguese man was
diagnosed three years
ago with C.N.S.-affected
sleeping sickness.
His only connection
with Africa was through a
girlfriend who'd served
with the military in Angola.
Boy. Where'd you find that?
The Journal of the Instituto
de Higiene e Medicina Tropical.
- You don't read Portuguese?
- You do?
Pretty sure that's what it said. Either
that or it was an ad for sunglasses.
Her husband has never
been to Africa either.
Oh, stymied again.
Your logic is bulletproof.
I think ignoring respiratory
symptoms is more likely than cheating.
Because? They're completely
devoted to each other.
Because? They love each other.
Or?
They're
overcompensating for guilt.
- Find out which it is.
- You want me to ask a man whose wife
is about to die if he cheated on her?
No, I want you to be
polite and let her die.
Actually, I don't want
you to ask her anything.
Foreman, take the husband.
Chase, take the wife.
You don't trust me to do my job?
We all formulate questions based
on the answers we want to hear.
And how exactly do you reformulate
"Have you screwed around?"
Did you know she's been
trying to get pregnant? Yes.
After you got so freaked
about the sick babies
a while ago, I figured
that was your thing.
But you've never been
prescribed folic acid, and
you can't lose a baby if
you've never been pregnant.
You pulled my medical records? You
coughed the other day. I was concerned.
You were curious, like an
eight-year-old boy with a puzzle
that's just a little too
grown-up for him to figure out.
Tomayto, tomahto.
So it's either, uh, sleeping
sickness or this rabbit thing?
They're both fatal
without treatment.
And unfortunately, the treatment
for both is extremely dangerous.
Are there tests you can
do? Not at this stage.
But each condition
has a unique history.
We're hoping your answers
to a few questions will help us.
Sure. Whatever you need to know.
Before the sleeping problems,
did you have any trouble breathing,
a cough that wouldn't go
away— Anything like that?
No.
- Are you certain?
- Absolutely.
I've never been away from
her for more than a night.
If she had breathing
troubles I would've noticed.
The other condition is
significantly more likely if...
If you've had an affair.
Have you ever had an affair?
Of course not.
- Are you sure?
- I think I'd remember
cheating on my wife.
You might be
reluctant to admit it. No.
I just want to be
perfectly clear.
If your wife has sleeping
sickness, and we don't treat her,
she'll die.
I would never do that to Ed.
I love him. Absolutely not.
I love her.
All right.
All right then. They say no cheating,
we cross off sleeping sickness.
Any new ideas?
Okay. We go with
Foreman's tularemia.
Start her on I.V. chloramphenicol, 25
milligrams per kilogram, four times a day.
Good night.
Where's Ed? Right next to you.
Well, you're two
down, two to go.
Two days?
No. Doses. You have about
20 more days of this fun.
What time is it?
About 4:00 a.m. I
pulled the short straw.
Flow rate looks good.
No rash or flushing.
What time is it?
4:00 a.m.
Do you not remember just asking?
I don't...
Elyse?
Elyse? Elyse?
- Elyse.
- What are you doing?
- I'm trying to wake her.
- She fall asleep again?
In the middle of a
sentence. Elyse. Elyse.
- What's happening?
- Patient's not responding.
Pulse is fine. Airway's open.
Check her blood pressure.
Pupils are reactive.
Elyse, wake up.
You gotta wake up.
- What does that mean? What are you doing?
- She's unresponsive to pain.
Come on, Elyse.
- Is she dying?
- I don't know.
She's in a coma.
There's only one way a tularemia
patient goes into a coma...
while on I.V. chloramphenicol.
The patient doesn't have
tularemia. And then there was one.
Patient comes in 'cause
she's sleeping too much.
It takes 10 doctors
and a coma to diagnose
sleeping sickness. And
then there was none.
We still have the problem of explaining
how a white chick from Jersey...
who's never traveled south of
D.C. has African sleeping sickness.
Still have the
obvious explanation.
I made it clear. If
this guy's lying about
sleeping around he knows
he's murdering his wife.
Does seem unlikely.
Go away.
What are you doing?
Checking for lymphadenopathy.
And waiting for
you. Who are you?
I'm Dr. House.
Your wife has human
African trypanosomiasis.
Sleeping sickness. You
mean it's not tularemia,
a virus, tumor or—or cancer?
No.
I've never had an affair.
I believe you.
And I trust Elyse.
The treatment for this
disease is a drug that's...
fatal on its own
10% of the time.
Which is why I need your written
consent before I can legally prescribe it.
Why would she lie if she knew it could
kill her? I don't ask why patients lie.
I just assume they all do.
But why? To protect you,
because she didn't think it mattered,
it just seemed easier, because...
that's what people do.
If you're absolutely certain that your wife
has never had sex with anyone but you...
since you were
married, then I'm wrong.
But if you think there's a
possibility that just one time...
she wasn't perfect...
One weekend you’re out of town,
one fight where
she ran to a friend,
one stupid Christmas party...
Then you need to allow
me to start treatment.
Because if we don't,
she's gonna be dead
by tomorrow morning.
You trust your wife that much?
I don't know.
I'm gonna start the treatment.
Glass syringes? And
special I.V. tubing.
Why do we need this stuff?
Because melarsoprol melts plastic.
This stuff's basically
arsenic mixed with antifreeze.
What doesn't kill us
makes us stronger, huh?
Nietzsche wouldn't have been so
glib if he'd been prescribed melarsoprol.
"Can cause vomiting,
abdominal pain,
blood toxicity, neural
damage, cardiac arrhythmia."
They forgot to say it's
gonna hurt like all hell.
She's lucky she's in a coma.
How long before we know if
it's working? It's tough to say.
It's a good sign that she
hasn't gotten any worse.
Does she even know I'm here?
She knows you're
always there for her.
Yeah.
If she gets better,
it means she wasn't
always there for me.
It means she made a mistake.
I can't help it.
Part of me—a big part
of me— Can't handle that.
It doesn't want
her to get better.
Does that make
me a terrible person?
Yes.
So you're treating her for
African sleeping sickness...
because you don't think it's possible for
someone to be faithful in a relationship?
And you do? Yes.
And you need to tell me that.
Look. I am not having an affair.
I had lunch with someone
I work with—at work. Once.
I believe you. What I don't
believe is it'll be just once.
I love my wife. You
certainly love saying it.
I'm sorry. I know
you love your wife.
You loved all your
wives. Probably still do.
In fact, you probably love all the
women you loved who weren't your wife.
You can be a real jerk sometimes, you
know that? Yeah. And you're the good guy.
At least I try. As long as you're trying to
be good, you can do whatever you want.
And as long as you're
not trying, you can say
whatever you want. So,
between us, we can do anything.
We can rule the world.
Mixing up some margaritas?
Mine's a double, senorita.
That's Portuguese,
you know. Spanish.
Uh-oh.
What's goin' on?
I'm recalibrating
the centrifuge.
Turn around.
It's a very sad thing.
An uncalibrated centrifuge.
Makes me cry
too. I'm not crying.
Okay.
I told the husband
he was a jerk.
Why?
When I was in college, I...
I fell in love,
and I got married.
And...
At that age, the chances
of marriage lasting...
It lasted six months.
Thyroid cancer
metastasized to his brain.
There was nothing they could do.
I was 21, and...
I watched my husband die.
I'm sorry.
But that's not the whole story.
It's a symptom,
not your illness.
Thyroid cancer would have been
diagnosed at least a year before his death.
You knew he was dying
when you married him.
It must have been
when you first met him.
And you married him anyway.
You can't be that good a
person and well-adjusted.
Why?
'Cause you wind up
crying over centrifuges.
Or hating people?
Her fever spiked at 104.
Echo shows global hyperkinesis.
Blood pressure?
Barely 90 over 40.
Did you give her dopamine? Started
270 micrograms per minute 10 minutes ago.
Still no change.
Killing the parasites isn't gonna do much
good if we kill her heart at the same time.
A heart can be
replaced. A brain can't.
Right now we're killing both.
If she's gonna die, we
should at least let her do
it without that acid
flowing through her veins.
What's happening?
We would've expected your wife's
condition to show some improvement by now.
It hasn't.
It's going the other way.
Please don't die.
She's awake.
Hey. She's gonna be okay.
Yeah. Sure.
What are you gonna do?
Were you always honest with her?
Do you know how lucky you are?
Your wife is alive. She loves you.
What she did...
You can't love a person
and do that to them.
She loves you.
I need to know who
you had the affair with.
He has to be notified so
he can get treatment as well.
Why did you lie to us?
You knew your life was at stake.
He's not coming back, is he?
We all make mistakes,
and we all pay a price.
I need that name.
Hey, there. How you doin'?
Fine.
Do you know where your dad is?
Can I help you?
That's some bad hat, Harry.