When you're a kid,
you always want
things to stay the same,
the same teacher, same house,
same friends.
Being a surgeon is no different.
You get used to
the same attendings,
same scrub nurses,
same hospital.
Hey, Cristina.
Of course, that all changes the
minute fifth year comes around.
Cristina!
Hey! Hey.
And you have to find a new job.
How was Dallas? Bad.
I can operate circles around
the head of the program.
I'm sick of all this schlepping.
From now on, they're
gonna have to come to me.
How was yours? Boston, right?
San Francisco.
I'm supposed to leave
for Boston tonight,
but I think I may cancel.
What? Only an idiot
cancels the Brigham.
And didn't Bailey
set that up for you?
No. Uh-uh. She's gonna kill you.
How cute is she?
Hi!
Hey, do you need
a ride, or is Owen...
Picking me up? No.
So how'd it go? It was great.
Hi, baby girl. Oh, my love.
Look who's here.
Mama. She missed you.
Your idiot wife wants to cancel
her interview at the Brigham.
No. You don't
cancel an interview
with the best general
surgery program in the country.
What I said.
Why would we move? You've
almost finished the house,
and you have a job here.
There are other homes
and jobs in Boston.
You're going. End of discussion.
Good husband. Okay, let's go.
I will ride in the
back with my girl.
I'll get the bags.
Here we go.
I snagged the last croissant,
and I only had to elbow one
orderly out of the way to get it.
I got a secret.
Oh, really?
If I tell you, you
can't tell anybody.
You promise? I promise.
I'm in love.
Okay. With...
With whom?
This is getting ridiculous.
The NIH?
Since when does the NIH bribe
residents to come work for them?
Oh, they don't, except
when you're me, a God.
Hey. Cookie's stale.
Aw, Karev. Is this hard for
you, having to beg for interviews
while some of us just
sit back and get wooed?
No one is begging. Oh,
yeah, maybe you should.
Maybe that way, you'd
actually get an interview.
Ha! I love mean Kepner.
I got an interview.
Oh, really, where?
At...
places. APRIL: Uh-huh.
Whatever! Look,
this sucks, okay.
I mean, we got boards
in a couple of weeks
and now they want us to
go on freaking job interviews?
There's only so much crap
a guy can have thrown
at him before he snaps.
There's a trauma
coming in on the roof.
Kepner, Karev, come with me.
I gotta leave for my
Northwestern interview in an hour.
I told you yesterday. Avery?
Sloan's got me all
day, Chief. Sorry.
I'm free. Great.
Thank you.
Female hiker found at
the bottom of a ravine.
Positive LOC with obvious
head and abdominal trauma,
hypothermia,
frostbite, you name it.
Let's go.
Airway looks clear.
Weakened pulse.
I'm Dr. Grey. You're
in the hospital.
Can you tell us your name?
Okay, okay. Let's
go. OWEN: Let's go.
Out of the way.
Okay, I'm gonna be right
on the other side of that glass.
You just try to stay calm.
You weren't hiking
out there, were you?
What's the holdup, Grey?
I'm staying in. Get me an apron.
Okay. Here you go.
Okay, I'm gonna stay with you.
I'm not leaving. I'll be
right here the whole time.
Displaced tibial fracture.
Rib fractures, too.
Lungs look fine.
How far did she fall?
Don't know. Some
hikers found her.
What is it, Karev?
Jane Doe looks to be
around 15-years-old.
Hunt wants you to
take a look at her.
Hey, any word back
on my interviews?
Yeah, I'm working on it.
The angle's off on this elbow.
You've been working on it
for a couple of weeks now.
Well, you're an acquired
taste, like blue cheese.
Some people love
it and some people
can't stand to be in
the same room with it.
They think it's stinky.
So now I'm stinky cheese?
You can tell Hunt
this isn't a peds case.
She's an adult. The
growth plates have closed.
And tell him this elbow
was broken a while ago.
See the curve in her forearm
and the periosteal
reaction on her humerus?
These are fractures
that never healed right.
Or were never treated.
I've seen injuries
like this in Iraq
in patients who were tortured.
She was abused.
It's all over the x-rays.
Okay, we have
to call the police.
Just stay calm. We don't know
anything for sure until she talks.
Hunt, she has a
temporal bone fracture.
I'm gonna have to do a
middle fossa approach.
There's an aneurysm
in her celiac artery.
I'll need to put a graft in.
She's ready to be
put under, Chief.
Wait.
You were running from someone,
right? Is that how you fell?
No one's gonna hurt you. We
just need to know your name.
He called me Susan.
But I think it's Holly.
Beneath the purple tab you'll find
case studies from the past year.
Under the yellow
tab, a list of programs
instituted during my
tenure as Chief Resident.
Under the green tab...
"Dr. Kepner's cheerful demeanor
and pleasant bedside manner
"made my recovery
period a true pleasure."
Letters from former patients.
This one's five pages.
Just one of many
satisfied customers.
Okay, moving on to the blue tab,
awards and accolades.
Yes, her name was Holly Wheeler.
We don't know anything yet.
Let's not jump to conclusions.
It was all over the news.
She was in the grocery
store with her mom,
and somebody just took her.
It was the summer of 2000.
So this could be her.
I mean, what, she was
probably 8 or 9 at the time?
She was 6, and they
weren't in the supermarket,
they were outside.
Her mom bumped into a friend,
started talking about the block
party they were having that weekend.
Could she bring a salad? They
had enough dessert already.
I mean, that's how long
it took for her to realize
that her child wasn't
there anymore.
That story runs through my head
every time Tuck
walks out the door.
And, and yeah, we
don't know if this is her,
so please let's just stop
talking about it and operate.
Bailey, Shepherd, can
you stop for a moment?
What is it?
The police want us to check
for a birthmark under her arm.
The other side, further up.
Delivery for Dr. Yang.
Thank you.
That's not for you.
Call a cop. There's
one over there.
Who's on my jock now?
Cleveland Clinic.
Pretty impressive.
I'm not gonna grovel.
You know we're as good a
program as Cleveland Clinic.
And we've got a
major stem cell project,
one that I welcome
your input on.
And as far as teachers,
I'm a catch.
And I'm groveling. It's sweet.
Come on. Let's go.
Can you wiggle your toes?
Painful?
Yeah. You hit your head
pretty hard when you fell.
But you're doing great, okay?
Holly, I'm Dr. Fincher.
I'm a therapist who
works for the hospital.
Is it okay if the police
ask you a few questions?
Only if you feel up to it.
Do you know his name, Holly,
the man that was keeping you?
It's okay.
Joseph. Joseph Ingles.
That's great. Really helpful.
Now can you tell us anything
about where you were living?
Was it a house, an apartment?
It was a house.
One story. It has a basement.
Do you know if there
was any roads nearby?
Could you hear cars?
He didn't let me go outside.
Holly, we can
stop if you need to.
Just let us know.
Okay, then. Maybe
we should take a break.
Sure.
You should've called me the
minute you talked to the police.
She had major brain
and abdominal injuries.
My first concern
was keeping her alive.
I understand, but the protocol
is to call psych right away.
You didn't, and now our patient
has bonded with a surgeon.
Her name is Dr. Grey.
Dr. Grey. Fine. That's
who Holly has chosen.
There's no breaking
that bond now.
What's going on?
Dr. Fincher thinks that it's
best that you stay with Holly,
at least until her
parents arrive.
I have no psych training.
Holly spent the last 12 years
with little to no control
over anything in her life.
Our job is to break that
pattern by letting her know that
she and she alone
is in control here.
Whatever she wants, she gets,
including you.
We'll have to work
together on this.
Okay.
Thank you. If you'll excuse me,
the family's
waiting for my call.
What was I supposed to say,
I'm flattered that she likes me,
but I have a really
important job interview?
I just wanted to ask you, did you
need me to reschedule your flight?
Yes, I can take the last flight out
tonight and get a cab from here.
Okay.
Hang in there. Yeah.
Tough case.
You're doing a good job.
Except that I'm not.
Her parents are on their way,
and the press are
filling up the parking lot.
I think I might be
out of my depth here.
I'll deal with the parents.
You call Phil in security
and have him double
the guard presence,
then call Heather in PR.
And tell her to
wrangle the press.
You go home, make sure
all your suits are clean.
You'll need 'em for
the press conferences.
You'll be okay, Hunt.
What is she like? Did
she speak English?
Or is it like that
Jodie-Foster-in-the-woods movie?
English, although
she's not really speaking.
She was just flipping
through the channels.
I'm guessing the TV reception
in the basement wasn't that great.
Are you trying to get
out of your interview?
The parents are on their way.
I'm going. I want to. Really?
'Cause it seems like
you want to stay and raise
happy cutie babies with
your happy cutie husband.
Why are you so
fine with leaving?
Because I'm a surgeon,
and I want to work
at the best hospital
with the best people,
as should you.
Since when did you
turn into such a sap?
What do you guys know
about Carson Methodist?
Nothing. I'd like
to keep it that way.
It's in Toledo. Or
an hour outside,
I guess. I interview next week.
Where's Toledo? Canada.
Ohio. A quarter of a
million people live there.
But this is an hour outside.
Robbins set it up
for me. I can't not go.
I've enjoyed our time
together these past few years.
What are you doing?
We are officially on
different career paths.
It's only polite
to say good-bye.
Oh, my God. Holly?
It's her.
I'd know you anywhere. You
are still my perfect baby girl.
Holly, I know it's soon,
but I would like to hug you.
Would that be okay?
Oh, my baby girl.
My baby girl.
Baby girl.
We're a new program,
so you're on the verge
of something great here.
You're lucky you're
getting in now.
Really? Oh, yeah.
We're even about
to upgrade our NICU.
Just waiting on the
final round of funding.
In fact, that's why we were so
excited to get Dr. Robbins' call.
She told us all about that money
you raised for
those African kids.
Melinda, these are
the discharge papers
for the liver transplant boy.
Could you prep
him for transport?
You're discharging
a liver transplant?
We're not equipped to deal
with cases that serious yet.
So we're shipping him to
our sister hospital in Toledo.
You hungry?
It's make-your-own-sundae
day at the cafeteria.
You're gonna love it.
Hey. Whoa. Sorry.
I thought you were...
I thought you
were the kidnapper.
No, no, I... You hear
they caught him last night?
Yeah.
That's why I'm here,
actually. I needed more suits.
You know, for the
press conferences.
I thought you were
studying at Meredith's.
Well, I came home
to take a shower.
Well, I'll clear up and
I'll get out of your hair.
You know, just
leave it. Stay here.
Oh, no, no, no, I...
No, I'm staying at
Meredith's until the boards.
I'm never here. So just stay.
You sure?
Until the boards are over.
Okay.
I'll go now.
Give you some privacy.
This is, I think, your
first day of school.
6th birthday.
Looks like that's where
the bunny came from.
So today Dr. Torres will
be realigning your arm.
You'll have a lot more
mobility in your elbows.
Did they really think
that this would work?
Give me some photo
albums and a stuffed animal,
and we'd be normal again?
No, I think that they are just
trying to help you remember
because you were only 6.
Well, then tell them
that I remember all of it,
the first day of school
and my 6th birthday.
Just like I remember
the first time he made
me take my clothes off
and how hard he kicked me
when I didn't
act like I liked it
or how his breath
smelled like cigarettes,
how I could've gotten
away a bunch of times.
But every time I
made it outside,
I could hear his
voice inside my head,
that they didn't want me,
that I was dead to them,
and that the only
reason I finally ran away
was because he told me that
he was gonna take another girl.
Because I was
too old and used up
and disgusting now.
Tell them that.
We will then repair
numerous fractures
that never healed
properly the first time.
The patient is in good spirits,
and we're grateful for
the chance to allow her
to heal in a way
that wasn't positive...
Pausible... Possible before.
We hope... Thank
you, Dr. Torres.
How does Holly feel about
Joseph being captured?
And her parents, when
can we talk to them?
Look, I'm sure the Wheelers
would appreciate some privacy.
Is it true Holly's refusing
to speak to them?
Where are her parents?
It's a very
complicated situation.
It's not complicated.
It's not complicated at all.
The guy's a monster who
stole our kid for 12 years,
and we're the ones who
are allowed to see her
for only one
supervised hour a day.
Holly's in a fragile state.
She'll need all of us
to abide by her wishes,
even if that means
giving her space.
She was brainwashed by him.
She doesn't know what she wants.
Possibly. But she still has
feelings of blame and resentment
that she has to process.
Right now you're
still strangers to her.
'Cause you won't let us go
in there and be her parents!
Did you show her the photo
album? Did she remember?
Not even the bunny?
She loved that thing.
She didn't remember. I'm sorry.
She'll come back to you.
It might take some time, but
the memories are still there.
You just have to be patient.
Oh, hey, Chief. I haven't heard
back yet from Northwestern,
and I know you're
close with Dr. Mitchell.
Have you spoken to him?
Yes, he said your
resume was impressive.
Oh, thank goodness.
Keep your options open, though.
What do you mean? He said
he thought I was impressive.
He also said he wasn't sure if
it was a match personality-wise.
Personality? I'm asking for
a job, not a date to the prom.
Damn reporters.
Sorry. Hello.
Dr. Llewellyn to OR 2.
Chisel, please.
Man, look at all
this callus formation.
He would've had to break
this arm three or four times
to get this amount
of scar tissue.
And the humerus is pretty
strong, even in a young kid.
Kinda makes you sick just
thinking about the amount of
force it took to break it.
Can we talk about
something else?
I mean, you know, who knows
what they hear subconsciously?
So it...
Maybe it wouldn't hurt to
come up with a conversation
about something other than
every parent's worst nightmare.
Avery scored an
interview at UCLA.
That is not what she meant.
No, that, that's good.
Let's hear about that.
Well, it's a top-10 program,
which is impressive.
Of course, it's just
as much a reflection
on me as a teacher
as it is his surgical skill.
Okay.
Hey. How was Canada?
Canada would've been
better than that dump.
You want me to call
the Chief at Duke?
He wants me so bad, he'll do
anything I tell him, even accept you.
Drill, please.
What's Hunt gonna
do anyway if you leave?
Oh, that's right.
You say "Duke," and
he's on the next plane.
Guy's so whipped.
She's not going to
Duke, and neither are you.
This is a great program,
and we'd be crazy to leave.
That's because you want
to play shrink to your patient
for the rest of your life.
She imprinted on me.
What am I supposed to do?
How's she doing anyway?
Great. I mean, better.
I found two granola bars
under her bed this morning.
But at least she didn't lie
about where they came from.
Fincher says she's
talking more in therapy,
although she's not talking
to Frank and Kathleen.
She was being kept 5
miles away from their house,
and they didn't find her.
You don't just get over
something like that.
Maybe she could move in
with you when we all leave.
Adele, baby.
Are you ready for dinner?
This is a private room!
Get out!
You get that man out of here!
Dr. Webber... It's assault.
She was vulnerable.
You just don't let a man...
Please, sir... He took
advantage of my wife.
He's a predator. If you
don't get him out, I will sue.
Dr. Webber, Allan
has Alzheimer's.
His is quite progressed, further
along than your wife's, even.
He's not a predator.
He's a patient here.
I don't have to tell
you that Columbia
has a cutting-edge
cardio program.
So I hope the fact that
I've flown cross country
to come knocking on your door
shows you just how
serious we are about...
Can you pass me the butter?
Yeah.
Thank you.
You should come
to New York to visit.
You like theater? I can get you
tickets to any musical you'd like.
I hate musicals.
I do like wine, though.
Waiter.
More wine. Coming.
There's an old
fracture in your pelvis
that Dr. Torres is
concerned about.
It's called an
avulsion fracture.
At first I thought it might have
happened when you ran away,
but this injury is a
lot older than that.
Do you remember
when the pain first started
or anything that might've
happened right before that?
A fall, maybe?
No, I don't.
Oh.
Maybe it happened
after I had the baby.
It was a few years ago.
I think it died.
I couldn't walk for
a long time after. I...
It must have
happened then, right?
Uh...
That's...
Yes, that's...
I'm sorry. I didn't...
No. No, it's... Should...
Should I not have said anything?
Excuse me.
It's okay.
Sorry I'm late.
No, it's been a while since
you've been in my OR.
I'm honored you showed up.
Has Grey been ditching
you, too, for interviews?
Cristina has been so distracted.
Meredith, do you know
who she's talking to today?
Stanford, I think.
Stanford?
Since when has she been
interested in Stanford?
You blame her? You'd be a fool
not to pursue cardio at Stanford.
Kinda like general
at the Brigham.
I told you, the program director
was very understanding
when I called.
And you believed her
after canceling three times?
You know how many strings I
had to pull to get you in there?
Well, the Chief
assigned this case to me.
What am I supposed to do?
Stanford? I mean,
that is just... That's far.
Hunt is really okay with that?
Grey, will you tie these
vessels off? Mmm-hmm.
She's been through enough.
She doesn't need to worry
about some jerk taking
her picture in the hall.
I am so sorry.
Well, don't be, just...
Help me, okay?
Help me keep her safe.
It won't happen again.
Hey, Teddy needed
you to sign off
on the stem cell
paperwork. Okay.
People have cameras
on their phones.
He can't expect you to ban
phones from the hospital.
No, no, but I can make sure
that the hallways are clear
before they move her, or
security keeps a lookout.
I'm not thinking.
I'm making mistakes.
In over my head.
I wasn't supposed
to be the Chief.
to be this guy. I'm...
I mean, how am I the guy
that ends up making
this man's daughter
more hurt than she already is?
I'm just... I'm failing. I'm...
You're doing the best you can.
And how was your day,
my little scootchie coo?
Did you just have so
much fun playing with Zola?
You know, she doesn't
understand you any better
the more idiotic you sound.
Hey, Zola. Good evening.
Good evening. How are you?
Tuck?
Tucker?
Hey, don't be shy.
Hey, where's Tuck?
I'm not sure. He was just here.
You don't know? You know it's
your job to know where my son is?
Tara, when's the last
time you saw him?
A few minutes ago. I
swear, he was right here.
A few...
Call a code pink.
Right now. What?
No, there's a
protocol for a code.
Hey, hey, my son is
missing. Okay? He's gone.
You took your eyes off
of him, and he's gone.
Now you pick up that phone
and you make
that call right now,
or I swear to God, I
will have your throat.
Tara, just do it.
Just call the code pink!
I'll look for him.
Yes, we have a code pink.
A 5-year-old boy, missing,
I'm not sure how long.
I don't know.
He's wearing a green-striped...
Please don't just
stand there. Okay?
Look. Help me find him. Oh, God.
He's probably screaming
'cause he knows to
scream if there's a stranger.
Oh, God. He's
screaming. He's screaming.
Dr. Bailey.
What?
He had a nosebleed.
I took him to the nurse.
What? What?
There you are!
Come here. Let
me see. Is that...
Let me see that tissue.
Oh, my goodness.
Oh, well, then I guess...
Yes, you can cancel.
Where was he?
Nosebleed.
Get you an ice cream.
Yeah? Yeah? Well, let's go home.
And let's get some ice cream.
Here. Come on, sweetheart.
I can't believe you
had a nosebleed.
And
that should just about do it.
Impressive.
Most of our candidates
can't get the detail
on the triangular fossa.
Yeah, well, if this whole
surgeon thing doesn't pan out,
then I guess I could
take my act on the road.
You know, just set up a little
whittling booth at a county fair.
I think people would
pay good money for that,
especially when they hear it's
made by Harper Avery's grandson.
Which reminds me,
do you think that he'd ever be
interested in doing a lecture here?
We've been after him for years.
Mmm.
You're a name brand.
You're like the freaking
Ritz-Carlton of surgery.
Who cares if that's
why they want you?
Because he knows deep down
he's more of a roadside motel.
Oh, she's going for the soup.
Bold move. She's gonna
have to talk to the soup guy.
She's looking good.
Looking confident.
And she bails.
No soup for Holly.
She looks terrified.
Why are you so mean?
Would you just go
buy her some soup?
No, it's not mean.
She's going home soon,
and Dr. Fincher says
she has to learn to
do things for herself.
And you're gonna finally have
to go to Boston for your interview.
I am not avoiding
the interview. Really?
Well, whenever you go,
just beware, they may judge
you more on your personality
than what really
matters, like your resume.
Meredith is not like you.
Her personality doesn't suck.
Pizza station.
Hey.
Whatever! You know what?
Those programs can suck it.
I'm tired of trying so hard not to
be me. You know what? I like me.
That makes one of us.
You make it so easy.
Look, you don't
have to not be you.
Just be a little
less you. That's all.
Get up. What are you doing?
Claire Hiatt just
called to tell me
you walked out
on your interview.
Call her back, apologize.
Look, I respectfully
withdrew my application.
You want me to drag
you out by your ear?
I...
Freaking Robbins.
Uh... So I didn't
actually speak to anyone.
But I
did go to the
self-serve station.
And it actually
wasn't that hard.
What?
Nothing. Looks good.
You know who is
an awesome mentor?
You're gonna say me, and
we're gonna high-five, right?
Sloan. He gets Avery
interviews at hospitals
who have more to offer than
the sundaes in their cafeteria.
Oh, relax. I just heard back
from a colleague in Florida,
and he's dying to meet you.
Miami? Tampa.
Well, just a little outside.
Why are you doing this?
I thought you liked me.
Of course I do, that's
why I've spent tons of time
turning you into a great doctor.
And now for my trouble,
what, you're gonna ditch me
for some other program?
You don't want me to go.
You've been tanking
my recommendations.
I know. It's awful. I
feel really guilty about it.
But you don't know how hard
it is to find a good peds fellow,
and I'm not gonna let them
take my best candidate.
I'm your best?
Go away.
Look, get on the phone,
tell the people you actually
respect that I'm the best,
Yale, Baylor, Brown.
No more "one hour
outside of Toledos."
Did you not just hear me?
I'm not gonna help you leave.
You want me to stay
here because I want to,
not because I have
no other choice.
Call.
Hey. How are you feeling?
That was a pretty big deal.
Not really. I don't know.
Braving that cafeteria
line is pretty major,
even for those of us
who haven't been...
Kept in a basement for 12 years?
For those of us who
haven't been through
what you've been through.
Why do you do that,
talk around it?
The therapist and
my parents and...
What I've been through is being
kicked and raped and
slapped and starved.
I mean, I get it, but...
It was my life.
And I didn't get to talk to him
about my life with my parents,
and now I don't get to
talk to anyone about him.
But you can talk about him.
No, I can't.
No, you'll think...
You won't get it. Try me.
He wasn't only bad.
Sometimes he was okay.
He'd let me go upstairs and
we'd watch stuff together,
movies.
And it was like it was normal.
When I came back here, I
turned on the TV, and there was
this movie on that
we watched together.
And I started to miss him.
And I know that's
bad, and I must be sick.
And don't tell the shrink that
I said anything, 'cause she...
She's gonna ask
me how I feel about it.
And I don't know.
All I know is
I should be happy that
I'm here and not there.
But sometimes I'm not.
That's okay.
However you feel is okay.
They've called three times
to see if you'd received it.
What self-respecting program
sends a fruit basket anyway?
Champagne, sure, but fruit?
Fruit just says
your program sucks.
Who's that?
Hopkins.
Hopkins in Maryland?
Yeah.
Hopkins is a great program.
And they're recruiting
you, so that's...
That's something to be proud of.
Do you want an apple?
Yeah.
You have a better
view of the pond.
You know, I heard that Mrs.
Thompson across the hall
has a great movie collection.
Adele, what is it?
He hasn't come to visit or call.
I don't know what I did wrong.
You did nothing
wrong, honey. It's just...
I'm your husband
for 30 years now.
I'm right here. I...
This is us
on our wedding day.
Your mother took it
right after the ceremony.
You and...
We're married?
Yes, honey.
I proposed on New Year's,
and we were married
the Valentine's after.
Allan?
Where's Allan?
Can you help me
find him, sir, please?
This isn't like
him. He loves me.
He wouldn't just
disappear. He loves me.
Allan?
Where are you?
Allan, please come home, baby.
Please.
The CT showed a leak
in her celiac artery graft,
so we have to take her
into the OR right away.
Where's Bailey?
I think you should go in
and say good-bye to her
before we take her to surgery.
No.
No, you go do that.
Help her. Please.
Kathleen, this is very serious.
She doesn't trust
us like she trusts you.
Take care of her, please.
She's crashing. I
need a chest tray.
Let's get some gloves.
Coming through.
She arrested. I need
to crack her chest.
Someone page Altman.
Let's get some drapes.
Scalpel.
Thank you.
Rib spreaders.
- I need some suction.
- Suction.
Let's get those blinds.
Patient is 18-year-old
female Holly Wheeler.
Dr. Altman?
I got the page from
Dr. Yang at 22:18,
and then met her and
Dr. Bailey in the OR.
Where we discovered
that the previous graft
had become infected.
While we tried to interpose
another graft away from the infection,
she arrested several
times on the table.
We had to restart
internal cardiac massage,
give her an intracardiac epi,
and fortunately, we were
able to resuscitate her.
Dr. Bailey was then
able to repair the graft
and other than some initial
touch-and-go in the CCU,
she has been stable ever since.
Your recommendation?
Patient is healthy
and ready to go home.
Neuro? Signed off.
Ortho? We're good.
Plastics? Send her home.
And general?
Dr. Bailey?
Dr. Bailey signs off. - Great.
Well, Holly will continue
her therapy with Dr. Fincher,
but as far as
surgery is concerned,
she's set to go home.
Thank you, everyone, and
especially, a thank you to Dr. Grey.
Okay, that's...
That's enough. Let's
get back to work.
Great job, Hunt.
Thanks. Thank you.
They're good parents, right?
I mean, they seem
like good parents.
They've been here every
day since you came in,
all day, just in case
you want to see them.
I have a daughter.
And I know I would want
to hold her and never let go.
And they haven't done that.
They have tried
to give you space
and just tried to understand
what this must be like for you.
Just give them a chance.
Just talk to them the
way you talk to me.
The car's all packed.
We have everything?
Yeah, I think so.
We can't thank you enough.
Of course.
You don't want to
leave this behind.
Uh...
Yeah.
Actually, I do.
I don't know. It just
reminds me of everything
that I missed out on.
I'm sorry. I know that it
means a lot to you guys,
so we can take it
if you want, but...
No, it's fine. We can leave it.
It's one of those
things that people say.
You can't move on until
you've let go of the past.
You have to make her stay.
What? Cristina.
She just told me that she is flying
to New York tonight to visit Columbia,
and they are gonna roll
out the red carpet for her
just like every other
hospital in this country.
And pretty soon, we are gonna be
one of ten places
that she can pick,
and we are gonna lose her.
We can't let that happen.
She is gifted and
brilliant, and I...
This hospital can't lose her.
She wants to go.
It's her decision.
I can't make her stay.
Owen, you are her husband,
and whatever is going on
between the two of you, I don't care.
Just fix it and make her stay.
You make her stay.
You're the head of
cardio. She's your resident.
If you want her to stay,
you make it happen.
And don't you ever talk
to me about my wife again.
I'm your Chief, not your friend.
You've made that very clear.
Letting go is the easy part.
It's the moving
on that's painful.
You have a good life here.
You have friends, and,
you know, sometimes...
Well, I can get in
the way of all that.
Of course, now if
you need anything,
just pick up the phone,
and I'll stop everything,
and I'll come right over.
I love you, Adele.
And I always will.
Allan.
Come, come and sit down.
I was just on my way out.
Where have you been?
I've been waiting for you.
So sometimes we fight it,
try and keep things the same.
"Be less you"?
How do you be less yourself?
There.
Less you.
What?
You put on your suit?
I gotta be at Yale first
thing in the morning.
What if my flight gets delayed?
Or even worse, what if you
go in there looking like a hobo
in a wrinkled-ass jacket?
Where'd you learn that?
I'm an Avery. We
know these things.
Hey. So I rescheduled
my interview at Brigham,
and I leave in an hour.
Cheers to that.
Jackson, we gotta go.
And we're out. Yeah.
Happy interviewing, losers.
I should go, too.
Don't leave.
It's Yale. No way in hell
am I missing that flight
to hang out with you two drunks.
Later. Don't choke.
Bartender. Yeah?
Two tequilas, please. Two more.
You know...
This wouldn't be a totally
bad bar to hang out in
if we miss our flights.
Plenty of traveling
salesmen to hit on.
Well, our husbands
would never know.
Cheers. Cheers.
Things can't stay
the same, though.
Flight 1243 to JFK is
now boarding at gate 19.
Well,
free flight to New York.
I'd say wish me luck,
but I don't need it.
Cristina.
You really want
to do this, leave?
We've been preparing for
this for the past five years.
Of course I want to leave.
You should, too.
At some point, you
just have to let go,
move on.
So if Miranda Bailey tells me
I need to meet a young surgeon,
then it's obvious I
need to meet them.
Still, before we go any further,
I need to know
how serious you are
about our program,
moving to Boston.
Because no matter
how painful it is...
Very serious. In fact,
it's my top choice.
It's the only way we grow.