When I was five, my
mom lost me in a park.
I don't remember much,
except that one minute,
I was riding the carousel,
and the next...
She was gone.
I'll be home before you know it.
It's good. It's time.
I know. I just feel
like I just got you back,
and now you're going again,
and I just have to stay here.
You're right. You do.
You have to stay here.
Stay here. Don't
move. Don't move.
Wait for me.
I don't remember
how I found her.
Richard!
I don't remember how I got home.
Are you okay?
All I remember is
what happened next.
She told me not to worry.
She told me everything
would be fine.
I'll be back before you know it.
Funny, isn't it, the
way memory works?
The things you
can't quite remember
and the things you
can never forget.
The carousel
never stops turning.
Okay, Zozo, walk a little
faster 'cause we are late.
And who can never be late?
Surgeons.
What happens if
surgeons are late?
People die?
Right on, sister.
Hey, it's me.
I'm on the ferry.
I just wanted to say that...
You're never gonna
make your flight.
I'll make it.
No, you won't. You're
gonna miss your flight.
Now, who's that? Bailey?
I'm not gonna miss my flight.
There was a huge accident on
the 5. All the lanes are closed.
The traffic is insane.
Now, why does Kepner make
that sound like it's a good thing?
We have a guy from
the accident on our table.
Bailey and Kepner are sewing
up all the holes in his gut.
I am repairing the un-repairable.
I am out-of-control amazing.
No, I am out-of-control amazing.
You are a guest
in my guts. Hush.
The point is,
you might as well
turn around now
'cause you'll miss your flight.
I'm not gonna miss my flight.
I have a secret shortcut.
There are no
shortcuts to the airport.
- That you know about.
- Come on.
I'm doing a
spondylolisthesis today.
I'm saying if you head
back now, I might let you...
I'm gonna lose you here in a
second. Cell phone reception's bad.
Derek, are you still
there? I can't hear you.
No, I said I'm gonna lose the
cell phone reception. It's bad here.
Amy?
Derek? Derek?
Amy, are you there?
Lost him.
Look, I'm doing 10
miles over the speed limit.
That's not fast
enough for you? Gee.
Where's my phone?
Hey. Ma'am? Ma'am?
Winnie? Winnie?
My name's Derek. Are you okay?
Winnie?
Winnie! Winnie! Winnie!
Hey, I can't open
the door. Winnie!
Winnie! Winnie! Ma'am. Hey.
Hey. What's your name?
Sarah. Sarah, who's Winnie?
My daughter. She's,
uh... She's in the back.
She's not answering, and
I don't know if she's okay.
Sarah. Sarah, I need you to stay
calm, okay? Deep breaths. Good.
Stay calm. I'm
gonna be right back.
Okay? Try not to move,
okay? Okay. Mmm-hmm.
Hey. You Winnie?
Is anything hurt,
like your neck or...
Is that why you can't talk?
I think I'm dead.
Am I dead?
Let me feel your wrist.
Well, you're not dead.
I can feel a pulse in your wrist.
You know what that means?
What?
It means your
heart's still beating.
And you can't be dead if
your heart's still beating.
See, I'm a doctor,
and I'm telling you,
if you ever want to know if
you're dead, feel your pulse.
I can feel it.
I'm not dead.
You're not dead.
I'm not dead, Mommy!
She's okay?
Okay, she's fine.
Do you have a cell phone in
there? I need to call for help.
Yeah. I see it.
It shattered, though. It...
It wouldn't matter, anyway.
I drive this road every week,
and there's never any cell signal.
Okay, I'm gonna check
on the other driver,
see if they have a
phone. You're leaving us?
What? No. I just said there's
never any cell signal up here.
It's not gonna be different.
Sarah, I'm gonna
check on them. I can't...
Like I checked on you,
okay? I can't move. I am stuck.
Please don't leave.
I'll be right back.
You promise?
I promise.
Okay.
Hello?
Help.
Help!
Hey.
Can you tell me your name?
Alana. Alana.
It's hard to breathe. Okay.
All right. Let's take a second.
You probably got the
wind knocked out of you
when you hit the ground.
Lucky you didn't
hit the pavement.
Yeah.
You feel any pain?
I don't... I don't think so.
Does it hurt anywhere? No.
I'm not supposed to
be here. I have to go.
I have to go. I have to go.
Careful. Careful. Okay, enough.
I have to call my mom.
Where's my phone?
My phone's not working.
Why is my phone not working?
Okay. Listen to
me. Listen to me.
You're probably in shock, okay?
You have a lot of adrenaline
going through you right now.
There might be
something wrong with you
that you don't feel right now,
so I need you to slow down.
Okay. Okay.
All right.
Can you tell me what day it is?
Thursday. I'm
supposed to be at school.
Chem. We have a quiz.
Is that why you were
driving so crazy?
I wasn't driving.
Who was driving?
Charlie. It's his dad's car.
Hey! Hey, Charlie.
Hey.
Stop.
You okay?
Yeah. I'm fine.
Hey, let's get out of the road.
I don't feel good.
What happened? You
were in an accident.
Hey, what happened?
Let's get you out of this
road. I really don't feel so good.
What happened?
Um, let's get out of the road.
Sir, do you know what
happened? Yeah, you...
'Cause I really
don't feel so good.
No, no, no, no, no. Charlie.
What... What happened?
I don't know what
happened, Charlie. I don't...
Oh, my God, Charlie. Look
at your head. Are you okay?
Help me get him down.
What's wrong with him?
Why isn't he saying
anything? Charlie?
He hit his head really hard.
I need to find a first-aid kit.
Oh, you got to be kidding me.
Okay.
Okay, are you... You guys
still doing okay in there?
Yeah. You're gonna
get us out now?
I need supplies. What
do you got in the back?
Um, a first-aid kit,
Winnie's backpack.
Okay, Winnie, it's safety
glass. It's not gonna hurt you,
but I need you to
get back, all right?
Get back.
Are you gonna
leave us here again?
No.
Think you can climb out for me?
Yeah, I can. SARAH: Be careful.
Can you make sure Winnie's
careful? Okay, I got her.
Is she out? Yeah, she's out.
I'm out, Mom. I'm good. Okay.
All right, Sarah,
I'll be right back.
Not going anywhere.
I'm gonna get your mom.
Winnie, you think you can go down
there and keep those two company?
The people who hit our car?
No, thanks. I'm good to wait here.
There's bandages in
here. They could use them.
My mom's gonna
be in a lot of pain,
and you don't want me to see it.
No.
Yes.
I can deal with seeing stuff.
My dad died
right in front of me.
We were fishing on the lake,
and he had a heart
attack on the boat and died.
Do you fish?
No one's gonna die, Winnie.
You aren't God,
so you don't know.
I'll go wait with them.
Okay, Sarah, you
ready? One, two, three.
I loved this car so much!
It's the first new
car that we ever had.
And boom, some rich guy in
an overpriced midlife crisis just...
You saw him, right?
The guy that hit us?
Total pig, right?
He was a 17-year-old kid.
Crap. Now I can't even hate him.
I bet his parents are awful.
All right, Sarah, I got
to get you out of this car.
Listen, getting you
out is going to hurt a lot.
Okay.
I know that I should be in pain,
and I don't know if it's shock
or if it's that my
leg hurts so badly
that I almost
can't recognize it.
Almost feels normal, so maybe
it won't be so bad getting me out.
Sounds like you
dislocated your hip.
Which means I got to
get you out of this car...
Okay. Down on the ground,
and then pop it
back into the socket.
Okay. All right.
All right, I'm not gonna
sugarcoat it. It's gonna be horrible.
What happened?
There was an accident.
There was a car
accident, Charlie.
Ow!
Are you okay?
My stomach hurts. Really bad. I
think I'm gonna throw up or something.
Where are we?
We had a car accident, okay?
We had an accident!
Okay, stop. Please
stop. I need to fix your leg.
No, let's wait.
Let's wait, uh, for help 'cause
help's coming. It's coming.
Sarah, the dislocation has cut
off the blood supply to your leg.
If I don't do something,
you could lose it.
Wait, wait, wait.
Please, please, please.
Okay.
Oh!
Good.
Oh. Thank God.
It's good.
I hate you.
Derek! Charlie's
car! The car's on fire!
Hey!
Alana, run! What about Charlie?
Get away from the car!
Come on, Charlie,
you got to get up.
Get up, get up, get
up, get up. Come on.
Aah! Aah!
Come on.
Oh, my God!
That explosion was huge.
Do you see all that smoke?
Someone's gonna see it,
and then that someone
is gonna send some help.
It's like a smoke
signal. Mmm-hmm.
We're so rescued.
I'm not supposed to be here.
Okay, we just need to
hang on for a little bit longer.
Is everybody okay? I'm
not supposed to be here.
I'm a mathlete. I
take five AP classes.
I'm first chair on cello. I have
a perfect attendance record.
I haven't missed one
day, not one day of school.
I'm boring.
Charlie Abbott's prom king.
He's in remedial math.
He's never even heard of AP.
He's dumb and popular
and totally gorgeous.
And this morning, he says,
"You want to go for a ride?" to me.
So, the Earth is shifting on
its axis or something crazy
because no way.
Charlie Abbott is not
supposed to kiss me.
Aah!
So something is wrong.
Some wormhole to another
universe has opened.
I don't know, but
now I am on a road
because the car I was
in just flew through the air
and I just ran
from a giant fireball
and Charlie Abbott's brain is
broken and my stomach is killing me.
So I am obviously not
supposed to be here.
So, can someone
please wake me up
or wave your magic wand
or click your heels three times
or whatever so I can go home?
Please. Please.
What? What is it? What's
wrong? Just look at my eyes.
Look at my face.
Look at my eyes, okay?
I'm scared.
Okay, okay, just look at me.
Derek?
Okay, we need to get her down
on the ground. Help me, okay?
Just come with
me right now. Okay.
Easy, easy.
I just need to undo a button so I
can look at your stomach, okay?
I'm scared. I know.
I'm not gonna go anywhere.
I'm here, okay? Look at me.
Look at me. Look
at me in the eyes.
All right, I'm gonna
open up your pants
so I can just see
your stomach, okay?
I just want to
take a quick look.
I'm gonna take a look.
Oh, God!
Sarah. Derek.
What's wrong with me?
Is it my stomach? Is
it bleeding? It's okay.
Am I dying? Please, I
want to know. No, no, no.
You have a little cut in your
tummy. It's gonna be okay.
It's no big deal. I
can take care of it.
How? How are you gonna fix it?
You don't know.
Oh, my God, I'm
gonna die out here.
Can you stop saying that? It's
insulting. I don't let people die.
I'm very good at my job, even
next to the roadside, okay?
I'm thinking. I'm thinking.
Sarah.
You have dry-cleaning
in the car, right, Sarah?
Yeah, I think so.
So, Charlie kissed
you this morning.
Was that your first kiss?
Yes. Except for the guy
who plays second-chair cello.
He doesn't count. Why?
It was just practice kissing.
So, should I be practicing?
No.
Yeah, but she just...
But how much trouble do
you think she's gonna be in
when her mother finds out
what she's been up to today?
She has a point. I'm
not your role model,
and I don't think kissing
Charlie was worth all this.
Every kiss before the right
kiss doesn't count anyway.
I've kissed a lot of women.
The first time I
kissed my wife, well...
I mean, she wasn't my wife then.
She was just this girl in a bar.
And when we kissed,
it... It was like...
I got to tell you, it was like I never
kissed any other woman before.
It was like the first kiss.
The right kiss.
Do you have a brother?
It's a beautiful
day to save lives.
What... What does that mean?
It's just a thing I say.
Oh.
Do you hear that?
Hear what?
Hear that?
They got our smoke signal!
Yeah, they got our smoke signal.
They got us!
I'll visit you first thing in the
morning at the hospital, okay?
Thank you.
Okay, watch your step.
Got to hand it to you, Doc.
Now go home and
have yourself a drink.
You earned it. Thanks.
She told me not to worry.
She told me everything
would be fine.
Funny, isn't it, the
way memory works?
The things you
can't quite remember
and the things you
can never forget.
What do we have?
Where should I start?
A bad one. Jerome Davis.
Blunt-force trauma,
open skull fracture.
He keeps trying to die on us.
Let's get him inside.
Let's go.
No, no, no, wait.
What, no! Another one?
No, no, no, no, no.
We've already got
that lady and her kid,
the girl with the guts, and then
that dude with the head injury.
When it rains, it pours.
Okay, it needs to
pour somewhere else
because we are
not a trauma center.
We're not properly
equipped for this kind of thing.
We don't have rooms.
You guys know that.
Make room.
What are we supposed
to do with the guy?
Look at him.
All right, fine.
This isn't on me.
John Doe broadsided
by a semitruck.
Blunt-force trauma to the
head, chest, and abdomen.
Persistent hypotension
after two liters of saline.
Pulse is thready at 130.
You're not dead.
Just breathe.
I need four units of blood.
Scalp lac. Probably multiple
fractures. Try to hold still.
John Doe. Bad MVA.
Had to be extricated.
Positive loss of
consciousness at the scene.
He's poorly responsive.
GCS of 10.
What's your name,
sir? Can you hear me?
Yes. Yes, I can hear you.
Loss of verbal skills.
Possible bleeding in the brain.
His pupils are
equal and reactive.
Good sign. Still
should get a CT.
He's got a flail chest in the
right. I need a 36 French tube now.
Sir, can you tell me your name?
He's still hypotensive and
tachycardic after two fluid boluses.
He could be
bleeding in his chest.
Hang two units of
blood on the infuser.
I need a trauma panel and
X-ray, and cross him for four.
And somebody page surgery again.
- Right away.
She's smart. I like her.
I'm sorry. This is gonna
hurt, but we have to do it.
That must have hurt. I'm sorry.
Can you please
tell me your name?
Can you tell me anything?
Excuse me, Toby?
Mom, I'm going to the bathroom.
Ask a nurse where it is.
Ow. Yeah. Right there.
I'm ordering a head CT.
We don't know the
extent of his head injury.
She's right. You don't.
Look at the ultrasound.
He's bleeding into his belly.
We don't have time for a CT.
Arrogant. Because
she's younger than you.
And probably because
she's a woman.
I just think that...
We don't have time for a CT.
He needs to go
straight to the OR.
You have this. Come
on. Don't back down.
But I don't think we
have a handle on...
His GCS hasn't changed
since he got here.
The CT can wait.
C-spine, chest, and
pelvis films are up.
Derek?
Winnie. You
shouldn't be in here.
You're not dead.
I know you're not dead.
You know how I know?
'Cause I can feel your pulse,
which means your
heart is beating.
Your heart is beating,
which means you're
not dead, okay?
Hey. Eyes on me.
You stay not dead, okay?
It's a beautiful day
to save lives, right?
So you stay not dead.
Where are you supposed to be?
Is he gonna be all right?
Whose kid is this?
I'll deal with it.
I'm not dead. I'm not dead.
That man, do you know him?
Yeah, that's Derek.
Derek? Derek who? Is he a
family member? A neighbor?
He's my friend.
Okay. Do you know
your friend's last name?
No, I mean, I just
met him today.
He pulled me and my mom
out of our car after the accident.
He fixed her leg,
he helped Charlie,
and he put Alana's insides
back in. He saved us.
He saved you?
All of us.
He's a doctor.
He's a doctor?
A surgeon, I think.
My head. Look at my head.
Sedation, please!
You need to calm down, buddy.
He's a surgeon. Let's get a...
He's a surgeon, and
he just saved everyone
from the car accident
that just came through.
Doctor, we're gonna
sedate you now
so we can secure your airway.
You're gonna be fine.
No. I'm not.
You need to wait.
Sux and etomidation in? Yes.
It's okay. We've got you.
It is all gonna be okay.
This isn't right.
You should have taken
me to get a head CT.
His pressure's holding.
Maybe we should get the scan.
Yes, listen to her.
Too risky. He could
bottom out in the scanner.
We need to open him up.
Find the source of the bleeding.
No, you don't.
You have the time.
We have to work
fast, people. I'm stable.
Guys, I'm stable.
Take me to get the head CT.
Let's set up for an
ex-lap. Coming through.
I'm going to die because these
people aren't properly trained.
One, two, three.
He's hypotensive.
Start him on pressors. Betadine.
I can't feel my arm.
What is happening?
Ready to put him under.
No, I have a head lac.
Don't miss. Don't miss!
The colon's avulsed.
We'll need to resect and
create a temporary colostomy.
Well, it's better than
being dead, I guess.
He's got a
grade-two splenic lac.
Meredith would leave
it. PAUL: Let's leave it.
Check the four quadrants.
And she'd double check
the retrohepatic space.
Make sure to check
Not bad.
Crap. Dropped his sats.
Decreased breath
sounds on the right.
Check the chest tube.
The chest tube looks good.
Check it again.
Crap. He's got a
huge hemothorax.
We have to open his
chest. Thoracotomy tray.
No, don't. Just wait. See
how much blood comes out.
It'll probably stop. Just wait!
Scalpel.
He's still hypotensive.
I can't find any
lung laceration.
Hilum's intact. He's not
bleeding into his chest.
This makes no sense.
We're missing something.
Set up for a TEE.
Not that. That's not
what you're missing.
Persistent bradycardia.
Check my head.
I don't understand
what the hell is...
He had a head lac.
Check his pupils.
His right pupil is blown.
Page Neurosurgery
right-freaking now.
We did.
Then page them again.
Any word?
The neurosurgeon
was at a dinner.
Dinner? DEREK: Dinner?
He said he'll be
here in 20 minutes.
It will be too late.
Damn it.
Where the hell is he?
Page him again.
Thank God.
What the hell have you
people screwed up now?
Us?
You're on call for trauma.
What took you so long?
Who the hell are you?
Your response time was
supposed to be 20 minutes.
It wouldn't have
made a difference.
If you guys had
ordered a head CT,
you would have called me sooner.
What am I supposed
to do about that?
We needed to control... He
was bleeding into his belly.
He was stable. You had the time.
Now I've got to work like hell
to save this man, thanks to you.
There's no point.
You were supposed to
be here in 20 minutes,
not an hour and a half.
We had a chance. He
had a freaking chance.
Get out of my OR.
What?
You heard me.
Unless you're gonna be
cutting into this man's head,
you can get out. Now.
Now!
I'm gonna scrub in.
Someone pull in
the craniotomy tray.
We've already
wasted enough time.
It's too late.
You're too late.
Hey.
What did you do?
I did what I always do,
except I almost
killed myself doing it.
Don't make jokes. I was scared.
No, don't be scared.
I'm not going anywhere.
Come here.
Mmm.
I'm right here.
Ma'am?
Ma'am, is this the home
of Derek Shepherd?
It is. He's my husband.
I'm afraid there's
been an accident.
Could you come with us, please?
Are you okay?
I can't just go. I...
What am I supposed
to do with my kids?
Blood. It's just blood.
Meredith, don't be
afraid. Don't be afraid.
911. What's your emergency?
My mother tried to kill herself.
Dr. Grey.
Dr. Grey, I can't...
We can't tell you how sorry...
I am so sorry for your loss.
Dr. Shepherd was a
tremendous surgeon,
a tremendously gifted...
I've long admired
his techniques. I...
It was an honor.
The call to not get a
head CT was a bad call.
We're not a trauma center.
We're a teaching hospital.
You did the best you could.
Ma'am?
I thought that if this
was a good time,
I might take a moment to
explain how this all works.
Where are the papers?
Mrs. Shepherd, there's
some things you need to know,
some things we need to discuss.
Difficult things.
I'm a doctor. Dr. Grey.
I'm a surgeon, just
like my husband was.
I know how this works.
You've waited the
requisite number of hours,
and now you can
officially declare him dead.
Normally, you'd talk to
me about organ donation.
But by the looks of his chart,
there's not much left
that works to donate.
So, the ICU needs a bed.
Those must be the papers.
The papers you want me to sign to
decide what to do with my husband
now that he's dead,
but not really dead.
Do we ship him off to
a long-term care facility
and cross our fingers and
hope for fairy tales and magic?
Or do I pull the plug?
And stop all
curative intervention?
Discontinue all
routine monitoring,
remove all the catheters,
drains, and tubes,
end any and all
treatments that might
provide comfort to the patient.
Terminate all
life-sustaining measures
and behave as any sane
doctor would behave.
Does that about
cover it, Doctor?
Is that what you want
to talk to me about
while I sit here with
my sleeping children?
You want to talk about
killing my husband?
Give me the papers.
Ma'am...
Give me the papers!
I'm so sorry.
I know that that's
useless to you right now.
But I am.
He saved all those people.
And it was my job to save him.
And I failed.
And now he's gonna die
because I was not a
good enough doctor...
to keep him alive.
Yeah, you're right. You did
fail. You weren't good enough.
But do you know
what tomorrow is?
It's Friday. There's gonna
be more patients who come in
who need you to save them,
someone's mother, someone's
kid, someone's husband.
They need you to save them
because they can't save themselves.
So learn from
this, better yourself,
and you will be
better for next time.
What if I'm not?
You will be.
How can you know that?
Because he was your one.
Every patient you treat, you're
going to see my husband's face
and remember that he was
the one that died on your watch.
He will haunt you. The
hard ones always do.
And it only takes that one.
But that one will make you work
harder, and they make you better.
Or they make you quit,
and you don't get to waste
what would have been
the rest of my husband's life
being a quitter.
So get back inside because
you're not saving any lives out here.
I really am... Yeah,
I know. I know.
There's a social worker
out there with my kids.
If this takes a while...
We got them. Don't worry.
I just need the papers.
We're gonna begin now.
You can sit next to him.
Wait.
Ma'am... Just wait!
Derek.
So, what's your story?
I don't have a story.
I'm just a girl in a bar.
I'm just a guy in a bar.
Want to go again?
I love you, Meredith Grey.
And I want to spend the
rest of my life with you.
You're the love of my life.
I can't leave you.
You were like
coming up for fresh air.
It's like I was drowning,
and you saved me.
I'm in love with you.
I've been in love
with you forever.
So, um... Goodbye...
Um...
Derek. Derek.
Right. Meredith.
Meredith. Yeah.
Mmm-hmm.
Nice meeting you. Bye, Derek.
Derek?
It's okay.
You go.
We'll be fine.
Are you ready?
No. But go ahead.