♪ Ohhh ohhh ohhh ♪
There are basically five steps
to the ivf process.
One, they stimulate
and monitor the development
of healthy eggs
in the ovaries.
Two, they harvest the eggs.
Three, they select
and secure sperm.
Four, they combine the egg
and the sperm in a lab
and provide an appropriate
environment for fertilization
and early embryo growth.
And five,
they select--
identify the best embryos
and transfer them to the uterus.
I'm at step one. Heh.
How are you feeling
about that?
I feel like...
Heh.
Like I'm at step one.
I got hormones.
Congratulations.
You pulled the trigger.
It's not quite
congratulations yet
because I haven't pulled
the trigger,
because the shots
go in my ass.
Sam can't pull the trigger?
I like to be sexy with Sam,
and shots
that stimulate egg production?
Not sexy.
Enough said.
Okay.
And this stays between us,
right?
I have no idea
what you're talking about.
God, I miss Naomi.
What are you--?
What are you doing?
Just calm down.
Massaging the area
helps to absorb the hormones.
I'm deriving absolutely
no pleasure from this
whatsoever.
Well, ahem, thank you.
Now it's congratulations.
Well, my fsh is really high.
I don't know if I'll get any
good eggs out of it.
It's still congratulations.
There's no way to know
unless you try
and you're trying.
- It's not safe.
- No one should go up.
Wes. Wes.
No one is gonna do anything
to you, honey.
You wanted to give them
your painting.
I'm not going up there.
I don't wanna be here, mom.
It's not safe.
No one should get in there.
Karen. Wes. Everything okay?
He's refusing to take
his heart meds.
He's refusing
to take any meds.
Hey, Wes. Is this your painting
here? It's really beautiful.
Is that this building, Wes?
Yeah. The elevators hear.
- They hear you.
- Right.
They want you to go in.
Know who would love
to see this?
I'm not going up.
Dr. Turner.
Dr. Turner, Wes.
Why don't we both take
the stairs up--?
They hear you
and they watch you.
He needs to start seeing
her again. He's in trouble.
Everything's gonna be okay.
Why don't you--?
I can't go up there.
All right.
I can't be here.
I can't. I can't. I can't.
Take that.
Ah!
I can't believe you have been
running around Italy
for six months.
I'm jealous.
Don't be jealous.
Just go.
And get the pizza in Naples.
It is insane.
And then head straight
to Rome,
buy a large box of condoms
and never leave.
Italian men are ridiculous.
And they're everywhere.
Italian men in Italy?
Just standing around
in Armani suits, eating gelato.
Waiting to get attacked
by a predatory American tourist.
Never a tourist.
There I am che Donna stupenda.
A hot piece of ass.
Ha-ha-ha.
When did your symptoms
start?
Couple months ago,
in ravello.
We can try meds.
There are ways that
we can manage your symptoms.
Amelia, thanks to you,
I had a beautiful six months
in Italy,
which I wouldn't have had,
and I am grateful.
So grateful.
But I'm not gonna die
a slow death from huntington's.
I am not going the way
my mother did.
I'm not. You promised.
Michelle-- I know, but--
it's time, Amelia.
I mean, I've had great food,
great sex,
great love in my life.
And a great friend.
I'm happy.
And I'm ready.
I need you
to help me die.
All right, you wanna open it?
All right. Open it up.
Hi. Hey, uncle Sam.
How you doing?
Hey, buddy.
Hey, have you ever, um,
baked anything?
Like tried to bake?
Because it's hard.
Really hard.
I had no idea how hard it was.
It's harder than med school.
Yeah.
We have a little 2-year-old
sous-chef here.
- I want candy.
- I...
Yes. You.
Why are you here?
It's Wes.
Do you remember him?
Patient, the painter.
I know Wes.
He's off his meds.
Psych meds or heart meds?
All of them.
He won't see Sheldon,
he won't listen to me.
You're the only one he trusts.
I know that you can't talk
to him officially,
but--
damn it.
Unofficially,
I was thinking maybe--
yeah. I'll get a sitter.
All right.
Watch him for a minute?
Yeah.
What's happening,
buddy boy?
If you and Mason are gonna be
seeing each other,
we should set some rules.
Ground rules. Okay.
Yeah.
First, your wife--
yeah.
--Is not allowed to speak to
Mason or be anywhere near him.
Charlotte should never
have done what she did,
but she's sorry.
She's actually very different
once you get to know her.
No, thanks.
Secondly,
I don't want you telling Mason
that you're his father.
Ever?
For now.
Okay. If you wanna see Mason,
those are my conditions.
Beautiful. All of this is
so beautiful.
The colors.
The textures.
Everything around us.
It's life on a canvas.
Hey, Wes. It's me.
It's Dr. Turner.
Do you remember me?
You're not Dr. Turner.
Yes. Yes, I am.
Listen to me, Wes.
Do you remember when we
started working together
and you were living in a box
on venice beach?
Do you remember that?
And I used to come
visit you
and we would talk about
how you were feeling.
About the voices in your head,
the ones that frightened you.
You're not Dr. Turner.
Remember what happened
after that?
You started taking medication
and you kept coming to see me
and you got better.
And you didn't live
in a box anymore.
You had an apartment.
You paid rent.
The apartment
on third street.
Yes, the apartment
And you had a show
in the local art gallery.
People loved my paintings.
They did.
You made beautiful paintings.
Don't you wanna get back
to that?
You are not Dr. Turner.
Wes.
The machines got Dr. Turner.
The machines took over her mind.
They made her leave me.
Wes.
The real Dr. Turner
would never have left me.
You're a machine.
And I'm not talking
to you anymore.
Michelle is 30,
her cag count is 43.
She should've had a couple more
years before symptoms started.
How advanced are they?
Tremors, rigidity,
seizures.
The younger the onset,
the faster they progress.
It's a daunting prospect,
but there are support groups
and therapy.
And she'll still have time where
she's lucid and functional.
But she doesn't want the time,
does she?
She wants me to euthanize her.
Your friend Michelle,
is she a puppy?
Because unless
she's a puppy--
I promised her I would.
It was the only way I could
stop her from killing herself
when she found out
she had the huntington's gene.
Wait, Amelia.
The puppy thing
is kind of a good point.
Why are we more humane
in our treatment of animals--?
You're not considering this?
He did it.
Okay, okay, okay.
One, when I tell you something,
just keep it to yourself,
okay?
And two,
my patient was in his seventies.
He was in excruciating pain
and he only had
a couple of weeks to live.
What if you were seizing and
losing control of your muscles,
of your bowels,
of your mind?
Would you want to stick around
for that?
You took an oath.
You think I would do less harm
by letting her die slowly
and painfully?
I know you're sad.
I know you're scared,
I know you wanna help
your friend.
This is not how to do it.
Physician-assisted suicide
is legal
in Washington
and in Oregon--
but in California,
we're talking about murder.
You got that, right?
You're talking
about committing a murder.
I got one. What do I do?
What?
- What? Wait.
- Oh, reel it in.
Reel it in.
There you go. Nice and steady.
Oh, my god.
- Mason, you really got one.
- Steady.
- Yeah.
- There you go.
Bring it up. Bring it up.
Yes.
Yeah.
Ha-ha-ha.
Good job, man.
Check that out.
Look at that, man.
I'm hungry.
You want a hot dog?
Sure.
Hot dog? Ha-ha-ha.
No thanks.
You're pretty good.
You wanna go again?
Are you dating my mom?
No, we're just friends.
Well, whenever my mom
has a friend that's a guy,
it usually means
that he's her boyfriend.
And her boyfriends
are kind of dumb.
Oh, well, it's a good thing
I'm not her boyfriend then, huh?
I mean, do you think
a dumb boyfriend
could do like this?
If it's all right,
I kind of wanna go find my mom.
Okay. Go ahead.
Hey.
So did you hear about
my former patient?
My schizophrenic patient, Wes,
who because I was suspended
and forced to stop seeing him,
has stopped taking meds.
And is living
on the streets
talking to traffic lights.
I heard.
It's not okay.
Okay.
I'm thinking about suing.
You're gonna sue a homeless guy?
The medical board.
And if I can't sue,
then I am gonna go to the press
and I am gonna bring attention
to this system.
To this process
that is so broken,
I don't even know
where to start fixing it.
Okay, are you angry at me?
Because you're actually
yelling at me.
No. Oh, no, Addison.
I just--
ever since Pete's
heart attack,
I feel like I've been trying
to be the perfect wife
and mother and not a doctor.
I haven't let myself realize
the effect that my suspension
has had on my patients
whom I just abandoned.
You didn't completely
abandon them.
No, I did. I did.
That's how it feels
to them.
And it sucks.
Nai used to put food
on top of feelings.
Addison, I'm a therapist.
I don't eat for comfort.
That's not healthy.
It's disordered eating.
Try a doughnut hole.
They help.
They're good, right?
Hey. I got an idea about Wes.
You got a moment?
Yeah. I have nothing but.
How you doing? You good?
I'm great.
I have doughnut holes.
Oh.
You wanna lock my son up?
Not exactly.
We just wanna keep him
in a psych hold.
Because of Wes' pattern
of destructive behavior,
severe delusions
which result in him
not taking
his heart medication--
he could die.
We think we could get a judge
to sign off on the hold.
I had him committed before,
Dr. Turner. It makes it worse.
Being held down
and being strait-jacketed?
His paranoia
goes off the charts.
And then
when he goes off his meds,
which he always eventually does,
he trusts me less.
I need him to trust me.
I'm his mom.
The only way I can be there for
him at all is if he trusts me.
I... I can't have him
committed.
I mean, he's still my boy.
He's in there.
He's somewhere in there.
You know, in the cracks.
In the moments
where those voices get quiet,
he's my wonderful,
wonderful boy.
I won't allow you to hold Wes
against his will.
And if you pursue this,
I will fight you.
How did you do it?
Morphine.
My patient was halfway there
on a cocktail
of sedatives
and sleeping pills,
so it didn't take much.
What happened?
After you gave him
the drugs?
Well, at first
he was ecstatic.
Maybe because he was free
from the pain.
But after his body started
to shut down,
well, there was so much fear.
He said
it was what he wanted,
but I don't think
he was prepared for the...
How terrifying
and lonely it was.
And what did you do?
I stayed with him
till it was over.
It takes
an emotional toll on you.
Sometimes I wonder
if I gave him the morphine
because I was the one
who couldn't take it anymore.
That if I had been
stronger for him,
maybe he would've died in his
sleep, without any of that
regret or despair.
If you knew then
how you would feel now,
would it have stopped you?
No. But that was different.
And no matter
what Michelle says,
she has no idea what it's really
like to face death, believe me.
It's not gentle or sweet
or a relief.
I gave her my word.
Then take it back.
Take back your word
before you ruin your life
and your career.
Take it back.
So have you seen
Amelia?
I don't have her on GPS.
I'm just worried.
So am I.
You don't think
she would actually--?
I don't know.
I don't...
I'm sick. I'm actually
worried a little sick.
I mean,
physically nauseous.
But I'm not her shrink,
I'm not her father.
That's the way you feel
about her? Fatherly?
You two have been spending
a lot of time together.
I don't know. I don't know
what I'm feeling. Except sick.
Hey.
How was fishing with the kid?
It was good.
He'd never been before, he did
great. He caught two fish.
Which he couldn't care
less about.
No, it wasn't good.
It was awkward.
It was weird and awkward,
and it was like he didn't wanna
have anything to do with me
and I just don't get it.
Hi.
Hey.
What now?
Mason and I were getting
along great, until--
until what?
If you're having an issue
with him,
it has nothing to do
with me.
I only talked to the mother.
We hung out and it was awkward
and it never was before.
If Erica hates you,
or us, that is gonna
influence Mason.
Coop, I understand you're going
through a rough patch.
If you think you can blame me
because an 8-year-old
doesn't want to share
a corn dog with you,
you have another thing
coming.
Son of a bitch.
Excuse me.
Hey. Is everything okay?
No, I'm very definitely
not okay.
If you try to do one thing,
one simple thing,
like rename the practice
and suddenly,
I'm in a blizzard of paperwork,
you know?
I got the building
management people,
I've got
the insurance company.
Oh, I've even got the guy
who paints our damn
parking spaces.
This is not
what I signed up for.
Heavy is the head.
Seriously?
Are you trying to piss me off?
Because I'm looking for someone,
anyone, whose face I can just--
it's not your fault.
I'm sorry.
You have massive doses
of hormones
coursing
through your veins,
your emotions are elevated,
your filter is gone.
You feel like you've been hit
by a pms truck.
No kidding.
How do I make this stop?
Just breathe, okay?
And if you start to feel
like you wanna cry or scream
or rip somebody's face off,
walk away.
Go someplace quiet.
Avoid emotional triggers, like--
Sam.
Hey.
What's going on?
Just giving Addison
a pep talk
on how to get
through paperwork.
Hang in there.
You okay?
Yeah.
Sweetie, I'm right there
with you.
Ugh. I hate this thing
that's going on with Wes.
I feel so bad for his mother.
I feel bad for my moth--
I feel bad for all mothers
everywhere.
Did you know that Wes
was a perfectly normal kid
up until
he was Maya's age?
So you're worried
that Maya might have, um,
a schizophrenic break?
Yes, I am.
And I'm worried about
a million other things
because my baby girl's
living in New York City.
She's a blessing.
Maya is the biggest blessing
of my life,
but sometimes,
I don't know...
Sometimes I just wonder
if not having the burden,
of the fear and the stress
of having a child,
maybe that's a blessing too.
You know what I mean?
Addie, where are you going?
Going for a walk.
Addie.
Yeah, this is Dr. Bennett.
Okay. I'll be right there.
So, what happens
after I'm gone?
I call the police.
I tell them I found you.
And they'll think
I took pills?
Hold this.
Put some fingerprints on it.
Should I just take
the pills?
You could end up
in an irreversible coma
or with just really bad
liver damage.
I don't want to get you
in trouble.
I don't want you
to suffer.
First, I'll inject a benzo
to relax you.
Then a barbiturate.
It'll put you under.
And finally,
potassium chloride.
It'll stop your heart.
Okay. I'm ready.
Thank you.
I love you.
I know.
If you see my dad,
you tell him I said hi,
okay?
Maybe I'll fix him up
with my mom.
Why can't I breathe?
You could be having
an adverse reaction.
I'm gonna keep going,
okay?
This barbiturate will depress
your central nervous system.
Amelia.
Should I keep going
or should I stop?
I don't know what that means.
Stop.
Okay.
Okay, I'm stopping.
It's okay, Michelle.
I'm gonna call 911.
Michelle?
It's okay. Michelle,
it's okay. I'm stopping.
No. Get away from me.
He had a psychotic episode
and collapsed on the street.
His mom called it in.
He was upset. He was ranting
at a kid on his cell phone
and then he just dropped.
They'll take over.
Can I get help?
Okay, he's got
hypertrophic cardiomyopathy.
It's gone unmedicated.
Probably arrhythmia.
He came in the ambulance.
Thinks the EKG and every other
machine was trying to kill him.
Can't you hear?
Can't you hear it?
They're trying to send signals
into our brain.
Let's 51, 50 him and 5
milligrams of haloperidol iv.
- You gotta trust me.
- You're not my friend.
You're trying to poison me!
Sweetie,
please let the doctors help you.
What are you doing to him?
Gonna put him on a psych hold.
Mom. Mom, make them stop.
Make them stop.
Don't let the machines
get me!
Haloperidol, 10 milligrams.
Stop! You're hurting him!
- Get her out of here.
- No!
All right.
Mom! Mom! Mom, don't leave me!
Don't let them
do this to me! Mom!
It's respiratory distress.
Secondary to benzo.
Okay, I need point two
milligrams of flumazenil iv.
And 02 at 6 liters.
She got a hold of drugs, Pete.
I don't know how. She did
this herself. I found her--
she changed her mind.
She had a bad reaction
and she changed her mind.
Pull an intubation tray.
Let me help.
No, Amelia,
it's time to step back.
Please, Pete.
Amelia, it's time to go.
Go to the waiting room.
I'll keep you updated.
So I've gotten to know
all of the guys here,
but you women are harder
to crack. You're like a coven.
Oh, god.
It's just the hormones.
Don't even pay
attention to me.
I'm just being ridiculous.
I've heard that before.
I feel like my brain is broken.
And that.
I hate my boyfriend.
Heard that the most.
Do you know he basically said
it's a blessing
that I can't have children?
Doesn't sound like Sam.
Oh, yeah. Yeah.
That's what he said.
"It's a blessing."
A blessing. Really?
For whom is it a blessing?
Him?
Is that the only reason
that he's with me?
He thinks
I'll never get pregnant?
Because I prefer to think
that it's because
I'm awesome in the sack.
Addison. Addison,
listen to me. Okay?
I can't get myself zipped.
You're brave to do this,
okay?
It's a brave and wonderful thing
you're trying to do.
And all of the thoughts
and tears
and
"I hate my boyfriend" talk
is just the hormones, okay?
But the fact of the matter is
you cannot do this alone.
Of course I can.
Lots of women do.
No, they don't.
Even single women.
They have friends and family
and book clubs.
You're afraid to tell
because you're trying to keep it
secret from your boyfriend.
What are you gonna
tell Sam
if you get pregnant?
Or when you're
six months along?
What are you gonna do
when the baby comes?
Hide it
in the liquor cabinet?
I've seen the road
you're heading down,
and you're not gonna make it
unless you have people
on your team.
Hey.
Hi.
Um, this isn't gonna--
I have to cancel.
I'm sorry about
the late notice.
What? Wait. Why? Why?
He had a meltdown.
Ten minutes ago.
Sorry I didn't call you sooner,
but I was kind of busy trying
to talk him out of his bedroom.
It's not me.
Mason doesn't want
to spend time with you.
Oh.
Did he say why?
He's 8, who knows why?
But if he doesn't want to
spend time with you,
I can't force him.
Maybe that would change
if he knew I was his father?
You say you want to be a dad,
but are you ready?
I mean, I'm not talking
about buying him stuff
or pulling a quarter
out of his ear.
I'm talking about
have you thought about
making room in your life
for him?
Or your home? Have you talked
to your bitch of a wife about--
don't call her that.
--How fatherhood
would change your lives?
Yes, I have.
I really have.
I get that
she scared you off.
I get that you think
that she's awful
and I must be awful
if i' married to her,
but you really
don't know her.
She's like a mama bear
when she's threatened,
and you threatened her.
Or she thought
you were threatening me,
and so she, you know,
growled loudly and...
Okay, the metaphor
wears thin,
but my point is
my wife loves me,
and so she will love Mason
because I love him.
He's my son.
And I love him.
And you were the one
who showed up in my life
to tell me that he exists
and I'm glad you did.
And maybe you wish
you could take that back now,
but you can't.
You wanted Mason
to have a father?
Now he does.
Hey. Have you seen Amelia?
Hey.
You okay?
You're worried about him.
Yeah, I'm just waiting
for Sam or anyone
to come and update me because
I'm not allowed in his room.
That new lawyer is working
overtime to re-open my case,
so I am following the letter
of the law.
No contact
with my former patients,
but, um, yeah,
I'm worried about him.
I'm worried about
all of them.
It's gonna be okay,
Violet.
How?
I don't know.
I don't know how,
I just...
This is my favorite thing
about you.
When I get the crazy eyes?
No. That--
that's pretty cute too,
but my favorite thing
about you
is how much you care
about your patients.
I'm glad
you're fighting the board.
I'm glad you're remembering
things you like about me.
Amelia!
Amelia, open the door. I know
you're in there. I saw your car.
Amelia, open the door because
I'm not leaving until you do.
Amelia!
Are you crazy?
Are you actually
clinically insane?
Did you really
do this thing?
Because even I didn't think
you were stupid enough
and crazy enough
to actually go through with it!
Do you get that you basically
confessed your crime to me
before you did it?
Do you get that I could
and should call the police?
And if that woman had died,
I would call the police.
Because I am not gonna be
an accessory to murder.
What is wrong with you?
Why are you
this self-destructive?
She didn't die?
She's alive?
Yes.
She's alive.
You ready to go?
Yeah.
I got you.
You okay?
I'm sorry.
I am so sorry.
Do not apologize to me.
I mean it.
I was so sure
that I wanted to die,
but now I don't--
I don't know.
I just-- I don't know
if I panicked or--
hey, you don't have to
figure it out today.
Or tomorrow for that matter.
I know it's not easy
being alone.
Your mom had you
and you--
you have me.
I will be there the whole way.
You can even move in
if you want.
Oh, I couldn't do that
to you.
You'd be helping me too.
I know it doesn't compare
to what you're going through,
but I struggle too.
Every day.
Pills?
Booze.
I'm branching out.
I didn't know.
I'm sorry.
You don't have to be sorry.
So we're both screwed up,
but maybe we can be there
for each other.
Like some kind of--
like some kind of messed up
buddy system.
You know, I won't drink today
if you don't kill yourself.
Deal?
Deal.
We got his heart stabilized.
For now.
How are you doing there,
Wes?
He can't hear you.
Not when he's like this.
That's why he never could stay
on his meds.
He said they made him feel like
he was 10 feet underwater.
Working with Dr. Turner helped,
but I knew
it was just a matter of time.
We should talk about
other options for Wes.
What to do next.
I think that you should legally
petition for a conservatorship.
You'll be able to make
all of Wes' medical decisions.
Place him in a facility
for his own safety.
We already
went through this.
Hear me out.
I'm not talking about
a temporary psych hold here.
I'm talking about something--
I said no.
I'm not gonna put my son
in some clinic
where they keep him locked
and drugged.
I won't do that to him.
Uh, my sister,
Corinne.
She was a lot like Wes.
She made a habit
of disappearing too.
My mother would do everything
she could to keep her home,
but Corinne
would always find a way out.
One day, she left
and she never came back.
That was a long time ago.
I still don't know
if she's dead or alive.
But I do know
that my mother's
never been the same.
I've never been the same.
I know that you love Wes,
and that you respect
his right to be free.
But are you prepared for the day
that he walks out of your life
and disappears forever?
I don't...
My son is an artist.
He's a thinker.
He's funny and sharp
and he's passionate.
Do you see that man,
Dr. Bennett?
Do you see my son in this bed?
If I keep him like this,
then he's already disappeared.
Carlos, Carlos,
you have to leave.
My boyfriend's
gonna be home soon.
Carlos?
Heh, heh.
You know-- you know I have a
soft spot for the Latin lovers.
You better watch it.
Oh!
What's the matter?
What happened?
What's up?
I started...
I started ivf treatments
a couple of days ago.
I am sore.
Ivf.
Jake's been giving them
to me.
Jake?
Yeah,
Jake's the only one
who knows.
I didn't want the entire office
gossiping about it.
I'm sorry.
No, no. It's okay.
Huh.
Um...
I don't want to have
another kid,
because I already
got mine through.
What?
No, I was
terrified every single day
of Maya's childhood,
but I got her through.
I mean, it was--
it was wonderful
and it was terrible.
Both equal parts.
And it's definitely an
experience that you should have
if that's what you want,
but...
I just don't know if
I have it in me to do it again.
But that doesn't mean
that I don't support you.
That doesn't mean
that I don't love you.
And it doesn't mean that you
get to keep secrets from me.
Okay?
Okay.
Hands off the ass.
I'm sorry.
Michelle! Get in here!
We're doing girls night in.
I got rocky road and a DVD
of the second twilight movie.
The one with
all the hot werewolves.
Michelle?
She had a degenerative disease
that was progressing rapidly.
It was painful
and she was taking oxycontin.
Those bottles hold 30 pills.
I found a bunch
on the bed beside her.
If she got half of them down,
she didn't last long.
You all right,
Dr. Shepherd?
You have someone
you can call?
I'm all right.
You're sure?
No.
I miss my friend.
So I'm not all right.
But I will be.
I'll be fine.
All right.
Are you sure you won't ride
in a taxi with me?
Cars aren't safe, mom.
Please don't ride in cars.
The night sky is much better
for you than cars.
Okay, honey.
You're gonna need
some money.
Okay.
And I want you to have
my phone number
and not lose it.
Thanks for saving me.
You're my hero.
You're mine.
You're still here.
Yeah.
I thought
you might need a ride.
Thank you.
I'll be in the kitchen
if you need me.
Okay, thanks for this.
Hey, Mason.
So, uh, I had fun yesterday.
And I'd love to, you know,
keep hanging out if...
If you don't like fishing,
we can do something else,
you know?
Whatever you want,
really.
Uh...
Are you my dad?
I'm pretty sure you are.
I look like you.
And mom acts weird
when she talks about you.
How do you feel about that?
I don't know.
But if you're not gonna be
around, like all the other guys,
we can't be friends.
He's your dad, Mason.
I am your dad.
And, uh...
I'm not going anywhere.
So you want to watch
some Phineas and ferb?
It's good.
Yeah.
Step one is the hardest.
I mean, they say that
kind of about everything.
You know, it's like
when you watch a baby
take her first step.
I mean, she's spent days
and weeks and months
literally teaching her muscles
how to function.
But once they do,
it's never that hard again.
Okay.
You are all set.
Do you want to be
my fertility doctor?
I mean, mine's fine,
she's great.
But you're clearly
the better choice for me.
I mean, that's assuming
that you would still take me on.
I wouldn't blame you
if you didn't--
yes.
So, what muscle did you train
in order to take this step?
You'll laugh.
I won't.
Hope.
I had to learn
to let myself hope.