- Previously on The Resident...
- What's your agenda?
I need half a million
dollars to make bail
so I can get out
of this rathole.
Recently I've been attracted
to somebody else.
- I can't marry you.
- Get out.
I never want to see you again.
What about an outpatient
clinic for the uninsured?
We will have to hire a
top primary care physician.
We need a diagnosis.
- I have Crohn's.
- At QuoVadis,
we manufacture everything
ourselves in Atlanta.
Your lab is a sham.
Do you know what
I hate the most?
Betrayal.
He needs emergency
surgery. Find Conrad now.
He's bleeding out.
Compress the vein
above and below.
I can't see it. There's
too much blood.
Activate massive
transfusion protocol.
Get the Cell Saver.
Give him one gram of TXA now.
He's about to code.
Get me more suction. Keep
slamming blood into him.
Clamp.
Killer! Murderer!
I'm outside the Atlanta
Detention Center
where Dr. Lane Hunter is
expected to be released on bail.
Hunter is charged with
giving hundreds of patients
unnecessary
chemotherapy for profit.
With trial just weeks away,
her release comes as a shock.
No bail for killers!
Move back. Back up.
You bitch!
Bitch!
You let her out just like that?!
No bail for killers!
No...
♪ ♪
During the resection, all
the planes of dissection
were obliterated and his
bowel was adhered to the IVC.
Eight hours, 20 units of
blood and blood products.
I did manage
to repair the injury using
a saphenous vein graft.
Well, what's his prognosis?
That's too soon to
tell, but he's alive.
Thank God you were on call.
I hate to think what might have
happened to Marshall Winthrop
in the hands of a
less gifted surgeon.
I should've been there with him.
There's nothing more
you could have done.
They got him into
surgery right away.
I left him all alone with Bell.
Mina was there to help,
and according to her,
Bell did everything right.
We haven't had enough
time to sort out our issues.
And now, just
when I was starting
to get to know my
father, I could lose him.
Hey. Don't go there.
I'm sure he'll wake up soon.
But in what condition?
He could have neuro deficits
from being under so long.
20 units of blood, FFP,
and platelets transfused?
That alone carries a
25% chance of mortality.
If someone hadn't run
that surgical checklist
- and had blood on hand...
- They did.
And your father is strong.
All we can do now is wait.
It's gonna be okay.
They let her out?
Hey, what's going on?
Lane Hunter. She's out on bail.
- What?
- That's impossible.
Bail was five million.
That's probably nothing to her.
I heard she billed Medicare
over $20 million a year
for unnecessary chemo.
But her accounts were frozen.
She found the money somewhere.
That won't change the
outcome. She's a murderer.
The jury will convict her.
We have interviews at the clinic
for our new primary care doc.
- Yeah.
- Good, I'll meet you there.
I have to check
in with Dr. Austin.
I can't believe this.
We have to let the
legal system do its job.
I'm thinking two zolpidem
and a half a quart of whiskey.
He left a fine woman
at the altar last night
in front of both their families.
I have no sympathy.
Go home!
- Ooh.
- I can't.
Priya's there. She doesn't leave
for San Francisco until Friday.
Wow, no wife and no home.
I at least feel pity for you.
He was sniffing around
Julian. The device rep?
An engaged man out
there, on the prowl.
I thought better of you.
You're a little too hard on him.
The heart wants
what the heart wants.
Sometimes the
head has no control.
We all have a moral compass,
and we have a choice
to follow it or not.
He had feelings for Julian?
He should have avoided her.
Instead, he kept
spending time with her.
What did he think would happen?
Anyway, when I'm done
with the clinic, I'll find you.
What do we have on deck?
Uh, just a VATS case.
You'll be bored.
Go join Dr. Voss.
Here are files
on the candidates.
Are you going to be
volunteering on a regular basis?
Bai was our first med
student to sign up.
Who do we have first?
Um, Dr. Christina Ruiz.
Graduated from Johns
Hopkins in family medicine.
Huh, sounds promising.
Let's get started.
Your clinic would
be the perfect fit
for me.
I spent last year in Haiti
with Partners in Health.
I grew up in Atlanta
and want to give back.
Serve the underserved.
Access. Too many
hospitals treat and street.
There's no continuity.
Do you have any
questions for us?
Yes. The salary posted,
was that monthly?
I'm kind of between jobs.
What if you pay my
malpractice insurance?
I've got a fair number
of totally frivolous lawsuits.
I'm sorry, but with the amount
of med school debt I'm carrying,
you don't need a
physician, you need a saint.
Is that really everyone?
Okay, uh, I wasn't
gonna mention it,
because it's a super long shot,
but if "saint" is the
criteria, I do know of a guy.
Oh, there he is.
Dr. Alec Shaw.
First he was an
infectious disease doc,
then he volunteered on a
Navajo reservation doing outreach.
After that he got
into family medicine.
I first saw him in my
hometown, New Orleans.
Why didn't you
mention him before?
He just landed in Atlanta.
He's always on the move.
And he hates hospitals.
Hates institutionalized
medicine.
Oh. I like him already.
So he has no fixed
practice? No office?
He has kind of an office.
Well, let's go talk to him.
Um, you'll have
to wait your turn.
He never lets
anyone jump the line.
Hmm. My shift
starts in 20 minutes.
Oh, you guys go. I-I got this.
- You sure?
- Yeah.
All right, good luck.
- Thank you, Doctor.
- You bet.
Belly bomb?
Solid cream center
with a fine dusting
of powdered sugar on
top, courtesy of QuoVadis.
You're now the device
rep? Where's Julian?
Who-who's Julian?
Hold on.
I bet you're more
of a glazed man.
H-How about jelly? No?
That guy is Julian's
replacement.
Where is she?
I don't know.
She said she was gonna
quit and leave town,
and now she's ghosting me.
That's harsh.
Look, about yesterday,
I'm sorry, man.
How's your dad?
Not clear yet.
You should go home.
I don't have one at the moment.
And I'd rather work.
I hear that.
There's an arm lac in ER Three.
I think you might
want to take this one.
- Okay.
- Look, what do you want me to do?
They're gonna stitch me
up and then we'll leave.
I... you know, I didn't
mean to fall, I fell.
We should have
just watched it on TV.
No way. You, of all
people, had to be there.
I'm Dr. Hawkins.
What's going on?
We were at a
protest, it got crazy.
- At the prison?
- Yeah.
And neither one of us are
happy that we ended up here.
Lane Hunter killed
Roger's sister.
She came in with
stage I breast cancer.
Lane treated it
like it was stage IV.
All Judy probably
needed was a lumpectomy.
Instead, she died from a
reaction to Dr. Hunter's chemo.
I am so sorry.
I am not exactly a fan
of Dr. Hunter either.
Let's have a look at that arm.
- She had a pretty bad fall.
- Uh, it was a big crowd.
I tripped. Just stitch me
up and send me home.
Natalie used to be a cop.
- Nothing fazes her.
- Well, I'm seeing
some bruising here.
I'm gonna order an X-ray just
to make sure there's no fracture.
Hey, you're not hearing me.
I'm fine. Stitch me and I'm out.
And she doesn't like doctors.
I get it. I know
what Dr. Hunter did.
Dr. Hunter gave Natalie chemo
and she didn't even have cancer.
She's the reason
I'm no longer a cop.
Soon as I get an
answer, I'll let you know.
Doc-Doctor Bell.
Yeah?
My hero.
Dr. Bell, you have a call...
I bailed you out,
I got you a great legal team.
Now it's time to hand over
the deposition and the tape.
I'm checking into a
very nice hotel. Come by.
Alone, of course.
And let's discuss.
I'll send my lawyer.
Excuse me. Turn around here,
go to Chastain Park.
I'm on my way to you.
What hotel?
Roger and I became
friends at Dr. Hunter's clinic.
Poor guy drove his sister to
every one of her appointments.
That's a good brother.
Yeah, that's what I tell him,
but he still blames himself.
What diagnosis were you given
for the weakness in your legs?
Neuropathy from the chemo.
It just won't get better.
Yeah, today it's even worse.
Protest must have
really wore me out.
Well, let's make
sure it's nothing more.
-We have one of the best -No.
Orthopedic spinal surgeons
in the country, Dr. Voss.
I want her to check you out.
Look, I was a legacy
officer in the Atlanta PD.
My mom before me,
Grandpa before that.
I wish I could have
it all back, but I can't.
Accepting that was the
hardest thing I've done,
but I did it.
This isn't the discharge desk.
I had a patient here.
She came in after having a
reaction to chemo from Lane.
Shock again, at 360!
The night she coded,
we all fought to save her.
I can't bring Lily back,
but if there is any possible way
to fix your legs,
I want to find it.
Give me and Dr. Voss one hour.
One hour.
- How long has that
been going off?
- It just started.
The RT's in a code down the
hall. Should I call for backup?
No, hold on, his
respiratory rate's too high.
Mr. Winthrop's peak
pressure is climbing.
He needs more sedation.
No, it's the vent settings.
It's trapping air in his lungs.
We need to get him off of it.
But he hasn't had a
spontaneous breathing trial.
I'm getting an attending.
The vent's too high.
It was stacking his breaths.
He's awake, we can extubate.
It's okay. I got you.
So you blackmail
me with a sex tape,
tell me to come alone,
and now you bring a lawyer?
Ugh, calm down.
Now, Martin handled
the wire transfer.
You are paid back, my friend.
The funds were transferred
from a shell company
in the Bahamas to an
account in your lawyer's name, -
so there's no evidence
of a financial relationship
between you and Dr. Hunter.
Great.
- Now the deposition
and the sex tape.
- Okay,
- Randolph, relax, please?
- Not feeling too relaxed.
Well, then, try.
I plan to.
Probably somewhere with
palm trees and dark rum
and pool boys with
very little clothing.
Oh.
But first we have
to get past this trial.
Cancer treatment is complicated.
The trial's outcome will
depend largely on how
Dr. Hunter's chemo
protocols are perceived.
The jury will rely on
testimony from medical experts.
Pillars of the community,
ready to stand up for her.
You want me to testify publicly
about what a great doctor
you are? Are you insane?
Uh... why don't you just tell
the jury the facts, Randolph?
Cancer treatment
requires experimentation.
Oncologists routinely
use drugs off-label.
When ones that the
FDA approves don't work,
we improvise.
Why? To save lives.
Find someone else.
All right, can we just
have a minute alone?
All right, I'll tell you
what... Release the tape.
I'll bounce back.
I'm not the only CEO
who's had consensual sex
with an unfortunate partner.
I'm done being blackmailed.
You're done when
I say you're done.
- You killed Lily Kendall.
- No, I didn't.
Which is exactly why they
have no evidence to prove I did.
You're the only
one with a motive,
you were at the
hospital that night,
I saw you there,
and I'll testify to it.
Hmm. You know, I heard once
about an appendectomy patient
that died in your OR.
You know, we all make
mistakes, but something tells me
you've had more than your share.
Whatever secrets
you have, Randolph,
I'll find them.
I'll hire a medical detective,
I'll depose your
entire OR staff.
Well, my staff will back me up
long before they'll support you.
Good news, brother.
You're not dead. Bad
news? You got maggots.
Hold tight, you're up next.
Oh, um, I'm not
actually a patient.
I'm a nurse practitioner
from Chastain Park.
I wanted to talk to you
about the community clinic
- we're opening...
- I already told
your med student no.
You want to switch it
out every couple hours.
Hamburger's gonna draw
'em out faster than any drug
you're gonna get
at her hospital.
Cheaper.
Safer, too.
Come on, Sammy, we're next.
The clinic will be free.
And with more supplies
and volunteers, you
can reach more patients.
And it's a lot bigger than
what you're working with here.
I grew up in a converted
school bus in Tennessee.
It was my dad's idea,
and not his best one.
Or his worst.
11 kids. Lots of
government cheese.
So, to me, this
is the Taj Mahal.
Sammy, knock it off.
- This is fun.
- You know, he's going through
- this licking phase.
- Is it metal?
It is metal.
I got something for him.
Strawberry, my favorite.
Good choice, little man.
All right, Gladys,
let's see that finger.
So, your boy's licking metal
- 'cause he's got
a mineral deficiency.
- Oh.
A good multivitamin
is all you need.
Oh, okay.
Let's see here.
Hey, look at you. Sugar's down.
You been hitting that South
Bend Park? Eating those greens?
Stopping diabetes before
I get it, just like you said.
Thanks for the lollipop, Doctor.
Look, I'd love to talk to
you for just a few minutes.
Look, I don't have
time for breaks.
I got a long line
out there, so...
I heard you got free flu shots.
Yes, we do.
You ever had a
reaction to one of these?
- No.
- Take a seat.
I'll help you get your line down
if you give me some pointers
on how to run our clinic.
All right, you're gonna
feel a light pinch.
You were diagnosed with
nerve damage from the chemo,
but actually the chemo
caused osteopenia.
You see this here?
You had a tiny
fracture on your T12.
That's what caused the
weakness in your legs.
When you fell
today, it got worse.
Now it's compressing
against the spinal cord.
It's become an emergency.
I knew it. I knew one test
and I'd end up in surgery.
No, Natalie,
these two are the real deal.
Listen to Dr. Voss.
It's nothing short of a miracle
that we caught this.
If we don't operate,
you'll be paralyzed from
the waist down within hours.
But if you get in there
right away, there's a chance
they can remove the
compression altogether.
You would have
your strength back.
And then everything
that Lane took from you,
that'd be in the rearview.
Back surgery is dangerous.
Are there risks? Yes.
But the alternative
is you'll spend your
life in a wheelchair.
I can give you a really
good shot at walking alone.
I'm so mad at you.
Is that a yes?
- I don't get it.
- Thank you.
I don't know why she's
not texting me back.
Salespeople move
on. So should you.
Julian still thinks I
got married last night.
I have to tell her, or then...
Julian is not
returning your texts.
Get a grip, bruh.
- How many did you send?
- Like...
Oh, so y-you're going for the
crazy stalker approach, huh?
Listen to me, it's
not a good look.
Stop.
As new technologies
emerge in medicine,
as in other fields, the
U.S. military strives
to be on the cutting
edge of the industry.
That's why we're
at QuoVadis today.
Gordon, I hear from DARPA,
the first thing they want to look at
is the impact of your
VNS device on memory.
You want to use it to cure PTSD?
We're interested
in the possibility.
This company's future
with the military is limitless.
Don't you agree?
- Hey, you ready for the OR?
- I'm a little stressed.
No.
No, make that scared.
- But let's do this.
- Is she okay?
I need an EKG now.
Your heart's racing.
Has this ever
happened to you before?
Palpitations
sometimes. Nothing big.
I've never had my
spine sliced into, so...
Natalie, breathe.
Breathe. Natalie.
Get the crash cart.
Pulse 160, BP's dropping.
She's in unstable V tach. Defib!
All right, 200. Let's go.
- Clear.
- Natalie.
300. Clear.
Give her 150 of amio
and transfer her to the ICU.
What's wrong with her?
With the amount of
chemo Lane gave her,
I'm worried the dosages
also damaged her heart.
All right.
You bought a good hour
of my time by helping out.
Why do you do it?
What drives you?
Uh, grew up in a church.
Service to the poor,
the needy, the stranger...
It's in my DNA. You know,
I'm a lapsed Catholic, at best,
but the drive to reach people
others ignore is still there.
You did a stint on a
Navajo reservation
- with PIH?
- Yeah, that's where I learned
problems start upstream.
You got to keep people
from getting sick to begin with.
Vaccines are gonna
do more than rosaries.
Now I hand out condoms
instead of prayers.
- I noticed you're low
on basic supplies.
- I get more
from the Georgia Prescription
Assistance Program next week.
What if I could score
what you need now?
This place could use some love.
Well, if you know
any contractors
jonesing to help some
people out, let me know.
So why are you doing all this?
Knock-knock.
Oh, sorry, sir,
we're not actually
open right now.
Oh, okay, uh, I-I just
saw the sign and...
What's going on here?
I was playing catch with my
kid and, uh, took one in the eye.
- Oh.
- Can't really see
anything out of it.
- What's your name, brother?
- Russell.
Let me just look
at this eye, Russell.
Yeah, orbital
compartment syndrome.
Yeah, if we don't relieve
some of that pressure,
he's gonna lose his eye.
Do I have to go to the ER?
I have lousy insurance.
Huge deductible.
And I just paid
my student loans.
Uh... you'll need an
ophthalmology consult
in the ER after this, but we
can do the procedure here.
Yeah, we have
everything we need here,
and it'll save you some money.
Okay.
♪ ♪
Here you go.
Thanks.
Okay, you ready?
Just breathe.
Okay.
All right, let's see.
What about that?
- You feel anything there?
- Mm-mm.
Good.
All right.
There you go.
There we go.
There you go. There you go.
My eye still there?
Still there.
Congrats.
Looks like your clinic
just treated its first patient.
Well, he still needs that
consult, so it looks like
you're going to
Chastain after all.
Natalie definitely has
chemo-induced cardiomyopathy.
And the compression fracture
has a large bone
fragment that's causing
- her spinal cord compression.
Decompression and fusion
is the only way to give her
- a chance of walking.
- We need to get in there now.
Implant the cage
here for spine fusion.
Her heart might not
be strong enough.
- She's in the ICU
on an amio drip.
- We can try
to manage it with ACE inhibitors
- and beta-blockers...
- We don't have time.
We've got three,
maybe four hours
before the compression
becomes irreversible.
If she survives surgery.
Lane took Natalie's
choices away.
We're giving her this one back.
I came in for some
damn stitches!
Natalie, they're trying to help.
This is crap! My options are
full paralysis or
possible death?
Or full recovery.
That's the hope.
We do the fusion
while monitoring
your cardiac function.
You're the heart guy, right?
So?
Well, under normal
circumstances,
I would advise against it,
but these are not
normal circumstances.
Dr. Hawkins...
what would you do?
You are the one who's gonna
have to live with this decision,
so you are the one
who needs to make it.
But if it was me...
I am not letting Lane
Hunter hold me down.
I'm taking the risk.
Crap.
I got to try.
- You gave me a scare.
- They said...
I almost died.
I'm sorry I wasn't here.
I shouldn't have left you.
Always taking the weight of
the world on your shoulders.
The blame.
Not this time.
Well, you asked for
one thing: no Bell.
I guess he's
better than nothing.
I want things to change for us.
I've waited a long time
to hear those words.
Well, hey, we're both stubborn.
Yeah, that's... that's true.
Hmm.
I have spent half my
life without a father.
We're gonna fix that.
I'm gonna hold you to that.
Thank you.
Excuse me, um, I'm
looking for Dr. Bell's office.
Tenth floor.
Hey, uh, you're
Julian's boss, right?
Yeah. Gordon Page.
Devon Pravesh. Have you spoken
- to Julian today?
- No. She didn't show up
for work.
Had to get a replacement.
A no-show isn't like
her, but I guess it's
because of what she's
been going through.
Yeah. She, um, mentioned
some issues with work.
Really? What'd she tell you?
Honestly, not much.
Yeah, Julian told
someone in the office
that she got too close
to a doctor at Chastain,
and it turned into
more than she wanted.
I just hope he didn't
scare her off. She's good.
Anyway, thanks
for the directions.
Great news. Ophthalmology says
that Russell's eye
is looking good.
They're gonna keep him
overnight for observation.
Is that necessary?
It's gonna rack up a bill
- he won't be able to pay.
- Hey.
- Can I help? I doubt
you can do anything
about a bloated
hospital billing system
that charges 300
bucks for an aspirin.
Conrad, this is Dr. Shaw.
Alec, Dr. Hawkins.
- We're trying to get him
to run the clinic.
- Ah.
Can't get past the
toxic hospital culture,
the lack of transparency,
the endless documentation...
Don't forget about the upcoding,
fragmentation of care,
over-testing, overtreatment.
- Not helping.
- Look, we know
we're going up against Goliath.
And it's true, all
we got's a slingshot.
But we have damn good aim.
Well, it seems like a
waste of both your talents.
I do my own thing. Sorry.
Eh. No worries.
Just remember, wars are
fought on the battlefield,
not from the sidelines.
Look, let me buy
you a cup of coffee,
- introduce you to the team...
- No, I got to get back.
It's nice meeting you, Nic.
Damn. He was perfect.
I don't believe it.
Deflating the lung.
Dr. Voss, you
have spinal access.
I would have risked
the surgery, too.
Really? You would
risk it all just for a chance
of something better?
For the chance at
the life you want,
so would I.
Oh, hell.
The bone is weak from the chemo.
- I can't get fixation.
- What about a graft
from her hip?
We can't get it fast enough.
Dr. Okafor, what's our move?
Let me see her X-rays.
All right, show me her ribs.
They're less damaged. We
can make a graft from her ribs.
How long do you think it'll
take? Her echo was showing
severely depressed
ejection fraction.
We'll have to move fast, then.
Julian?
Hey, it's Devon.
Are you okay?
Look, I know I
shouldn't be here,
but, um, what you
said about QuoVadis...
we should talk about it.
We should talk about everything.
Just call me.
Please.
All right, he's gone.
Mr. Page?
Yeah, the place is clean.
Someone came by.
Yeah, same guy.
Security's on the way.
This office is a
shrine to your ego.
Lacking confidence without me?
Hardly. You have
about two minutes
to say whatever it is
you came here to say.
You know, words aren't
getting through to you, Randolph.
So I thought that this... might.
Really brings out the
desperation in your eyes,
don't you think?
Where did you get that?
That lawyer you found me,
he can dig up anything.
Now, tell me something.
What do you think is worse?
Trying to buy sex
from an undercover cop
or failing to
self-report your arrest
to the State Medical Board?
So, where's the copier?
I think everyone
- will want their very own.
- You're a monster.
Look around, Randolph.
Either you agree
to tell the jury
how wrong you were about me,
or all of this disappears.
You can call off your dogs.
Happy to show myself out.
♪ ♪
Nice of you to stop by.
Sorry.
Busy morning.
You're recovering well.
Hematocrit's stable.
Kidney function's good.
I'm a little surprised
you didn't kill me
when you had the chance.
You know, my first
year as an attending,
they brought a guy into
my OR with six bullet holes.
He killed two cops,
and everybody said
he deserved to die.
When I pick up a
scalpel, I don't care
who's on the other end.
That's the discipline.
I'm a surgeon first. That's
all that matters to me.
Oh, so you wanted to
kill me, but you were...
too principled.
That's charming.
You paged me?
You don't 911-page
me to come to you.
That's Natalie Ramirez.
Lane Hunter ruined her life.
Destroyed her
heart and her spine
with chemo that she didn't need.
And now she may die in that OR.
And she's one of the lucky ones.
You think I don't care? I do.
Then why was
Lane in your office?
Guess what. I am sick and tired
of you thinking you have
any right to question me.
You're a resident.
Who I would love to fire.
Except your father,
whose life I just saved...
Thank you very much...
Would fire me.
So you got me down
here to see this woman.
I've seen her.
Good for you.
Made my day.
If Lane gets off,
how many others
like Natalie will there be?
This should do the trick.
Spinal nerves
still viable.
She's in V tach again.
Wet laps.
The anesthesia
is too much for her
heart. We need to stop.
Get the cage and screws ready.
- Clear.
- Just let me finish fusing.
- Clear!
- It's in.
On three. One, two, three.
Clear.
She needs double
sequential defibrillation.
Give her another 150 amio.
Start a procainamide drip.
Clear. And go.
She doesn't have the time
you need to finish the spine.
We need to take her back
to the ICU, let her stabilize.
We do that, she's paralyzed.
We don't and she's dead.
Can you stabilize her here?
Central line to assess
the cardiac index
and output numbers. How
long would it take, Okafor?
For most, five
minutes. For you, four.
And if she needs
ventricular assist?
20 to deploy percutaneously.
Her spine can stay in a
sterile dressing while you work.
I need 30 to finish, then
we get her back to ICU.
All right. Heart first,
then spine, if
she's still stable.
And if her spinal
cord is still viable.
Nic?
You're here.
Grant applications.
All day...
I've been trying to
get you to join us.
And it has been...
a day.
There's so much I can't fix.
But this, this clinic...
I can do.
And I'll do it without you.
Don't get me wrong...
What you're doing here is great.
But is it really
about the patients?
Seems like...
you'd rather rail
against a broken system
than actually
fight to change it.
You serious?
I spent the better part
of my life in service.
All I do is fight.
Well, maybe not hard enough.
So, this is about one
- of your employees?
- Julian Booth.
Um... she never
showed up for work today
and is not the type
to just disappear.
Well, do you have
reason to believe
that someone
could have hurt her?
There's a guy you
may want to look into.
Um, he's an intern at Chastain.
His name is Devon Pravesh.
This is her work phone.
We found it at her desk.
Mm, I'm alive.
And you're gonna stay that way.
We had to place
a ventricular device
to keep your heart
pumping effectively,
and we'll schedule a transplant
eval when you're healed.
Right now it's
working perfectly.
And after PT
and rehab, you'll be
able to walk again.
Will I be able to go
back to the police force?
We don't know that yet.
But...
you are gonna lose that cane.
That much I can promise you.
I hate that thing.
You deserve to be happy.
So do you.
Your sister
would've wanted that.
Thanks, guys.
Easy on the hot water.
Sit when you pee.
You may use my condiments,
but do not touch my alcohol.
I would never.
Outside of the guest
room, it's either clothing
or a bathrobe
with full coverage.
I don't want any surprises.
Why are you helping me?
Because you need it.
Wayne Jackson.
In asystole for 15 minutes
before anyone noticed.
Kathy Mars. The hospital
billed her 12 grand
for a damn bee sting.
Matthew Teter came in
with stage IV colon cancer.
He would've lived if
he'd had early detection.
Every time I thought I got
close to making things better,
I saw another patient
lose to a broken system.
So, yes, it is about
the patients for me.
But you're crazy if you
think you can change things.
Maybe I am.
I like crazy.
- Yeah, sure.
- Here.
We'll just, uh, get these...
So the pay sucks.
Beyond sucks.
And Chastain could slash
our funding at any time?
Without warning.
I won't be bossed around.
You start tomorrow.
I start now.
Congratulations.
You graduated from the ICU.
Eh. Yeah, unfortunately,
not from clear liquids.
You need something for the pain?
No.
No, I want to be alert for this.
Son, I've been fighting
this disease for a while now.
I got lucky this time,
but it only gets
worse from here.
Dr. Simmons says you will
be back on semisolid foods
in a week. In two to three days,
you will be out of the hospital
and starting physical therapy.
- You will get
your strength back.
- We both know
my chances for a meaningful
recovery become less
and less with each
surgery I have.
I need you to stay positive.
Patients who believe they'll
recover have better outcomes.
Positive thinking won't
change what's happening
to this body of mine.
I'd like to formalize things.
You want an advanced directive.
If something like this
happens to me again,
I don't want my life prolonged
by aggressive measures.
That's a long way off.
I'm serious.
I need to know you'll
respect my wishes.
Of course.
Thank you.
♪ ♪
Dear Board of Directors,
Leading this hospital
has been a joy and a privilege.
However, in the coming days,
you will learn of a terrible
mistake I have made.
I betrayed your trust.
You deserve someone
who will always put
this community first.
And I am deeply ashamed
that I have not always
been that person.
I put my trust in
the wrong person.
Coming.
And I take full
responsibility for my actions.
I will step down and step away.
I hereby resign as CEO
and Chief of Surgery.
Dr. Randolph Bell.
Uh, Dr. Bell?
You need to see this.
Grayson, what?
It's the news.
Shots fired in a Buckhead hotel.
Police report they
found the body
of accused murderer
Dr. Lane Hunter.
Recently out on bail
after several months
in the Atlanta Detention Center,
Hunter was arrested
for first-degree murder
and involuntary manslaughter,
as well as insurance fraud
and money laundering.
No suspects have
been named in her death.
In related news, victim
rights advocates...
Um... thank you, Grayson.
You can go.
Not stepping forward,
not commenting on the death.
Many of them vocal just
months ago, and now they're not...
Captioned by Media
Access Group at WGBH