People are really romantic
about the beginnings of things.
Fresh start.
Clean slate.
A world of possibility.
But no matter what new
adventure you're embarking on...
you're still you.
Well, I am going to
get ready for work.
- Next time.
- It's not gonna work.
A baby doesn't want to set
up shop in a hostile uterus.
It's gonna happen. We just have
to keep doing it until we get it right.
- Right?
- Right.
You bring you into every
new beginning in your life.
So how different
can it possibly be?
Damn it.
Torres! Come on! Let's go!
Coming!
What the hell?
Oh! Good morning!
- What are you doing here?
- I bought out our subletters.
I'm moving back in. Hooray!
They weren't your subletters.
They were my subletters.
Well, now, um,
I'm your subletter.
Hooray?
My lack of interest in
seeing you is not a strategy.
I'm not, uh... I'm not playing
hard to get. I don't want to see you
because I turned my life upside
down for you, and you walked away
because for a week, I was
cranky. You're untrustworthy,
so I don't want to see
you. You're self-centered,
so I don't want to see you.
I am 100 percent certain
that if I let you back into my
life again, you will hurt me again.
So I don't want to see you.
This isn't a ploy. I'm not pouting.
I don't want you in my life!
Get your crap out
of my apartment.
- Hm.
- It's good that she's mad. It means she cares, right?
Try again. Could be a false
negative. Maybe you tried too early.
- What is it, day ten?
- Yeah.
Totally early. Pee on a
bunch of different sticks.
- Don't let the one stick win.
- It's a scientific test.
I hardly think I can
bend it to my will.
I'm doing three surgeries today,
did four yesterday. I'm unstoppable.
And you got defeated by a piece
of plastic covered in urine? Buck up.
What is this,
everybody got paged?
It's that time of year again.
- The chicks have hatched.
- Is that some sort of a code?
Those chicks.
Oh. First year med students.
Too dumb to find the toilet.
Good morning. Behind me stand
the interns and residents of tomorrow.
Today you will show them
what it's like to be a surgeon.
When you go into surgery,
they go into surgery.
When they have a
question, you will answer.
It's like court-ordered
community service.
I'd rather be picking up trash
off the side of the highway.
Fred Wilson,
you're with Dr. Yang.
Kira Donnelley, with Dr. Grey.
Hudson Powell, with Dr. Kepner.
- Laurel Pinson...
- Mine.
Laurel, you're with Dr. Karev.
Edward Taylor, Dr. Avery.
Really?
- Kim Peterson...
- Hey, man.
Dr. Yang. Um...
You were out of the game for a while
so you'll be with me on my service today.
- I'd like to monitor
your progress.
- I think you'll be pleased.
I don't doubt it.
I will be picking my chief
resident in a few months,
and you're still a
prime candidate.
The race for chief
resident is on?
- Since when?
- How long have you
been evaluating us?
Since your first day here.
- Sorry.
- When you gotta go,
you gotta go.
OK. We are with, uh,
Shepherd today. He's Neuro.
- Is he nice?
- Uh, he's my husband,
so I have to say he's nice. But
he's also a damn good surgeon.
Oh, thank God. I'm just glad you're
not one of those "obsessed with my job
- but cold
and dead inside," surgeons.
- We have rounds.
Henry Burton has Von Hippel-Lindau
disease and a pheochromocytoma.
It's extremely rare, causes
blood pressures to skyrocket
- and it's treated
with alpha blockers.
- Well, look at that. He reads.
- Sorry...
- Med students are like children
at the dinner table, to
be seen and not heard.
- Dr. Yang.
- Sir.
- Good to see you, Henry.
- Thanks.
- I wore my best gown
for the occasion.
- I am Dr. Bailey.
I'll be working with
Dr. Webber today.
I feel like I already
know you, Dr. Bailey.
Eli here has been
telling me all about you.
Don't worry, I didn't
tell him everything.
Oh! Hi, I did not know
that you were on this case.
- Sure you didn't.
- No, I didn't...
- Bailey?
- Sorry, sir. Um...
Where was I? Dr. Yang
will run, uh, scans,
- and then we'll be ready to go.
- Sounds like an idyllic day.
- Who's he?
- Nobody.
I mean, uh, he's... He's
here observing, ignore him.
Mr. Wilson's a first-year med student
and Dr. Yang is showing him the ropes.
Have you told Mr. Wilson about the
most interesting aspects of the case?
- He's been brought up to speed.
- - Did she tell you that Henry here
originally was denied this
surgery because he was uninsured?
Um... No. I mean,
she didn't mention...
That's too bad
about the insurance.
I got married. I'm on
my wife's insurance now.
Congratulations. Your
girlfriend finally wised up.
- Uh, nope.
- Oh, uh...
Sorry. Um, I'll come back later.
No, it's OK, I've got
the, uh, forms right here.
Just a few signatures
and we're good to go.
Great, great. Um, I'll have them
back to you in a couple hours.
Great, thanks.
That's my wife. Upgrade, right?
The ex was a cater waiter.
- Dr. Torres.
- What?
- Nothing.
- Well, you said my name.
Just as a, you know, "Good
morning," type of thing.
Where's the stupid meat wagon?
- Morning, Dr. Hunt. Dr...
- Don't.
Brady Sullivan, 32,
stable vital signs,
complains of neck and back
pain, possible crush injuries.
- He was trampled by a horse.
- Horse?
A team of horses. Like,
three horses, if that helps you.
Please, don't let him
die on our wedding day.
- Push five of morphine.
- We were going
downtown this morning
- to sign domestic
partnership papers.
- A lot of bruising here.
I had a horse-drawn carriage
to pick us up from City Hall.
And bagpipers,
because Brady is Scottish
and he really likes
being Scottish.
I feel tenderness in C6.
Get X-Ray in here stat.
Brady, I'm so sorry.
The bagpipers started up,
and they spooked the
horses and they ran...
Over me! They all ran
over me, Kyle! Bagpipes?
Exam shows weakness in lower
extremities, got diminished reflexes.
- Move. I can't work.
- Dude!
- Sorry. Sorry.
- I agreed to the tuxes,
but horses?
- It was supposed
to be a surprise.
- It was.
OK. Looks like L4 and L5 are affected.
Page Shepherd. Get him ready for CT.
- Sir, I need you
out of here now.
- I want to stay with him.
I have a right to stay with him.
Avery, get him out of here now.
- Move!
- Sorry.
OK, everybody out now!
Now, before I have
to take someone out!
You married a patient
to give him insurance?
Have you lost your mind?
Insurance fraud is a serious offense.
According to the National
Medical Anti-Fraud Association,
it's not insurance fraud.
It's just frowned upon.
It's highly unethical. You're
a doctor, for God's sakes!
The medical community
is fairly split on this.
Is it more unethical to deny
a patient life-saving care,
or to marry a patient and give
him that care? It can get murky.
Don't you have
somewhere to be, Dr. Grey?
I'm on Dr. Altman's
service today.
We are doctors.
We save people's lives every
day without marrying them.
- You marry someone you love.
- Well, I love him. I do.
I mean, I love him so much.
Dr. Altman, this isn't a joke.
I appreciate your concern, chief.
But it's done. He has insurance.
You're his doctor, and
now you can save his life.
Please don't tell the chief I said this,
but I think what you did was awesome.
I mean, I get it. She's got a
hang-up about me being perfect.
Everything comes easy for
me, and I don't have any flaws.
Now that I've clearly made a mistake,
she's gonna pound the crap out of it.
- So you don't
think you're perfect?
- No. I have lots of flaws.
I'm competitive. I'm a workaholic.
I smoke when I'm stressed.
- It's disgusting.
- Sure she'd love
to hear all those.
Along with any other real
faults you come up with.
You were that guy on Seattle Med,
right? Who made a trachea from scratch?
Oh. Stem cells. Not
scratch. But, yeah, that's me.
Bad-ass. I'm really interested
in regenerative medicine.
Yeah? I'll show you a bladder
we're growing in the lab after rounds.
- OK.
- Ladies first.
- You're her teacher, Alex.
- Only for the day.
Sarah Cassidy, 15,
has a rare genetic condition,
called Treacher Collins Syndrome
which caused her to be
born without cheekbones,
leaving her orbital floor unprotected
and vulnerable to eye injury.
Which means the only
extracurriculars I can sign up for
are the ones that don't
involve things flying at my face.
- She rocks the chess club.
- - I just wanna play sports.
- You bowl, honey.
- Not really a sport, Dad.
Do you mind if I take a look?
Scoot over a little
so Laurel can see.
Sarah, we're going to
take pieces from your skull
and transplant them into your
face to rebuild new cheekbones.
Do you have any
questions or concerns?
Volleyball tryouts are in
two months. Can I try out?
Hey.
Sorry I'm late.
Here are the forms.
- You are officially insured.
- Amazing.
And I have nothing to give you
in return. Wait. Are you hungry?
- You want a fruit cup?
- Henry, you needed insurance.
- I was happy to give it.
- Come on. Take the fruit cup.
Fine. I'm starving.
- That's disgusting.
- I wouldn't eat it
if I were dying.
I should go. Um... Good
luck with your surgery.
Thank you, Dr. Altman.
Wow, volleyball player!
Digging into her skull will tack on
an extra year of healing, you know.
Maybe she'll play in
a couple years then.
Did you consider the stem
cell surgery they did in Cincinnati
- using a cadaver bone graft?
- It's too experimental.
I think it's worth
considering, given her age.
I think considering her age, it's best to
be conservative. I'll see you in surgery.
Can we, uh, go in
and see the scans?
Pretty small room.
Let's just wait.
He's got tandem lesions.
A fracture
translocation at L4 and 5
and a unilateral jumped
facet at C5 and 6.
- What does that mean?
- One of the joints in his neck
was knocked out of place,
and he's got a broken back.
- That one's your husband?
- What? Yes.
Can I just say, jackpot? You
get to be at work with that all day,
and go home to him at night?
I'm gonna go see
where they're at.
I'm worried about his neck.
I don't think he should be
intubated with a cervical injury.
I could do a little traction. Snap
it back in before we do surgery.
- Hell of a wedding day.
- Hm.
They say if you want to piss
off God, just tell him your plans.
Dude! Out!
That's the biggest
pheo I've ever seen.
- Is it infiltrating
the kidney there?
- That's the spleen, right?
- No, that's the liver.
- Oh.
- OK. Is that the tumor?
- That's a gallbladder.
- Wait, really?
- Cross my heart, hope to die.
The image is reversed on
an MRI. It's confusing at first.
I'm sure Dr. Yang can remember
seeing her first MRI and empathize.
Empathy is a good
quality for a chief resident,
- don't you think, Dr. Bailey?
- Oh, I do, sir.
This is from the feet looking
up, so that's the kidney,
that's the adrenal gland
and that is the tumor.
That's the tumor? It's
eating into the kidney.
Right. I was hoping we'd only
have to remove the adrenal gland,
but it looks like I'm gonna have
to take Henry's kidney as well.
Dr. Shepherd will decompress
the nerve roots from behind,
and then I will put in a graft
and a plate for stabilization.
But, before any
of that can happen,
we need to move your
neck back into place.
- Fun.
- I'll be done
before you know it.
Sir, you probably don't
want to be here for this.
- No, I'm staying.
- Kyle, don't overdo it. You always...
- There's gonna be a lot of...
- I'm staying. It's my fault he's here.
If he's in pain, I'll be here with
him. Stop trying to kick me out.
No, you're right.
You should stay.
Hold his hand.
- OK? OK, Brady.
- Thank you.
- You ready? OK.
- OK.
One, two, three.
Oh, my God!
- How'd my tumor look?
- We don't have the result
from all the scans yet.
I've had 11 operations
in the past three years.
I have tumors removed as a
hobby. I know how this works.
You know the results but you
can't tell me. So give me a hint.
I mean, look, are we talking
marble? Grapefruit? Basketball?
Dr. Webber will be up shortly
to discuss the results of the scan.
- Come on, Fred, what'd you see?
- Oh, he's
a first-year med student.
- He can't even read a scan.
- Then why does he look like
he's gonna piss himself?
Look at his face. He's sweating.
- What's going on? Am I gonna die?
- No, I'm not... My face...
Don't let me... I'm just...
Like she said, pretend I'm...
Stop talking.
- What'd you see, Fred?
- Nothing. It's gonna be OK. Truly.
My uncle had his kidney
removed and he's...
- What?
- Oh, God, I'm sorry.
- Stop talking. Mr...
- You have to remove my kidney?
Do you? Do you have
to take out my kidney?
The tumor on your adrenal gland
has compromised your kidney.
It's enough damage
that we need to remove it.
I know it sounds like a lot,
but it really is our best option.
Could we ask Dr. Altman
what she thinks?
Dr. Altman is a cardiothoracic
surgeon. This isn't her area of expertise.
I know, but...
She did this amazing
thing for me. I trust her.
I'd feel a whole lot better if I
knew that she was on board.
- I've got a consult waiting.
- We'll be quick. Karev?
We put together some stats
comparing the surgical
options for Sarah.
As you can see, this slide
shows the donor site morbidities
associated with using
Sarah's own skull.
- Next slide.
- And here you can
see the pros and cons
of using skull bone versus cadaver
bone. You can see that the benefits
- of cadaver bone
are quite extensive...
- Turn the lights on.
- We just got started.
- Lights. Now.
Mark, I know what
the research says.
So there's a chance of some
donor graft complications.
Complications?
No. You, come here.
We do your procedure,
we'd incise here and here.
- What's happening?
- Stand still.
There's risk of hitting
brain, causing a hematoma.
But we take the cadaver
route, you avoid that completely,
which means all of this...
- doesn't even get touched.
- She's a child.
And that procedure is experimental.
So as the lead doctor on this case,
let me be clear. We're
doing the surgery as planned.
You're a crappy listener.
Add that to the list.
- What?
- Just saying,
there's more wrong
with you than the
fact that you smoke.
I probably shouldn't have used
permanent marker. My apologies.
Mrs. Burton?
Mrs. Henry Burton?
Your husband requested that I talk
to you about his upcoming operation.
We would like to
remove the kidney.
Well, a man can live without a
kidney. If that's your recommendation.
Funny, because that's exactly
what I would recommend,
but, apparently, my
recommendation as chief of surgery
with over 30 years of general surgery
experience under my belt isn't enough.
He would like your
recommendation,
the recommendation of a cardio
surgeon who happens to be his wife.
I see.
Yeah, I agree with
your recommendation.
Go...
This is a totally inappropriate
relationship! Totally inappropriate!
You want to talk to me about
inappropriate relationships?
Everywhere I look in this hospital,
there's inappropriate relationships.
Grey and Shepherd.
Hunt and Yang.
- The other Grey and Sloan.
- Dr. Bailey's dating a nurse.
- Taking full advantage.
- Oh!
Ignore him. We are not dating.
- No plus sign yet?
- No. And I'm so tired
of peeing on sticks.
It's exhausting.
OK, you think peeing is exhausting?
Wait till you have a mewling,
poo-covered infant hanging
off of your boobs 24/7.
Why is my baby
gonna be poo-covered?
OK, what is that about?
That's right, do another
loop there. Beautiful!
You're a fast learner.
I have a good teacher.
Come on, you
blame him? She's hot.
Don't be a pig.
He's being gross.
- Not to mention unprofessional.
- Well, the thong
is unprofessional.
- Damn it!
- Unprofessional!
What is wrong with them? I was
never that dumb in med school.
- They're weak and gutless.
- Boy crazy.
- Oblivious.
- Slutty.
Wow. You all sound really old.
Hey, I know I'm not perfect. I
know sometimes I don't listen.
I'm sorry about that. So
here I am, ready to listen.
- Oh. You're ready to listen.
- Like a priest at confession.
You wanna hear what I'm
saying, and really take it in?
- And try to give me
what I want?
- Yeah. I really... I really do.
Get your crap out
of my apartment.
Let's bandage him up and get
him ready for the next phase.
Kira, do you want to take a
look at these sutures before...?
- Kira?
- Sorry?
- Are you texting?
- Oh, I was just telling
my boyfriend about this.
- Can I send him a picture, do you think?
- - No.
All right, everybody,
take your places.
- Can I help roll him over?
- Edward, move!
OK, we're gonna roll him on
my count. Everybody ready?
One, two, three.
- He's got a junctional rhythm.
- Is there a pulse with that?
All right. Pulse is
thready, but it's there.
He's hypotensive.
Grey, hang some FFP.
- Let's push one of epi.
- Lost his pulse. Starting compressions.
He could have delayed internal
bleeding. Get ready for a laparotomy.
I need to get in there! Gown me!
- What about
hyperkalemia?
- All right. Out, now!
I saw the monitors when you
turned him. He had peaked T waves,
then a widened QRS,
then a sine wave rhythm...
- Dude!
- Push two of calcium,
two D50 and ten units
of regular insulin IV!
Uh, they just taught
us that on Friday, so...
- What's your name?
- Edward, sir.
Good save, Edward.
OK, tell me about your
cadaver bone thing. For Sarah.
Really? Look at you!
Did somebody maybe listen to
what someone else had to say?
OK, I get it, I suck, I'm a
stuck-up self-righteous bitch,
and Callie wants nothing
to do with me ever again.
But can you just drop it and
tell me about the damn surgery?
We'll inject the donor
bones with stem cells.
This way the bones will grow
and conform to Sarah's face.
There's a much lower chance
they'll degrade over time.
Which is key, especially
if you want to play sports.
Cool. Random dead
guy's bones in my cheeks?
My teammates will
call me zombie face.
But it's still highly
experimental.
- Jared...
- What about the original plan?
This surgery is more advanced
and would decrease the
chance of complications
that could make the
kind of sports Sarah wants
to play out of the question.
It's just sports, honey.
You're good at other things.
- You paint. You draw.
- Because that's all
I've been allowed to do.
I'm a tomboy, but I've never
been able to be a tomboy.
I know you want me to
draw and paint and bowl,
but I want to play volleyball
and softball and soccer.
- I don't know.
- - If you guys don't let me
take this chance to
be who I really am,
I'm gonna be more
prone to teen depression,
eating disorders,
drug addiction.
- Is that what you want?
- You are too smart
for your own good.
Because all I do is read.
Let me be a dumb jock. Mom, Dad?
Please.
Dividing and ligating
the renal artery and vein.
Beautiful. Nice work, Dr. Yang.
Mr. Wilson? Would you like to
take a look at the tumor up close?
Oh... Sure. I mean, yes.
- Yes.
- OK. So these
are the hilar vessels.
- My med student's gonna faint.
- Catch him, people.
- Thank you.
- Sorry about that, sir.
Oh, it's fine. That's
exactly why I like seeing
first-year med students
here once a year.
Reminds me where
I started. Humility.
That's another good
quality for a chief resident.
Wouldn't you say, Dr. Bailey?
It was always one
of my best qualities.
Also, it's funny
when they fall down.
Sir, you want to
take a look at this.
He's doing fine. His
spine's been stabilized.
- And he'll be awake soon.
- He's fine? He'll be OK?
His recovery will be slow. And
painful. You should be prepared for that.
This was supposed to be
the best day of our lives.
You think I'm silly, I know.
With the horses
and the bagpipes.
So does he.
We don't get marriage
in Washington,
we get domestic partnerships.
We get to go to City Hall
and stand in line and
sign some papers.
Mail it in, if you're
even more romantic.
So, call me crazy, but...
I just wanted the big day
that everybody else gets.
And I fought for it. I
organized rallies. I...
stood in the cold
outside the State House.
I had some Neanderthal throw hot
coffee on me. I fought for a wedding.
And waited.
And they still said, "No."
So when we got tired of waiting, and...
Brady and I went to go sign the papers,
I wanted it to be special.
He's the best thing that's
ever happened to me.
And I wanted it to feel like that.
Not like some trip to the DMV.
I wanted it to be special.
Instead, I nearly killed him.
Things don't go the
way you want them to.
Ever.
Come on. Let's go see him.
You paged me, chief?
We found a cyst
on Henry's pancreas
that's in danger of rupturing.
Removing it means removing
a large portion of his pancreas
which would make Henry a
diabetic. We didn't discuss
- that possibility with him.
- OK.
Do you think that's
something he could live with?
- I don't know.
- - I hate to ask you on the spot,
Dr. Altman, but
technically you are the wife,
and you are also his
emergency contact person.
So I am asking you, do you think he has the
support system to manage a very tricky disease?
- I don't know.
- Is there someone
we could call?
- A next of kin? Anyone?
- I don't know.
You've signed a marriage
license, and you haven't asked him
the most basic questions on
how he wants to live or die?
Do I have your permission
to act as I see fit?
Yes.
That's all, Dr. Altman.
So... did you get my note?
- Eli...
- I guess you got my note.
What do you think?
I think you're
dirty, is what I think.
You wanna be dirty with me?
Show me those on-call rooms you
doctors are always having sex in?
I'm going home. Mm!
If you change your
mind, I get off in an hour.
I have a PhD.
Um...
After college, I got a PhD. And
then I went to medical school.
And I'm number one in my class.
I know you think I'm
an idiot, but I'm not.
I've seen this stuff in textbooks,
I've just never seen it up close before.
- Whatever. Think
what you want of me.
- You wanna not be an idiot?
Back up your resident,
no matter what.
Never undercut them
in front of their boss.
When a patient asks you for information
you're not allowed to give them,
stall, or say you don't know.
Just wait long enough
until the attending gets there.
The attending takes the lead.
And if you ever panic or
feel faint in an OR again,
just stop thinking, "There's
a body open on a table
in front of you."
Just stop thinking.
And take a deep
breath. It usually helps.
Wow.
Now, I feel like an ass.
Just disregard my evaluation.
What evaluation?
We turned in
evaluations on you guys.
What did you say?
Um...
I might have used the
word, uh, "heartless."
Among others, there were...
- Thank you, doctor.
- OK. Lay it on me.
- Lay what on you?
- The speech.
You know, "The chief
is right, and what you did
- was totally
inappropriate," speech.
- Oh, uh, the speech.
- Yeah.
- Um...
OK, I am not dating a
nurse. We are not dating.
But we are having... fun.
I... I look at him
and he's pretty,
but there's no
future. He's just...
I mean, I would not have him to
my house or introduce him to my child
because who knows
what he would do...
He left a dirty note
for me in a chart.
Now, what if the chief opened
the chart and found the...?
It's inappropriate! That's
what he is. He is inappropriate!
But I'm gonna go with it,
because, you know... Why not?
That's my attitude these
days, why the hell not?
The cadaver bone doesn't have
any bone-growing cells or proteins in it,
which is why we're
drilling holes in it.
- Would you like to hold it?
- - What do you think you're doing?
Teaching.
Dr. Karev, do you really
think it's appropriate
for someone with so little experience
to be handling these cadaver bones?
- Relax.
- Karev, Kepner's right.
Your student's allowed
to observe. That's all.
Stubborn. Passive aggressive.
Uh, I resent obligations. Just tell
me when I'm getting warm here.
I choose her over you in the
divorce. You know that, right?
Of course, of course. That's because
you two have been friends forever.
And you and I are like... siblings. We
fight, we get on each other's nerves,
but... point is, you're
like family to me, Mark.
I mean that.
Patronizing. Add
that to the list.
Periosteal elevator,
please. Thank you.
Hi.
Here, have some water.
Just tell me.
There was a large
cyst on your pancreas.
When they got in there, it was
necrotic and close to rupturing.
They called me
to make a decision.
Because you listed me
as your emergency
contact person.
Oh, what did you decide?
They removed a large
portion of your pancreas,
which means that you might
be an insulin-dependent diabetic
for the rest of your life.
It's gonna be a very
big adjustment for you.
I'm a man who has a
green thumb for tumors.
I'm familiar with adjustments.
- I really am... I'm sorry.
- You're also angry.
That I put you as my
emergency contact.
This was supposed
to be about paperwork.
Life and death decisions
wasn't... It wasn't part of our deal.
I'm 42-years old.
I lost my... mom and dad
four and... five years
ago, respectively.
My sister lives in Prague,
which is a longer story
than you want to hear.
And when I talk to her, I
tend to err on the side of,
"How are the kids?" and
"Everything here is great."
Because she's broke, and...
because my health thing is...
It's exhausting.
I used to have a best friend, but
he married a woman who made sure
that I knew that my health
thing was exhausting.
And because I kept maxing
out my insurance policies,
I had to switch jobs about
nine times in the past five years,
so I've always just been the new
guy in the cubicle by the bathroom
who takes a lot...
takes a lot of sick days.
That's not a guy people
make friends with.
It's not my intention to
make you feel sorry for me.
It's my intention
to apologize and...
and to explain
that, in this city...
you're the closest
thing I have to a friend.
That's why I put you down
as my emergency contact.
Not because of
the fake marriage.
But because I
consider you a friend.
I might be a diabetic?
Yeah.
- That sucks.
- Yeah.
Hey. How you feeling?
Ow.
Brady, I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
- I just wanted it to be...
- Special, I know.
You always do.
Shut up, I have to say this
- before I fall asleep again.
- Brady... please.
I forgive you.
Do you hear that?
So stop apologizing.
And please do not
try to make it up to me.
'Cause you'll kill me for sure.
I love you.
He's up, if you want to
do a post-op assessment.
- OK, thanks. Good night.
- How long does the post-op
- assessment take?
- Kira, why don't
you just go home.
- No, it's cool.
- You're obviously
not interested
- in learning anything.
- I am. I totally am.
- Today was really interesting.
- Really? Because
you had the chance
to observe a very rare surgery
today, and you looked at your phone
the whole entire time. You had the
opportunity to ask me any question
you wanted, and instead you
asked me about my husband.
You've been sneaking
off to the bathroom all day,
and I saw the pregnancy
tests in your locker.
So me asking about your husband?
I was just trying to
get on your good side.
Whatever.
You're kidding. They
were evaluating us?
Don't worry, no one will read
them. They'll just get filed away
in a room next to the morgue.
"Dr. Yang lacked patience
and basic compassion.
Dr. Kepner,
unwilling to delegate.
Dr. Avery placed his own learning
opportunities before my own.
And Dr. Grey seemed to have
a lot going on personally today."
The only one of you who seemed to
actually teach today was Dr. Karev.
The rest of you
failed. Big time.
I hate that guy.
I don't know. OK?
I don't know what my worst faults
are. I try not to think about them.
I'm not proud of
that. So just tell me.
What the hell do I have to cop to, to
make her give me another chance?
You bail.
When things get hard,
you bail.
"Unwilling to delegate?"
I am a great delegator.
It's key to why
I'm so organized.
Oh, hi. Uh, just wanted
to get some water.
Well, the glasses
are in that cabinet.
Ow!
Hey.
So, how'd you do today?
Med student screwed me.
I did pretty good.
- Want some dinner?
- Mm-hm.
So I peed on ten sticks today.
- Ten?
- And I stole
them from the clinic
because they're
$15 at the store.
So you're a thief, is that
what you're telling me?
A barren thief.
Look, it takes time
getting pregnant.
Not for some people. Some
people hit it on the first try.
- Those people
are overachievers.
- I am an overachiever.
That's the whole thing. I spent
my whole day peeing on sticks
and not teaching my med student so
I'm getting my ass kicked in this race
for chief resident, so I'm
not overachieving at anything.
I used to be hardcore.
Now, I'm softcore.
Did we just start
talking about porn?
- Stop it, I'm upset.
- You're just upset
because we haven't made a baby.
And I say practice makes perfect.
I bail. OK? When things
get hard, I walk away.
And maybe it's because
I grew up an Army brat,
and we moved every 18 months.
Maybe I never learned to commit.
But I'm here now.
And I'm staying because I'm gonna
fight to make sure that you know
that I'm committed to this thing.
I'm not perfect, but neither are you.
And you want to talk about faults?
How about not being able to forgive?
At some point, you're
gonna have to forgive me.
And it may as well be now
because I'm in love with you, Calliope,
and you are in love with me and
all I'm asking for is one more chance.
It's all anybody wants, right?
Clean slate? A new beginning?
- You want another chance?
- Yes. More than anything. I want another chance.
Like that's gonna be any easier.
Ask the guy pushing
the boulder up the hill.
Nothing's easy
about starting over.
Today, I found out
that I'm pregnant.
With Mark's baby.
How about now?
Nothing at all.