Previously on
The Good Doctor...
Dalisay! I know I
didn't show you enough respect,
and I didn't make enough effort to
see things from your point of view,
but I want to change.
How about dinner?
You pick me up at
7:30, Saturday.
We can try that Filipino place.
I think maybe you and I
could be gifts to each other.
And we should be open to that.
I have no idea what it looks
like for us to move forward.
We'll figure it out.
It's a perfect practice run
for when your own comes along.
I'm going off my IVF meds.
I'm not doing another cycle.
Eden, she's what I've been
waiting for. She's my daughter.
I thought it was Dr. Glassman's
cancer returning,
but it is damage to Dr. Glassman's
brain as a result of a mini-stroke.
It is permanent.
He shouldn't be doing
surgery anymore.
Ah.
Two weeks to Peanut Day!
Yes.
So you're making
lasagna for breakfast?
It's going in the freezer.
I've packed my hospital bag,
written my Birth Plan,
and soon all I'll
have on my list
is to do my nails and relax.
73% of births happen
before the due date,
so you need to start
relaxing immediately.
'Cause if there's one thing
you can cram, it's relaxation.
Yes.
Have you heard
anything from Glassy?
Hmm. Oh. No.
He might be mad
when he finds out
you went to Lim with
his brain scans.
It was very important
for his future,
both medically and
professionally.
Well, it's not just
the information.
It's the whole
behind-his-back thing.
He wouldn't listen to
me, so I had no choice.
I think you did the
right thing, but...
just talk to him?
- Okay.
- Yeah.
I've had a stroke.
Yes. A small one.
- I should probably give you some time.
- Yeah, you should.
He, uh, hit the brakes
instead of the gas
and thumped his head
on the steering wheel.
I'm a shoo-in for the Dumbest
Patient of the Day.
Oh, it's too early
to hand that out.
You want to hear
about a dumb patient?
Doctor says to her he's
waiting for her X-ray.
She says, "Well, that's weird. I
never dated anybody named Ray."
A little too early
for that, too.
The laceration's
superficial.
Couple stitches, and
you're good to go.
- Yay!
- You sure?
He hit his head pretty hard.
Maybe you should run some tests?
There's no sign of fracture,
closed head injury,
or brain bleed.
Dr. Murphy?
It's not about the accident.
He's been behaving very strangely
for the last six months.
Oh. He's alert, responsive,
engaging socially...
Which is nothing like him.
His whole life, he's
been... terrible.
Constantly fired, been
through four divorces,
estranged from all of
his kids, except me.
He was always just... a dick.
Then he changed.
Now he's telling dad
jokes, asks about my day.
He gave me a birthday present.
He is a different person.
This does not sound to
me like a medical issue.
But I will order a brain MRI because it
would be very interesting if it were!
Are you mad at me
for going to Dr. Lim
with your brain scan?
Yeah, a little bit.
But maybe you saved
my life, so...
I didn't think you were,
but Lea said you might be,
so we were both right.
What are you going to do?
About your job?
I don't know, Shaun.
I just found out I had a stroke.
I-I'm still reeling
a little bit.
Maybe when I decide,
I'll let you know.
Okay.
I hear it beating!
Wow. Dr. Wolke has a heart?
I wasn't sure
myself, to be honest.
I have one, too.
Now, that, we all knew.
Hey, Nico.
The doctors are
gonna take Olivia
to get some ice cream and
you to get some tests.
Followed, of course,
by some ice cream.
- Thanks, Dr. Marcus.
- Yeah.
Get some ice cream.
Nico's sarcoma has invaded his
thigh and hip, here and here.
But luckily, there's
no signs of metastasis,
which means we can
debulk the tumor.
How much time would
that give him?
Nine months, maybe even a year.
We could take him to Salzburg.
With Nico's illness
and all his surgeries,
he's never really had
a great Christmas.
He found this photo of the Salzburg
Christmas Market in Austria.
He talks about it all the time.
This surgery could
just get us there.
Not "just."
Th-There's always
medical advances.
We have to be realistic, Seb.
And you have to keep
a positive attitude.
This is good news.
Some final pre-op testing,
and Nico can have
his surgery tomorrow.
Come on.
Be reasonable, please.
You've been fed,
changed, swaddled.
I have walked. I have rocked.
I have bounced.
I've worn you on my front,
on my back, on my hip.
Shh.
Please, Eden. You
have to go to sleep.
Shh.
Be reasonable, please. Shh.
Okay, okay, okay, okay.
So... you gonna tell me or not?
- Hmm?
- Where are we going tomorrow?
Oh, it's a surprise.
Hmm.
As in, you have no idea.
It's been
harder than I thought.
All right? A movie's
too predictable,
an escape room is too dorky,
and, well, dinner
at my place is out.
I'll pick something.
No, see, I don't want
you to deal with this.
It's supposed to be fun, Danny,
which it will be, once we
get over this first hump.
So let me do it, okay?
And, yes, I said "hump,"
which I regret saying
for multiple reasons.
His daughter was right.
I will take ace inhibitors,
aspirin, statins
to help reduce the
likelihood of future stroke
to near absolute zero.
I will reduce my
workload by 25%.
Any operation over six hours,
I will have a backup in the OR.
I will even eat more broccoli.
I'm not really
comfortable with you
doing any surgery right now,
not until we've determined
the full extent of any
potential impairment.
Do I look impaired to you?
No, but I think we
should run a few tests.
Do you see any evidence at
all that my work has suffered?
You are a brain surgeon.
The margin of acceptable
error is miniscule.
I have a pretty good idea
of how precise I need to be.
I'm not comfortable
with subjecting
any patient to that risk.
Most of the patients
that I take on,
other surgeons won't even touch.
Without me, the likelihood
that they will die is 100%.
I am not questioning your value.
I'm just asking that you wait
until there is no doubt.
There's no such
thing as "no doubt."
Aaron, I...
I cannot have you
operating right now.
I'm sorry.
Then you will have to fire me.
And I will sue you.
You know, I'm
thinking of cooking up
a batch of the world-famous
Poulet a la Andrews tonight.
I'm in.
Hmm.
But I want to give you
a courtesy heads up.
The nurses are gonna send out
an official e-mail about
a unionization drive.
I just increased
the nursing budget.
More than a year ago.
And it mostly went to
temps or traveling nurses.
Not mostly. I can
show you the numbers.
Point is, we're underpaid,
underappreciated.
A union could protect us.
Sorry to interrupt. Got
Nico's pre-op testing back.
His chemo hit his
bone marrow hard.
Platelets only 22k?
He can't have the surgery.
You have a large malignant
hemangiopericytoma
compressing your frontal lobes.
- Malignant?
- Yes.
But it's operable.
Which is good, because
if left untreated,
this would likely kill
you within a year.
- Okay.
- You were right.
The tumor is probably why
your father stopped being
"a dick" a few months ago.
Sorry, Dad.
It's all right.
I knew our relationship
had improved.
I just didn't know it
was because of this.
So, if you remove it, could
that change my personality back?
Most likely.
Thank you, Doctor. I'm
gonna pass on the surgery.
If you want to bench
our top surgeon,
you're gonna need more than
one indeterminate scan.
Are you worried about losing our
top surgeon or our top earner?
Why does everyone think wanting
to keep this hospital solvent
is something to be
embarrassed about?
You want to open up the
door to another takeover?
I just want to be
clear about our agenda.
Well, then, let me clarify.
Yes, I'm worried about
losing our top earner,
but I'm more worried
about Theo Singh,
the 27-year-old newlywed with
the pilocytic astrocytoma.
We can refer him to
Dr. Cachoa at General.
Theo's tumor is
compressing his brain stem.
Cachoa probably
won't even take him.
I can deal with that. And
you're doing it again.
My department, my call.
Once litigation is threatened,
it becomes my call.
Glassman refused
cognitive testing,
and until I have
more information,
I'm not letting him into the OR.
So he does all of his
surgeries as planned,
but with a backstop.
You assign another surgeon
on all of his cases
and not just the OR.
And he'll be happy with that?
It's a compromise.
Nobody's ever completely happy.
- I know I'm not.
- Neither am I.
The hallmark of a
successful negotiation.
I forgot you were coming.
That's odd, given how you read
my text ten minutes ago, but...
Beautiful, healthy baby.
Beautiful and healthy mom.
So it looks like
things are going great.
Definitely.
Is she eating well?
- Like a horse. Shh, shh.
- Nice.
- Sleeping?
- Like a baby.
I underestimated diaper demand,
but everything else is...
perfect.
Shh. It's okay.
When Kellan was fussy,
we'd put his car seat
on top of the washing machine.
The vibrations
knocked him right out.
Well, this isn't like her.
Okay. Shh.
You mind?
Ah. All right.
Oh, I've missed this.
What?
See? Like a baby.
My patient is refusing
the hemangiopericytoma
resection surgery that
will save his life.
I want you to talk him into it.
That's not how
this works, Shaun.
It should be.
You are more
persuasive than I am.
Ask Glassman.
He's removed more anterior fossa
tumors than anyone on the West Coast.
But Dr. Glassman should not
be doing any surgery until...
I agree, but I was overruled.
If you want someone to
change your patient's mind,
Glassman's your best shot.
You are persuasive.
Nico's body isn't making the blood
cells and platelets he needs.
There's, uh... There's got to
be a way to get his counts up.
With Nico so sick...
it may be time to
consider palliative care.
- No.
- Let's hear the doctor out.
No, I'm not giving up on
him. Neither should you.
And neither should they.
Nico's been
through so much.
You think I don't know that?
I'm trying to save his life.
Dr. Park will pull
the team together
and see if there's a solution
that works for everyone.
Thank you.
So much.
He doesn't want
his tumor removed,
so I don't know what
there is to discuss.
Given the tumor's impact
on his frontal lobes,
he might not be competent
to make that decision.
And you don't think I'm
competent to be a doctor, so...
Oh, no. Just to
be a neurosurgeon.
The surgery should give
Kurt about 20 more years.
Let's recap, 20 more
years as a bad father
versus one year
as a good father.
There is no medical
justification...
Yes, there is,
Shaun. Yes, there is.
There's an emotional one!
There's an emotional issue!
Your voice is getting louder, and
your face is flushed. Are you upset?
You should have come
to me with the scan.
You don't go to Lim. You
don't show it to Lim.
You said you were only
a little mad at me.
Y-You ratted me out to
the head of the department
when I specifically
asked you not to do that!
Yes, I did that because
you did not believe me...
Well, then, you come to me!
You try to convince me.
Again and again and again!
Don't you think you owe me that?
That's four times. I tried
a lot more than that.
What do you want from me?
You want me to go with you to see
if he's competent? Is that it?
Okay. Fine. Let's go.
Hey.
Did Dr. Park find anything?
Not yet.
I just wanted to see
how you guys are doing.
Seb's with the kids.
I, um, needed a little break.
Seb and I used to talk
about how every day was a...
A beautiful day.
I remember.
Do you understand
what will happen
if you don't have the operation?
Yes. I'll be dead
within a year.
And why is that
preferable to surgery?
Hailey was right about me.
I was a terrible person,
a terrible father.
Never played with her.
I hardly talked to her.
I can't even remember
holding her hand.
The Wizard of Oz.
I was five, terrified
of the flying monkeys,
but when I reached
for your hand...
I pulled it away.
I never tried to again.
I don't want to go back.
I don't want to lose this.
I don't want to lose you.
The brain is a funny thing.
It wants to do the things
that makes it feel good,
get that dopamine hit.
In fact, it actually
can reshape itself
as it continues to try to
experience those good feelings.
So you're saying I m-might...
be able to stay this way?
Maybe.
You work hard to be the best version
of the person you want to be.
I've had that fight.
You should listen
to Dr. Glassman.
And he has removed more
anterior fossa tumors
than anyone on the West Coast.
Hey, I have faith in you, Dad.
You can do the work. You
could stay a good man.
Whew.
Well, uh, like the patient said,
"I didn't want brain surgery,
but the doctor
changed my mind."
That... was a dad joke?
And a "yes."
If you do the surgery.
I've heard that you, uh, know
your way around a fossa tumor.
As you wish.
- So, what are we doing here?
- You don't remember?
A bicoronal
subfrontal craniotomy.
- And?
- Possible orbital osteotomies.
Drill.
We would place a
lumbar drain first.
Before incision, yes. I thought
I'd focus on the surgery.
Be careful of the
sutura coronalis.
Why? Does the patient
have one of those?
All higher primates do.
If you don't remember...
That was a joke. In the
OR, we call that a joke.
Hmm.
Popping the top.
- And let's get under the lobes.
- Wait.
That is not the
next step. It's...
Assessing and ligating
the anterior third.
I thought I'd do that
after I get a better view.
That...
is an acceptable option.
Wonderful.
But you must remember to...
Shaun, no more talking while
I'm doing this procedure.
This is my patient, so
I should be able to...
Shaun, I'm asking you to leave.
I will be quiet,
but if another...
One of us is going
to leave, Shaun.
It's not gonna be the
one doing the surgery.
Let's get after it.
We'd start with
blood transfusions,
plus a cocktail of
five medications
to ramp up production
of blood cells.
That should get Nico
through the operation.
A few weeks later,
we'd follow up
with a stem-cell
transplantation from one of you.
What could the side effects be?
Elevated risk of infection
and bleeds from the surgery
and possible toxicity
from drug interactions.
You know the alternative.
He'd be gone in
just a few months.
If you were in our
place, what would you do?
I'd do the surgery.
- Okay.
- Thank you.
Thank you.
We'll prep Nico for surgery.
Okay.
If this works, it'll
be a real win-win
because one day I do
plan to do laundry again.
All right, Eden.
I'm just gonna sit
down for one sec.
No! No.
That'll stay just between us.
I want Shaun off the case.
It's his patient.
I don't want to crack
a man's skull open
while standing next to someone
who's waiting for
me to screw up.
I want a team I can trust
100% and who will trust me.
- Shaun's off the case.
- Thank you.
And I'll be assisting.
Welcome aboard.
This is nice.
Are you talking
about the chicken?
Not exclusively.
I just hope it doesn't get
messed up by things at work.
The unionization drive.
What if I could
squeeze the board?
Get them to sign off on some
real and meaningful improvements.
You might not even need a union.
Those would have to be some
pretty big concessions.
Okay.
How about a 5% raise,
1-to-4 cap on
nurse-to-patient ratios.
Might even be able to get a Chief
Nursing Officer on the board.
That's pretty interesting.
I have no idea if anyone
else would go for it.
Any chance you could find out?
Well, there's a big
difference how hard I can push
for a proposal that might
work versus one that will.
I could float it
to a couple people.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Dessert?
Yes.
As soon as the surgery's
over, the case is yours again.
I will watch from the gallery.
No need. I'll have a much
better view from the floor.
The video feed on the
monitors is excellent.
And it couldn't hurt
to have more backup.
Actually, it could, Shaun.
I was wrong, sending
you to Glassman.
He's pretty upset right
now, and if you push it,
it could really hurt
your relationship.
But if a doctor is
making mistakes...
You don't have to be
the one to catch them,
not when others can.
Not when the doctor is your dad.
There we go. There we go.
Come on. I have a few left.
It's okay. Don't worry.
Okay.
Oh, no, no, no, no, no. No!
I knew I was running
out! I knew it.
What kind of mom
runs out of diapers?
Morgan?
Eden, if you're
alone, open the door!
- I can't do this.
- Yes, you can.
I'm failing at everything.
You know, when Kellan
was three months,
Mia had to go out of town.
It was my first time alone
with him, and he was teething.
It was 4:00 in the morning,
and neither of us had slept.
And suddenly...
Hmm.
I knew exactly how
to fix everything.
One, or both, of us was
going out that window.
No one went out the window.
We both fell asleep.
Of the many times I've
heard about your failures,
none has ever made me happier.
You're not failing. You're
just, uh... muddling through.
I am not a muddler.
Mm. Every parent is.
Key is to not lose your
mind while you're muddling.
What?
I've freed
up the lateral aspect.
Cauterizing.
We're ready to
take out the tumor.
Dr. Kalu, you want the honor?
Thank you, Doctor.
There's mets all over his liver.
Can we resect the
most involved segments?
It's too widespread.
So... what do we do?
We close him up and
tell the family.
Start the timer.
Place the lumbar drain, please.
Hey.
- Tough day?
- Yeah, it was.
When I was arguing with the board
and fighting with Lim and...
I just found out I got
to tell a kid's parents
that a surgery I
recommended failed
and their boy has a
month to live. So...
that tipped it a
bit beyond "tough."
I'll come back later.
No. Look. I'm sorry. I'm okay.
What's up?
- This may not be the time.
- No. It's fine.
I floated your idea
to a few nurses.
They don't trust perks that
can be taken away at will.
They want a union. I'm sorry.
Which nurses?
- Their names?
- Yeah.
You're asking me to
inform on my co-workers?
I just need to know
how serious this is.
Are we talking
influential people
or some disgruntled part-timers?
No!
You need to use a
Penfield dissector
to avoid lacerating
the sagittal sinus.
- Dr. Murphy!
- I'm using the blunt end of the drill bit instead.
Okay. Carry on.
Well, thank you. Speak again,
Dr. Murphy, and I'll have you removed.
I heard you were here,
and I said, "Impossible,
because Lea and I talked about
how this is her very
precious and finite me-time."
Tonight's the big date
with Perez, right?
- Mm-hmm.
- What are you gonna do?
I have no idea.
I thought of this Italian place,
but then I remembered they
have house wine on the tables
and figured that might
trigger a relapse.
And then I thought of indoor
skydiving, but what if he gets hurt?
- So I...
- You're really overthinking this.
I thought maybe he
wasn't ready to date,
but now I'm thinking I'm not.
Maybe you're not, but you're
really gonna regret it
if you don't give it a shot.
Take him to the Batumi
Grill, order the khachapuri.
Now my Slanket is waiting.
Khachapuri. Okay.
- You're giving up?
- That's not what we...
You can't do this to us, to him.
I'm so sorry, Sebastian.
You can't promise that you have a
cure for my boy and then abandon us.
- There's nothing we can do.
- So find another surgery.
We need to focus on improving the
quality of the time Nico has left.
Do not tell me where
to focus. He's my son.
I don't... I don't... I
don't want quality time.
- All I want is my boy.
- Seb.
- I'm talking to him.
- You're being selfish.
Forcing any more operations
will only cause Nico more pain,
and you and Talia and Olivia
will have terrible
memories of his last days.
I don't care about memories.
You should.
Because soon they
are all you'll have.
Hey.
You wouldn't let
me give up before.
And you were right.
But now it's time.
Dads are supposed to
fight for their kids.
So you fight...
to give your son as many
beautiful days as you can.
You need a rest?
No. Just stretching.
Okay.
And there is our houseguest.
Having overstayed his welcome.
- There's a lot of bleeding.
- Vascular clips.
Must be a tear
in the anterior cerebrals.
No, it's
from the dural feeders.
Hmm. As expected.
- And there we are.
- Hmm.
Oh, the
bleeding's stopped.
Nice.
No!
Dr. Glassman, please tell
us what the next step is.
You hesitated.
You need to say what
comes next in the surgery.
Somebody please call security.
Shaun, you are out of line.
Answer.
Please.
It's, um...
We need to
decompress the optic nerve.
Rhoton dissectors.
Hey.
The patient's in recovery.
Your surgical plan was flawless.
Alison Borden.
34-year-old mother of two.
My first solo surgery.
Frontal AVM. It was
a walk in the park.
I was pumped. I was flying.
And then... her
feeding artery tore...
and I couldn't
stop the bleeding.
Bipolaring, clipping, suturing.
We thought we were
gonna lose her.
And I couldn't get this
image out of my mind
of her kids coming
home from school
and seeing their father just
sitting there, you know?
Finally, I stuck a neuro-patty
on a muscle patch graft.
That did it. It held.
And when I walked
out of that OR,
I thought, "I am never
going back in there again."
Then I saw Alison in recovery.
Husband, kids. All smiles.
She gave me a big hug.
Despite my raging ego...
I've tried... I've always tried
to make it about the patients.
To do what's best for them.
I never thought that would
mean putting down my knife.
The surgery
went very well.
We were able to completely
remove your tumor.
Hey. Dad. How are you feeling?
Well, my head kind of hurts.
I bet.
I gave you that locket.
Yeah.
For my last birthday.
Yeah, that seems
like a long time ago.
♪♪ Rock-a-bye
baby On a treetop ♪♪
Okay. I know. I know.
Okay.
Hey, Siri. Play
"Deceptacon" by Le Tigre.
♪♪ Who
took the bomp? ♪♪
You like this?
You like dancing with me?
Well, I love dancing with you.
Your mommy loves
dancing with you.
♪♪ Every day and night ♪♪
♪♪ I can see your
disco, disco ♪♪
♪♪ Is sucking my heart out... ♪♪
Boo.
- You look great.
- Thank you.
- So do you.
So, where we heading?
It's a Georgian place. Lea
swears by their khachapuri.
Oh, that sounds amazing.
I have no idea what that is.
I had to look it up.
It's cheese bread.
- Oh, okay.
- Yeah.
Sorry about earlier.
Not your finest moment.
This, on the other hand...
Amazing.
Wow.
Hey. Do you think maybe...
We can do dinner another night.
I like the suit.
Oh! Ho, ho, ho, ho, ho, ho!
No, like, I really
like the suit.
Maybe it could, uh,
come home tonight?
Ho, ho... ho.
It's a beautiful day.
Kurt and Hailey held hands.
It must be hard to accept
you are compromised,
but you did not hurt a patient,
so now you understand
why I did it,
and you can't be mad at me.
You didn't have to
do it that way, okay?
You were right. You didn't
have to do it that way.
- But if I was right, then...
- You humiliated me in public.
In my operating room, in
front of my colleagues.
Do you have any idea how much
that hurt, coming from you?
I don't know what to do.
You could just leave me alone.
Hello? Lea?
The Peanut's coming early.
The Peanut is coming!