I know that one.
I was at the studio when
Grandfather recorded it.
You thinking about your mom?
Mama, everything, my whole life.
It was all a lie. I
never knew you.
I never knew you were my dad.
Your life's gonna
be okay, Leona.
You're a good kid.
You got it together.
You survived the last
eight months on your own.
You're not your
grandfather or your mom.
You're not gonna make
the same mistakes they did.
I'm proud that I'm your father.
Glad I'm getting this chance.
I'm glad I'm getting this
chance. This chance...
Ready for a cookie, darling?
We gotta go! Get out of here!
Leona!
You've reached a number
that has been disconnected
and is no longer in service.
If you feel you've reached
this recording in error, go with it.
Hang up. On three. One, two...
House, pick up.
I know it's your day off, and no
doubt got lots of exciting plans,
but I've got a case.
A 16-year-old girl presenting
with cardiogenic shock,
no heart attack.
Dr. Willis, 5-2-2-1.
Her heart looks fine. ER
did a full cardiac workup.
Tox screen's clean,
blood shows no infection.
All on the top page.
I'm a real good reader.
Personal chart handoff
means there's something else.
I'm hoping it's not personal.
The guy who brought the
girl in says he knows you.
I thought I'd met
all your friend.
I was also wondering if you
could take a look at these.
When you have a
chance. No hurry.
It's just a couple
of medical histories.
One with a minor cancer
concern. No problem.
G-man!
You thought I was gonna do
it, didn't you? Do I know you?
Come on it's me.
Crandall. Doesn't ring a bell.
Man, I can't believe...
Unless you mean Dylan Crandall,
a man who will believe anything.
See, I just made you believe
that I... You haven't changed.
Heard about your leg. Yeah.
Pulled a hamstring playing Twister.
Just gonna walk it off.
So who's the girl? Jesse
Baker's granddaughter.
You always said you'd give
your right hand to play like him.
No. I said I'd give my
right hand to have his left.
Why is she with you?
She lost her mom in
Katrina, her home, everything.
Wow.
And I'm her father.
Hmm.
Yeah, she looks just
like you, got the same 'fro.
I wrote a book about Baker.
Hung out with him, his daughter.
Yeah, that is how
babies are made.
I never knew. She never
knew. Her mom lied for 16 years.
That's unbelievable. Yeah.
No, seriously, I
don't believe it.
Her mom was pissed
at me about my book.
I trashed her and her dad.
She wouldn't talk to me,
obviously she's not
gonna tell Leona that...
You're a sucker.
You always were.
Does that mean you're not
gonna help her? Why wouldn't I?
She's not scamming me.
Acute myocardial
infarction? ER said no. Retest.
Wolff-Parkinson-White
Syndrome? ER said no. Retest.
And read the damn file.
You just gave them to us.
Delta wave on the
EKG... It's all a no.
Everything about her heart is
healthy. She's a Katrina victim.
It's better than Crandall.
He's a Katrina-victim victim.
I don't think she was
expecting your sympathy.
I think her point was New
Orleans was a Third World country:
toxins, mold, sewage
in the streets...
What if her heart
is like my bike?
Runs like crap when I'm by myself, but
I take it to the mechanic, it runs great.
An arrhythmia. A one-time event.
What are we gonna do?
Keep her in her room on a cardiac
monitor till she has another arrhythmia?
That could be
weeks. Months. Relax.
I happen to know she's going to have
one right after lunch. We are golden.
You can't induce an arrhythmia in someone
whose heart nearly gave out 48 hours ago.
Sure you can.
It's kind of technical,
but you stick all these cool
little wires inside her somehow...
I mean you shouldn't. Oh, right.
'Cause it'd be much more ethical to
let it happen in an uncontrolled setting,
'cause there's always
a team of cardiologists
having lunch at the
next table. This is Jersey.
She's a minor, she's
gonna need consent.
I'll go talk to him. Oh,
that's an excellent plan.
We'll give him the form, and
tell him it's wrong and dangerous.
I can handle a simple consent
form. Okay, I'll be Crandall.
Dr. Cameron. House, from
what you say, this guy will...
Are you in this scene?
Go.
I need to talk to you about a
procedure we'd like to do on Leona.
"Like to do?" Is
this fun for you?
He's not you, he's not gonna
mock me. Stay in character.
I'm so scared, hold me.
In order to figure out
which circuit is misfiring,
we need to map all the
electrical activity in her heart.
Swear to me on the Bible
you'd do this if it was your kid.
Goodbye.
To map the electrical pathways in a
heart, we send electricity through each,
one at a time, till one fails.
That sounds dangerous.
It's a risk I'm prepared to take.
If she's got an
electrical problem,
couldn't more electricity
blow her whole system?
Well, look who's been watching
Bill Nye, the Science Guy.
The test is perfectly
safe. We do it every day.
All right. And you believe me?
I shouldn't do the test?
It's crazy dangerous.
Just sign the damn form.
I'm not crying. I
can handle this.
Then blow your nose, I
need DNA from somewhere.
You're not running
a paternity test.
She's gonna stay
around just long enough
to get your bank account,
your credit card numbers,
then she's gonna be
off with her next daddy.
With what she's been through,
why would you assume...
Because of what
she's been through.
Because that's your default
position, always has been.
Because she's still alive.
Raised by a junkie,
living on the streets,
that tends to kick the
sweetness out of you.
I figured you'd have mellowed.
Because you're an idiot.
If I let you do the test, it
means I don't trust her.
No. It means I don't trust her.
199,
98... She's out.
Heart rhythm's normal.
Insert the first catheter.
I'm in.
All heart rhythms still normal.
Haven't zapped her yet.
Send the first electrical pulse.
Sinoatrial node is normal.
Next.
Got supraventricular
tachycardia.
Stop the current.
Is she hallucinating?
IV push stat, 12.5 adenosine.
She's crashing. BP's plummeting.
Foreman, is she hallucinating?
No, normal waves.
Then the AV node is not the bad
pathway. All that was, was a heart attack.
Reset her, so we can
find the real problem.
Charging. Clear.
Normal rhythm.
Chase, high right
atrium, please.
Her heart's fragile after that last
attack. Chances of tachycardia.
You have my permission to blame
Foreman at any negligence trial.
Send the electrical pulse.
That's the one. She's hallucinating.
It's near the coronary sinus.
Freeze it.
Damaged heart muscle
gone. Cryoablation complete.
EEG's back to normal.
No hallucinations.
She'll be fine by breakfast.
Interesting reading.
Those are my top two
choices for sperm donors.
I wanted your medical
opinion on genetics.
They're losers.
Medically? Or...
Donor 1284 likes square dancing.
No one likes square dancing.
613, he's been practicing
medicine for five minutes,
calls himself a
healer, loves Mozart.
I'm not going dancing with them,
I'm looking for healthy sperm.
He's got four
living grandparents.
Who they are, what they
do, that doesn't matter?
I'm leaning toward 613. Oh,
sure, go with the Jewish number.
1284 has a cousin that tested
positive for the BRCA gene.
But his mother was negative,
which means so is your baby.
What about the...
Mediterranean/Dutch factor
on the dad's side?
It's not a problem,
because his dad's mom didn't
carry the thalassemia gene.
Bigger issue is the
jerk and poser genes.
This Mozart lie. People
can't like classical music?
You're designing a kid, a loser kid.
He's already getting pummeled at recess.
Here, knock yourself out.
Go find sperm that
can beat up 613's kids.
And thanks for your help.
Pretentiousness is hereditary.
Just 'cause they haven't
found the gene yet...
Could I have some water, please?
Hello?
I just need some water.
Is anyone there?
Mama?
The second hallucination
means we didn't fix her heart.
Maybe we missed something.
Her heart's fine. If she hallucinated,
it wasn't caused by her heart.
If? The screaming, the
floundering, it was an hallucination.
What if it wasn't
a hallucination?
We covered... Not finished.
What if it was an atypical seizure?
- Seizure?
She saw her mother. Mother's
dead. Ergo, hallucination.
Anyone wanna explain
that? His leg hurts.
Walking takes his
mind off of it. Flashback!
All that wind and rain from the
hurricane, post-traumatic stress syndrome.
Why are you so bent on her
not having a hallucination?
If she did have a hallucination,
then the heart problem
that we predicted,
found, and fixed was
just a gigantic coincidence.
His leg always hurts.
It's getting worse.
What if the heart
isn't a coincidence,
and isn't what caused
the hallucination?
An arrhythmia hurts.
What if her hallucination
was caused by pain?
What if she has a disease that translates
pain into a bizarre physiological response
like a hallucination? She
has an autoimmune disease.
She needs a CRP,
a rheumatoid factor...
I can prove an autoimmune disease
in five minutes. She needs a PET scan.
You can't test for
autoimmune in a PET...
I'm proving that her hallucinations
are a consistent response to pain,
which proves that she has
an autoimmune disease.
How do you test
someone's response to pain?
Easy. Hurt them.
It's not gonna hurt at all.
We just need to make
sure you don't move.
I won't.
Okay, give me your arm. I need
to check your muscle responses.
Okay, turn it over. Palm upward.
Everything okay? Yeah.
What the hell was
that? Diagnostic test.
Cerebral cortex responded
normally. She's not hallucinating.
You know he's not
your father, don't you?
He's my dad, Mama told me.
I'm sorry, I didn't
mean to hurt you.
House, leave her alone. Come
on. We both know it's a hustle.
Are the walls closing in?
No. Why are you doing this?
Spiders coming out of
my nose? Let me out.
House, the test is over.
Dorsolateral prefrontal cortex...
Give me your hand. No!
Give me your hand.
Forget him.
He's not the perfect mark,
because he was the perfect mark.
Plenty of people
got there before you.
He's used up,
tainted, pumped dry.
She's hallucinating.
She's lost everything, and
you're breaking fingers. A new low.
Diagnostically, she
needed to be hurt.
I wanted to hurt her. Win-win.
What I didn't consider was a
threshold to trigger the hallucinations.
Otherwise, I'd have done
the finger-bending first,
instead of stabbing her
twice. That was cruel.
If her autoimmune disease is this advanced,
usual treatment is not gonna help.
We don't even know which
autoimmune disease she has.
This could be Lambert-Eaton,
could be Graves'...
Good point. Let's
kill them all at once.
The only way to do that, is to
replace her entire immune system.
Good point. Let's do that.
Bone marrow transplant
requires an exact match.
Leona has no siblings.
Good point. She's all alone, poor
thing. No one in the whole wide world.
I asked for this tuned. Did
you get this instrument tuned?
If my daughter
needs bone marrow,
why are you looking in
a bone marrow registry?
Because that's where
they keep the bone marrow.
I'm her father.
How does somebody who
believes absolutely anything
become a non-fiction
writer? Test my bone marrow.
Here's how this is gonna end: One
day, you'll be sitting at your computer,
writing one of your little music books,
and your daughter will come home
with a big, angry policeman,
who'll throw you in jail because,
"Daddy touched my poozle."
Test me. Happy to.
Just my marrow. I'm not
authorizing a paternity test.
You're that afraid of the
truth? I know the truth.
Easy-Lay Fay's truth was that she needed
a bus ticket home to see her sick grandma.
You gave her 100
bucks. She bought weed.
I know, because I told her you'd
go for the sick-grandma story.
If our friendship
means anything to you...
Come on. Do you know me at all?
If you do the test, one
of two things happens.
Either you're right or I'm right.
If you're right, I'll be miserable.
And if I'm right, I'll hate
myself 'cause I didn't trust her.
Either way I lose.
They don't itch, not raised.
He's had his MMR,
no one's sick at school.
His father took him camping.
We caught two spiders.
You didn't tell me about the
spider. Did you get a new couch?
Do you think there might
be some sort of toxin...
What color is it?
Red.
Is that where you watch your
cartoons after you take your bath?
Mmm-hmm.
Fall asleep sometimes?
Yes. Bless you.
Need you. Now. Yes, mistress.
I'll write you a prescription for
one of these. Just wet and apply.
You didn't tell anyone else
what I'm doing? Not a soul.
Wilson?
Cameron, maybe you
mentioned it to her?
No. I'm a really
good secret-keeper.
I've never told anybody
that Wilson wets his bed.
Oh, you tricked me.
Part of the protocol
for in vitro fertilization
is twice-daily injections
of menotropins.
I can't do it myself.
Turn around.
No clever comments about bending
over? Not unless you want me to.
I'm just not used to
House the professional.
I was just thinking about
what your mother looked like.
'Cause your father obviously
chose her for breeding purposes...
Shut up. Natural
selection sucks.
We pick our mates based
on breast size, cars they drive.
They did autopsies on married couples,
found a correlation in pancreas size.
We're hardwired to
pick for stupid reasons.
You have the chance
to pick for smart reasons.
I think the Germans had a
similar theory about 60 years ago.
I'm not advocating wiping
out entire races, I'm just saying
you don't wanna mate with the
first plastic cup that buys you a drink.
I'm pretty sure you got that.
Microbes can be sneaky.
Thanks.
Twice a day. This
is gonna be fun.
I got it.
So why were you
friends with this guy?
We were 20 years
old. He had a car.
If he'd been a woman, I
would have married him.
Is he a match? No.
Lying girl lucked out, we
found one in the registry.
Is he the dad?
I don't think so. You
didn't run the test?
Said I wouldn't.
Okay, so either you lied,
or he has pictures
of you being nice.
Stop the radiation.
What the hell is that?
I have no idea.
Lab results on the black ooze.
You're not gonna believe it.
She pooped out of her mouth.
The sample contained
stool and digested blood.
How did you guess?
'Cause it oozed.
If it was in her stomach,
it would've sprayed.
If it was in her lungs,
she would have coughed.
This oozed, as in squeezed, as in
reverse peristalsis. Who's hungry?
Mexican takeout?
In order for digested
blood to be in her intestines,
she had to have
internal bleeding.
Yeah, but for whatever
was in her intestines
to come back up, there
had to be a blockage.
Liver failure.
There'd be no proteins
to clot the blood,
so it would leak into her
stomach, mess up her intestines.
Means, oops, we were wrong,
because no autoimmune disease
shuts down an
organ in two hours.
We need to do a liver biopsy,
find out what the real problem is.
Hey.
Need to talk to you.
The good news is, she doesn't
have an autoimmune condition,
so she doesn't need a
bone marrow transplant,
and we were able to
stop the irradiation in time.
The bad news, she
has potty mouth.
Her liver is failing which has made
her digestive system go in reverse.
It's actually much
worse than it sounds.
We need to do a liver biopsy.
I don't know what's gonna happen
when we stick a needle into her liver.
She could die
right then and there.
Ease it. Tell me what to do.
No inside information
on this one.
Look, Crandall, three days
ago, you didn't even know this girl.
If she'd been hit by a bus, you
wouldn't lose a moment's sleep.
There are people all over this
hospital in just as much trouble,
just as not related to you.
You telling me I shouldn't care?
Prepping me to handle
it for when she dies?
It's brown, it's lumpy,
I'm going to heave all over
my desk. Chicken mole.
Twenty-one herbs and spices.
I find it very comforting, you defending
a man you haven't seen in years.
To know my friend, no matter what,
will always be my champion, my protector.
I'm not protecting
him, I'm smacking her.
The modesty of the true hero.
Push me and I'll let her die,
just so you'll stop annoying me.
Here's my theory.
You're jealous.
He's maturing, he's
accepting responsibility,
you're emotionally stuck at 17.
He's manufacturing
responsibility, he's not maturing.
He hasn't changed at all.
So, then why do you care?
That black ooze we saw?
That was a bowel movement
out of her mouth.
You're trying to end this
conversation by grossing me out?
I'm an oncologist.
Half my patients have
their skin sloughing off.
Why are you so
worried about this guy?
He was having a rough
time with his girlfriend.
He was in love,
he's always in love,
he wanted to marry her.
And I thought she was flaky,
was sending mixed signals.
So you gave him advice,
and she dumped him.
No. I told him that
I would talk to her.
And you blew it? Technically...
I was doing him a
favor. She was nuts.
Stop the biopsy.
I'm right at her liver.
It's House. He says stop.
Check it out.
Look, please tell me you didn't
stop the biopsy to play us some tunes.
The left hand is very
subtle, very delicate.
This girl is dying.
Be dying a lot faster if I let you do
that obviously unnecessary biopsy.
Now, listen.
I asked for this tuned. Did
you get this instrument tuned?
My God. Grandpa was an
angry drunk. If only we'd known!
Here's how to become a
great artist. First, get miserable.
Misery drives you to become a great artist,
but the art does nothing for your misery,
which drives you to drugs,
which makes you a lousy artist.
And this is not lousy.
You saying he didn't do
drugs? Not when he played this.
Something was screwing
with his personality.
Yeah. Drugs and
alcohol don't do that.
And that note that he
says is out of tune, it's not.
Which means that something is
screwing with his aural perception, too.
Now, what happens when you
add all of that to the liver disease,
which he supposedly died of?
Too much iron. He could
have had hemochromatosis.
That's genetic.
Unless you can tell me Miles
Davis couldn't play stoned...
Played better when he wasn't.
I think. I mean, no
one knows for sure.
I'll get Leona a TIBC
and serum ferritin.
We can test this
in three minutes.
So, what is she, Foreman,
a light-skinned black chick
or a dark-skinned white chick?
I'm not sure. Can we
hear the music again?
It's too early to see
jaundice from her liver.
True. But this is a photograph of
Leona when she was 13 years old.
She's darker now.
She's been living on the
streets for eight months.
No tan line.
So, unless those streets she's
been living on are indoor streets,
I'm thinking she's got
iron deposits in melanin.
Both byproducts of hemochromatosis,
just like Granddad used to make.
SQUID exam to calculate
the amount of iron in her blood,
and treat her with deferoxamine.
She'll be fine by lunch.
'Cause, you see, I was wrong
before about the breakfast.
There's the iron. Lots of it.
I'm not gonna
get this job, am I?
It's a done deal. I knew
it the moment I saw you.
Interview's just a formality.
House, what are you... Lisa
Cuddy, this is Patrick Linehan.
Patrick's gonna be the new
intern rotating in my department.
I didn't even know you were
looking for one. Nice to meet you.
Sorry. I laugh when I'm nervous.
Bet you've been doing
that your whole life, huh?
What kind of medicine are
you interested in, Patrick?
Cancer, infectious
disease. The big devils.
I think that medicine has
become too institutionalized.
We need to send a message to
our patients that we're just like them.
I mean, we're all people.
"We're all people." I like that.
See, she's all
hard science, facts.
I like to know a person's
hopes and dreams.
What kind of music do you
like, Patrick? Actually, I don't...
I'm a Mozart man.
He says what I feel
but can't express.
I'm late for a meeting.
You see, this is why the
face-to-face interview is so important.
You gotta know who
you're getting in bed with.
Get him out of here.
Deferoxamine is
a chelating agent.
It binds to the iron, so
that her liver can get rid of it.
Once the iron's
out of the liver,
it's finally evacuated by
the body in the form of urine.
Should be quick and painless.
Leona? What's happening?
Crash cart. She's
not getting any air.
CT showed her lungs
are Swiss cheese.
Ventilator's helping, but at
this rate, her time's basically up.
We developed a theory,
hemochromatosis.
Like good scientists, we tested
that theory. We proved that theory.
We acted based on that
proof and we treated her.
As a result of which, she
is on the verge of death.
Is it just me, or have we discovered
a flaw in the scientific method?
Walk me through it step by
step. What is supposed to happen
when you give
someone deferoxamine?
It's a chelating agent. And
what does the chelating do?
It removes excess
iron from the liver. How?
The iron is heavy, it gets stuck.
Deferoxamine is like a lubricant.
It makes the iron slick, so
it can move around again.
Moves around where?
It's supposed to be
discharged through waste.
Her waste system is a
little screwy right now.
Means the iron can't
go where it wants to go.
What if it moved to her lungs?
Then whatever's in her lungs likes
iron, bound with it, started poking holes.
What likes iron?
Oxygen attaches itself to iron, which
increases her chance of infection.
No, we started massive
antibiotics prior to the radiation.
Some neurodegenerative
diseases like iron. MRI was clean.
No iron deposits on the
brain. Fungus likes iron.
No objections to that one?
If a fungus is doing
all this, she's dead.
There are 25 antifungals, if
we don't know which fungus...
When in doubt, go broad.
Most common is aspergillus.
Continue to ventilate her lungs.
Get her on a voriconazole drip
and hope she has aspergillus.
The process is confidential.
You violated his privacy.
But how did you even...
I looked up "loser"
in the cryobank.
You wouldn't go within
100 miles of that idiot.
Yet you're willing
to have his baby.
I'm not looking for a
date, I'm tired of looking.
Cotton ball?
I don't care if you marry this guy,
date this guy, go through his garbage,
but you should know.
Genes matter. Who
you are matters.
Find someone you trust.
Someone like you?
Someone you like.
Listen... Oh, sorry. Okay.
It's not what you
think. I rub his leg.
Oh, Ingrid.
Hi.
Okay, you feel guilty about
stealing the guy's girl, I get that.
And I'm glad, it's a good thing.
But you did the paternity test.
And either the paternity
test comes back negative
and you shove it
in the guy's face,
or it comes back positive, and you
shut up, and your leg starts hurting.
Or I never ran the test.
Not what you think. CAMERON:
Leona's lungs collapsed.
The treatment's not working.
We've got the wrong fungus.
You can stop. She ruined it.
Three rules for hunting fungus:
location, location, location.
Crandall says she was living at
the children's shelter in Ridgeland.
Okay. The one thing
we know for sure
is she was not living in the
children's shelter in Ridgeland.
Why would he lie about that?
- He wouldn't.
But he'd believe her story about the sweet
little girl trying to do the right thing.
We can't ask Leona where
she was. She's intubated.
Don't try to talk.
You got a big medical
thing in your mouth.
Just blink if you understand me.
Fantastic.
Blink if you lied to
Crandall about everything.
You picked up a
fungus somewhere.
If you were living at this shelter,
like you told your new daddy,
then I got nothing to
go on and you will die.
So, did you lie to Crandall?
You're a lousy con artist.
First rule of the game
is know your mark.
Once you got Crandall to bite
on the papa thing, you had him.
You could have told him
that you were servicing
Al-Qaeda suicide
bombers for crack,
and this guy would still have let you
pick out the colors in your new room.
Did you lie to Crandall?
Where were you?
And the winner is...
Oh, you read it, I just get
so nervous at these things.
Recording studio?
She read the book.
She knew how much Crandall
hated that place, what went on there.
- She overplayed her hand.
- She was desperate.
If she didn't sell this,
she was stuck in hell.
Recording studio
doesn't help us medically.
Recording studios.
Why are these buildings
different from all other buildings?
Sound-proofing. Absorbs
sound, also absorbs moisture.
Where there's moisture, a
lot of it, say Katrina-moist...
Zygomycosis. Only occurs
at the highest levels of mold.
Start her on an IV drip of amphotericin
B with colony stimulating factors.
She'll be fine by
dinner.
She's gonna be fine. She
said she'd never go back there.
She lied to you. She's
your kid. Get used to it.
Thank you for the injections.
You're welcome.
You came all the way up
here just to tell me that?
No.
Pretty much normal. Liver
function tests are good.
Thanks, G-man.
What makes you think
you'd be a good father?
I don't know.
It feels right.
It feels good.
Well, at least you
got a good reason.
Feels good is a
good enough reason.
What's happening? She's
choking. She can't breathe.
Get him out of here, will you?
- Come on...
Out!
Quick, the curtain!
You're breathing on your
own. The choking's normal.
I lied to him. I ran
a paternity test.
Your lie was a bad one.
He is your dad.
We're even.
Your machine's broken,
there's not even a message.
House? Are you there? Okay.
See you Monday, I guess.