You okay?
Yeah, just got
clipped with a beam.
What the hell do you
two think you were doing?
We thought we heard
someone in there!
You never go in
without authorization!
Captain, this is all me.
Amy just followed me in.
So torching your ass last
year wasn't enough, huh?
You need to stop trying to prove how tough
you are before you get yourself killed.
Yes, sir.
Let the paramedics
look you over.
Come on, Derek. Let's get this
ladder to the second story. Let's go.
Derek! Derek!
Derek!
What's happening?
I'm freezing.
I'm fine.
ER docs don't think so.
Your temperature's been going
up and down like a rollercoaster.
How old are these skin grafts?
Last one was about
six months ago.
We're gonna run some tests and
we'll get a consult with Dr. House.
I'll be fine.
You'll be doing what
the doctors say. Got it?
I'll check in later.
Hey.
The way you covered
for me last night...
He's my brother.
I know how to eat it from him.
I'm gonna stop by
after my shift, okay?
Okay.
So where is this Dr. House?
Speaking engagement.
Not guilty.
And on the charge of gaining control of
said medication by fraud, how do you plead?
Not guilty. Very well.
Preliminary hearing is set
for the 19th at 10:00 a.m.,
at which time I'll
determine whether
there's enough evidence
to proceed to trial.
Next case on the calendar.
People versus Williams.
Charge is assault
in the second degree
with intent to cause
injury to another person.
I see the defense has
submitted a motion to dismiss...
You gonna go talk to him?
I was just gonna ask him
where he gets his hair cut.
They have your signature in the
prescription log, a security camera video,
and a pharmacist's sworn statement
saying you stole a dead guy's pills.
You're already
looking at 10 years.
You wanna add a witness
intimidation charge?
Go ahead, ask
him about his hair.
He suffered third-degree burns
over 54% of his body, a year ago,
and arrived in the ER last
night, disoriented and shivering.
For 12 hours his temperature
was bouncing between 96 and 102.
Why don't you contest the
search of the pharmacy records?
Yeah. You could argue it violated
doctor-patient confidentiality.
Except he wasn't the
patient or the doctor.
He was the guy who stole
from the patient and the doctor!
This was the third time he'd been
disoriented in the last two weeks.
Running into smoke-filled burning
buildings can be a bit disorienting.
Fortunately, I have
the cure. Stop doing it.
He's not in a burning building
anymore, and he's still shivering.
A hypothalamic tumor could
cause a vacillating temperature.
So could ER nurses who
were too busy to notice
that a patient likes both
hot coffee and cold sodas.
He tested negative for Hep C, TB,
HIV, Lyme, and his tox screen's clean.
In case you hadn't noticed,
not exactly in the mood to dance.
I'm not asking you to dance.
I'm asking you to do your job.
EKG showed arrhythmia.
Probably just a mild heart attack.
No chest pain. And smoke inhalation
already explains the arrhythmia.
The guy was in the burn unit for six
months and had multiple surgeries.
Could be a hospital-acquired
infection. Maybe MRSA.
Works for me.
Draw a blood culture,
start him on antibiotics,
vancomycin plus broad
gram-negative coverage.
If you called to see the design for
my prison tats, they're still in R and D.
You need to talk to Tritter.
Not according to my lawyer.
Your lawyer isn't gonna be able to
get the DA to drop the case. Tritter can.
Yeah, you know what
else Tritter can do?
You are not impressing anyone!
You may call
yourself principled,
but what you really are is
a stubborn adolescent idiot!
This isn't his fault!
I'm not the one who...
You used the rectal
thermometer on him.
You insulted him
instead of apologizing.
You flaunted your drug use in his
face and you refused to accept a deal...
I accepted the deal!
Not until after you
stole a dead guy's pills!
Allegedly.
Tritter has been opening doors
for you every step of the way
and you keep slamming them shut.
There are no more
openings to give, House.
If you wanna stay out of prison,
you got to make one for yourself.
It's Vicodin. You function
better on it. Talk to him.
MRSA's a bacteria that
often infects hospital patients.
The burns on your chest and arm exposed
raw flesh that made you a wide-open target.
But the antibiotics would
take care of it, right?
Depends on what strain it is.
We'll know more once we get
the results back from these cultures.
So this MRSA thing,
would it make
everything look blue?
He's seeing blue.
Who'd you get the scrip from?
Cuddy. You wanna
know what I gave her?
MRSA wouldn't change
his ocular palette.
Heavy metal poisoning could cause
vision changes, particularly thallium.
If it was thallium,
he'd be losing his hair.
So maybe it's menopause.
He's 28 years old.
Yes, his age is the reason it's
weird that a man has menopause.
Male menopause. High
estrogen, low testosterone.
Explains the temperature
swings, disorientation,
endocrinologically similar
to female menopause,
but without the vaginas
and the mahjong tiles.
Male menopause doesn't
explain the blue vision.
Blue vision isn't a symptom.
It's a side effect of Viagra.
It's right there on the label,
which I'd had no reason to have
read, except that I'm a doctor.
He's not taking Viagra.
You mean he didn't tell
you he was taking Viagra.
I don't care how sick he is. Trust
me, he still thinks he's got a shot.
Menopause causes temperature
swings, limpness, limpness causes pills,
pills cause the blues.
He's presenting no other
signs of premature aging.
Aging's not the only cause.
You said that he's got
burns on 54% of his body.
Sure it's not 55%?
Burns to his genitals could
cause testicular trauma.
Which could in turn cause...
Run a hormone panel.
When it comes back positive, pump him
full of testosterone and send him home.
Stop following me!
Thank God my parents are dead.
If the old man had heard I had
menopause, I'd never live it down.
It's nothing to be ashamed of.
Once these testosterone pellets dissolve,
your system will be back to normal.
Yeah, but until
then I'm an old lady.
Okay to come in?
It's not MRSA. He's not
being isolated anymore.
Anyone not in a
white coat is welcome.
You're looking better.
How you feeling?
I'm good.
It turns out I got some hormone
thing. They're fixing it right now.
Are you okay?
Yeah, I think so, I just...
Derek, are you in pain?
You need to get these out!
Okay, hold on, what's wrong?
Get these out! What's going on?
Looks like an allergic reaction.
Hold on! We're going to
get you something to stop it.
It's okay. No,
just take them out!
But you've got to calm
down. It's okay. Get them out!
Derek! Get them out!
Derek, let her go!
Two milligrams of
IV lorazepam, stat!
Get them out!
The complaint department
is across the hall.
I'm busy.
Can I just assume that you told
me how unfair I'm being and...
I'm sorry.
You could throw a dart at all the
adjectives between arrogant and unhinged,
and I'm sure you'd hit
one that describes me.
There's a reason
I operate that way.
I live in pain.
Pain that on good days
is merely intolerable.
And on bad ones will suck
the life force right out of you.
It doesn't mean that
I've handled this right.
Actually, it means I was wrong.
Thank you.
I know that couldn't have
been easy for you to say.
Even if you don't
mean a word of it.
I'm sorry.
Look, you can hook me
up to a damn polygraph...
And I'm sure you'd pass.
The thing is I've never been
interested in what you have to say.
All I care about is what you do.
I'll see you at the hearing.
It wasn't the medicine.
Contamination and allergy
tests both came back negative.
There was nothing to
suggest a pulmonary embolism.
And his EKG showed the expected tachycardia
from the exertion of the attack.
And I'm fine, by the
way, thanks for asking.
Aggression comes on that fast
has got to have a neurological basis.
We should do a CT for a frontal
lobe tumor and an LP for meningitis.
Great. Have at it.
That's it? No challenging our
theory, no tearing us down?
No need. You got
it under control.
Where are you going?
Upstairs this time.
To do what?
Check myself into rehab.
Did Tritter offer
you another deal?
Nope. This is all me.
So, no slaps on the
back? Encouraging words?
We're just trying to
understand what this is.
I hope it's me detoxing,
otherwise I soiled a perfectly good
pair of underwear last night for nothing.
So this is for real?
It's not just a
show for Tritter?
Absolutely it's a show
for Tritter. And the judge.
And, unfortunately, unless
it's real, there is no show.
Hey, if it doesn't help my case,
at least I can go to prison
with heightened senses.
All the better to enjoy
my strolls around the yard.
Time's up. Group's starting.
Gonna need to check that stuff.
When I lead the
big patient rebellion,
Voldemort here
is the first to go.
CT was normal, no
frontal lobe tumor,
LP was negative for meningitis.
We're back to square one.
What about something
vascular? Polyarteritis nodosa?
Brain lesions would
have shown up on the CT.
Legionnaire's explains
the chills and temperature.
Altered mental status
causes the aggression.
We would have seen
respiratory problems.
We're throwing darts.
We need to go to House.
We need to deal
with this ourselves.
He can make the time!
Derek's still his patient.
The man's life as he
knows it could be over.
I think you of all people would
want to cut him some slack.
We're treating a man who runs into
burning buildings for perfect strangers.
He didn't ask for what's happening to
him. House did everything to himself.
He's been cut more
than enough slack.
Right now, House has more
important things to deal with.
It was the first time
I'd seen him in months.
I guess I was hoping he'd put his arms
around me and tell me he understood.
But he said he wasn't
ready to forgive me.
Well, he may never be ready.
You're doing the only thing
you can do. You're trying.
How about you, Greg?
Have you thought about how to
fix things with people in your life?
No need.
The people in my life
have no expectations of me.
Makes all our lives easier.
Apparently not.
The first step in recovery...
Is admitting I have a problem.
I've obviously done
that or I wouldn't be here.
I've even embraced step two and
accepted that there is a higher power.
Maybe not a god per se, but that
André the Giant guy was powerful.
Where I start to butt up
against it is step three,
surrendering my will
to this higher power.
I'm sure André's ghost has
my back and all, but my free will,
I never leave home without it.
Kind of like your pills.
If you could do this on your own,
I assume you wouldn't be here.
True.
Everybody lies. His tox screen.
It's been clean every time.
Exactly. It shouldn't be.
He's had extensive skin
grafts, which hurt like hell.
Not everybody's House. People
can handle pain without medication.
But they do have pain.
This guy's worried about losing
his job, so he's hiding the pain.
We find out where the pain is,
maybe we find out what the problem is.
Or he doesn't feel pain.
Either way, it's something.
When? Two minutes ago.
Pulse is 157, respiration 42.
He was fine. He was
just telling me a joke,
just a minute ago...
Get her out of here!
No fluid in his lungs!
O2 stat's 85. He's hypoxic!
We're gonna have to intubate!
It's not his lungs! He's
got marked ST elevation.
He's having a heart attack.
Pick a color.
Medication time.
"You are a ray of
sunshine on a cloudy day."
He's stable.
Won't stay that way.
His blood tests showed
troponins and CK-MB up.
Chase was right. He
was hiding chest pain.
He's been having a whole
series of heart attacks.
Heart attacks can't cause you
to reach out and choke someone.
Lack of oxygen to the
brain causes disorientation.
Increased adrenaline
causes rage.
The more important question
is what caused the attacks?
Where are you
going? To see House.
We have a 28-year-old with clean
arteries, no valvular abnormalities
having multiple heart attacks.
I'm not gonna wait for Chase
to give us another breakthrough.
Maybe we should go.
We don't have an answer yet.
I'm fine, by the way.
Thanks for asking!
Whoever came up with buprenorphine
to wean off Vicodin should be shot.
Then stabbed in the eye.
I think someone needs
to adjust my meds!
The heart shows no
signs of inflammation or...
If the cause of the heart attacks
isn't internal, it must be external.
Something environmental.
None of the attacks
happened in the same place.
Still must be
something in common.
First one happened in
an apartment building fire.
Fire, water, smoke,
oxygen masks...
The second and third
ones happened here.
There was no fire,
no water, no smoke.
His clothes were all
different, he'd been cleaned.
That's the "whats".
How about the "whos"?
His partner Amy was
at all three attacks, but...
Anyone else?
People don't
cause heart attacks.
Well, then you shouldn't be
worried about proving me wrong.
Amy? Would you
come with me, please?
Anything new on my brother?
We're not quite sure yet.
Could you come with me?
Yeah.
What's this all about?
I don't know.
They wanted to
talk to us together.
Derek!
House was right.
I don't get it.
How can I be causing
his heart attacks?
You may be carrying an
agent that triggered them.
It could be anything, mold
spores, poisonous plant residue,
something you
picked up at a fire site.
Until we identify the agent,
we can't allow you near Derek.
I can't believe that
I'm doing this to him.
You can't blame
yourself for this.
You know how he
got those skin grafts?
He was trapped in a fire.
We were clearing rooms
in an office building fire.
And the ceiling collapsed, and it
cut me off from the rest of the group.
And I kept yelling
that I was fine,
but Derek refused to wait for
the team to clear the debris,
so he took off looking
for another access point.
He got caught in a backdraft.
He almost died
because of me once.
And now it's happening again.
You're not my mom. You don't
have to keep checking up on me.
How you doing?
Not bad,
considering I've just learned
I'm completely powerless.
See this big fancy wing?
It was built because
this program works.
Faulty logic.
This big fancy wing exists because
some people with money think that it works,
wanna believe that they
can buy a better world.
This is nothing short of idealized
despair. Let other people wallow in it.
I don't even know
what that means.
None of this means anything.
It's just nonsensical
slogans and platitudes.
Meaning takes
time, it takes work.
What do you think
I've been doing?
You've been here for two
days! Talk about wallowing in it!
We all get it. We know
how much pain you have.
You're here to deal with
that and get on with your life!
Right! I should have an affair with a
dying patient and move into a hotel.
You're a coward, House.
You find fault in everybody because
you're afraid to look at yourself.
Thanks. I was running short on
platitudes. You can leave now.
We tested Amy for about a dozen different
agents, but they all came back negative.
So she's not
causing the attacks.
Derek, are you in love with her?
What does that have
to do with anything?
Amy told me how you
got those skin grafts.
And the way you're always watching out
for her, and I see the way you look at her.
Have you told her how you feel?
She has a six-year-old daughter.
Women with daughters
can still fall in love.
I know.
Because she did.
With my brother.
They're engaged.
Broken heart syndrome.
He's in love and it's killing him.
I thought that only happened
to 80-year-old widows.
Thanks to his menopause and estrogen
level, he basically is an old woman.
BHS is an acute physical
response to an emotional experience.
Stress triggers a flood
of catecholamines...
That's a plain old stress
cardiomyopathy, not a heart attack.
But if you're too worried about
losing your job to get it treated,
they can devolve into
full-on heart attacks.
You think it's a coincidence this
started when Amy got engaged?
No, I don't.
But now that you know the "why",
what are you gonna
do to stop the "how"?
I already put him on beta-blockers
and nitroglycerin. No effect.
We need to put him
on antidepressants.
Not if you're right.
Antidepressants would inhibit
his autonomic nervous system,
which would only speed
up the heart attacks.
We could try propylthiouracil,
slow down his metabolic rate.
Thyroid effect would
only weaken the heart.
The only other option
is blood thinners.
This is not a fat guy with plaque-filled
arteries and a swollen heart.
He's a guy whose brain
is trying to kill his heart.
So buy him a girlfriend,
make him happy.
That might make you happy.
The only thing that'll
make him happy is Amy.
So keep him away from her.
He has a myocardial infarction
every time she walks in the room.
What do you think
will happen to his heart
when we tell him he
can never see her again?
He needs a shrink.
Chase's idea is as good as any.
But short of frying his brain and
wiping Amy out, he's screwed.
We need Cuddy.
Why?
So you can tell her why
you need to fry a guy's brain.
The guy's heart isn't working
and you want to shock his brain.
Electroshock therapy is the only
way to erase his memories of Amy
and stop the brain's
chemical attack on the heart.
This isn't 1940!
The problem can be
controlled with antidepressants.
Cameron?
Antidepressants would inhibit
his autonomic nervous system,
speed up the attacks.
LMNO, PTU, blood thinners,
none of them will solve this problem.
The man's got a real-life
Harlequin Romance in his head.
We're gonna pull out
the 1940 playbook.
Bilateral electrodes,
high-stimulus sine-wave intensity,
turning that dial
all the way to 11.
It's basic brain chemistry.
We interrupt protein synthesis,
altering the neurotransmitter system.
End result, no memories,
no Amy, no problem.
Go ahead.
You heard the
lady, go plug him in.
Am I really that pathetic?
What are you talking about?
If I had pitched
electroshock therapy
as a cure for broken heart
syndrome any other time,
you'd have dug in, made me try a
hundred other useless things first.
So either you're actually
beginning to trust me
or you just feel sorry for me.
You presented a
reasonable argument.
You were clear-headed
and non-impulsive about it.
Never once used
the word "moron."
The rehab's working, House.
You'll still be able to
perform routine functions
like walking, talking,
tying your shoes.
The treatment targets the
anterior cingulated cortex.
It should only affect your
experiential memories.
So my parents? My childhood?
If this works, you
won't remember them.
Or your firefighting training.
And Amy.
Are you okay with that?
I wouldn't miss her, right?
Tell Amy how you feel.
Because if she loves you...
No. I won't do that to
her. Or to my brother.
You're effectively killing who
you are just to keep this secret.
She doesn't love me.
Caterpillar?
Lower intestine
with ulcerative colitis.
You crash art therapy classes
just for the adrenaline rush?
Cuddy wouldn't get off the phone until
I promised I'd come and see for myself.
I got to admit, this
move I did not expect.
Well, don't tell anyone, but the photos
of smiling people in the brochures,
it's just marketing.
Well, you're obviously
making an effort.
So I suppose the next step
is for me to talk to the DA.
Which you have
no intention of doing.
No.
So words mean nothing, actions
mean nothing, what the hell is left?
You son of a bitch!
What about your
words, your actions?
"Got to get House cleaned up. Got
to get him to show some humility."
But when it comes to
actually doing something,
you prove that all you care
about is bitch-slapping a guy
who refused to kiss your ass!
You ever trust an addict?
You ever give one the
benefit of the doubt?
How many times did
that work out for you...
Yeah, I get it.
And so you were screwed over by
your wife, your mother, your partner.
But you keep sending them Christmas cards
while you take it out on everyone else!
No more Christmas cards.
No, I learned.
People like you,
even your actions lie.
I'm scared.
I know.
I'm gonna give you a muscle
relaxant so your body doesn't convulse.
Count backwards from 10.
Ten, nine, eight,
seven...
Go.
What's your name? Derek.
Heart sounds good.
Do you know what city we're in?
No.
Would you be okay
with a couple of visitors?
Derek, it's me. Brock.
I'm your brother, and when you get
out of here, you'll be staying with me.
I'm Amy.
I'm your friend.
I'm sorry, but I don't
remember either of you.
We've given him four
rounds of electroshock.
The charge made his voice a little
higher, but the EKG and BP are good.
Good.
We're gonna give him his
last round in the morning,
then be in court
for your hearing.
Thanks.
I'm gonna stay
here. Monitor Derek.
Thanks for the update.
My next condolence call is
arriving. I'll see you guys tomorrow.
I got you something.
Nice.
I figured it might help make a
good impression on the judge.
It's not that nice.
I had no business
blaming you for any of this.
I know you were just trying
to help me. Protect me.
That's what friends do.
Is this an apology?
Part of the program.
If you don't like it, I
can stop. Not at all.
It's just so
unfamiliar.
Please, keep going.
He looks lost.
It's gonna take him a while.
Brock's pulling a double shift.
He can't stand to
see him this way.
Derek's gonna need him, Amy.
I know the timing isn't great
with a wedding coming up.
What wedding?
Yours. You and Brock.
We're not getting married.
We don't even date.
Why would you think
we're getting married?
When you first offered Dr. House
the chance to check into drug rehab,
how did he respond?
He told me to get
out of his office.
I warned him that he could end up
in prison and lose his medical license.
If he was concerned,
he didn't show it.
So you continued
your investigation?
Yes.
Which is what led me
to the hospital pharmacy.
Turn it off. What did
you tell the pharmacist
was the reason for your visit?
I thought I told you never
to call me when I'm on trial.
The memories were false.
We fried his brain for nothing.
Whatever was killing
him before is still there.
We did an MRI.
There's slight hypo-perfusion
in the anterior cortex.
What did you find when you
checked the pharmacy log?
Hold on, Mr. Vickers.
Thanks, Your Honor.
It's hard to hear.
Did you test for clotting
time and LV function?
I believe that this is a medical
emergency, Your Honor.
His blood's normal and his
heart's pumping it up to the brain.
But it's not all getting there.
Something's obstructing
the blood flow...
Dr. House, you were
given adequate notice
to make arrangements
for your patients.
There's no hyper intensity to
suggest a foreign body near the region.
And no signs of infection
or vascular malformations.
It's lower down.
Dr. House, hang up!
The cytology on the LP
doesn't suggest a tumor.
Now!
Hang on a second.
Does your voice always get that
high and annoying when you're angry?
Do you want to go to jail?
No, thank you.
Set him up for a selective vertebral
angiography. I'm on my way.
Dr. House.
House! Sit down!
Why? I'm bored.
There's nothing I can say or do
that's gonna make a difference here.
If you leave this room, I
will find you in contempt.
Get a recess.
Are you out of your mind?
They said they wanted me
there, but I don't think they like me.
His voice isn't high because
of the electrical charges.
It's another symptom
of menopause.
His system keeps getting
hit by women's issues,
so let's follow the pattern.
What might obstruct the blood flow
that's more common in women than men?
- Is the catheter in?
- Go back to court.
We'll let you know the results.
Shut up and wire him.
Center the image on the
interpeduncular cistern.
Keep it moving at
30 frames per second.
If you think the arteries are
narrowing, you're gonna need still shots,
which we can do without you.
The problem is not
how wide the road is.
There's a guy with a squeegee
on the sidewalk flagging cars.
That's what's
causing the slowdown.
We find him, we
find the problem.
He's wired. Go!
Injecting the dye.
Blood's in the capillaries.
There.
Mr. Squeegee.
Spinal meningioma pushing
on the nerves to the vocal cords
creates the voice change.
And that nerve just happens to
live right near the meningeal branch
of the vertebral artery, obstructs
the blood flow to the brain.
The brain malfunctions,
creating false memories.
Memories cause love. Love kills.
And we didn't
completely screw up.
Cleaning the slate bought us
time to find the real problem.
On the other hand,
if we had been better,
we wouldn't have
needed the time.
Schedule him for
surgery. Dig that thing out.
He can start enjoying real
misery instead of the fake stuff.
House.
I just heard that you
apologized to Wilson.
Detoxing. I didn't
know what I was saying.
Excuse me.
I have to go to jail.
What is your position
at Princeton-Plainsboro?
Chief Administrator
and Dean of Medicine.
And you're responsible for
oversight of the pharmacy?
Yes.
Sorry. I didn't
mean to interrupt.
I hope you don't mind that
we continued on without you?
I said I was sorry. There's
no need to be sarcastic.
What is this?
That's our prescription
sign-out log from December 24th.
Does that appear to be
Dr. House's signature?
Yes.
What has he signed for?
A prescription for oxycodone in
the name of patient Larry Zebalusky.
And did those pills
ever reach that patient?
No. Why?
He was already dead.
And Dr. House knew this?
Yes.
So, Dr. House had no legal or medical
basis for acquiring that oxycodone?
Dr. Cuddy?
He never got the pills.
It's his signature. The
log is strictly controlled.
Dr. House did pick up a prescription,
but it wasn't for oxycodone.
It says oxycodone.
You testified...
I know, but it wasn't oxycodone.
Dr. Wilson informed me that
Dr. House already tried to steal
the pain medication of this
patient, which made clear to me
that Dr. House was in a particularly
vulnerable and desperate state.
So I went to the pharmacy
and I swapped bottles.
Dr. House only got a
bottle with placebos.
I understand your impulse to
protect a valued colleague...
I have it right here on
the inventory report...
Your Honor, she's lying! She's
obviously forged that report.
In light of this evidence...
If this is real, why didn't
she mention it earlier?
I move to dismiss this case!
There is other
evidence, Your Honor!
Everyone shut up and sit down.
Dr. Cuddy, why are you only
now coming forward with this?
I guess I never
expected it to go this far.
The witness is excused.
Your Honor, you can't
seriously believe...
Dr. House, please stand.
My suspicion is your boss...
My suspicion is you have
better friends than you deserve.
Rules and laws
apply to everyone.
You are not as
special as you think.
But Detective Tritter
chose to make you so.
Detective, I don't know
exactly what's going on here,
but I am sure that this man is not
flooding the streets with cocaine.
I'm also certain that,
knowing Dr. House,
he must have done
something to set you off.
But you're gonna
have to live with it.
Given Dr. Cuddy's testimony, I'm not
going to allow this to proceed to jury.
Case dismissed.
Court is adjourned.
Dr. House, you're still guilty of
contempt for that little walkout earlier.
You'll be spending
the night in jail,
and after that you're going
right back to your rehab.
Bailiff, take
Dr. House into custody.
Dr. House.
So should I be looking
for you in the shadows,
or flinch every time
a car backfires?
Good luck.
I hope I'm wrong about you.
They got the meningioma.
Your brain should start
generating real memories again.
What do I do when I get out?
You have people who love
you. They'll take care of you.
You start over.
I'm surprised to see you're not
spooning your way through the walls.
So, what do you say? How
about a conjugal visit to celebrate?
There's nothing to celebrate,
House! You made me perjure myself.
Fabricate evidence.
You make everyone around
you worse for being there.
The only bright spot is
that now I own your ass.
When you get out of rehab, you're
gonna be pulling double clinic duty,
giving lectures to students,
helping me find donors,
pretty much anything
else I ask. You got it?
Your buprenorphine.
You get these from the
pharmacy or from Voldemort?
Voldemort. Why?
What difference does it...
That's Vicodin. He's
been slipping you Vicodin?
No! He'd be risking his
minimum-wage job to do that.
The whole time?
My higher power
said it was okay.
Nothing's changed?
Nothing's changed.
The apology.
You didn't need to do
that to make this work.
Believe what you want.
Good night, House.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Good night, Wilson.