- Previously on The Resident...
- You led me to believe
that my arrogance
killed my patient.
It was a company that
makes defective valves
and owns you.
You've already lost a son,
and I want to do
everything possible
to ensure that
doesn't happen again.
With our VNS poster child,
Henry Barnett. Has
he been admitted?
Brought in with a
possible seizure.
The VNS is being featured
at the Innovation
Summit tomorrow.
If any issue comes
up, I want it handled.
Quietly.
The QuoVadis
device malfunctioned.
Every three minutes
it fired and stopped
Henry Barnett's heart.
And each time, we
managed to bring him back,
but it got harder and
harder every time.
Until Dr. Hawkins managed to
locate the programming wand...
that deactivates the VNS.
And the only reason
that Henry's alive...
is because
it malfunctioned
in the hospital.
It's not the first time a
QuoVadis device has failed.
A former resident died
from a defective heart valve.
Which is why we're here.
I've halted the use of all
QuoVadis devices at Chastain.
We believe it's best
to sever ties with Gordon Page
and his company immediately.
As bad as this is,
we're talking about
isolated incidents.
All medical devices
come with risk.
QuoVadis insisted
the VNS was safe.
So far, our partnership
with Gordon Page has been
a resounding success. Volume,
revenue... they're both up.
And let's not forget we
stand to make a killing
from stock options when
QuoVadis goes public.
When the truth comes out
that these devices kill people,
there will be no IPO.
There will, however, be lawsuits
that could bankrupt
this hospital.
QuoVadis is hosting an
innovation summit today
with investors
coming from all over.
Let's not rush to
any conclusions.
Randolph, you
brought Gordon to us.
Yeah, I did.
And a child nearly died.
And I cannot live knowing
we'd allow that to happen again.
Can you?
You're telling me the hospital
won't break with QuoVadis?
Few things are harder than
making a large corporation
renounce a profitable
revenue stream.
Bell didn't even try
to convince the board?
Believe it or not,
Randolph did the right thing.
Well, he'll turn on a dime
whenever it suits him.
We can't count on
him for anything.
The court of public
opinion is our best shot now.
Well, that's good.
Zoey's furious.
She's dying to talk to
the press about QuoVadis.
Well, a statement to the press
from a mother who almost
lost her child will go a long way.
Keep me posted.
Sergeant Jones served two tours.
Fought bravely beside
our men and women
in the Kandahar Province and
is the recipient of a Purple Heart.
But like so many of
our brave soldiers,
he has debilitating nightmares.
The QuoVadis VNS
has been approved
to treat a range of conditions,
from epilepsy to depression.
And now... PTSD.
And it is going to end Sergeant
Jones' suffering for good.
And he's not the
only one we'll help.
Later today, 20 more veterans
like Sergeant Jones will receive
their very own QuoVadis VNS.
And to show how simple
and safe a cure can be,
we will be streaming
these surgeries live
from VA hospitals
across the country.
♪ ♪
Meanwhile, "Waaa!"
"Who is that?"
"It's Nic!"
"Hey, Conrad! I came to help!"
"Sure. Great."
"Just because I wear
casual clothes does not mean
I'm not a doctor!"
Hey, buddy, how you feeling?
Okay.
He drew this.
What?!
Wow. Who is this?
That's Nic. See the cape?
Yeah, I see the resemblance.
How you feeling?
You need to get some rest.
I'll be fine.
You're gonna get to
make that statement
about the VNS to the press.
Hopefully today.
I know you're
concerned about Henry...
I'll make time.
I think I can get the
reporters to interview you here.
All you have to do is tell the
truth about what happened.
Of course.
Is Henry gonna be all right?
For now, yes.
Eckart thinks we should
consider moving Henry
to Duke University Hospital.
And... I agree.
Duke has a comprehensive
program for pediatric epilepsy
with new surgical options.
They're experimental,
but they're our best hope
to get Henry off the meds.
The issue is,
most health insurance won't
cover experimental procedures.
But don't worry.
We will figure this out.
You got to see this.
Gordon Page is putting the VNS
in 20 soldiers today
to cure their PTSD.
And 100 more will be implanted
over the next few weeks.
There is no proof that
it's gonna do anything
for PTSD. It might
even kill them.
The same way it
almost killed Henry.
Well, we have to stop this.
Is the hospital coming
out against QuoVadis?
No. But Zoey Barnett is.
In an hour, she'll be on all
three local news channels.
She's telling them the
VNS nearly killed her son.
The optics here are a disaster,
and the timing
couldn't be worse.
Where is she now?
At Chastain with the child.
Have the boy's
seizures returned?
Is he on multiple drugs again?
Dr. Bell isn't returning
our calls. We're in the dark.
Get me everything there is
to know about her and the kid.
Okay.
Incision to close in two hours.
- Nice work, Dr. Bell.
- Thanks, Paul.
I'll check on
Mr. Flynn in the ICU.
You leave any
blood in the patient?
What'd you do, saw him in half?
A liver resection. You know
how the liver bleeds, Simon.
Yeah, so I noticed.
You in for scratchers this week?
Whoa, yeah, I got a
feeling today's the day.
You've had that feeling before,
and how much have we lost
- on the lotto already?
- The only reason
why we haven't won the
jackpot yet is you're bad luck.
Then why do you play with me?
Oh, I got a soft spot
for the ugly ones.
You all right?
Yeah. Getting old... it sucks.
Guess it's better
than the alternative.
Let me see that.
Your feet swollen, too?
Ah, been eating
too much salt lately.
You've eaten too much
salt all your life. This is new.
- I'd like to run a couple tests.
- And I'd like to have a date
with a Rockette, but that
ain't gonna happen, either.
Come on. You're
already in a hospital.
I'm gonna come and find you.
Pain in the ass.
Oh!
Excuse us. Sorry. Where is he?
Okay. Come on. Excuse me.
Sorry. Excuse us.
Excuse us.
- Hi. Sorry.
- Hey, welcome.
Can I get your, uh, name?
Uh, Marilyn Spoelstra. I just...
Oh! Okay.
Here, let me get you a chair.
Three hours in a hatchback.
Wouldn't even let
us stop and stretch.
I raised a drill sergeant.
Well, it wasn't
some joyride, Ma.
I was doing 75
to save your life.
What brings you in today?
Oh, just a little bit of stomach
pain. Comes and goes.
Any past medical issues?
Marilyn has diabetes,
high cholesterol,
high blood pressure.
She also has perfect pitch and
two majestic German shepherds.
- Oh, just one. Phineas passed.
- No, not Mr. Phin.
Wait. How do you
guys know each other?
Uh, we're from Cecil, Alabama.
Dr. Shaw used to come
with his mobile clinic.
Parked outside our
church once a month.
And Kay always made sure
that they were first in line.
When you didn't show
two months in a row,
I looked online, saw you
on Chastain's website.
Her pain's never been this bad.
Where exactly is the pain?
It's over here.
That's right upper quadrant.
Could be gallstones.
Oh, God! And there it is again.
We should probably
get you to the ER.
- Ooh!
- Uh, we have
an ultrasound machine.
Let's try to figure out
what's wrong here first.
Is all this really necessary?
Nothing's too
good for Chastain's
longest-serving employee.
Well, can I get a
'65 Mustang instead?
You can buy it yourself.
You're winning that lottery.
This is gonna be cold.
O... kay.
How have you been sleeping?
Fine, when I'm in my recliner.
But when I lie flat, I
feel like I'm drowning.
And then, I've been
getting these chills.
Chills? Since when?
Mm... last Tuesday, I think.
I hear you're Chastain's
unofficial historian.
Keeper of secrets.
Oh, I've seen a few things.
I was here when
Randolph was a resident.
Keep in mind
before you continue,
that as CEO, I can fire you.
I did not know you did
your residency here.
Oh, he was as green
as new-mown grass.
His first week,
I'm putting supplies
away, and who do I find
in a custodial closet?
Young Randolph Bell.
- Oh!
- Yeah. He tried to play it off
that he was lost, but he
wasn't the first resident
I found hiding
from his attending.
You're fired.
All right, spit it out, boys.
That's not supposed
to be on my heart, is it?
No.
It's called a myxoma.
It's probably been
growing there for months.
Thing got so big
it started to block
- the blood flow to your heart.
- Which explains
the fluid buildup
and pitting edema.
It's all signs of heart failure.
Look, the good news is
we caught it early
while it's still operable.
When Bell brought
you in for testing...
he probably saved your life.
Well... I guess
being friends with you
finally did me some good.
I'm not sure the myxoma
explains all of Simon's symptoms.
- It was confirmed on the echo.
- Yeah, but there could be
a coexisting condition, and
that would complicate surgery,
so I'd just like to
run a few more tests.
Delaying his tumor resection is
just gonna worsen his prognosis.
But if there is
something else going on,
it would increase his risk for
perioperative complications.
Yeah, okay. Yeah,
fine. Run your tests.
But I'm not gonna postpone
the surgery much longer.
Well, barring any issues,
we'll still get it done today.
Okay.
How's Henry?
Uh, well, his...
heart's not stopping anymore.
But he has a long road ahead.
It happened
because you told Zoey
the VNS was safe when it wasn't.
You put profits
over patients, again.
I pulled all QuoVadis
devices as soon as I learned
the VNS was flawed.
Good for you. But Gordon Page
is still putting patients at
risk, now more than ever,
actually.
I've done everything
I can to stop him,
and you have no idea
what I've sacrificed
to protect patients
from this man.
He's coming for me next.
So you save your
morality lesson.
I'll let you take that.
Feeling a bit better?
Yeah, thanks to your drugs.
Are you single, honey?
Kay's got a boyfriend,
but it isn't serious.
- Ma, quit.
- Oh, you can fuss
over me, but I don't get
to be involved in your life?
I see gallstones.
But there's no
gallbladder wall thickening.
You're right, no sign
of acute cholecystitis.
That's a good thing?
Yes and no.
We've controlled
your flare-up today,
but I think you'll need surgery
soon to remove your gallbladder.
Well, let's do it
now, get it over with.
I can't take this
pain much longer.
That won't actually
be possible here.
You don't have insurance, and
Chastain is a private hospital.
They're not gonna
do that surgery
unless your situation
is life-threatening.
So I got to be dying
to get some help?
Well, who the hell
made these rules?
Well, we could refer you to
County to get it scheduled.
They take uninsured patients.
Typically, their wait
list is months long.
Well, we can't wait here. Uh-uh.
We got no place to stay.
- We're gonna have to go home.
- You'd make her go home
and suffer like this,
for months, maybe?
And what if she
suddenly gets worse?
You know what? I
have a friend at County.
Let me reach out, see if
they can get her in right now.
- All right, then.
- Thank you.
You know, Bell
told me about you.
He said you are one
real pain in the ass.
I'll take it. Pain-in-the-ass
people get things done.
You know...
when Randolph was
young, he was a lot like you.
I remember his second
year as a resident.
He got into a real
shouting match
with his chief of surgery.
He wanted to stop doctors
from smoking in the hospitals.
Said it was no good
for anyone's health,
patients or doctors.
Everyone, they just
thought he was no fun.
But... he was right.
And eventually,
they banned smoking.
And the very next year...
- he helped me quit.
- Oh, Bell,
a reformer?
That's hard to believe.
This place has a way
of changing people.
Just wait.
Change you, too.
Hey.
- Hey.
- You need anything?
- No.
- You ready?
Yes. I want to do this.
Yeah, you're gonna be great.
We'll be all set for you in
about ten minutes, Ms. Barnett.
Thanks.
I'll be with Henry
until they need me.
Yeah. Go.
W-What's your
favorite kind of game?
On the story mode games,
there's a bad guy
that you have to stop
with missions that connect
- to each other.
- Oh.
And it's really cool.
Ooh. So you're hunting bad guys.
- What are you doing here?
- Ms. Barnett.
I came here to check
in on you and Henry.
Mom, he gave it to me.
Look, I understand
that you're upset.
I am, too. That's
why I'm here... to help.
Hey.
I was just coming to check in.
What's going on?
Mr. Page was just leaving.
You all right?
Yes.
Well, they're ready for you.
I'll stay with Henry.
Thanks, Nic.
Hear me out. Henry had
a very rare adverse event.
Is that what you call it?
Every new lifesaving device
has glitches in the first few years,
and then we adjust and we learn.
He's going to Duke.
They'll help him.
Now, please leave us alone.
And who's paying for
his treatment at Duke?
If the surgery is experimental,
insurance won't cover it.
Will you be able
to keep your job
while you're with your
son in North Carolina?
Without a job, will you
even have health insurance?
- What do you want?
- Henry's condition
is likely permanent.
I'm here to tell you
that QuoVadis is willing
to cover all his
medical bills...
Not for a month,
not for a year...
For his whole life.
I don't believe you.
I'll put it in writing.
It's the least we can do.
And in return, I'm guessing...
you don't want me
to go talk to the press.
Don't make me your enemy.
Take the offer.
And if you go public with a
grievance against QuoVadis,
now or ever...
this deal goes away.
We're ready for you
now, Ms. Barnett.
How much?
How much was Page's offer?
I heard he was here.
There were more zeroes than
I've ever seen in one number.
You can't take it.
We'll find another way
to pay for Henry's
treatment, I promise you.
- You can't promise that.
- Yes, I can.
I do promise that. Zoey,
you need to speak out,
or people will die if you don't.
I get it, I get it... that kind
of money, it is tempting.
Even all that money,
it can't be enough
to stop me from
waking up every night
and running into Henry's
room to make sure
he didn't stop
breathing. It won't...
It won't bring his brother back.
I signed already.
QuoVadis wired the money.
It's done.
I am not a horrible person.
I will help arrange...
for Henry's transfer to Duke.
We need to get him
there as quickly as we can.
Thank you, Conrad.
For everything.
Good luck, Zoey.
What about cancellations?
There's got to be
some way to get her in.
Okay, thanks, man.
Nope. I understand.
They wanted to
schedule Marilyn's surgery
seven weeks out.
I talked them down to three.
- This isn't your fault.
- No, in a way, it is.
The mobile clinic helped me
stop crises before they happened.
I am sure that you
encouraged Marilyn
to live a healthier
lifestyle many times.
I mean, there's only
so much we can do.
This is the situation, so
we have to deal with it.
Okay, how?
Where's your RV?
- It's down the street.
- Pull it around.
We're gonna have
a working lunch.
Welcome to Le Château Shaw.
- Château what?
- Come on.
You're mere steps from
the best medical care
Atlanta has to offer.
What on earth...?
- Oh, my.
- We provide our guests
with the utmost privacy.
Unfortunately, the pool's
closed for renovation indefinitely.
- Are you sure this is okay? It should
be fine until your mom has the surgery.
- And there's a supermarket within
walking distance. Yeah. And there's
a kitchen in the clinic...
Use it anytime you need.
But...
no more fatty foods.
They'll only worsen
your gallbladder attacks.
Listen to Dr. Shaw on
this. It's very important.
No more peanut butter.
No fried chicken.
No chocolate, no dairy.
And... definitely no more bacon.
- Well, then what's left?
- Fruits,
veggies, whole
grains, lean protein.
No bacon? Harsh.
Mina said you're
storming the castle.
We're going.
Bradley's dead.
Julian is still missing.
I'm not gonna just sit
around while Gordon
- keeps hurting patients.
- His Innovation Summit
is open to the public...
We can walk right in.
We need to get the truth
about the VNS to the
military leaders there
who can actually
stop this thing.
Wow. Leaking what
the VNS did to Henry...
Now, that would be
a violation of HIPAA.
Which is why we're removing
anything that would
reveal the patient's identity.
Go get 'em.
One of my investigators
was able to locate
a former QuoVadis employee
who witnessed
fraud at the company.
- Will they come forward?
- No, they're afraid of Gordon.
So we'll have to
find proof ourselves.
What proof?
Zoey's out.
The VNS surgeries
are in a few hours.
- We're running out of time.
- I know.
I figured you'd be halfway
to QuoVadis by now.
I can't leave. I got
critical patients.
There's one now.
I got to go.
He's not responding
to fluid boluses.
Still hypotensive.
You thinking cardiogenic shock?
He's vasodilated.
His fever just spiked to 103.
This is septic shock.
Draw a lactate, set
up for a central line.
We've already
got blood cultures.
Let's get him started on
vancomycin and cefepime.
Hang norepinephrine
and titrate to a MAP of 65.
Stay with us, buddy.
I'm seeing Osler's nodes.
Those splinter hemorrhages
weren't there two minutes ago.
Cardiac mass must be infected.
It's not just a myxoma.
He's got endocarditis as well.
I've only seen two patients
with both in my entire career.
And did they survive?
One did.
Well, at least his pressures
are starting to come back up.
Obviously, under
normal circumstances,
we would recommend
holding off on surgery
with such a recent infection.
But with Simon's
valve deteriorating -
and his heart failure
worsening, he needs it soon.
His surgery just got
a whole lot riskier.
Let's broaden his antibiotics to
cover any possible resistance.
Do we still go forward?
If he does nothing, he'll live
for a couple more
months. Operating under
these circumstances might
mean he never wakes up.
I'll talk to him.
It's his decision.
This was all they had left.
Apparently, the word is out.
You know, if I got sick,
half this hospital would
pop a bottle of champagne.
Why? The other half don't drink?
Okay.
So, how bad is it?
Surgery's risky.
Even in Austin's hands, uh...
the odds of
survival aren't great.
What happens if AJ doesn't
cut this thing out of me?
What then?
Then the tumor will
completely obstruct your heart,
and...
you'll have a month,
maybe two.
Get your affairs in order.
So my choices are
risking dying on the table
or...
start saying goodbye.
Yeah, I'm afraid so.
Want to take a day
and-and think about it?
I'm a betting man.
I've beaten long odds before.
Nah...
let's do it.
All right.
You know,
I love my job.
Pay's not great.
But every day, I...
get to help you save lives.
And I sleep like a baby.
Oh, it's been a while since
I slept through the night.
You love this place
as much as I do.
I know you'll do
whatever you have to
to make things right.
Hey.
You better get ready.
The VNS stopped
the patient's heart
every three minutes.
It's a miracle he survived.
It nearly killed him.
If you move forward with this,
you are putting a ticking time
bomb in every one of these vets.
I'm sorry, wh-who are you again?
We're doctors who
work at Chastain.
The device is FDA-approved.
But the FDA doesn't
do independent testing.
And they're notorious
for grandfathering devices
based on previous ones
that don't even work.
We're satisfied
with the trial data
Gordon Page provided us.
Look.
That's Raptor's mentor...
The one that recommended
the heart valve that killed Bradley.
I don't suppose punching him
would do us any good, would it?
Come on.
May I have your
attention, please.
Our presentation will begin
shortly in the main lobby.
Dr. Benedict, I'm Dr. Okafor.
I met you with Dr. Austin.
Yeah, who could forget?
We're here because Gordon's
VNS is as deadly as his heart valve.
And it's about to
endanger dozens of lives
if we don't stop it.
Give AJ my best.
Dr. Benedict, you still
have a reputation to protect.
If you know anything... No, no.
The greatest
betrayal of Austin's life
was when his birth
parents abandoned him,
throwing him away like trash.
You were a close second.
That's how much your
friendship meant to him.
That's how much he trusted you.
The man you used to be
and the one you can be again.
When Mina said
the VNS will fail,
you weren't surprised. Why?
I didn't have a choice.
We had to get the
device to market.
You and Gordon?
I swear...
- I didn't know at first.
- Know what?
Let's take a walk.
Your pre-op numbers look
quite reassuring, my brother.
Once that tumor's removed,
we'll see about finding
you that Rockette.
Ah, I thought I'd seen
this room from every angle.
But I've never
seen it like this.
Okay, transfer on three.
One, two, three.
Starting the propofol.
Randolph.
Yeah?
Try not to make a mess.
She's on the floor.
It looks real bad.
- The pain usually goes away.
- And it's gotten worse.
We need to get her to Chastain.
Marilyn, one of your gallstones
is now causing an infection.
It's a good thing you didn't
head back to Alabama.
This could've happened on
the road, with nowhere to go.
Ultrasound shows
pericholecystic fluid.
And her white count
is at 20,000. No fever.
I'm Dr. Nolan. I'll be removing
your gallbladder today.
Oh, hallelujah.
Don't usually get that reaction.
You can take it out now?
Now it's an emergency.
Get her prepped for surgery.
I'll see you in the OR, okay?
I can't thank you enough.
Whatever you've done,
it is not too late
to make it right.
- Talk to us.
- What do you know?
What has QuoVadis done?
How can we stop this?
Oh...
I want to talk to AJ.
He deserves the truth.
Just him, not you.
All right.
Here we have the QuoVadis
vagus nerve stimulator.
All cities are online.
The surgeries
are about to begin.
Dr. Stevenson presiding.
The patient is David Jones.
Date of birth 8/6/1989.
Procedure to be performed
is surgical implantation
of a vagus nerve stimulator.
Let's begin. 10 blade.
I can't reach Austin.
I've called three times.
He's in surgery.
What is going on?
Abe doesn't trust us.
He'll only talk to Austin.
He knows something
that can help.
I'm on it.
All right, let's start
rewarming Simon
and get his heart pumping again.
Defib paddles to me.
Charge to ten joules.
Clear.
He's in V-fib.
Give 300 of amio and try again.
I'm here. I'm here.
And clear.
He won't stay out of V-fib.
His electrolytes are normal.
I've given him more magnesium,
but it's not doing anything.
Get the intracardiac epi ready.
Just worried his heart
sustained too much damage
during the procedure.
Injecting one milligram
of epi.
I can't get to him.
You have to.
I can't. His patient could die.
Let's get him on a balloon pump.
Charge to 20.
Clear.
Come on, Dr. Benedict,
please, tell us
whatever you know.
Where's the balloon pump?!
General?
My name is Marshall Winthrop.
I'm chairman of the board
at Chastain Park Memorial.
We'll be cutting
ties with QuoVadis
because of some information
I thought you'd be
interested in seeing.
Don't you understand
that lives are at stake here?
Please.
- Come on.
- Let's go.
Come on.
Mr. Page wants
to speak with you.
QuoVadis is engaged
in wide-ranging fraud.
All of their devices,
including the VNS,
are being shipped in from China
and then relabeled
as made in the USA.
By law, the military cannot use
any medical device
not American-made.
And those are shipping records
over the last few months.
You have more proof
there than you'll ever need.
What happened?
What happened is the
U.S. military partnered
with a liar and a fraud.
Our contract is
now null and void.
All surgeries are canceled.
Austin said Simon's
heart was too weak.
There is nothing
anyone could have done.
He would have hated this.
♪ ♪
What did you tell them?
I didn't tell them anything.
I wouldn't do that to you.
Good.
I knew I could count on you.
We have some storm clouds ahead.
But we will weather it
if we all stick together.
Talk tomorrow.
Hey. I hear Marilyn's
out of surgery.
Yeah, it went great.
Uh, Nolan did it
laparoscopically,
so she and Kay get to
go home in the morning.
Great.
It smells good. What is that?
Eight piece, extra crispy,
with a side of crunchy.
And a milkshake.
Everything we
told her not to eat.
She didn't forget our advice.
She knew exactly
what she was doing.
She just took matters
into her own hands.
She gave herself
a gallbladder attack
to get surgery right away.
What's wrong with
a hospital system
when patients have to put
their own lives in jeopardy
just to get access to treatment?
I, uh, was thinking about
what you said earlier.
Made me wonder if
you regret taking this job.
Well, it's complicated.
No. I mean, I get it.
We're saving people
from drowning.
You want to teach them to swim.
Look, you got us up and running.
I understand if you want
to go back on the road.
Yeah, you know, I may.
But, uh...
You know why I stay, don't you?
You're here.
We make a great team.
Yes, we do make a great team.
But it feels like maybe
there's something more.
Um, it's late.
I'm gonna take this
stuff home to wash it,
- and I'll see you tomorrow.
- Yeah. Okay.
Good night, Alec.
♪ ♪
It's done.
Well done.
Well, the investigators
came through just in time.
It was a team effort.
And the board?
I've already canvassed them all.
We're out.
Is QuoVadis finished?
It was a big financial blow.
But they have hard assets.
So if they find
an angel investor
to get them back on their feet
and pull them
out of this mess...
Well, then we have
to deliver a death blow.
We'll find one.
You saved more
lives than I did today.
It's a big shock today
for the Atlanta-based
QuoVadis Corporation.
The medical device
manufacturer suffered
a very public rejection
of its hottest new device,
the vagus nerve stimulator,
or, as it's better
known, the VNS.
QuoVadis CEO and
founder Gordon Page
had orchestrated a li...
Gordon. This is
Marshall Winthrop.
Oh, what do you want...
Twist the knife?
Just the opposite.
Do you know how
I made my fortune?
By taking over companies
on the verge of collapse.
And making millions
for everyone involved.
We should talk.
Captioned by Media
Access Group at WGBH