- Previously
on "New Amsterdam"...
- I have Obsessive Compulsive
Disorder.
I'm gonna move back in
with my parents.
In Idaho.
- Maybe you can
move in with me.
- What do you think
would happen
if you stopped helping people?
What would they see?
- They would see
what a complete loser I am--
corny, nerdy, fat.
- San Francisco's sounding
really good right about now.
Let's get out of here.
- The pattern of your behavior
can actually be indicative
of a more substantive
diagnosis per the DSM-5.
- Such as?
- Narcissistic Personality
Disorder?
- Effective immediately,
you are stripped of your title
as cochair of oncology,
as well as your duties
as deputy medical director.
- ♪ Computer, what's the point
in this? ♪
♪ You do all the thinking
♪ Where are we?
♪ Just building shelters
in the snow ♪
- At the center,
where they belong,
so I am introducing
a new initiative
to change that,
one that reconnects
all of our doctors to our...
- ♪ I know it's fallen down
♪ Got my headphones on
♪ And I won't hear a sound
- Ligon did what?
- I know.
Who could've guessed
that having sex with my doctor
and fellow drug addict
would turn out poorly?
- Are you okay?
- No, not really.
But is it crazy to think
that this all happened
at exactly the same time
I get a large chunk of money
from my family's trust?
- What, you think
the money's cursed?
- I think bad things happen
anytime my family does
anything,
but especially
when there's money involved.
- How much are we talking?
- Whatever amount
is in your head,
times it by ten,
and then taint it with
toxic family relationships.
- Well, just buy a house
in the Hamptons
so we can grow old
and "Grey Gardens" together.
- How are you holding up?
- Great.
It's good.
I've got so much time freed up.
- Helen.
- It's horrible.
Honestly, I thought
that it would be easier,
but I feel like I'm trespassing
in my own hospital.
But I'm not gonna dwell on it.
I'm just gonna keep
my head down
and just focus on my patients.
- Well, look,
at least they still let you
monitor my drug tests.
- Yes.
Still allowed
to watch you pee.
- Hey, missed you
at the department head meeting
this morning.
- Oh, I'm sure
it went swimmingly.
How's my little munchkin
doing today?
- I don't like you being
out of the loop.
I didn't get to tell you
my big idea.
- Is Luna going on rounds?
Everyone loves seeing
baby boss.
- Actually, it's time
for our six-month checkup,
so we're headed
to the Ped's wing
for some important vaccines.
- Gosh.
Have fun.
- Wait, I didn't get to
tell you my big idea.
- No need.
- But I want to tell you.
- I have patients.
- Sounds like you have
zero patience,
with a C.
See what I did there?
It's a pun.
- It's hilarious.
Gotta go, bye.
Terrible.
- Hi.
- Just one sec.
I can take that.
Welcome home.
- Thank you.
That was beautiful.
- Hot chai is ready.
- Oh, thank you, I just--
I have to rush off to work.
- Okay, then I'll quickly
show you my home.
- Okay.
- This is the kitchen.
- Yeah.
- And this is the living room.
- Kay.
- That's my mandir.
- Mm-hmm.
And this will be your room.
- I-It--it appears
occupied.
- Yes, this was Rohan's room.
- You don't say.
- When he first left home,
his mother insisted that
we leave the room as it is,
in case he needed to come back.
We will squeeze you in.
And this is his famous
posters wall.
- Right.
- You cannot touch these.
Come with me.
- Kay.
- I have to show you something.
And my wife's sewing room
is perfect for the baby.
- Where will the crib go?
- Oh...
No need to change much.
Oh.
What about here?
- Uh, great.
- I'll show you
the bathroom now.
- Kay.
- Elandra Siefert,
33-year-old woman.
Restrained driver in a MVA.
Multiple crush injuries.
- What do you got?
- Hemothorax.
I suspect a lacerated
pulmonary artery.
She's losing blood by the pint.
- When can we get her
to the OR?
- Tying off an arterial pumper
now, then she's all yours.
- Ma'am why don't you come with
me so the doctors can work?
- No, she's my sister.
- Floyd, this is gonna be
a long surgery.
You sure you're up for it?
- Wound's healed, I'll be fine.
What about you?
- Wound's healed.
I'll be fine.
- B/P 80/40 and dropping.
Tachy at 130 and rising.
- Yo, we gotta go.
- Okay, I'm almost there.
- Breathing pattern
ineffective.
- Okay, she's all yours.
- Is Elandra on
any medications,
or has she had
any health scares?
- No meds.
She was a Marine.
She's crazy healthy.
Please help her!
- Okay, all right, we're gonna
do everything we can.
Let's go!
- Incoming!
- Out of the way.
- Trey Masterson.
18, with an anaphylactic
reaction.
Epi Auto Injector times two
with no response.
- High-dose Epi.
- Original B/P 130 over 70,
down to 110 over 50.
- Heart rate 148.
O2 sats 84 and dropping.
- Okay, doubling dose.
- Heart rate at 160.
- Okay, but O2's up to 90.
- We got him.
- Trey?
Trey, has anything like this
ever happened to you before?
- No.
- Okay.
Any medical history
we should know about?
I had lymphoma.
Four years ago.
- Okay.
- Dr. Sharpe treated me.
- Okay, okay,
we're gonna run some tests
to figure out what caused
this allergic reaction,
and let's page Sharpe.
- Hey.
- Hi, Dr. Goodwin.
I'll let Dr. Elder know
you're here.
- Thanks.
- Oh.
- Is anyone--
- Oh, sorry.
- Thanks.
- Are you gonna walk for me?
Are we walking today?
- How old is yours?
- Six months.
- Walking's right around
the corner.
- Yeah, so I've heard.
I keep putting her
on the treadmill, but no luck.
- Well, this wobbly girl
is Bobbi.
- Oh.
Hey there.
This sweet girl is Luna.
- You know, it's nice
that the adults
don't have to put
the qualifiers
before our names too.
- Actually, I think we'd treat
each other better if we did.
Hi, I'm "anxious in hospitals"
Alice.
- I'm "hiding behind my smile"
Max.
- Hey.
Have you heard Max's big idea?
No screens?
- That is a big idea.
- No screens in patient rooms,
no tablets, no computers.
He's not serious, is he?
- He's definitely serious.
- But we don't actually
have to do it, do we?
- You most certainly do,
and not only that,
but as chair, it's your job
to share this new rule
with your entire department.
One down.
Good luck with the rest.
- Dr. Sharpe.
- Dr. Baker.
- Don't say my name nicely when
it's clear how furious I am.
This is unacceptable.
- I'm not sure
what you're referring to.
- No screens?
- I had nothing to do
with that.
- Then veto it!
We need screens.
This isn't the Stone Age.
- As I'm certain you've heard,
I'm no longer management.
I am just a doctor
like yourself,
keeping my head down
and focusing on my patients.
- Dr. Sharpe.
No screens during any
patient encounters
is, frankly, outlandish.
- Dr. Eliraz, long time.
I'm doing well.
Thank you for asking.
- Dr. Sharpe.
- Without looking
at a computer screen,
I can't keep my patients' names
straight.
- I suspect that's why
Dr. Goodwin instated
the policy.
More face-to-face
emotional engagement.
- Since I was an intern,
I've always had a screen
in my exam room.
- We can't do our jobs
without our screens.
- You have to make this
go away.
- Enough!
I am not the deputy
medical director,
I am not a department chair,
I am not anyone who is
in charge of anything,
so my advice to all of you
is to suck it up,
swallow your pride,
keep your head down,
and do the one damn thing
that Max has asked of you,
which is what I am
trying to do!
And just for the record,
you should bloody well know
your patients' names.
- Hi, Luna.
Can you say hi?
Say hola.
Shalom?
- Bobbi, you wanna say hi
to Luna?
She's totally thinking "hello."
- Yeah, totally got that.
What are you in for?
- Bobbi keeps getting
these ear infections.
- Ouch.
- Yeah.
They're scared they could
delay her speech,
so an ENT's putting these tubes
in her ears.
- Tympanostomy.
- That's the word
I keep meaning to write down.
Maybe you could toss them
on in,
seeing as you're already
in scrubs.
- Yeah, I'm not really
an ear guy,
but if she had Ebola--
- In that case, we'll stick
with the ear infections.
- That's fair.
- Dr. Goodwin.
- Yep.
- You can come on back now.
- Oh, great.
Hope the doctor
gets to you soon.
- Thanks.
Nice to meet you.
- You too.
- And Luna.
- Yeah, she's totally
thinking "bye!"
- Say "bye!"
- Bye!
- Bye, Bobbi.
- Bye, Luna.
- And on a scale of one to ten,
how bad is the pain?
- Maybe a four,
but it's nothing
compared to my knee.
- So it's your knee as well.
And what number would you give
your knee?
- Well, if my foot is a nine,
then I'd say my knee
is an eight.
Shouldn't you be typing this
into a computer?
- I've got it all right here,
okay?
So, it is your shoulder,
your knee, and your foot.
And that is everything.
- And my skin is very dry.
- Huh, so that's not
everything.
- I wasn't sure if you did
skin stuff.
- Okay, Mr. Pembroke,
why don't you just tell me
all of your concerns?
- Well, the only other thing
I can think of
is muscle aches...
- Mm-hmm.
- Blurred vision, exhaustion,
headaches, constipation,
oh, and I'm always freezing.
- Okay, I'm gonna go
and get this logged
into your chart
before I forget, and then
I'm gonna be right back, okay?
Okay, so you've got
shoulder pain,
connected to the knee pain,
connected to the foot pain,
dry skin, blurry vision,
muscle aches, exhaustion,
constipation, and...
Oh, no.
- Making the incision between
the sixth and seventh rib.
Get me a pair of.
- Gonna need a saline flush.
- Isolating pulmonary artery.
- Polypropalyne sutures.
Need a new carton
of lap pads.
- Suture.
500 milliliters.
- That should do it.
- Her heart rate's
still rising.
- Should be slowing down.
- And her blood pressure's
dropping.
- I got all the bleeders.
- There must be something else.
- Hypotensive, tachycardic--
- And a lacy red rash.
- That's a transfusion
reaction.
Her body's rejecting the blood.
Disconnect it!
And call hematology!
- Assess for DIC.
- She's oozing blood
everywhere.
- BP is still dropping.
- Gauze.
Come on, come on.
Dr. Reynolds,
tell me what's happening.
- Where's Sharpe?
- If there's an issue
with the blood product,
the chair of hematology
gets paged,
and right now, that's me.
- Sorry, just habit.
- You suspect a transfusion
reaction?
- Yeah, a big one.
- Okay, I'm on it.
- down.
- Get a new one.
- Dr. Sharpe.
Long time no see.
- Hello, Trey.
How are you feeling?
- Like someone who was almost
murdered by crab cakes.
They figure out
why it happened?
What is it?
- Trey, I have some bad news.
The newfound allergies
that you have
are from your lymphoma,
which means that it's returned.
- So, it's back to chemo?
- The cancer has spread
too aggressively
for chemotherapy.
It's beyond anything
that we can treat.
- But we beat it.
You and me.
You said we beat it.
- It's not fair,
and it doesn't make any sense,
and I am so sorry.
- How long?
- Four months.
Maybe six.
Are your parents here?
I'm gonna call them.
- No, don't.
- Trey--
- I don't want them to know.
- Have you got a minute?
- Oh, hi.
Yeah, actually,
I'm glad you're here.
Would you say that I have
Narcissistic Personality
Disorder?
Because the DSM says that
people who are narcissistic
are typically quite haughty.
Is that how you would
characterize me?
Haughty?
Just give it to me straight.
Am I haughty?
- You know, I heard
a really good hypothetical
to tell if you're a narcissist.
- Good, what is it?
- If a colleague shows up
at your office
during the work day,
do you assume they're there
for a reason,
or just to hear you talk
nonsense?
- Lay it on me.
- His name's Trey.
He's 18, and he wants
to die alone.
- The mutiny is upon us.
- Why does no one ever stop me
with good news?
Honestly, I'm gonna start using
the air ducts.
- The neurology
and neurosurgery departments
are in open revolt.
- So naturally, you come
to an oncologist.
- Max's ban on screens
is completely impractical.
Screens are vital
even for the most basic
neurological patient encounter.
- Do you know what's most
interesting about neurology?
- What?
- I couldn't tell you.
It's not my department.
- My clinic is in chaos.
You must help.
- I can't.
I don't have a position
of authority, Vijay.
There's no reason for roving
gangs of rebel neurologists
to listen to me.
- Max listens to you.
It's not about your title.
You have Max's ear.
Please.
For the patients.
- Yeah.
- Just so you know,
your big idea
is going down
like a lead balloon.
- Look there's something--
there's something wrong
with Luna.
- Max, what--do they know
what it is, or--
- Not yet.
What do you need?
- Nothing.
I'll handle it.
- A small bump, Dr. Goodwin.
Likely a lipoma.
- Do you wanna biopsy it?
- I don't want you to panic.
- Well, I have--
had cancer.
- Cancer is so unlikely.
- Yeah, I know, I know,
but it could be,
or it could be a hemangioma
or a Budd-Chiari malformation--
- I highly doubt that.
- I don't want to doubt, kay?
I'd like to know.
I need to know.
- I could biopsy it, but--
- Okay.
- We could be opening up
ourselves to a false positive--
- Do it.
Kay?
Hey.
- It has come to my attention
that you have been brazenly
disregarding Max's directive.
- Because it's crazy.
- And yet, I'm fairly certain
it wasn't optional.
- We need our screens
for consults.
- And Max believes
having your faces buried
in your tablet
only alienates you
from your patients.
Now, I've spoken with Max
directly
and he would like you
to get this done,
so tell me, how can I help?
- Do you know
how much information
we're expected to enter
for each patient?
- 36 pages.
- 2/3rds of which is insurance
coding and billing questions.
- And we have no choice
but to do it
during the consults.
- Since it takes
about 15 minutes of scrolling
to fill it all out.
If we can't do it
during the patient visit,
we'll have to do it after.
- Which means each patient
will take twice as long,
and we'll end up seeing
half as many patients.
- And some of us
are not the fastest typists.
- Okay.
So, what if we were to hire,
say, medical scribes
who could input the data
while you were consulting.
Would that help?
- That would be incredible.
- You can do that?
- No, but Max can,
and if Max wants this done,
then consider it done.
Six new medical scribes
coming your way.
That's--thank you.
Thank you!
- See, I knew Max
would listen to you.
- How about an indoor
rock climbing wall?
- Okay, what part of
"this money is cursed"
didn't you understand?
- Sauna and hot tub?
- No.
- Jet skis.
- Sure.
- Really?
- No.
Eli, Eli, Eli.
Okay.
Now you, you nearly had me
stumped,
what with your litany
of issues.
I mean, the headaches,
the knee,
the inability to regulate
your body temperature.
I mean, I really had
to dig deep,
and I searched far and wide.
I mean, I even consulted
a dusty old medical text.
But I have figured it out.
I know what you have.
It is called a low thyroid,
and it explains
all of your symptoms.
- Even the cut on my leg
that won't heal?
- What cut on your leg
- Did I forget to mention
that one?
- Yeah, must've slipped
your mind.
- So, do I still have
a low thyroid, Dr. Bloom?
- No.
Okay, so,
cut on your leg
that won't heal...
Constipation...
headaches...
- Dr. Sharpe.
- Sandra Fall from billing.
- Why did you requisition
six medical scribes?
- I didn't.
That was Max.
- Except the entire neurology
department said it was you.
- Doesn't that sound
like something Max would do?
- Unfortunately, yes.
So, why didn't he sign
the paperwork?
- You know, that also
sounds like something
Max would forget to do.
- I can't approve
the requisition of new staff
without the medical director's
signature.
- Okay, wait.
Turn around.
- Why?
- Plausible deniability.
Okay, you can turn around now.
That looks like Max signed it
to me.
- That does seem like something
Max would do.
- Have you ever heard
of magical thinking?
No?
It's the belief that
our thoughts
can shape reality.
The idea that
our deepest wishes
can somehow shape
the physical world.
Or sometimes, we hope
that if we don't talk
about something,
it won't happen.
- You think I'm in
some weirdo headspace
where if I don't tell
my parents,
I think I won't die?
- I think it's possible.
- Okay, no.
That's not me at all.
I'm fully clear
on my situation.
- Okay.
- In six months, I'm toast.
- Yeah.
So, why not tell your parents?
- Look, I'm 18,
and three years of that was
spent sidelined with cancer,
so experience-wise,
it's like I'm 15.
I've got less than a year left,
and I want to go live.
- That's great.
Why don't you tell them that?
- If I did,
every time I leave the house,
I'll have to deal
with their sad faces.
That I'm choosing
to spend my last days
with people that aren't them.
- Okay, I get that, Trey,
but you know there are physical
signs of cancer, right?
Bottles of painkillers,
your body will be in decline.
- So?
- So your parents are bound
to notice that,
don't you think?
Terminal cancer's not really
something you can hide.
- That's why I'm leaving.
- Leaving?
- I've been thinking about it
all morning.
My buddy Jem is doing
a semester in Barcelona.
I'm gonna take the semester off
and go crash with him,
then after that,
I'll go wherever.
Peru, climb the Andes,
hopefully lose my virginity.
It's okay to laugh.
- I'm not laughing.
- There's just so much
I haven't done.
- So, your parents
are gonna hear about you dying
on a mountain
thousands of miles away,
all alone?
- And it'll be awful for them.
- Yeah.
- But it's gonna be awful
for them no matter what.
At least this way,
it won't be awful for me.
- Yeah.
Okay.
I'm gonna go get
your discharge paperwork.
I know.
I know, I know, I know.
- Everything okay?
- They need to run some tests,
but--
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
Sorry.
Can't seem to--
- Don't worry about it.
- Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey.
My wife would have been
better at this.
- Have you tried the Ss?
Give it a try?
- Oh, yeah, yeah, sure.
Hey, hey.
Oh, hi.
Hi.
Raising a child by yourself
is hard.
- Yeah.
Hoping it gets easier.
- It won't.
But you get better
at getting through it.
Yeah.
- Ms. Healy?
The doctor will see you now.
- There we go.
- Thanks.
Hi.
Hi!
Yeah, was that better?
Good luck.
- Thanks.
You too.
- Hang another liter
of normal saline.
- She has a positive ANA
and double-stranded
DNA antibodies.
- She has Lupus?
- And it's making antibodies
that are reacting to the
transfused red blood cells.
- That's why she rejected it.
- Any blood we give her needs
to be meticulously matched
to dozens of proteins on the
surface of her red blood cells,
or she'll react again.
- Okay, so get it up here.
- We don't have any.
But I'm gonna search
every hospital and blood bank
until we find it.
- Well, you better hurry,
or she's gonna bleed out
on the table.
- Where's Bobbi?
- Still back there.
- Oh.
- They let me watch
as she went under, but then
said I had to wait here
till after the procedure.
- Yeah, that's typical.
- Since my husband passed, I...
I hate having her
out of my sight.
I know she's okay, but--
- I know, um...
Come with me.
- Are you sure we can be
back here?
- I know a few people.
You can leave that there
if you want.
Chuck Turnbill's one of
the best ENTs in Manhattan.
Now you get to see why.
- Thank you.
- Sure.
- Dr. Goodwin,
we have Luna's results.
- Excuse me.
- We want medical
scribes too.
- Oh, do you now?
- We heard what you got
the neurosurgeons,
and we want
the exact same thing.
- Mm, but I distinctly recall
you telling me
how much you love your screens,
so hiring medical scribes
isn't gonna solve your problem.
- So what are you gonna
give us?
- Home visits.
- Home visits?
- To forge authentic
connections
with the people that you treat,
you need to do far more than
just set your screens aside.
You need total immersion
in the lives of your patients.
- Even if we wanted to do that,
which we don't,
our schedules would never allow
for that.
- I'm cancelling all
pulmonology clinic appointments
for the next month.
That should free up some time.
- Wait, you can't do that.
- I'm not doing it, Max is.
- You talked to him about us?
- Yes, and he agreed
this is exactly what you need.
You and your colleagues
are gonna start
visiting your patients
in their home,
and you are really gonna
get to know them.
Max suggested
that you could start
by learning their first names.
- Eli.
Okay.
Now, I think I figured out
what is wrong with you,
and this is the treatment.
- It looks big.
- Yeah.
Yeah, it is.
So look, I went over
your landfill of symptoms
a million times, and...
the only diagnosis
I could come to
was malnutrition.
Now, Eli, are you
having trouble buying food?
- My Social Security check
pays most of my rent,
but to cover the rest of it,
I sell my food stamps,
and eat fast food
'cause it's cheap.
- Okay.
Well, look, you can't do that
anymore.
- I knew I was cutting corners,
I didn't know I was hurting
myself.
- What about the shelter?
I mean, they offer
three healthy meals a day.
- I won't take food away
from people who really need it!
- You really need it.
I mean, your body
is basically starving.
Have you heard of something
called Meals for Seniors?
I mean, it is a great program
that is designed to help
with the nutritional needs
of the elderly.
- I've been on a waitlist
since June.
Of 2016.
- I don't understand.
Why can't you find a match?
- Your sister needs
an extremely particular
blood product,
and so far, no hospital
within 6 hours
has it on hand.
I'm so sorry, Justine.
If there's any other
family members
you wish to call,
now would be the time.
- Elandra's a Marine.
She did three tours
in Afghanistan,
and now a commute to work
is going to kill her
because you don't have blood?
- You paged me?
- Look, I know I'm stepping
over Castro,
but my patient needs
all the help that she can get,
and I'm not gonna let
chain of command
get in the way
of saving her life.
Will you help?
- Ella.
I have something for you.
I realized mine
were a little old,
so I thought maybe
these new ones
will make you feel
more at home.
- Vijay, I really appreciate
what you're doing.
I just--
your home?
- You mean our home.
- Yeah.
There's so much
of your old life there,
so much of everything,
really, and...
I just--
there's no space
for anyone else.
There's no space for me.
- Oh, we will move
Rohan's books.
- It's not about the books.
I just--
feel like I picture myself
there,
and I just--with my OCD,
and--
I know that you are just
trying to be helpful,
and that really means so much.
I just--it's just not
gonna work for me.
- I...
I'm sorry I did not think of--
- No, I'm sorry.
I--
you're being so great, and I--
- You need to do what is best
for the baby, and--
and for you.
- I'll come by after my shift,
and I'll pick up my things.
- Where will you go?
- I'll go stay with a friend
till I figure it out.
- Okay.
- It's not cancer.
It's not some obscure
infection.
Luna has an epidermoid cyst,
a simple fold of tissue.
A small injection of steroids
and she'll be fine.
- That's great news.
Thank you.
- But if I may, Dr. Goodwin,
today you let
your parental fears
override your medical judgment
and mine.
- What do you mean?
- From now on,
when Luna visits this office,
I don't want her coming
with Dr. Goodwin.
I want Luna coming
with her father.
- Got it.
- Okay.
For your discharge,
my mountain-climbing friend.
Here you go.
- Sweet, thank you.
- So, listen, before you leave,
if you don't mind,
I have one more shrink thought
for you.
What do you say about making
a video for your parents?
- What kind of video?
- Well, when you leave,
and you say good-bye,
your parents aren't going
to know
that that's really good-bye,
so why don't you give them
that gift?
The real good-bye?
And then when I receive word
that you've passed,
I will make sure
that they get it.
- Yeah.
Seems like a good idea.
- Great, okay.
I'm gonna set this up.
We'll get you off to Aconcagua
in no time, my friend.
- What should I say?
- I mean, that's up to you,
really,
but try to remember that
when your parents see this,
they're gonna be dealing
with the fact that you're gone.
All right?
So--
I don't know, maybe tell them
how you want to be remembered.
Five most important memories.
- Hi, Mom and Dad.
Hi.
When you see this,
I'll be gone,
and I thought you'd like
to hear this message from me.
Anyway,
here are my five most important
memories.
Okay.
Here's one.
The day I got diagnosed
with cancer.
We were driving home
from the hospital,
and you offered to get me
ice cream.
And I was 15, and trying to be
a tough guy or whatever,
so I said no.
But later that night,
you brought me some anyway.
Rocky Road.
And it had been years since I'd
asked you to get me ice cream,
but you remembered
my favorite flavor,
and that made me feel so good.
Number two.
Playing Toss the Trey
when I was little.
Might be my first memory,
actually.
Getting tossed up in the air,
and not worrying
if you were gonna catch me.
And...
and Thanksgiving.
When I tried to eat
Dad's stuffing after chemo,
but I got sick, and I...
And you had to help
clean me up.
And I hated it, but I remember
having this thought of,
"Jesus,
what would I do if I didn't..."
"If I didn't have you?"
Could you--could you
press stop, please?
- You hired unbudgeted
medical scribes?
You cancelled clinics?
You forged Max's signature?
Usually, I save my indignation
for Max,
but this time,
you outdid even him.
- Mm, it has been a busy day.
- This isn't a game, Helen.
You're on a branch
all by yourself,
and if you don't want me
to run you
out of this hospital for good,
you better start talking.
- Do you mind walking
a bit faster?
- I do mind.
Did you learn nothing
from your recent demotion?
- What I learned
is that sometimes
we have to bend the rules
in order to help our patients,
and it certainly helps that
I have no titles to stop me.
- God, you sound just like him.
- Good, because everything
I did today,
Max would have done too.
Patients are the most important
part of this hospital,
the center of everything
that we do.
- Believe it or not,
emulating Max's reckless
and irresponsible behavior
is not gonna win you
any points.
And where the hell
are we even going?
- Ma'am, inside this cooler,
you'll find the synthetic blood
that you requested.
- What's going on?
Who are you?
- When the Marines found out
one of our own was down,
we were determined to help.
- Thank you, Colonel.
You were saying?
- That blood will help
Reynolds' patient?
- It will.
- Then go!
- Your call is very important.
Please continue to hold,
and the next available Meals
for Seniors representative
will assist you.
- Meals for Seniors.
This is Linda.
- Hi, Linda,
this is Dr. Lauren Bloom
over at New Amsterdam.
I've got a patient
who is on your waitlist.
- I'm sorry,
I know it's frustrating,
but it can take years
for a client
to work their way to the top.
There's just too many
hungry elders.
- Right.
Well, look,
how much would it cost
to wipe out the waitlist?
- Are you trying to bribe me?
- No.
No.
I just wondered how much
it would cost
to service everyone
who's been waiting?
- That's a big number.
- Try me.
Oh, Eli.
I called Meals for Seniors.
Turns out they had an opening
after all.
- Hey.
- Hey!
Bobbi just wanted to make sure
Luna was okay.
- She is.
And Bobbi?
- Good.
- That's my number.
- Oh, I'm not really--
- The number's for Luna.
For a playdate.
- Playdate?
- Yeah, you know,
babies on blankets,
spilled Cheerios, toy battles.
- Right.
Playdate, yep.
Heard of those.
- Yeah, welcome to the next
level of parenthood, Max.
- You gave my sister
experimental blood.
- Synthetic blood.
It's used mainly
for battlefield injuries.
- Which isn't actually blood
at all.
Scientists take hemoglobin,
the molecule
that carries oxygen,
and they wrap it
in a polymer coating.
Which means that
your sister's body
gets the oxygen that it needs,
but won't reject the blood
carrying it.
- Elandra's responding well
to the treatment.
She's gonna pull through.
- I didn't know any of this
was an option.
- It wasn't.
But Dr. Sharpe
made it happen anyway.
- Oh.
- Thank you.
- Floyd, you paged?
- I don't know
how I'm gonna say this,
so I'm gonna just say it.
- Okay.
- So Evie took this new job
in San Francisco,
and it's everything
she's ever wanted,
but it means it's gonna be
a lot of changes
happening for us,
and I just wanted to be
straight up with you
about my future here.
- Well, I think that's amazing.
Yeah, I totally get it.
And look, we'll make
whatever happens next
as painless as possible.
- I appreciate that.
- Mm-hmm.
- Thank you.
- Sure.
It's crazy.
You and I have been linked
since my very first day here.
You were my first hire.
- Mm-hmm.
- You know that?
- Best decision I ever made.
- Oh, thanks.
- Look, just know that
whatever you need from me,
I got you.
- I'm flattered, I really am,
and I'm definitely gonna
take you up on that.
- Good.
I know how brutal
long distance
relationships can be.
- Oh, no, no, I'm--
- Just take a few weeks
and help Evie move
and get settled and--
- Max, that's very generous,
but that--
- Yeah, well, good.
You deserve it.
We'll make it work,
for both of you.
Right? We got this.
All right?
'Cause teamwork
makes the dream work!
Right, buddy?
- How did you get him
to change his mind?
- I didn't.
I think Trey just realized that
he can't finish his story
without them.
- ♪ A year from now
♪ We'll all be gone
♪ All our friends
♪ Will move away
♪ And they're going
to better places ♪
- Hey.
- I want to show you something.
- ♪ Nothing is
♪ As it has been
♪ And I miss your face
like hell ♪
- ♪ And I guess
♪ It's just as well
♪ That I miss your face
like hell ♪
- What about what your wife
wanted?
- This is what
she would have wanted.
Rohan never came back home,
but his child has.
♪ Oh
- ♪ If you don't know what
♪ To make of this
♪ Then we will not relate
♪ So if you don't
know what ♪
♪ To make of this
♪ Then we will not relate
♪ Ah
♪ Oh
- ♪ Rivers and roads
♪ Rivers till I reach you
- Hey.
- Luna's fine.
She's totally healthy.
Turns out I was the one
who needed a little help.
- Did you get it?
- Yeah.
Think so.
Oh, and I heard my "no screens"
idea went down without a hitch.
- Indeed.
Smooth as silk.
- Good.
Best ideas usually are.
Good night.
- I'm kidding!
It was a joke.
It was a disaster.
I heard it was horrible.
I know.
I know everything that you did.
I know that my ideas only work
because of you,
and so, I just wanted to say--
- No.
- No?
You were gonna thank me,
right?
- I was.
- Good, no.
Because I'm gonna thank you.
- Why?
- I finally felt
what you must feel
every time you turn
this hospital on its head,
and it is quite the rush.
It is thrilling!
And I want more of it.
I want it every day.
But Max, I have been
your safety net for so long
that if I go down this road,
I am gonna need you
to start being mine.
- How can I help?