Good afternoon, Cedarville!
It is my distinct
honor to present
our annual community
service award
to one of our most
outstanding citizens.
Now, many of you may
recognize him as Coach Bob
of our champion
Little League team.
And some of you may know him
as the treasurer of our
Harvest Scholarship Fund.
But I know that all of
you know him as the guy
that owns the only
gas station in town.
Bob Harris, get on up here
with that beautiful family of yours.
Bob Harris, folks!
Bob, your community
activism, charity work
and character represent the
finest Cedarville has to offer.
Please accept this
on behalf of all of us
and know that we love you.
Are you all right?
Bob?
You're crushing me.
Wake up!
I think you're having a heart
attack. I'm gonna call the ambulance.
No. Just drive
me to the hospital.
As the new Dean of Medicine,
I'd like to personally welcome
all of our new employees and ask
why the hell do you
want to come back?
Tired of surfing.
He hasn't changed.
And neither has the job, right?
We still get to do crazy crap?
Save people's lives
instead of just their noses?
About that, about
the crazy stuff...
Here we go. He's
gone from ally to enemy.
He has no choice.
He's the boss now.
He has to be professional.
Has to base his decisions on
what's best for the entire hospital.
We can't take it personally.
Couldn't have
said it better myself.
You did.
I'm just reading the
notes on your desk.
He also wants us to spy for him.
Not spy. I'm trying to
keep House out of prison.
To do that, I need to know
what he's doing and planning.
Spy. Spy.
Come on, guys.
Look, I am your boss, you do
have to treat me appropriately,
but it doesn't have to
be awkward and weird.
Outside of work, I still
consider us all friends.
I'm glad you feel that way,
because I do have a favor to ask.
I told House I couldn't
come back until next week.
He said he understood
completely and that I was fired, so...
Since I have my kids for the
next two days, I need a babysitter.
No.
Male patient went into V-fib, but
shows no signs of heart disease
or any other symptoms
for that matter.
What was he doing when his
heart decided to do the mambo?
He said he was at work.
You're late.
According to my
calendar, I'm a week early.
Beard's a nice touch.
Lets everyone know that
you're not a teenage girl.
Now, you two make a cute couple.
And you two...
It's not important.
Dr. Park.
You're a lot taller
than I thought you'd be.
And I look forward to
working with you, as well.
He's lying. Not just
Taub, the patient.
These abrasions on his
knees, they're minty fresh.
They're about 10 hours old.
He got them
playing flag football.
He said he got them
I'm sure that's true, if flag
is a euphemism for "penis"
and football is a euphemism
for "entering a vagina".
Why lie about it?
Everybody lies.
Speaking of which, how
are your two baby girls?
Wow, twins. Congratulations.
Awkward.
He knocked up two different
women at the same time.
At least he thinks he did. Did
you have the DNA tested yet?
Why would I? They
look just like me.
But they will grow.
Find out what else
he's lying about.
Do an exercise
test, see if you can
get him to go back
into V-fib again.
But we could end up
causing another cardiac arrest.
Hopefully, then we'll
know what set it off.
He means, it's better to do it
here where we can revive him
than have it happen
somewhere else.
The prodigal son has returned.
Now if you'll excuse
me, I have to go
slaughter a fatted
calf for lunch.
I told you, I was sitting at my
desk when the attack happened.
These rug burns
are from last night.
We think you were having sex, but
memory loss could also be a symptom.
Maybe we should ask your wife?
Don't.
I did something stupid last
night, but it was a one-time thing.
You have no idea
how bad I feel about it.
Your guilt is between
you and your wife,
we just need to
know what happened.
I was having sex at a motel
when I started to
feel light-headed.
Next thing I knew, I
was lying on my back,
I could barely breathe.
Is everything all right?
We'd like to perform
an exercise test.
Recreate the stress that may
have caused his symptoms.
He was sitting at his desk.
It's his heart we're
worried about.
The test will monitor its rhythm
so we can check
for any abnormalities.
I spent a month in solitary. You
don't think I can keep this up all day?
I have a headache. Could
you just lower your voice?
Chase and Taub are back!
You want me to pick
up an ice cream cake?
I also think that Taub
has brought his little Taubettes
into work with him today.
And why would he do that?
Because I didn't give him
time to do anything else.
So then I started wondering,
"Who'd be sappy enough
to watch them for him?"
They're not here.
What?
I just came for a
chat with a friend.
What's that I smell, friend?
I understand your confusion.
I was eating a
baby for lunch and...
I have a massive migraine.
Will you, please, just go away?
You should probably
lie down to rest.
Yeah, I was trying to.
Oh...
There is one more thing.
He's in too good of shape.
We need to get him to the
point he was at last night.
Don't look at me,
but if you want to.
Cute,
but I didn't mean
physical stress.
Don't you guys think
this is irresponsible?
It's like you getting two women
pregnant at the same time.
I just mean the part about
the odds of it happening.
They had to be incredibly high.
And if we induce V-fib,
odds say that we'll
be able to revive him,
but there's always
a chance we can't.
It's extreme and reckless.
That's House. You get used to it.
Or I fire you.
Look what I found.
Kiddie-winkies. I wonder
who they belong to.
Give me my kids.
No, I genuinely wonder
who they belong to.
I need a DNA sample.
I'm not letting you
DNA test my kids.
I already did. This
swab's for you.
Fine, if you don't
mind paying a fortune
in child support for
some other guy's kids?
No skin cells off my cheek.
His heart rate's
finally elevating.
Dr. Chase said you had
something to tell me?
We were talking about how you
got the abrasions on your knees.
The flag football game?
Oh, um...
Yeah, honey, I'm gonna
need you to let the guys know
I'm not gonna be able
to play on Saturday.
The whole town knows
that you're in the hospital.
I wouldn't worry about it.
That's not what you
wanted to tell her.
You said the
game wasn't typical.
Something happened
that you were upset about.
I don't understand.
What are you...
I don't... I don't feel very...
What's happening?
It's not his heart. I know.
He's having a seizure.
There wasn't any
abnormal electrical activity
in his EKG when
the seizure occurred.
It wasn't caused by V-fib.
We still can't rule it out.
His EKG from the
E.R. documented it.
Myocarditis?
Viral infection weakening
the wall muscles.
We'd need to biopsy
his heart to confirm.
Myocarditis wouldn't
cause a seizure.
Could be genetic.
Brugada syndrome?
Oh, my God.
Two prodigal sons.
Come on, let's hug it out.
You really like
the idea or you just
wanna grab some
hair for a DNA test?
It's a stupid idea.
We would have seen
evidence of Brugada in the EKG.
You know, this is...
It's just messing with my feng
shui here. What about over there?
A pheochromocytoma?
Excess adrenaline can cause
heart problems and seizures.
Boring. I'm sorry.
I thought I was here to treat
the patients, not entertain you.
Would it hurt to do both?
This is much better.
I said it was boring, I
didn't say it was wrong.
So I'm right?
Nope, you're wrong.
Photic epilepsy.
It's equally boring, but it has the
advantage of possibly being right.
Give him an EEG to confirm.
If you ever hear me mention
anything about wanting kids,
please feel free to
punch me in the liver.
Why?
Like Satan's alarm clock.
What's House up to?
He hasn't asked me for anything,
he's been incredibly
well behaved,
he's doing his clinic hours.
That is a sign of concern.
You know him as well as I do.
He needs to constantly
establish he's the alpha dog.
He's got his team back,
he's got his office back,
he's got everything he needs.
You really believe
that? He's content?
I don't want to let House
sabotage himself by sabotaging me.
And I need your guidance
and your trust to do that.
No, no, no.
Cuddy had a problem with
House, she came to me.
Wanted to vent, me.
How did that turn out?
You have a problem with House, deal
with it, or find someone else who can.
We're sorry about earlier, but
we needed to provoke a reaction.
It worked.
I can barely look her
in the eyes anymore.
I'd want my husband
to tell me the truth.
Sure.
You'll feel better,
and she'll feel what?
Devastated,
betrayed, heartbroken.
You really want
to do that to her?
No.
But I can't live like this.
But she can.
All set.
All right, we need you to
sit back and try to relax.
Just look at the light.
What exactly are they
building back there?
A dream. The EEG didn't show
any abnormal brain activity.
He doesn't have photic epilepsy.
I know, because he has
a pheochromocytoma.
You said I was wrong.
You were wrong not
to rule out epilepsy first.
That only takes
a couple of hours.
Finding a tumor that's flushing
adrenaline through his system
is gonna take all night.
Monitor his brain activity,
start a continuous urine test
and blood draws every two hours.
I can't, I have my kids. Wilson's
leaving in, like, 15 minutes.
Chase and Adams
can do the tests.
Thank you.
For the massage bed.
You and Park are checking the
motel he was bumping uglies at
for environmental factors.
He couldn't find a
babysitter. Get over it.
You're gonna get us killed.
She thinks I'm a
prostitute on her turf.
Showing weakness
is what gets you killed.
Why would she think
you're a prostitute?
I'm in a dump with a
guy almost twice my age.
What else is she gonna think?
How old do you think I am?
So who cheated on you?
We just met.
Don't you think it's a little early
to be dragging up our baggage
in front of each other?
Who says I have baggage?
I know when House went
to prison, you quit medicine.
You don't do that, unless...
I didn't quit, I
took a vacation.
I knew when he got
out, I'd get my job back.
House didn't even know
he was coming back.
I had faith.
Now that has baggage
stamped all over it.
Seizure activity?
No, one of the
sensors came loose.
I'll fix it.
What is it?
Not a pheochromocytoma.
Our patient now has
a mass in his neck
and his body temp's been
rising over the last three hours.
Where's the construction crew?
Well, I'm not gonna make
them work day and night.
So I chose night.
And his urine and blood
tests didn't show any evidence
of an adrenaline
secreting tumor.
Meningitis? We can do a
lumbar puncture to confirm.
Sorry, I had to drop my kids
off at day care across town.
What'd I miss?
It's not meningitis.
His neck isn't stiff and
his mental status is normal.
He's only guessing.
I'm talking to Taub.
He can't say "my kids"
until he lets me test him.
So tell me about the love shack
where he cheated on his bride.
The quarters came in handy.
My kids loved the massage bed.
Lab tests show the bed
tested positive for, uh, semen,
vaginal secretions,
saliva and fecal matter,
both human and animal.
You probably
want to boil the kids
for a couple of hours
when you get home.
The bathroom also
tested positive for
five different types
of pathogenic bacteria.
Fusobacterium
necrophorum was one of them.
Yeah. How did you know?
The bulge in his neck.
The bacteria colonized
his parapharyngeal space,
moved into his jugular
vein causing a thrombus.
Lemierre's Syndrome. Treat
with amoxicillin and clavulanic acid.
Dig out the clot before it
moves to his lungs and kills him.
You got at least
a trillion cells.
You're gonna misplace
one of them eventually.
I have to tell
my wife the truth.
There's plenty of time
for that after the operation.
What if I die? And one day
she finds out I cheated on her.
I'll never be able to explain.
Never tell her how sorry I am.
You're increasing the odds of
that every second we waste here.
No, I'm not agreeing to
anything until I talk to her.
Daddy!
Hey!
Hey, guys.
Ew! Your neck
looks really gross.
I missed you both so much,
but I need to ask you a favor.
I need to talk to Mommy
alone for a second.
Would you mind
watching them for us?
Um...
This guy's an idiot.
I think he actually
has a good point.
What would you think if
you found out, years later,
your beloved dead
wife cheated on you?
I wouldn't believe it.
As long as I don't
hear it directly from her,
then I can hang on to
hope that it's not true.
But this way,
she has to either
dump him or forgive him.
Guys, get your
stuff. We're leaving.
I'm so sorry.
I'll be back.
I'm gonna drop our
kids off at my mother's.
Look, he made a mistake.
A stupid, horrible mistake.
But we'll get through this.
All I care about right now is
that my husband gets better.
Sorry about yesterday.
House was like Child Catcher
from Chitty Chitty Bang Bang.
Why is he so obsessed
with my kids being my kids?
Because he sees insecurity,
and when House senses
weakness, he pounces.
And because his
insecurity is the fact
that other people can have faith
and don't have the obsessive
need for physical proof.
Also, he started a betting pool
on which kid is
yours and which isn't.
An entire hospital betting
on the legitimacy of my kids.
It's great to be
back among friends.
I'm not the bad guy here.
I'm betting on them
both being yours.
I would have donated
the money to charity.
Approaching the
clot, stand by for...
That's not a clot.
It's his lymph nodes.
The bulge wasn't caused by pus
or blood. It's tissue inflammation.
How could there be
that much... Lymphoma.
We need to take a biopsy.
- Did I nick something?
- I don't know.
I don't see any
bleeding in here.
His sclera is jaundiced.
I think it's his liver.
It's failing.
We did a major operation for no
reason. It's not Lemierre's Syndrome.
We would have had to biopsy his
lymph nodes anyway to check for cancer.
Which it's not,
biopsy was clean.
We could be dealing with an
alcoholic going through withdrawal.
Explains his heart,
seizures and liver failing.
But not his swollen lymph nodes.
Why are we stealing
cable from here?
We don't even have
a TV in our office.
I'm an ex-con trying to adjust
to a world that's passed me by.
Stealing's all I know.
And the fact that I was right
about what's wrong with our patient,
just wrong about what.
He means it's not Lemierre's,
but it's still an infection,
which is why it's
spreading so rapidly.
Cultures take time and his
liver doesn't have much left.
That's why we're gonna blast him
with broad-spectrum antibiotics.
The blast will fry what's left of
his liver. The cure will kill him.
Not if we get him a
liver transplant first
and then treat him
with the broad-spectrum.
And old team for the win.
Not that I'm keeping score.
It's more of a grid where I assign
numerical values that determine
who gets raises, vacation
time and my respect.
We have him on the donor list for
a liver, but these things take time.
So he could die
before he gets one?
It's a possibility, but
we have another option.
We can do a partial liver
transplant from a living donor.
I'll do it. CHASE:
If you're a match,
but to increase our
odds, we'd like to
get your friends and
family tested, as well.
Is it safe?
It's a major surgery.
Donor spends a
week in the hospital
and up to three months
convalescing at home.
I can't ask someone
to do that for me.
There are hundreds of people
who would do that for you.
Because they don't
know the real me.
You are a good man
who made a mistake.
Then I have to tell them first.
I have to live with this, too.
I know. And I'm sorry,
but this is the only
way that I can do this.
Before I ask any of you to sacrifice
three months of your life for me,
I have a confession.
I had an affair.
I cheated on Denise.
I wouldn't blame
anyone if you decide...
I forgive him.
That should be
enough for all of us.
Thank you so much
for coming here...
There's more.
Larry, that new transmission
I put in your truck,
you didn't need it.
Joe, same thing with
the engine rebuild.
In fact, I cheated most
of you here tonight.
Half the time you bring
your cars into my garage,
there's nothing wrong with them.
I've been ripping
you all off for years.
I also took $10,000 from
the Harvest Scholarship Fund
and I lost it gambling.
I'm sorry.
I'm not the man
you thought I was.
That went over well.
Out of the two donors
who didn't walk out,
both were negative
for a potential match.
Telling the truth may
have just killed this guy.
I told him to tell
his wife he cheated,
not confess every sin
he's ever committed.
If everybody did that, we'd never
find a donor for anyone again.
Everybody doesn't lie, cheat
or steal from their friends.
Yeah, they do.
Maybe not as much as this guy,
but if people told
nothing but the truth,
the world would probably
burn down over night.
Some people think
it's burning now.
Maybe if everybody didn't lie...
Aww, that is cute.
I'm talking about your breasts.
They always get perky when
you're being painfully earnest.
Truth.
It's uncomfortable, isn't it?
More truth, I only noticed
because Chase was staring at them.
He'd never admit it because
he doesn't want to offend you.
Same reason he'd never tell you
that he's thought about
having sex with you.
Although, to be fair,
every man you've ever met
has thought about
having sex with you.
They'll lie, because
if you knew,
you probably wouldn't
want to have sex with them.
And that's just some of
the lies from the last minute.
And here's a bigger one.
You already know this,
but you pretend you don't
because it makes you feel civilized.
Most people find it
easier to ignore the truth.
Ask Taub.
Our patient can't wait for a
transplant that's never gonna come.
We need to get
reckless and extreme.
CT his liver, find the
damaged area and cut it out.
Hopefully what's
left will be enough
so we can start treatment
with broad-spectrum antibiotics.
I'm sorry the first time I had
both of you together, I had to work.
But Daddy's boss is
what we call a jackass.
It's okay. Stay right there.
I'm also sorry
for what I'm about to do
because nothing will ever
change how I feel about you guys.
But Daddy is weak
and needs to know.
Okay. I'm just gonna
put this right here, okay?
It's 3:30 in the morning.
Why are you still here?
House is here.
And apparently
prepping for an operation
that will probably
kill a patient.
I wouldn't be doing this if I
thought there was another way.
There is. He needs a transplant.
You have one lying around?
'Cause he'll be dead if he doesn't
get one in the next few hours.
That falls under natural causes.
If you kill him,
we're looking at...
Dead is dead.
Not as far as our
lawyers are concerned.
I'm not being a dick.
This is a real issue and I have to
worry about the big picture now.
I don't.
I'll be doing what you
would have done a year ago.
I'll be in surgery.
Chase? You need
to check this out.
This is his CT scan of
his liver from 10 hours ago.
This is from now.
It's healing itself?
When I left the room,
he was telling her about
the strippers from
his bachelor party.
Liver function has improved 30%.
It buys us a few extra days
before he'll need a transplant.
Interesting question is,
"Why is it regenerating?"
And scene.
Now we're back to
boring reality, reality.
His liver was in shock before.
He's been having an allergic
reaction since he got here.
It would explain why his
symptoms appeared so rapidly.
And maybe it's
starting to go away.
We need to run a scratch
test to find out what set it off.
Or who.
This all started when
he cheated on his wife.
He's allergic to a person?
Or something she's wearing.
Makeup, perfume,
birth control method.
Her Hello Kitty doll.
Two of you go find
her and find out what.
Two of you start treatment with
corticosteroids and epinephrine
while you run the scratch test.
You think I did this to him?
Or something you wear,
own, use or gave him.
I gave him a condom.
He didn't have one.
What kind?
I don't know what kind. I got it
from a health fair I was working at.
You're in the
medical profession?
I'm Miss Cedarville, the health
fair is one of my responsibilities.
Is another one hooking up
with 38-year-old married men?
I guess I'm supposed
to be the good cop.
I know this is tough,
but anything you can
remember might help save his life.
He was giving me a ride home
and he always seemed so nice.
And then we ended
up at the motel.
Now everybody's
talking about it,
and if they find out it was me,
I'm gonna lose my title
and probably my job,
and no one in town is ever
gonna speak to me again.
I made a mistake and now
it's gonna end up ruining my life.
Denise never wants
to see me again.
What did you think
was going to happen?
I was sick of living a lie.
Everybody loved me,
everybody looked up to me,
but I didn't deserve it.
Everybody makes mistakes.
They just don't usually broadcast
all of them at the same time.
Well, if I'm gonna die, I might
as well do it with a clean soul.
And if you live?
You didn't just burn bridges.
You torched, nuked and
salted the earth with them.
Everybody has to
pay for their sins.
It feels like you stuck
me with a hot poker.
An allergic reaction.
It's the swab for
wheat-based allergies.
I've been eating wheat my entire
life. I'm not allergic to wheat...
Now it feels like my
whole body's on fire.
This doesn't make any sense.
He broke out with
a rash right after
I tested with the
wheat allergy swab,
but none of his blood samples
shows he's allergic to it.
Then he's not allergic to it.
Could the corticosteroids
have somehow caused it?
I didn't hook them up yet.
After he broke out,
I wanted to confirm
it was gluten before
we dosed him.
Could be a latex allergy.
It started with a
condom and we've kept it
going with our
gloves and equipment.
He doesn't test
positive for that either.
None of his samples
test positive for anything.
Then he's allergic to something
not on the tests. I'll
keep looking here.
We'll start the steroids
and see if it clears up.
You have one patient
and three DNA results?
How else do I compare him
to other genetic disorders?
What's up?
Chase basically
called me a sellout.
Just because you
hung up your lab coat
for more money
and a bigger office?
I hung it up because someone
had to run this place after Cuddy left.
There are a lot of good
administrators out there,
not many good doctors.
More to it than you think.
For example, you're
looking at monkey DNA.
My analysis,
House took your results after he
manipulated you into providing them.
He's shedding his
skin like a snake.
If it was an allergic reaction,
the corticosteroids
and epinephrine
would have made
him better, not worse.
Is everyone trying
to think of an answer?
Or is everyone afraid to say
what they think the answer is?
I take it you're in
the latter category.
Stevens-Johnson Syndrome.
It fits all of his
symptoms and explains
why he got worse
after the steroids.
Most medication
exacerbates the condition.
There's no treatment for it.
It fits.
Case closed.
You should go home
and get some sleep.
I feel like I'm in hell.
We can't give you too
much pain medication
or we'll make your
condition worse.
I got one final
confession to make.
What's left?
You cheated on your taxes?
I'm a murderer.
I killed my business partner.
I shot him in the head
and made it look like suicide.
And he was just the first.
You killed more?
Three.
Or four.
Try not to kill anyone
else until I get back.
It's neurological.
There's an aneurysm in the anterior
communicating artery of his brain.
The area moderating impulse
control and compulsion.
As it grew larger, so
did the confessions.
Watch.
Bob, one of my shoes is
missing from my locker.
I'm so sorry.
I needed the cash and
the locker was open...
I've never heard of a
neurological problem
that causes someone's
skin to fall off.
Because there isn't one.
The aneurysm is just another
symptom, it's not the cause.
We add them all
together, we get...
We get...
Kaw... Kawa... It's Kawasaki's
disease. It's autoimmune.
Yes, we knew what "Kawa" meant,
we just figured, since it basically
presents only in Asian children...
Which you might
have, by the way.
Which is basically
why we missed it.
Rug burns.
Certain carpet cleaning
chemicals have been linked to it.
Start treatment with
intravenous immunoglobulin
and monitor the aneurysm.
If it doesn't resolve itself,
we'll have to repair it.
Rest of you aren't
surfing enough.
Monkey DNA. Nice touch.
Really?
You don't think I should
have gone with rat?
I've been second
guessing myself all day.
Where are the DNA results?
First admit that I was right.
You manipulated
me into doing it.
Yeah, I'll admit to that.
Now you admit that
it was incredibly easy,
because you can't
cheat an honest man.
I love them. I don't care if one
of them isn't biologically mine.
What about both?
It could be. I
haven't read these.
Now say I was right.
No. I'll admit I was
weak for a moment,
but I'm not doing
this, I don't care.
You do and I'll prove it.
I will shred this,
I'll call off my pool,
return the money and
we'll forget all about it.
Or we'll go to the
light box in the lab
and know the truth
once and for all.
Stop.
Let me see them.
Just wanted to make
sure all three were inside.
The mayor checked.
There wasn't any money
missing from the scholarship fund.
Dr. Chase told me
about your disease,
how it made you confess to
crimes you hadn't committed.
The affair with that girl,
is that real?
Honey, I...
would never, have
never cheated on you.
I knew you could
never do that to me.
I don't know how, but I knew.
Glad to see taking a year
off didn't dull your skill set.
I got lucky.
About the other night,
I have enough
problems with this job.
Second guessing my best
doctors shouldn't be one of them.
Why are you up here?
You have your own
bathroom and office now.
To shower. I haven't left
the hospital in four days.
Why?
House won't go home
and there's no way
I'm leaving him
here unsupervised.
House is screwing with you.
By not screwing with you.
He's watching TV and
drinking martinis all night.
Meanwhile, he's keeping you here
searching for a plan
that doesn't even exist.
How the hell did I not see that?
I'm glad you're back.
Me, too.
Either a hot tub or a sauna.
A hot tub would be cool.
New team, old team,
I present phase one
of operation Outer Office 2.0.
Nothing's changed.
Oh, everything has changed.
No.