They say love knows no bounds.
I don't know about that.
I feel like I've seen the bounds
and pushed them
a couple of times.
It's gonna rain.
It's not gonna rain.
Told her to have
the reception indoors.
This wedding is
doomed even if it happens
because it's
definitely going to rain.
You want it to rain.
You are willing it to rain.
I am not willing it to rain.
She's just so full of
feelings all the time.
Why can't she just cram them
down and shut up like everybody else?
You can't expect
her to be Cristina.
Exactly my point.
She's definitely not
Cristina. That's what I mean.
Owen wants this?
Owen's marrying this?
He said yes when she asked.
Jo still hasn't
given you a reason?
I don't need a reason.
She doesn't want to marry
me. I'm done. It's over.
Maybe it's nobody's fault.
Maybe you only get one.
One what?
Soul mate? Or true love?
Well, then, who...
Izzie?
Alex, Izzie wasn't
your one true love.
And even if she was...
What was Derek?
Are you telling me that you
think that's coming around again?
That was different.
How?
Love definitely has bounds.
I've seen where it ends.
I told you it was gonna rain.
This wedding is doomed.
Mom. Mom! Mother!
I know I was engaged
before. I was there.
No.
I am sober.
Because we love each other.
Because we didn't
see a reason to wait.
Because people get hit by cars.
We've been together for a year.
Yes, we broke up, and then we...
So what if it has
been off and on?
Oh, hey, don't let me forget
the rings, and I called the...
Shh, shh. Shh. What?
Amelia's mom.
No one in the family is
coming to the wedding.
What?
And ask her
permission to live my life.
Because I do.
I'm alone.
If you don't
come, it is just me.
Mom.
Mommy, please, I
am getting married.
Fine. Yeah, no. Um...
Okay. I understand.
Yeah, it's so good to know that
all of the best people
in this family are dead.
Amelia, hey.
Rain is supposed
to be good luck.
Hey, uh, do you want to
go over there together?
Go over where?
To the wedding.
Do you want to drive
over together, or...
Well, at this point, I don't
even know if I'm going.
Trauma's strapped for
surgeons and residents.
Blake is gone. Wilson's off.
You could always put me back in.
Don't. Yeah, I know, I know.
Still, if you're shorthanded,
just makes sense.
Ugh, good Lord.
You're just like Tuck.
I tell you no... You keep
pushing and pushing
like it's gonna change my mind.
You don't think four months is long
enough for me to learn my lesson?
On a six-month suspension?
No, I don't.
If you think a scheduling glitch
will suddenly make me
trust you again in an OR...
Wait. "Trust me"?
What do you mean, "trust me"?
No, no. I get that you
needed to discipline me,
but you don't trust
me with patients?
It was a grave
error in judgment.
And you're gonna trust me
again in two more months?
That's what it will take?
Miranda, should
I be here at all?
I'll see you at the wedding.
I don't feel good about
how quiet it is in there.
She's fine.
You have no idea how many
people have locked themselves
in that bathroom.
They're always fine.
I am serious, Mer.
I'm worried about her.
This is her wedding day.
It's supposed to be the
happiest day of her life.
The magic day, the love day.
Amelia, we're
here for you, okay?
As long as it takes.
Twenty more minutes and I'm
ripping the door off the hinges!
Amelia, stuff your feelings in!
What? It's not my love
day. I have things to do.
Okay. Where is
she? Oh, thank God.
Amelia, open the door.
Amelia?
It doesn't matter.
If they don't want
to be here, then...
They shouldn't be.
We don't want them.
They don't get it,
and they don't have to.
I do.
And I'll be there.
And the only one
I want there is you.
You're not supposed to
see me before the wedding.
It's bad luck. I'll close my
eyes. I won't see a thing.
Come out, Amelia.
Come out and marry me.
Okay. Go. I will see
you at the church.
I am an excellent best man.
Forty-something male...
Multiple stab wounds
to the abdomen and arm.
He broke into an elderly woman's
apartment and attacked her.
Oh, for God's sake.
And the lady fought the
bastard off with a carving knife.
Damn, Gram!
Being controlled by an
inflated pressure cuff.
Vitals are holding so far.
Ah! I was boiling an egg.
He scared me near to death.
I bet.
Must've come in
through the window.
Came up behind me in my kitchen.
So I just... Hyah!
Yah-yah, yah-yah!
Pressure on that, Cross.
- I'm trying.
Oh, here, I got it.
Is she... Is she okay?
How about you
don't talk about her?
Yeah, you picked the
wrong grandma today, bud.
She's my mother.
I take care of her.
She has dementia.
She didn't know it was me.
She didn't know.
It's all right. We'll need
to get you some x-rays.
Can you move your thumb for me?
Where were you?
I'm sorry?
You left me all
alone, and I had to...
You should've been there.
You should've been there for
me, should've taken care of me.
Louise, do you
know where you are?
That's what a husband does.
Okay.
Don't leave me.
Don't leave. Don't leave
me. Oh, okay, all right.
Don't leave me again. Please.
Okay.
Let's make a baby.
What?
You said that you wanted a baby,
and you would make
an amazing dad.
And that's what you're
worried about, right?
That I'm not all in? But I am.
And I love you.
Are you gonna tell me
why you won't marry me?
I told you that I love you...
And that I'm not going anywhere.
So isn't that enough? Can't
that be enough for you?
I was with Mer this
morning, and I was thinking,
the two of us, we've
been through hell.
You know, all kinds of drama...
Crazy family stuff,
we both almost died,
losing people we love.
No, you're not losing me.
The point is, we grew up.
Mer and I are grown up.
We got through it.
And hell is behind me.
It's in my rearview mirror,
and I'm not going back.
I'm done.
I'm not some idiot
kid anymore, Jo.
I'm a man, and I'm
done with games.
I'm done with crazy.
I'm done with losing.
I'm done with drama.
I don't care about your secrets
and your excuses and your drama.
You know, I've had that.
Alex, if we could just... I just
said I don't want to do this!
I have never had one second
of anything real my entire life.
I want truth.
I want a wife and a
house and a family!
Amelia and Owen's
wedding today... I want that!
Hey. Hey.
Surprised to see you here.
I work here.
Well, I just figured you'd
be at the wedding by now.
So, um...
Do you have some time before
you have to be at the church?
Don't do that.
Do what?
Get any ideas.
Don't get any ideas.
There are no ideas here for
you. I don't have any ideas, okay?
This is... I'm just
making small talk.
Okay, well, don't do that.
Why not?
Because I'm busy. I'm working.
Okay. I'm busy.
I'm working, too.
I'm not trying to be mean.
I just... I don't want
you to get too attached.
I have three
children, a big job.
Okay, you jumped me.
Okay, not that I
minded. It was good.
We had a good
time. It was very good.
I don't know about you, but
that was some of my best work.
And in a car, which is
not easy. But now what?
Now you think, what,
you're my sun and my moon,
that all of a sudden
I think that the stars
shine down on only you,
that you touched me and
the heavens opened and I...
I'm blinded by the
angel that is you?
I mean, you're good,
but nobody's that good.
I did jump you, didn't I?
Yeah. You did.
Okay, well, point taken.
You are not after me.
I'm not after you.
We are friends
who maybe have sex.
We're friends who had sex once.
We are friends that had
sex four times in one night,
but let's not get picky.
Okay, yeah. So the
tux is here, shoes there.
Um, is there anything
else you need?
I'll be fine. You're good?
And did you
remember black socks?
Ah...
Ha, I knew it.
You know, thank God for you.
This is why I had you
hold on to the rings.
Thank God for me.
Oh!
Hey, am I the first one
here? Do you have a car?
Why? Do you have a car?
Yes. Why? Okay.
Ugh, damn it.
Hey. Hey.
Uh, Amelia's next door. You
can go through there if you want.
Here. Thanks.
Big day today.
Big step.
Mmm-hmm.
Really big step.
Meredith, why do you have a
problem with me marrying your sister?
I don't, but I'm responsible.
I mean, he left her to
me, and she left you to me.
I'm not a piece of
property for Cristina
to just hand over
for safekeeping.
I haven't told her.
Does she know?
No.
Don't you think you should call
her and tell her before you do this?
Why would I do that?
She was the love of your life.
If it were me, I
would call Derek.
I don't know... Just to see if
it came close to what we had.
Okay, look up for me.
Amelia.
This is your love day.
It is a happy
day. It's so happy.
I'm happy.
Amelia...
Nothing.
Derek was supposed to
walk me down the aisle.
My dad's gone,
and he's always...
He walked every one of
my sisters down the aisle.
Well, I'm here, and Meredith
will be here any minute,
and we will all be together.
I left the rings...
I don't remember
where I left the rings.
Well, uh, they say
if you think out loud
while you're looking for
something, you find it faster.
Who says? Scientists...
Who lose things.
Okay. Okay. All right.
I remember there was one
point that I went upstairs.
You okay?
Yep. I'm fine.
Uh, I went upstairs, and
Amelia was in the bathroom.
And... Okay.
Hey. I'm here. Sorry I'm late.
I had two patients
I had to discharge,
and Owen just
had cuff-link issues.
Are you okay?
Amelia?
You should probably go.
Where's Maggie? She's
checking on the weather.
It's raining. Didn't you notice?
What's wrong? What's happening?
What can I do?
What can you do?
What... That is amazing.
That is an amazing question.
What can you do?
Amelia.
Meredith, I am
flipping out here.
I'm wearing a wedding gown.
There is a good and
decent man in there
who loves me and is
expecting to marry me,
and I can't tell if I am marrying
him because I love him back
or because I just ran here
and picked up a scalpel
and slipped into
this shepherd skin.
And maybe it is right,
and maybe it's not,
but I don't know, and I am
marrying Cristina's husband.
I know what you
think about that.
And I don't know what I'm doing.
And there is no
one here with me.
There is no one
here to tell me to quit
or get me down the
aisle or... Help me.
That is Derek's job,
and Derek is dead.
And all I have is Maggie,
and Maggie is full of
sunshine and candy and hope,
and every time I try to tell
her that the world is on fire,
she hands me a marshmallow
to roast, so that just leaves you.
And you are rooting
for the other guy.
You told me to go
and be with Owen,
and then you turned on me,
and now you are not on my side.
And we both know you don't
like me, but you are stuck with me.
So here I am in a wedding gown
on the happiest
fricking day of my life
in a room with no
family and no help
and no one on my side but you.
So what can you do for me?
What can you do for me, Meredith?
You're me.
What?
You're me before Derek.
I can be here for you.
I know how to do this.
I can be a trusted
sister for you.
Just how do you
want to play this?
Do you need me to tell
you you're a beautiful bride
and kick your ass
down that aisle?
You're a beautiful bride.
Turn around. I'll start kicking.
Do you need me to call
your mother and yell at her?
I'm your girl.
Do you need a shoulder
to cry on? I have two.
If you want to freak
out and call it off,
if you want to run, I'll
drive the getaway car.
Just let me know what you need.
I'm here for you.
I am your family, Amelia.
Today, I am your person.
Just tell me what
you want to do.
- What are you doing?
- We're running.
Oh!
- Where are we running?
- Doesn't matter. Let's go!
Ah!
Oh, God. So many people.
All those people! Okay, stop it.
And the food! Oh,
my... All that food.
Stop. Don't do that.
The food doesn't matter.
Amelia's what matters.
Right. Okay. What happened?
Nothing happened.
What's wrong with Owen?
Nothing's wrong with Owen.
Well, he could use some sun.
There's nothing wrong with Owen.
Then why are we doing this?
Okay, so then I
hung up the phone,
and I went over
to the table and...
What? You okay?
Found it.
All right, look.
Let's get out of here.
Okay. Ah!
Okay, you're
having contractions.
No. Braxton Hicks
all day. Ben, I'm fine.
Mmm-hmm. Go on.
Sit down. Come on. No.
We got to get these rings
over to Owen, and I'm gonna...
Kepner, have a seat. Oh, boy.
Okay, sitting sounds good.
Okay. It's good.
So, I will repair this
tendon right here
and get you sewn right up.
I didn't know you could do that.
Are you a doctor?
I am.
Oh, I'm confused.
That's okay. Um...
Louise, do you remember
your son at all? Donnie?
Son? I...
I don't have any children.
Okay.
Well, actually, you do.
I'm having a baby?
We're having a baby? Whoops.
No, that is not what I meant.
We're having a baby.
I can't wait. Mmm-hmm.
Uh, me neither.
Congratulations.
You're dismissed, Doctor.
All right.
Avery's with the mom,
so I'll let him know
her son pulled through.
Page me when he
wakes up. Mmm-hmm.
How was she in there?
She's fine.
Bailey, she's not fine.
Sofia keeps asking
me why Mom's so sad,
and she wouldn't even
go to Owen's wedding.
I feel like I should
do something.
Robbins, there's
nothing you can do.
This isn't your
business anymore.
I... Now, look,
she lost her child.
The woman she loved
moved across the country.
So, no, she's not okay.
The only thing you can do
is get okay with it yourself.
It's over. I had the love of
my life, and I just... Pssh.
Pushed him away,
and now he's gone.
I lost him.
Let's not overstate this.
He's just living at Meredith's.
Steph, you didn't see his face.
He's gone.
Oh, God. I'm sorry. It's fine.
I'm sorry. He's not gone-gone.
Kyle is gone-gone.
Making it worse.
Hey, can I get a cheeseburger,
rings to go, please? Thanks.
Uh, hey, DeLuca,
are you working?
Ugh, I just got off
an 18-hour shift.
I've been dreaming of this
cheeseburger and my bed.
Wilson's your patient now.
I'm gonna go home. What?
Make sure that she
doesn't drive or fall in a toilet
or go anywhere near them.
No, Dr. Edwards. Please.
You don't have
to stay. I'm fine.
Hey, could I get that for here?
- Sure.
So, they're just gone?
All three of them?
Yeah, it would appear so, yeah.
And they didn't say anything?
They did not. Now,
let's just stay calm.
I'm calm. I'm sure
there's a good reason.
They'll be back soon.
Absolutely.
Hey, could you ask Kepner
to come here for a moment?
Right. Um...
It seems we've lost Kepner, too.
What?
Okay. Okay.
See, that one came a lot faster.
They're a lot
closer together now.
Maybe we should take this
party over to the hospital.
Wait, wait, wait,
Ben. Wait, wait, wait.
I don't want to have
this baby in your car.
Neither do I. We're
going to the hospital.
No. No, no.
Okay, but figure my
contractions are close together
plus traffic plus
the rain plus...
I don't know... A
tree in the road?
What, you're saying that you...
I'm saying that between
your car and this house
with heat, running
water, blankets...
I'll stay here. Yeah.
I'm gonna have
this baby right here.
April, no. Ben, come on.
It's having a baby at home.
People have done it in caves.
My mom did it once
in a barn, I think.
We can do this. We
should just get in the car.
Oh, oh, oh.
It's... Okay. Okay. Okay.
But you know what? I'm gonna
call an ambulance, though.
Get us some help.
Okay.
I'm gonna have a baby.
You're gonna have a baby.
On Meredith's rug.
Right on Meredith's rug.
Oh!
Is it happening? Am I
having the baby now?
Okay, you need to relax.
I wish you could stay.
I'm gonna stay right here
by your side the entire time.
When you wake up,
I'm gonna be right here.
Oh, you promise?
I love you.
I love you. Okay.
So weird.
No one say anything, please.
Warren has called 911, but I
might be having the baby here,
so, uh, just, you
know, get here, please.
Hey, you sure you
don't want to lie down?
No. Uh...
I wish I had an epidural
for you. Don't need it.
I am conquering the
pain with my mind.
You weren't kidding. You
know how to have a baby.
Okay, Ben, um, maybe
go wash your hands,
'cause I need you to give me an
exam, because my water just broke.
Okay. Okay.
You're probably gonna see
my vagina, which might be weird.
Yeah, but, you know, I'm a
doctor, so, you know, it's all good.
Okay. Right.
Tap it and let it settle
and then tap it some more.
You get more that way.
Why am I doing this?
Why did you make me do this?
Why the hell would
you make me run?
I didn't make you
run. You wanted to run.
You dangled the carrot.
You dangled it
because you didn't want
this wedding to
happen, so you dangled.
I didn't dangle anything.
You're not a victim here.
I presented you with
a menu of options.
You chose to run.
You wanted to run.
You're right. You're right.
Why am I marrying Owen?
Is my family right?
Is this just one more in a long line
of ill-advised, impulsive decisions?
I don't even know.
Shouldn't I know? Shouldn't
I know on my wedding day?
Probably. Mer.
I mean, what if I'm just...
What if Owen is my new drug
and I'm just using him
to ignore the fact that...
That what?
That Mer's right, that Owen's had
the love of his life and so have I,
and once it's gone,
everything else is just filler
and you'll never, ever
have that feeling again.
I mean, who gets that twice?
Some of us would
like to have it once.
So, he just kept asking me
to marry him again and again.
I just couldn't say nothing
anymore, you know, so I just...
Get you guys another round?
I just said no.
You could've said yes.
Here you go.
I should go home.
I need to go home.
What? Whoa, no, no, no.
You cannot drive home.
No, stupid, I'm gonna call.
I'm looking for my
phone to call a goober.
I can't marry him.
I want to, but I
can't marry anyone.
Why's that? Just 'cause...
None of your business.
Okay. Right. Sorry.
God, where is my... Oh, my God!
What?
This isn't even my purse.
Yeah, what can I get you?
I can't marry him because
I'm already married.
Okay, okay. It's
done. Go. Do it.
Okay, you just relax, all
right? You know the drill.
You're gonna feel
my hand... Okay.
Okay, Warren, let's wrap it up.
Sorry. I just... I can't...
I don't know what I'm...
Come on. You've done a
pelvic before, haven't you?
Yeah, plenty, but
this doesn't feel right.
Don't tell me it doesn't feel
right. It's my freaking cervix.
Just check how dilated
it is, and get out of my...
April...
It's a foot.
I feel a foot.
No. It's breech.
It's a footling breech.
Okay. Okay.
And I feel the cord.
What?
No. No. Is there a pulse?
Answer me! I don't think so, no.
No.
So my baby's gonna die?
No, April. No.
No, it just means that it's not getting
all the blood that it could be and that
we have to get the baby
out as fast as possible
so we can get the
pressure off the cord.
Okay.
So I need a C-section
as soon as possible.
Yes.
Okay, okay, okay.
Okay, um...
So... Okay.
So...
The light is better
in the kitchen.
What? Wait, wait,
wait. No. No. No.
I'm not giving you a C-section.
Look, there's an
ambulance coming.
Ben, we both know
it doesn't matter.
I'm not doing it. I can't.
We'll get you to the
hospital. My baby is dying.
Its blood supply is cut
off, and it's going to die.
There is an ambulance coming!
Ben!
Even if they were here
now, they can't help me.
You can. It's coming.
Come on.
Okay, I know, Ben. I know.
I'm coming. I got held...
Well, um, on the plus
side, um, you're well-liked.
A lot of people came.
And nobody wants to rush you.
They just want to know
what's gonna happen.
What do you think?
Here's what I think, Karev.
I think if you get to the point
where you're gonna walk
down the aisle with someone,
she's earned some trust...
And faith.
She's earned the
benefit of the doubt.
So I'm giving it to her.
She deserves that.
You're right.
You're absolutely right.
Are we going in?
Why are you looking at me?
Amelia?
I don't know.
If we don't go in,
where would we go?
Why's everybody asking
me? Come on, Mer.
What do I know
about getting married?
And who am I to say we only
get one great love in our life?
Lots of people get two.
Look at...
Well, I don't know. I can't
think of any right now, but...
Richard Webber. Yes!
Exactly. Thank you.
Richard Webber.
Exactly. You see?
Maybe we get two, maybe
we get 11, maybe we get 30.
Isn't that better, just
to believe that? Yeah.
I mean, Owen believes it.
I swear he does.
And he loves you.
And maybe this time
is different for you.
Maybe this time, you're right.
All right, now, listen.
There's no anesthesia.
Ice is all we got, so
the pain's gonna...
The pain's gonna be bad.
Okay. All right?
Mmm-hmm. Mmm-hmm.
Okay.
Wait, why is she at
Meredith's? I got to get my keys.
No, no. There's no time. Here.
Right. You rotate the
baby in utero... Face down.
No, I know. The position will
look different than you've seen.
Okay. Is she okay?
April? April?
Hey, April? Can she hear me?
Jackson, Jackson!
Jackson, I'm here.
Okay, okay, I'm right here.
Okay? I'm right here.
Okay. Okay. Okay.
Ha! Jackpot!
What? It's an old medical bag.
It must've been her mom's.
There's some gauze
and... A scalpel.
And some lidocaine? No.
Hey, Warren, what do
you have to pack her with?
Uh...
Dish towels.
Okay.
Can you feel that?
Yeah.
Okay, Ben, I need you to
promise me something, okay?
Yeah. If you feel like
you're gonna lose me,
if I'm bleeding out, you... No.
You make sure that
this baby is okay.
Oh. No, no, no. April, do not...
Ben, don't listen to her, okay?
You save her. You
save both of them.
You promise me that you will
save this baby, no matter what.
Ben, okay?
Warren, you have got this.
You have got them both.
Ben, please. Okay?
Please. Everybody,
just quiet! Please.
Miranda? Yes?
I want to do this, all right?
I have to do this, all right?
I know.
Ben, don't hang up.
I trust you.
Okay. Okay.
Okay.
What's happening?
April, please?
Say something. Ben?
Oh, oh, oh. Hey, hey, hey.
Okay, come on. Come on, now.
Okay. Here we go. Bedtime.
Let me get you some water, okay?
I was living in my car.
Did you know that I lived in
my car? Whoa, whoa. Hey, hey.
Where are you going? Whoa.
And then I met him, and I
wasn't living in my car anymore.
Everybody loved him.
I did.
What are you doing?
I'm gonna go to bed.
Okay. Um, I should go.
Okay, you're good, right?
Never wanted anyone
to stop loving him.
So if I...
I bought the wrong
something, he would...
He would hit me in my face.
Hey.
Or my stomach. Or...
Nobody knew that but me.
So I ran.
I had to make sure he
would never find me.
And if you try to divorce him...
He would find me.
Does Karev know
about any of this?
No.
Alex would try and
protect me, but he can't.
Not from this.
He doesn't even
know my real name.
You should tell him.
He'll understand.
Karev's a really...
Okay, hey, don't.
Okay, don't do that, okay?
Let's get you
into bed, all right?
No. Stop.
Okay, no.
Dr. Karev, hold on.
Okay! What are you...
Alex!
Hey. What are you doing here?
They asked me to give you this.
Well, Kepner's the...
Well, she forgot the
rings at Meredith's,
and then everything
went sideways and...
It's a girl. She had the baby?
Yeah. Some...
Well, I know you'll hear
about it, but, anyway, here.
Thanks.
You know, you
didn't have to do this.
I know.
It's funny. Um...
The way things are going,
I'm not sure Amelia and I are...
Hey. Hey.
She's back. Where is she?
No, she doesn't
want to see you now.
What? Before the ceremony...
It's bad luck. Hurry
up and get in there.
I mean, she needs 10 minutes.
Okay. All right.
Hey, um...
Happy for you, man.
Thanks.
Oh, hey, um...
There'll be food after.
So, are you staying, then?
I might.
Yeah, I mean, I like a wedding.
It's funny. Owen was
supposed to be my best man.
Anyway, what about you?
Did you have a big wedding?
No.
We wrote our vows on a...
On a Post-it note.
He was afraid of commitment?
No, just the
opposite. It was me.
He loved me so
much, he didn't care.
Poor guy. I barely
gave him a wedding.
What'd you give him?
We went to City Hall.
Just the two of us.
Nice.
Yeah, it was very nice.
Megan, um...
She wanted a huge wedding.
She said, "Like a big party."
Derek would've
loved a big party.
I should get in there.
You should.
Is this when we go? Do
we go? Did we miss it?
Just go whenever you want.
You sure you don't want to
run? Now's your last chance.
Please shut up.
We have to go. I'm going.
You look beautiful.
Congratulations.
Love has boundaries.
We know this.
I tried my best.
Please know that if I
could've done more...
I know. I do.
She's stable.
Yeah, uh, Robbins is closing.
Your baby girl has
a very strong mother.
Yeah, she does.
Dr. Warren.
Dr. Robbins tells me that
you showed superb technique
under trying conditions.
She said you saved
two lives today.
We knock them down,
build them back up,
and knock them down again...
Oh...
But does it have to be that way?
Hi, Mama! Hi! What's going on?
Plane tickets.
Bring her back next weekend.
And I want all summer
and every other school year.
I want Christmas this time,
but you can get next time
and we'll figure out
the rest of the details.
What? Are you saying...
Listen, we did this wrong.
We had a chance to do it right,
and we missed it.
Are you saying...
I'm saying that
Sofia deserves to
have two happy moms.
I'm saying let's all be happy.
Thank you.
Can't we learn?
Can't we be brave?
Can't we believe?
Because maybe
that's all we need...
A little courage,
a little hope,
a little belief.
She looks so lovely.
Maybe there are no boundaries
if we choose to not see them.
Maybe love is unlimited
if we're just brave enough
to decide love is limitless.
Maybe there's enough
happy for everyone.
I like him.
Who?
Riggs.
I really like him.
I think he likes me.
Or maybe...
Give me a minute.
I'll think of something.