A surgical residency is all
about training for the worst.
But as prepared as we might be,
we usually don't
see disaster coming.
We can try to envision
the worst-case scenario
to foresee catastrophe.
Kepner, where is everyone?
Anyone in particular?
Well, page everyone
now. A plane went down.
A small one, but it crashed
right in the middle of the city.
I didn't hear
anything about that.
There it is.
Let's move, people!
Hey.
Hi.
But when true disaster strikes,
it often comes out of nowhere.
Amelia.
I just don't think this,
us, is a good idea.
Mixing work and play. Play?
Play? What am I now, some screw?
I didn't say that. This is more.
Amelia, you and I
both know this is more.
I don't have any more to give.
I'm not trying to hurt you.
I'm not hurt.
I get it.
And
I'm done.
And when the worst
really does happen...
Owen. You don't want
real. You want the play.
You want the high. You want
the rush. And I'm not doing that.
I'm not interested,
so I'm done, Amelia.
I've had enough.
We need to set up
a central triage area.
Walking wounded can go to
the ambulatory care center.
We find ourselves
completely blindsided.
Hi. You've reached Dr. Shepherd.
Please leave a message,
and I will return your call.
Hey. So, I just got off the
phone with the White House,
and apparently you
missed your meeting.
I don't know what's going on,
but you probably owe them...
a phone call, I think.
Watch out! Coming through!
Hey! Slow down!
What's your problem?
Sorry. There was a plane crash.
This is gonna be so good.
We are probably looking at
piles of crush injuries, burns.
Compound fractures.
If we're lucky.
Move it or lose it, ladies!
Sir, I need you to be still.
Wilson, I need
a little help here.
Shut up! Shut up!
Derek!
Grey. Grey, we need a hand.
I flew a plane. I had
the controls in my hands.
I don't know how to fly a plane,
and I flew a freaking plane!
We were in a plane, and
it crashed. Plane crash.
All I could see
was freakin' sky.
Are you the pilot? No,
no, Sam. Sam's the pilot.
Where is he? Where is Sam?
I don't know! I
only have one shoe!
Oh, God, Sam.
Transfer her on my
count. One, two, three.
I'll need a trauma panel,
C-spine, chest, and pelvis.
Edwards, grab the ultrasound.
He had a heart
attack or something.
Something happened
to him, and I had to try.
I had to try to land the plane.
Visualize the paracolic gutter.
What's your name? Kate.
Okay, Kate? We're
gonna find your husband,
but first we're gonna
take care of you.
Make sure you check for
fluid in Morison's pouch.
He's not my husband.
It was a date. OWEN:
Smaller movements.
A first date from
that site where you...
Where you put down what
kind of date you want to go on.
And then you meet the
person, and then you go do it.
What about that?
Yeah. Yeah, I see it.
We're almost done here.
I've been on a
bunch of those dates,
and it's always bowling or
something that sounds fun,
but then turns out to be dumb.
This guy's like, "Let's
go up in my plane."
And I'm like, "Why not?"
Grey, over here.
And it was perfect.
He turned out to be nice and
funny, and we were up in the sky,
and I've never
felt like that before.
Not even with guys I've
been out with a bunch.
He's amazing. He's...
Is he gonna be okay? I just...
Like, I don't want to lose him.
I just found him.
Meredith. Get up!
Derek!
I heard your voice.
I thought I was dreaming.
Grey? Grey?
Where are we at?
She's got free
fluid in the belly.
We're gonna have to take her up
for a head CT and get her to the OR.
Page Shepherd. Sam,
he's not dead, right?
Where is Derek?
Please. Please. He can't die.
Have you seen Dr. Robbins?
No, I'm sorry.
Alex, where's Robbins?
I don't know. What do
you need, a consult?
I need Robbins.
There was a plane crash.
I know.
But we're okay.
'Cause it's not us.
It's not us, so
we're... We're okay.
We are okay.
We are... We are okay.
Did you see the guy out there?
His leg is severed beneath the knee.
Did you see him?
- I did. We're okay.
- Mmm-hmm.
The girl,
she can't find her boyfriend.
We're okay.
You're awake.
I am now.
Don't pretend staring at me
like that isn't creepy because it is.
Is it sexy creepy or just...
How long have you been
awake? It's still dark out.
A little while. Not too long.
Your snoring woke me up.
I don't snore anymore.
You know, in D.C.,
I could hear the metro
station from my apartment.
The trains would wake
me up every morning.
This is a much
better way to wake up.
Yeah?
Your snoring is like a
train. It's much cuter.
I don't snore.
Yes, you do. It's like music.
It's like a birdsong.
A loud, gargling bird.
On a train.
They just keep
coming. Is that the pilot?
Yeah, Sam Garrett, 36.
BP's 90 palp. Tachy at 120.
Probable abdominal injuries.
Then let's get him in.
Have you seen Meredith
or Arizona today?
Mmm-mmm. No. I
haven't. They okay?
There ought to be some rule
that people who have been in
a plane crash can't work on one.
That's not a bad idea.
We should, uh, you know, look
out for them today, you know?
Yes. Oh, uh...
No.
No. Uh, I can't.
I mean, I want to, but I can't
be that person for Arizona.
It's, uh, not my place,
you know. Not anymore.
Right. Yeah. Okay.
Yeah.
I need tocolytics for bed six.
One of the overflows
needs a fetal monitor,
and I need you to
call Labor and Delivery
and have them prep for a
C that's heading their way.
Right away. Oh, my...
Don't do that to people!
Sorry. You okay?
Are you kidding? Of
course I'm not okay.
Well, I figured. Look...
A plane crashes into a
whole prenatal yoga class?
I mean, what are the
odds of that? Wait. What?
We were just
doing triangle pose,
and there was this crash,
and a car came right
through the window.
It was terrifying.
Okay, um, moms one
and two are possible labors.
Mom three is hypertensive.
Mom four is possible
labor, or she's freaking out.
Why wouldn't she be?
And mom five is a small abruption
that might require a section.
I mean...
Yeah, you don't
really seem okay.
You need a hand?
No. I'm just in the weeds here.
Yeah, you need a hand.
Kate...
She was so good.
She was amazing.
Abdominal distension.
Diffuse tenderness.
He needs a scan
and a cardio consult.
A guy has a heart
attack, crashes his plane.
It's a miracle
he's still talking.
It wasn't me. It was
Kate. She was the miracle.
My chest... Like a
load of bricks on it.
I couldn't move.
She just took over.
I tried to talk her
through the landing,
but she was so
brave. She just did it.
Dr. Grey? Is this Sam?
This is Sam.
Kate won't stop talking
about him. How is he?
You've seen her? Is she okay?
We're taking very good
care of her. Don't you worry.
I'm gonna marry that girl.
Uh, I think the
feeling's mutual.
That sounds crazy, but I
will. I'm gonna marry her.
Oh, his pressure's bottomed out.
We need to get him upstairs now.
Hang another
unit on the infuser.
Tell me again.
He likes you.
One, two, three.
He gushed.
He said he was gonna marry you.
Oh, my God. STEPHANIE: I know.
He has these pretty
eyes where you can't tell
if they're green or
hazel or blue or what,
but against the
sky, they're blue.
And he was looking at me, and
he asked me if I was ready to fly.
And the next thing I
know, we were up in the air.
He said flying is his
favorite thing in the world,
and he's so excited,
and he was so good at it.
Like, this is what
he was born to do.
I fell. Right then.
I knew I was looking
at the love of my life.
And we were flying,
and the air was underneath us
and clouds all around us, and...
I mean, this doesn't
happen, right?
First dates like
this, guys like this?
Up until now, I
would have said no.
But then he started
grabbing his chest,
and then we were
falling out of the sky.
It's not fair.
Hey. Heard you
two caught the pilot.
Yeah, we did.
Going in on him now.
You good? You okay?
I'm fine.
'Cause, you know,
there was a plane crash,
and I just thought maybe...
For about a year after the
crash, Arizona had nightmares,
and if I'd come home even
10 minutes late, she'd freak out,
so I just wanted to
see if you're doing okay.
Derek missed his
meeting in D.C.,
and I haven't heard from him.
That's not weird. Okay.
It's not like I should
have heard from him.
We don't call each other every
second. We're not those people.
I'm a surgeon. I'm busy.
He's in D.C. He's busy.
So it's fine that I
haven't heard from him.
It's not a thing.
It's the plane crash, Meredith.
The plane crash is
making you worry.
I know. I know.
You call me if she...
Just call me.
For a while, I would
FaceTime Cristina.
I would prop her up right
there where your head is now.
Half the time, she
was in surgery,
so I would just watch her
operate until I drifted off.
I brought the kids
in the bed for a while
so we could all sleep together.
I printed a tumor, and I
slept with that there for a bit.
It's just weird. I...
That pillow's been
empty for such a long time.
Not now. Not anymore.
I know.
I just wished you didn't
have to go back to D.C. at all.
I wish you could just
stay right here, right now.
It's my last trip, and
then I'm back for good.
I promise. I know.
I've missed you.
I missed us.
I have, too.
Okay, let's pack
all four quadrants.
Can you feel the mesentery?
Grey. Did you find
the mesentery?
Oh. I was just... Sorry.
Dr. Grey, do you
need to be replaced?
No. I'm fine.
No, you're not fine.
You're distracted.
You and Derek went down in a
plane. You drowned. He got shot.
You gave birth
in a power outage.
Is this supposed to
make me feel better?
I'm just saying you have
every reason to be distracted,
every reason to
think the sky is falling.
Do you need to go? No!
Okay, well, how long can you go
without hearing from him
before you absolutely go crazy?
I don't know. 6:00, 6:30, maybe.
Okay, then, let's say 5:00.
At 5:00 p.m., if you haven't
heard from him, you can panic.
You can call the police,
call the paramedics.
You can freak out until
your little heart's content.
But not one minute
before and not in this OR.
Can you do that?
5:00 p.m.? 5:00 p.m.
Yes.
Okay.
So, it's kind of
an amazing story.
It was their first
date, and they both...
Chief, in or out, please?
I just need to know if Kate is good to
go to the OR for abdominal surgery.
I'm looking. Please look fast.
I'm on a timeframe here.
I will not hold you up.
Because this lady will bleed
out if I don't get her up there.
Yes, I am aware you are
impatient. I can't make it my problem.
Does the patient have
a brain bleed or not?
She looks clear. Edwards,
take her up to OR two.
Kind of amazing
about these two, isn't it?
They meet for all of 20
minutes and just fall in love.
I'm not someone who believes
in fate or anything like that,
but it kind of makes
you wonder, doesn't it?
Or maybe not. Maybe
they're both crazy.
But even then, that's what
my grandma used to say,
that that's what
love is all about,
that everyone is
crazy in their own way.
And the trick is finding someone
whose crazy
complements your own.
Edwards, let's just work
without all the talking.
Edwards, what?
Well, I have questions
about the procedure.
You're supposed to
allow me to ask questions,
and I'm supposed to
learn. I have a right to learn.
I'm not... Instead,
you're silencing me.
I've been silenced.
It's unprofessional.
Just because you're
having personal issues
with a co-worker,
with a neurosurgeon,
it's not fair that you
silence my voice.
Fine, fine! What
is your question?
Well, when you glare at me
like that, I can't remember it.
I actually felt it
before I saw it.
Even small planes have
that engine power, you know,
the kind that vibrates
inside your chest.
Did it seem like something was
wrong? As soon as I looked up,
I immediately knew the
descent was in trouble.
The drag, the thrust, the angle.
Practically scraped my
roof. I couldn't believe it.
Well, how close were you again?
I should, you know, probably
see how they're doing in the ER.
Uh, I thought Torres was
down here. I need a consult.
No, she's in OR six.
Hey, are you working
with Arizona today?
Is she doing okay?
Yeah, well, I mean, she
keeps yelling at me to do crap,
so I guess that's normal.
Anyone know how Mer's doing?
Uh, they, um, had a bad
experience on a plane a while back.
Oh...
Yeah, I get that. I hate flying.
My flight out here from
Boston was the worst.
There was some technical
problem with the plane,
and so they left us on
the tarmac for four hours.
And they wouldn't let anybody out
of their seats to use the bathroom.
They weren't serving
water, and it was so hot.
It smelled like boiled feet.
And then, after four hours,
they just canceled the flight.
I mean, they just kicked us off.
There was no
apology. There was no...
What? You tell her.
Oh, okay. Um...
Here we go.
Looking good here.
How are we doing there?
Looking good so far. Let's
unpack, check what we have.
Pressure's dropping.
That doesn't make any sense.
Uh... There's no
blood in the abdomen.
He's throwing PVCs, and
his pressure is still dropping.
He's going into cardiogenic
shock from the heart attack.
He might be having a repeat MI.
Get Pierce up here now.
Meredith's sister?
Yeah.
And that's how Arizona lost
her leg. I never wanted to ask.
Callie had to amputate.
She would have died if
the leg didn't come off.
It would have killed her.
Oh, my God.
Uh...
Cutting the
pericardium. Suction.
Here.
Okay, good. That did it.
Oh!
What are you doing?
Acute MI. Cardiac tamponade.
His ventricle ruptured.
You need to plug the hole.
I'm trying. I can't
find it. Suction.
Stick your hand in there.
There you are.
Gown me.
Don't move.
He's barely perfusing.
Are you compressing hard enough?
I know how to compress a heart.
Watch my finger.
Okay, Grey, you'd
do well to remember
who you talking to
before you get smacked.
I need a patch,
pledget, and 3-0 Prolene.
His tissue's pretty friable.
You sure a patch will hold?
It has to. In a perfect
world, I'd put him on bypass
and stop his heart completely,
give myself plenty
of time to make sure
that I am sewing
up healthy tissue.
No. No bypass.
Well, we have to
do a splenectomy
and a partial hepatectomy
in order to salvage the liver.
If we put him on bypass,
we'll have to heparinize him,
and he'll bleed out on the table.
- I know.
There's nothing I like more
than being painted into a corner.
That's the spirit. Let's
be optimistic, shall we?
Okay. Meredith, I'm gonna need
you to lift your finger on my count.
One, two, three.
Ugh.
We managed to fix
the intestinal tears
without having to
resect the bowel.
You're actually pretty lucky.
With the kind of sudden impact you
took, it could have been a lot worse.
Oh, yeah, and just so you
know, Sam is still in surgery,
but he is in excellent hands,
and we will let you know as
soon as we have more news.
Sam? Yeah, Sam, your date.
The pilot of the plane.
What plane?
Why do you keep
talking about a plane?
What happened to me?
Please, tell me what
happened to me.
Temporary memory loss is very
common in situations like this.
That's your assessment,
that this is all just temporary?
It's my opinion and my hope.
But I will do a repeat CT
and a neuro check every hour.
And you're sure you didn't
miss anything in the first CT?
I didn't miss anything
on the first CT
because there
wasn't anything to see,
but she could have had
a post-surgery stroke
or an evolving
intracerebral contusion.
So you're saying
this was my fault.
I'm saying this
is no one's fault.
This kind of thing
happens all the time.
Do the CT. Let me know
when you have the results.
Hey, mom four looks okay to me.
I think you can discharge
her when you're done here.
Thanks. Uh, who do we got?
Uh, mom one, possible
labor turned into definite labor.
Great. Need help? No.
Um, no, yeah. Check on mom two.
I just started
her on nifedipine.
Do what you got to do, but
you keep that baby in there.
What? Nothing.
Then go. Go. Go, go!
Okay, you may feel a little sting
here, but we are almost done, okay?
No, I could tell right
away there was a problem,
the pitch, the air speed.
And I'm wondering,
where does this pilot think
he's gonna land this
bird? But then it's too late.
The thing just roars
right over my head
and crashed in the
street right behind me.
Right behind you?
Hmm?
Behind? Yeah, well, a
little back, a little beyond.
I mean, of course, we're
moving in opposite directions.
Wow!
And then I'm racing to the ER
to prep it for the first casualties
and just thanking God I'm alive.
I mean, I knew that they
were stranded out there,
but what they went through?
They gave Dr. Sloan
a pericardiocentesis
with, like, a drinking straw.
They all almost died.
It was love at first sight.
It's real, and they had it.
Who? Oh...
Kate and Sam, the
plane-crash couple.
They had it, and now she
can't remember any of it or him
or any of their amazing,
unicorn-magical first date.
Did you know that it was Torres
who sawed off Arizona's leg?
That's what happened?
Yes, and it's so weird
because now we know them.
They're like real people, and
they were in a plane crash.
Oh, oh. And Alex used to
hook up with Grey's sister.
Pierce? She wasn't even here.
No, there was
another one, Lexie.
Was?
She died out there in the woods.
Oh, my God. What if Sam dies?
What if Kate never remembers?
What if Shepherd
made the wrong call
because she's so pissed at
Hunt, and Hunt's so pissed at her,
and he dies, and Kate
doesn't remember any of it?
Like, it never even happened?
Like, poof, gone, just
evaporated like it was nothing?
I can never look at any of
them the same again. Never.
Yeah, that woman is never gonna
find this kind of love again. Ever.
Hey, who is that?
Where'd you get that baby?
It came flying out of mom two.
I told you to keep that baby in.
I tried. She didn't
respond to the meds.
Little bugger
apparently wanted out.
How's his mom?
She's doing great.
Easy delivery.
All right, I'll check on her
after my section on mom five.
You need a hand
with that? No, I'm fine.
Well, I mean, it's not a
problem if you want an assist.
No, I got it. Well,
no, I mean...
No, Alex!
Just get that baby settled in
the NICU and this one, too.
Okay, last suture going in.
Okay. You can let go now.
Damn it! Damn
it. It's not holding.
So much for optimism and joy.
- What now?
- I don't know.
Maybe there's a way we can
put him on bypass after all.
Are you out of your mind?
No, but I am out of options.
Bypass isn't an
option. You know that.
Do you have a better idea?
Yeah, don't do something
that kills my patient.
Dr. Grey, this is our patient,
and you're having a bad day.
Pierce, you are a
very smart woman.
There has to be something that
we can do, apart from bypass,
that doesn't involve
sending this man home
with your hand in his chest.
So we are all going to
be quiet and let you think,
and you are going to
come up with something.
Cyanoacrylate.
Glue? You want to use
glue to put the patch in?
What makes you
think that's gonna hold
any better than
the stitches did?
Bailey's infectious optimism.
You heard the
woman. Cyanoacrylate.
We don't have any on hand.
Then go get some!
He's in fib.
What are you waiting for?
Go get that glue now!
Move! MEREDITH: Run!
- Charge to 25.
- Clear.
Again. Clear.
Come on, come on, come on.
- Come on. Come on.
- Come on, come on.
Oh, there he is.
We got him back.
He barely has a pressure.
Where the hell is that glue?
It's coming. Any minute now.
Any minute.
I have the glue!
Optimism for the win.
All right, nurse, I need
your finger back in here,
and I need another
patch. All right.
Let's try this again, shall we?
On my count. Hands
up and see if it holds.
One, two, three.
Pressure's
good.
Well, that was fun.
Okay, great. Now tell
me your name again.
Kate Shaw.
Good. Squeeze my finger.
What city are we in?
Seattle, Washington.
Very good, other hand.
Now, tell me who's the
current US President?
Unless it's changed in the last
hour, it is still Barack Obama.
Nice. Now, tell me about
when you got on the plane.
I'm sorry. I still...
No! No. Sorry.
You have to, okay?
Remember. Sam. Remember?
You thought he was really cute.
I know, you keep saying that.
And you really liked him,
and he really, really liked you.
Why do you keep...
Because I think you're
meant to be together, okay?
I don't... If you're not,
then what's the point
of a plane crashing and
bringing the two of you here?
It's just... Stop it!
I don't know,
okay? I don't know!
You keep telling
me all of these things
that I'm supposed to
know, and I don't know!
You're not helping!
- This isn't helping.
- Dr. Edwards!
Edwards!
What the hell were
you trying to do in there?
You do not push
a patient like that.
I just... I hoped
that I could...
What, that you could
badger her into remembering?
That is not how this works.
She was distressed
enough already,
and you are only
making it worse.
Dr. Shepherd, you can stop
yelling at my resident in the hallway.
Your resident?
Yes, yes, today
she's my resident.
Okay, I can yell at
any resident I want to,
especially if she has
been tormenting my patient.
It looks completely
unprofessional.
You really wanna
argue about this?
Listen... I do, actually,
because you have been
totally unreasonable
at every level.
And you are
completely out of line.
Listen! Okay?
This story? It's all about me.
When I tell it, it's about me.
It's not about you or you or the
fact that you two are messed up
'cause you can't figure
out how to date or hook up
or whatever it is that you're
doing that I just don't care about.
Me. I am the protagonist.
You don't interest me.
This story is about
love and I will find it,
that he is out there, and
that even if I crash a plane,
he is out there.
And it doesn't work
unless she remembers,
and you're ruining it for me.
I am the hero.
Kate is the patient
that I saved,
and you two, you
two are messing it up.
I'm gonna...
I should...
Hey. ARIZONA: Hey,
oh, please don't tell me
you've birthed another
one of my babies.
No, no. All the yoga
ladies are in repose.
Their word, not mine.
Oh, it's about time.
Is this the abruption?
Where do you want me? - Outside.
Oh, come on, let me
help. I don't need your help.
I need you to stop hovering.
I'm not hovering. Yes, you are.
You're hovering and
lurking and creeping.
Look, I'm just trying to help
you. No, Alex, you're not.
Meredith asked you
to watch out for me
because she thinks I'm coming
apart, but I am not coming apart.
But you hovering
doesn't make it any easier.
What would make it easier
is if you got out of my
OR and let me do my job!
I'll do a TEE on Sam later to
make sure that the repair holds.
Any word? No.
5:00.
What's at 5:00?
Derek missed his meeting
in D.C. this morning.
I called him, and
he didn't pick up,
and I haven't heard
from him all day.
5:00 is my deadline.
If there's no news, then I'm
gonna go home and freak out.
You're freaking out
now, though, aren't you?
Yeah.
Going over everything
you can think of.
You're going back to the
last conversation you had
and playing it over
and over in your head
from beginning to end, right?
Yeah.
Yeah. That's what
I would do, too.
You should go home, Mer.
Zola wants a car.
Did she tell you?
A car? Yeah.
I asked her, "I'm gonna bring
something back from D.C.
"What would you like?"
And she goes, "I
would like to have a car."
I thought we were at least
10 years away from that.
Oh, it's gonna be
here before you know it.
You know, remember ages ago,
you and I had a
really big fight?
And I told you, I said,
"You're like coming
up for fresh air."
Like I was drowning,
and you saved me.
I still feel that way
when I see you, what
we have, our family.
That's the feeling. It's you.
It's always been you.
And I want more.
Of this, of us, of...
I want to have more.
Let's have more.
I mean it.
You're crazy.
That's not a no.
Another baby? Sure.
Seriously?
I'm completely serious.
Like right now, you want to...
No, you are serious.
And now I see it,
like 20 yards out,
nothing but fear and
panic on the pilot's face.
You could see into the cockpit?
We locked eyes.
And then at the last second,
I dove into the passenger
seat. I could feel the plane.
Dr. Webber? Can I
grab you for a sec?
Um, excuse me.
So, I've heard you tell this
story six different ways today,
and each time, the plane
seems to be getting closer.
I'm pretty sure the next time
it'll end with, "And then I died."
I think you're
missing the point here.
I guarantee I am.
Maybe I didn't
exactly die back there,
but I sure as hell could have.
I did look up from my car today.
I did see a plane
coming toward me.
And for a split second, I
did find myself thinking,
"Maybe this is it. This
is where it all ends,
"on 37th street, between a
yarn shop and a falafel stand."
I know what a near-death
experience is, and this wasn't my first.
And it's true. Your life
flashes right before your eyes.
And this morning, mine did.
And suddenly, I
saw how much I had.
Catherine, this hospital,
all of the people I've affected,
all the people
who've affected me.
And let me tell you.
It scared the hell out of me.
Because the minute you
see all the things you have,
you see all the things
that you stand to lose.
Look, maybe I did
embellish the story some.
I mean, that's human
nature, I guess.
But right now, I'm taking
stock of what I have,
and I'm feeling pretty grateful.
Alex, hey. I'm sorry
that I snapped at you.
I know you were trying to
make me feel better, but...
I was making me feel better.
It's just I wanted you
to be okay, all right?
I'm sick of feeling bad.
Why? Why would you feel bad?
Do you know it was
me who cut off your leg?
Callie was stuck in surgery,
and your circulation
collapsed from sepsis,
and she decided
you had to lose it.
But I made the cut.
I'm the one who did it.
Just... I don't know if you knew
that or wanted to, but it's true.
Are you pissed? I mean,
you can be pissed. I get it.
Thanks.
For telling me.
You're sure it's okay
that we're up here?
Oh, yeah, totally sure, but
maybe keep your voice down.
People are sleeping. That's all.
Okay.
All right. Here we are.
This is him?
This is Sam.
You don't recognize him at all?
I...
I don't know.
Dr. Edwards.
You know what? Take your
time. I'm gonna be right back.
You are just trying to
get fired, aren't you?
Dr. Shepherd, I'm sorry.
I told you to take it easy.
This is not taking it easy.
She just had surgery. She
should not be out of bed.
I know. I thought that if
she saw... No, I disagree.
These are not the actions
of someone who thinks.
- This is someone...
- Oh, my God!
I'm sorry. I know I'm
supposed to keep it down, but...
We had sandwiches.
Wait... You did?
We did. He made them.
I don't like to eat on dates.
I never have an
appetite. I'm too nervous.
But he made them,
and so I took one,
and I ate it because I
wasn't nervous at all.
Not with him.
We had sandwiches
on his plane on our date,
on our first date.
This is Sam, right? And I'm
actually remembering this?
This isn't... I'm not just
remembering what you told me?
No, the sandwich
story is news to us.
I want to see his eyes.
You said they were
beautiful. I don't remember.
I wish he'd open them.
He will.
So, am I still fired?
Not today. Not for this.
But who knows what
you'll pull tomorrow.
Why didn't you tell me? Hmm?
About Alex and my leg.
Freaking Karev.
Don't be mad at
him. He's an idiot.
I was trying to protect him,
but why did he have to...
All this time, you let
me hold it against you.
Why?
I made the call.
I mean, no matter what,
it was still me making
the call to take your leg,
and I knew that you
were going to hate me.
I didn't want you
to hate Alex, too.
I wanted you to have somebody.
Thank you.
Chief!
Tell Kepner I'll be down soon
to help triage the stragglers.
I thought you'd like to know
Kate's memory is coming back.
It's still incomplete, but
I'm expecting a full recovery.
Thank you. I'm glad to hear it.
You say I'm playing games?
I am here, ready to talk,
but you are pissed at me,
so I'm getting punished.
I'm not punishing anyone,
and I'm not doing this.
I want to.
I want to do this because
this is unfair! This is...
Amelia, back off.
You wanted professional.
I'm giving you professional.
No, you're not. You
are hardly being civil.
I am sorry if I hurt your
feelings. I am, but...
This is not about you!
Everything isn't about you!
Then what is it? There
was a plane crash.
Yes, but... Not the one today.
I'm talking about the plane
that had Meredith and Derek
and Arizona and Mark
and Lexie and Cristina.
I put them on that plane.
I signed the requisition
for the airline.
I paid for it. I was in charge.
I don't care how long I've
been out of the service.
It was my watch, and
they were my men.
And...
I failed them.
It was my fault.
So, when something
like this happens today,
it brings it all back up.
There was a plane crash.
Owen.
And I won't survive
another plane crash, Amelia.
And that's all we are.
Why do bad things
happen to good people?
We ask that question so
often, it's become a cliche.
But that's because bad things
do happen to good people.
Constantly.
You just have to hope
that when it's your turn,
you'll know what to do,
how to cope,
how to persevere.
Help you with
something, Edwards?
No, sir.
What are you doing?
I am enjoying the view, sir.
Me, too, Edwards.
Me, too.
But the truth is
you don't know how you'll
react to your worst-case scenario.
None of us do.
Not until it happens.