There's an old story of a
father who had two sons.
When he knew a civil
war was about to break out,
he sent one son to fight for
the North, and one to the South.
He figured if he had
sons on both sides,
there'd be a better
chance one would survive.
Because when you fight a war at
home, the casualties are your neighbors...
your friends, your family.
Leaving you all alone.
I need you to do something.
I told you I'd do it. Just
separate out the delicates.
Not laundry. My thing is fun.
I need you to clip an
aneurysm at the hospital.
- I'm on leave. Yeah, I
need you to be off leave.
- No.
- Please. Come on,
it's a sweet little old nun and
she needs open heart surgery,
but she can't have it until
her brain aneurysm is clipped.
It's so sad.
- Poor Sister Agnes.
- Don't "nun" me.
The nun detail was a
little bit much. But please.
Please, come on. I
need you. You're the best.
And don't tell me that
you don't miss the O.R.
Just one little clip, and you
can scratch that itch. Just...
One little clip.
You'll be in and out.
And I'll make sure that Owen
doesn't see you. I promise.
Give me ten minutes.
Morning. Good to have you back.
- Morning. Thank you.
- So, um, when I was chief...
Interim chief.
I took the liberty
of catching you up
on all your backlogged
resident reports,
department budgets,
supply orders, so...
- I was gonna do that.
- Of course, you were.
I just figured, you know, same
way you fill the tank with gas
- when you return someone's car.
- You stole the car.
You're welcome.
Ah. Look who's back.
Have to say, I thought
you'd last longer.
- You folded quick.
- I didn't fold.
You're here, aren't you? And
the chief didn't fire Minnick.
Dr. Webber asked me to come
back. There was no folding.
If you say so.
If you're into the guy,
why not just be with him?
- Because I don't want to
be with him. Oh, come on.
Is it because of
Maggie? She'll get over it.
- No, I don't wanna be with him.
- Okay. You do, though.
But I don't.
Pain Management to the ICU.
- So, listen, are we cool?
- What do you mean,
"Are we cool?"
I don't want there to be
any problems with patients.
It's just...
are we cool, I mean,
to work together?
- We're cool.
- I had to ask. It's kids.
- Okay. Good.
Dr. Jacoby, 1011.
- The mattresses?
- Yes.
You need to replace every mattress
in every on-call room. Unacceptable.
He's not wrong.
These mattresses are lumpy, they're
misshapen, zero lumbar support.
Our surgeons need solid rest,
- not spinal damage.
- Noted.
You might tell Dr. Webber
that if he wants to sleep soundly,
he should come home
and sleep next to his bride.
I'll take this under advisement.
- New mattresses!
- Hey. You okay?
No. My back hurts.
Oh, and there's nothing like
having your dirty laundry aired
- for everyone to see.
- Hm, it's that bad, huh?
Yeah, as long as Minnick's
here, it's gonna stay bad.
I-I don't know what to do,
except maybe give up and give in.
No. No, that's not acceptable.
Everyone's behind you.
Everyone was behind me.
The longer Minnick's here,
the more people like her.
And the more people like her...
Well, I'm behind you,
then, so... Hey, listen.
Why don't you stay at my
place? I have a guest room,
- and it's got
a very good mattress.
- I-It'll be fine.
Arizona, thanks for sticking
with me. You're a good friend.
We're losing ground.
Everybody loves Minnick.
I wouldn't say that. I
mean, who said that?
- And now Meredith.
- I stood up for him
and got suspended.
Yeah, and now you're
back. You rolled over.
- Because he told me
to come back!
- That's not what it looks like!
All right, you weakened
our position here.
Well, we don't have a position
if he is asking us to stop.
- Meredith has a point.
- The problem isn't Minnick.
The problem is that
her program is good.
And now everyone
knows it, including Richard.
You guys are unbelievable.
You're just gonna abandon him now?
- No, we're not.
- No.
Well, I'm not gonna do
that. I'm gonna fight for him.
- How?
- My mother's not the only Avery
in this hospital.
Seems like the colovesical
fistula closed off on its own after all.
No abdominal
reconstruction needed.
Good. I was hoping to avoid
having to call Jackson in.
Things still difficult at home?
I'm not sure I can
stay there anymore.
I mean, I want to.
It's been so easy
with Harriet, but...
But everything's so much harder
than it needs to be right now.
- I know.
- Yeah. And...
And what?
It's just embarrassing,
being demoted.
You were not demoted.
From chief of general surgery to
trauma attending? It looks like it.
April. April. A title is only as
good as the person who earned it.
Grey is very good, but
when she wasn't here,
the person they
turned to was you.
- Oh, I know...
- Do you?
Then act like it.
So, hey. Heads, he's Leo.
Let's just wait until
we know he's okay.
Oh, come on, stop. You agreed
that we'd decide with a coin toss.
I noticed a systolic murmur
at the post-birth exam.
It's probably nothing,
but I called just in case.
I'll check it out.
DeLuca, get a pulse ox.
Baby, our little guy is
gonna need a name.
Hey, definitely before school,
but probably before we leave here.
So...
Heads, he's Leo. Tails, August.
- Okay, why is the name
I like tails?
- Fine. Heads, he's August.
- Heads?
- August it is.
Pulse ox is slightly
below normal.
Yeah. Let's get some
labs and page Cardio.
Uh, what's
happening? Is he okay?
He's got a heart murmur. I need
to take him to get some tests.
I'll let you know
more as soon as I do.
- What's the little guy's name?
- Gus.
Gus.
Hey. You got a minute?
Uh, just got paged
to the pit. Can it wait?
- Thanks.
- I need to talk to you
- about this Minnick situation.
- What situation? She's doing great.
Don't pretend you don't
know what you did, Mom.
People have been fighting this
since the minute you brought her here.
- Bailey brought her here.
- At your urging.
And since I am the voice of
the Avery Foundation at this...
Wait. I'm sorry.
You're the what?
I'm the foundation's
representative on the board, right?
A position that you gave
me, that you made me take.
Yes, and you kicked and screamed
and whined every step of the way.
And then I took it on.
So I am the Avery of this hospital.
The foundation speaks through me.
The foundation
oversees, we guide.
We do not interfere
in hospital politics.
How can you say that to me?
You started this by effectively
ousting Richard Webber.
Which, by the way, our rank and
file finds completely unacceptable.
I'm gonna be making
the decisions from now on.
I'm gonna go to
the governing board,
I'm gonna get Richard
back in and Minnick out.
I'm going over your head.
I don't understand. He's never
been that interested in the foundation.
I know. He does not appreciate
our role, or the scope of it.
Seventy-seven hospitals nationwide,
forty-three full service clinics.
Not to mention the
Worldwide Health Initiative.
Oh, somebody's been
doing her homework.
I've just been curious.
Or maybe you just
like being in charge.
You know, the thing is...
- I was good at that job.
- Mm-hmm.
I like doing that stuff, the
admin work, the scheduling.
Meredith doesn't even like it.
You know, I want you to see the
Avery Trauma Center in Chicago.
They do things very
differently than you do here.
- We should go.
- Absolutely.
I would love to see
how they run things.
No, honey. I want them
to see how you run things.
Oh, yeah. I'd love
that. Thank you.
Trauma One.
- What have we got?
- Turkey fryer accident.
Propane tank exploded.
Blew shrapnel everywhere.
His family's behind him, minor injuries,
but he caught got the brunt of it.
Full-thickness burns to the neck,
down the left side of his body,
extending into the perineum.
- Left leg partially degloved.
- One, two, three.
Suture kit and trauma dressing.
All right, check on that gauze.
Oh, wow.
His bowel is eviscerated.
I need to examine this
wound and the perineal burn.
- Somebody call Plastics!
- On it.
Yeah. So this kid
definitely has HLHS.
- Start him on PGE.
- Labs are back.
All righty, Gus. Let's
take a look at your labs.
- They landed on Gus, huh?
- How did their OB
not catch this?
Okay, DeLuca, we need to get
him on the transplant list ASAP.
Hold on. No, we're
gonna do a Norwood.
Well, I don't think so. He
has mitral valve regurg.
I don't think the little kid can
survive a full reconstruction like that.
I know he won't survive the
wait for a newborn donor heart.
He's stable for now. He
can tolerate a Norwood.
- So, what's next?
- Parents are freaking out.
We go talk to them next.
- Where did they take Dad?
- Let me check you out.
It's okay, Pammy.
It's gonna be okay.
Your fiancé just deep fried
our father! That is not okay!
- This is from a turkey fryer?
- It's the one thing
I know how to cook. I was just
trying to do something special.
You mean unforgettable? Like
"that time you killed my dad"?
- Pam! Come on! He didn't mean to!
- Rodney, Dad's leg melted off!
- You have no eyebrows!
- I'm so sorry, honey. So sorry.
- I know.
- Your arm has
a partial thickness burn.
You'll need to learn to
dress it while it heals.
I can help. How can I help?
Oh, I don't know, go back
in time when I told you,
"Deep fryers are
dumb" and listen to me!
Can you tell me
how my father is?
- Pam, I'm sorry.
- Maybe just stop talking.
Someone will come dress those
burns. And I'll go get an update.
All right, he's got a
lot of neck swelling.
Um, can you get me a
fiberoptic scope, just in case?
This wound extends deep.
The bladder is destroyed.
I need to get him in
an O.R. for a repair.
No, you can do the
bladder repair later.
I need to do an ex-lap with
an abdominal washout first.
Yeah, I can't even
see his vocal cords.
- Here. Let me try.
- No, I got it. I got it.
Okay. Warren, call up to the
O.R., tell them to place the patient
in lithotomy position
for a perineal evaluation.
Warren, let them know we
need a perc nephrostomy setup
and a possible ileal
conduit for reconstruction.
His small bowel is
sticking out of his abdomen.
What ileal conduit
are you talking about?
Jackson, the tendon is exposed.
He's gonna need a skin flap.
- No, no, that can wait.
- I'm just saying...
I know when flap coverage
is warranted and when it isn't!
And another bickering
family. Fantastic.
- Warren, did you say something?
- I said I'm gonna book an O.R.
- Okay, well, hop to it then.
- Hurry up.
- Get going, child.
- Come on, let's go.
Sister Agnes is good to go. It
went great. In, out, no problem.
- Feels good to be back, huh?
- Yeah.
Back at work.
I'm still not ready to see Owen.
I just, uh, don't know
what I would say to him.
Okay, well, I'm just riffing here,
but you could start with, "Hi, Owen."
Sorry. When you're
ready. No judgment.
Uh, could you just check the
hall so I can get outta here?
Yes, of course. Okay.
All clear. Go. Go, go.
It's called Hypoplastic
Left Heart Syndrome.
The left side of Gus's
heart is underdeveloped,
so it can't deliver oxygenated
blood to the rest of his body.
- Okay. So, what do we do now?
- He'll need surgery?
There are two options.
A heart transplant,
or an open-heart surgery
to reconstruct Gus's heart
called a Norwood. I
think we go with that.
And I think that we should consider
waiting for the heart transplant.
I'm concerned that your little
guy doesn't have the strength
to withstand a staged procedure.
- A staged procedure?
- Yeah. The Norwood is the first
of three separate surgeries
that will be performed
over the first three years of his life, as
opposed to just one for the transplant.
But, with a heart like Gus's, the
wait could be more time than he has.
Also, you're looking at a
lifetime of anti-rejection drugs.
As opposed to the strain
of multiple surgeries,
often resulting in a transplant
in the long run, anyway.
And in Gus's case, we have a bit of time
before his symptoms become intolerable.
I'm not willing to
accept that risk.
Okay, but he... he says that
Gus won't survive your thing, the...
- Norwood. And I think he can.
- Yeah, but he's a heart surgeon.
And I operate on
babies all the time.
I've seen more of these cases
than he has, I know how well they do.
Also, I'd rather
invest in a sure thing
than wait for a donor that
might not show up in time.
Okay, so you're just
saying that there's...
Okay, well, then
just tell us what to do!
My baby is dying, and I
don't know how to help him.
You're just confusing
us. Just... what do we do?
I think that we should
- just go with the transplant.
- Norwood.
Um...
You said that we
have some time, right?
What the hell, man? They're
overwhelmed, they just had a baby.
What, so they shouldn't
hear the whole story?
They don't need to
hear you argue with me.
Well, you should have heard me
out before you went running in there.
There's nothing to
hear. He's my patient.
He's a good candidate
for a Norwood.
- Well, I disagree.
- Or at least he is now.
He might not be once they
spend a bunch of time deciding.
DeLuca, let me know
when they're ready.
Call UNOS. Put that kid
on the cardiac transplant list.
I think Dr. Karev's really
into the Norwood idea.
Yeah, well, Dr. Karev's not making
the decision. The parents are.
And when they decide on a transplant,
I don't want to have missed out
on a heart because we
waited. Just put him on the list.
And don't tell Karev. I
don't want to hear about it.
The bladder isn't the
only thing at stake.
That's why I'm
saying I need to do...
I'm saying we do it first.
The patient's prepped.
- No. We delay
soft tissue coverage.
- No, it's a Gustilo type three.
- It's an obvious fix and flap.
- Not on a dirty wound like this.
Okay, we need to do a
delayed reconstruction,
not a primary bladder repair.
No, the reconstruction
should happen now...
We have a penetrating
wound to explore.
- before the tissues
become edematous.
- Okay, what about this?
Webber and Kepner
explore the wound
as Avery evaluates the burns to
determine the need for more coverage.
The other Avery can
do a perineal evaluation,
and after a full assessment,
it'll become clear how to proceed.
I just, you know... Minnick said that
we should work the problem with you.
Actually, Warren, that
should work. Thank you.
- What?
- You called it with Riggs.
- What do you mean?
- The guy's a snake.
- I didn't say that.
- He just made a mom cry.
Well, her kid's in the hospital.
There's a high probability of tears.
He thinks he's a cardio god or
something, like he knows everything.
When I'm the peds
guy, I know things,
if he would just listen. The guy's
a total snake, just like you said.
Well, I definitely
never said that.
Unfortunately, that's
all we have at this point.
- Oh, my God! Oh, my God! You're back!
- Oh, well, actually...
I'm so happy!
Dr. Minnick's method is awesome,
but I've really been
wanting to do it with you.
- Edwards...
- And I... wait. Stop. Hey.
Are you anti-Minnick?
Please don't be anti-Minnick.
- Stephanie!
- What? What?
- I'm not here. You didn't see me.
- Oh. Oh.
Would you mind just walking through
the ER to see if Owen is in there?
- No.
- Thank you.
No, I mean no. I have to work.
I don't want to get dragged
into your marriage again.
You know, boundaries.
- Right. Yeah, of course.
- Sorry.
Come back! Okay? Bye.
- Hi!
- Hi yourself.
How big is your stove?
I don't... I don't know
how to answer that.
I want to make pierogi for
you, but my stove sucks.
Oh, that sounds
nice. Uh, what is it?
- Something I do very well.
- Okay.
I don't have to stay or
anything. Just... pierogi.
Once you taste my pierogi,
you won't want anyone else's.
I've no idea what you just said,
but I'd like you to say much more of it.
- I'll see you around eight.
- Okay.
- I'll bring everything.
Let's divide the segment
and then I'll prepare
for a diverting colostomy.
Instead, actually, I think we can do
the primary bowel repair right here.
Kepner, you're no longer
running general surgery.
- So how about you let me
do my job?
- But she is running this case.
She brought in the trauma.
Her department, her patient.
Three-oh Vicryl for
bowel anastomosis.
I checked my
calendar for Chicago.
And I'm pretty booked
for the first two weeks,
but the weekend of
the 25th might work.
- Yeah, sounds good. All right.
There's an architectural boat tour.
Oh, I've done that.
It sounds boring,
- but it's actually fascinating.
- Oh, fun.
- What is happening?
- Weekend of the 25th,
I'll be out of town.
So you'll have Harriet.
- You two taking a vacation?
- It is not a vacation.
You're taking a boat tour, Mom.
If you're going to Chicago, you
really have to take that boat tour. It's...
We're visiting the Avery
Trauma Center there.
Trauma Center? Oh, why's that?
Is our trauma program
next on your chopping block?
I'm also getting
us Hamilton tickets.
- Yay!
- You're going to Hamilton
without me?
Dr. Hoffman to Oncology.
Hey. Oh, I'm starving.
I've been in this complex
sarcoma excision for seven hours.
And guess who got to dissect the
tumor from the vascular structure?
That's right. Me.
What's wrong? Is
there something wrong?
No. I, uh...
It's just...
I'm on a case with two attendings
who want different treatments
and have given me
competing instructions and...
I don't know what to do.
Well, you'll make the
right choice. You always do.
I gotta go.
Incoming MCC, I'm on it.
Dr. Taylor to the
Instrument Room.
- MCC?
- Unhelmeted.
GCS of four. Intubated on the
scene. He's got an open skull fracture.
- Conscious at the scene?
- No.
He has decorticate
posturing. Page Neuro now.
Neuro's here.
Let's go, let's go!
Minnick's method doesn't
just get residents up to speed,
it gets them there faster.
Faster isn't better. Unless
you're cutting corners,
- or creating some kind
of factory.
- I'm doing no such thing.
- In your opinion.
- You know what?
This stitch that I just did?
No one else does it like this.
And do you know why?
'Cause Mark Sloan took the
time to teach me how to do it.
'Cause I watched him and I
watched him and I learned from him,
much in the same way so many
surgeons have learned from Dr. Webber.
Learned from his artistry. And you're
telling me what? Those days are over?
Dr. Webber makes artists
here. Dr. Minnick makes robots.
Three-oh silk, please.
Bringing Dr. Minnick
here was not the right call.
Okay, you know
what? To be clear,
that particular decision was made
by Bailey. Isn't that right, Warren?
Let's just leave me out of this.
Even if Minnick's program
was good, the way you two
went about implementing
the entire thing
had zero respect for the
history of this institution.
Certainly no respect
for Dr. Webber.
- Jackson, that's okay.
- I mean,
are you really telling me
this is good management, Mom?
You think this is good for morale?
Maybe if you hadn't
talked the entire staff
into forming a coup,
you might have listened.
- Patient is getting
coagulopathic.
- Mayo scissors.
And you know what? You
have no clue about management.
I almost forgot. You got
a new minion in the deal.
Oh, come on.
What is it you wanna
learn from my mom exactly?
How to get an entire hospital
to turn against you in a day or...
Jackson, stop it! Just stop it!
You keep saying, "I'm an Avery,
I'm an Avery!" But you're not,
not in the way
you're trying to be.
Title doesn't mean anything.
It's the person who owns it.
Yes, I took your father's
name, but it's what I did with it.
It's what I made with it.
That's what matters. You...
You are an outstanding surgeon.
He's too far gone for us to
do anything more tonight.
We should take him to the ICU,
start fresh tomorrow. Agreed?
- Yeah. We're done here.
- Yeah, this isn't working.
Those sutures should
control the bleeding,
but he's got a big open
skull fracture up here.
- FAST exam negative.
- Pupils are sluggish.
I didn't realize you were back.
There's no other obvious injuries. I'm
gonna need to see those trauma films.
I just stopped by,
uh, for some stuff.
- Stuff?
- Stuff.
I was shopping. Odds
and ends. I needed floss,
and realized I had a bunch here.
Then this guy pulled
up. Positive Babinski.
- Floss.
- Can't sleep without it.
Yeah. I know.
Labs are back.
Trauma films are clear.
Thank you, Edwards. Page
someone from Neuro, please.
What? Why? It's fine. I'm...
This looks like it's
gonna be an uphill climb,
and if you're not
actually back...
Owen, stop. Edwards,
show me this skull fracture.
I just spent the day trapped
on a case with my wife.
And Jackson. And April.
- Yikes.
- Yeah.
So, if I may, I would
love to take you up
on your offer after all,
and stay at your place.
Enjoy some good company,
and, get a good night's sleep.
- Oh, okay. Uh, tonight?
- If the offer hasn't expired.
Yeah. Well, I mean, I have a
date now. But I can cancel it.
- Oh, no, no, don't.
- No, no, no. I can. Listen.
I just made it today.
And I probably shouldn't
be doing it anyway.
- So I can cancel.
- No. I wouldn't dream of it.
- You go have fun.
- Are you sure?
Yeah. I've got a patient
who's touch and go.
I should probably stick
around here anyway.
So, give me the dirt tomorrow.
- Oh, you're still here?
- Still here?
Uh, I got pulled onto a case.
Oh, okay. Well, Sister
Agnes is recovering well.
Her neuro scans
are perfect, great job.
- Thanks.
- Thank you
- for coming in this morning.
- No problem. Thanks, Pierce.
So you've been
here since morning?
Look at that, the scans are up.
Hey, first day back, and
pulling an all-nighter. Ambitious.
- What's going on?
- Why are you being a jerk?
- What?
- Alex said
you were being a jerk.
- Oh, of course. He tattled.
- Let me make something
very clear to you.
If you want to get anywhere with
me, messing with Alex is not the way.
Do not contradict
him in front of patients,
and please don't speak
to him like he's an idiot.
Okay. Back it up. Get anywhere
with you. So you admit it.
- Admit what?
- There's somewhere
to get with you.
Don't change the subject.
I'm talking about Alex.
Karev is pissed because I'm giving a
really sick baby a chance at a miracle.
He's giving it a Band-Aid.
Maybe he just wants to
play it safe, I don't know.
But whatever it is,
I really don't care.
- Why don't you care?
- Because I'm right!
And I don't have
to keep justifying...
Forget it.
Wait. Where are you going?
We're having a conversation.
No. I'm done.
- So you're just gonna walk away?
- Damn right! I'm a jerk!
But when your father
began to decompensate...
We decided to hit pause,
give him some time to rest
and get stronger
before we continue.
Oh, God. Oh, God.
- Can we see him?
- We? Who is we?
- Jim!
- I meant you guys, obviously.
- Can they see him?
- That's not really
a good idea, Jim.
He's not out of the woods
yet. I'd really like him to rest,
so we can go back in tomorrow.
Right now, you guys should just get
some food, get some rest yourselves.
No, we aren't going anywhere.
Tell you what, you guys stay
here, and I'll bring us in some food.
Food?
You're gonna get us food? You?
Rodney...
Maybe you should go.
Sure.
Okay, I'll come back in a bit,
- just shoot me a text and...
- No.
I know you meant
well, but my father is...
I can't.
It's all I'll ever think
about when I look at you.
Oh.
- Oh. Rodney...
- You should just go.
Okay, this guy's got
an epidural hematoma
and diffuse axonal injury.
Surgery may not
help, but we can try.
Obviously, even if
it is a lost cause...
You've been
working? Doing cases?
No.
Were you planning on
seeing me at all today?
No.
So you're just hiding.
- Is this your first time
coming in?
- Yes!
I-I came in as a favor
to Maggie. That's it.
Patient's prepped. We're ready.
You should leave.
- We're scrubbing in.
- You said it yourself. It's a lost cause.
Well, page another
trauma surgeon, then,
if you don't wanna
go in. I'm going in.
There are no lost causes.
I'm late, I know. Did
I miss the window?
No. No, I'm good. I'm ready.
Oh, no. You're tired.
- Why would you say that?
- 'Cause you were sleeping.
- And because I'm tired.
- I'm so, so tired.
I'm wiped. Residents are a
bottomless pit of questions.
And it's cute, but it's
also unbelievably draining.
Well, why don't
we rest a minute.
Like, just for...
just for a minute.
- Just a minute.
- Okay.
- Then rally.
- Mm-hmm. One minute.
Forty-five seconds.
Oh, my God. Oh, my God. Hello?
Okay, so O.R.
Seven if it's available.
What's going on?
I've got good news. Great news.
So try not to let
it piss you off.
- Just tell me.
- We got a heart
for the Endris baby.
- A perfect match.
- How?
- He's not even on the list.
- I put him on the list.
Without telling me?
Without the parents' consent?
Did you know about this?
- Well, if he wasn't
on the list...
- Karev,
this is a good thing.
Okay, all we gotta do now is
have an awkward conversation
with the parents and
then we save a kid's life.
You're unbelievable.
You know that?
I can talk to the
family with you.
Do you want to be married to me?
- Yes.
- Then why won't you talk to me?
- I'm not ready.
- For what?
- The fight.
- There doesn't have to be one.
There does. We are
on opposite sides of this.
We both want
completely different things.
We can't both have what we
want. So there will be a fight,
and somebody has to win.
Or no one wins.
I'll talk to the family.
Hold on.
This is why you called me all
the way in here at this hour?
Look, he went behind
my back. He lied to me.
- Hey. What's going on? We ready?
- Hold on.
Look, I don't trust him.
I don't want him
in the O.R. with me.
Uh... What?
Dr. Karev has raised a
complaint against you.
- Oh, come on! He
says that you've been...
We had a disagreement
about treatment. That's all.
- He would have survived
the Norwood.
- Or he wouldn't.
Now we don't have to
risk killing him to find out.
No, you just killed some other
kid by directing that heart here.
- Congrats on that.
- All right, all right! Enough!
The only fight here is
to keep this child alive.
To fix his heart. You
won. You won that battle.
Now, finish the freaking
war. You two figure out a way
to work together long enough
to put that heart into that baby.
Understood?
What happened? Blood
was seeping out of the vac
and his pressure was dropping.
So they rushed him up
here to find the bleeder.
- Have lap pads ready.
- Whoa, whoa, whoa! What's...
Got it. Yeah, I got it.
- Sorry, I was right here. So I...
- No, no, no. Nice work, Warren.
- Go ahead.
- Can you see the source
of bleeding?
Uh, yes, yes. I see it,
it's, it's in the mesentery.
DeBakeys at a right angle,
please. Should I keep going, sir?
- Here. I'll suction for you.
- Really.
The patient's a little unstable.
You don't want to take the lead?
Well, I don't think I need
to. I think Warren's got this.
So why are we even here?
Warren? You feel
like you got this?
Yes, sir. Two-oh silk, please.
More laps.
- You called UNOS behind my back?
- I did.
- I thought we were cool.
- We are.
You went behind my back
when I specifically said...
Look, it's like
you said. It's kids.
So what was that?
- Excuse me?
- You're just giving in
to this new way of teaching?
I was teaching a capable
resident. Same as I always have,
- long before Minnick.
- No.
No, in there that
was... that was different.
Look, we can win
this thing. All right?
There are strings that I can
pull, you know? I have a voice.
Jackson, don't do it. It'll tear
you and your mother apart.
Tear us apart? What about
you? You're her husband.
You don't think this whole
thing is pushing you away?
You don't know the first thing about
my relationship with your mother.
And you don't know my mother.
I mean, you don't know
this is what she does.
She finds a weakness,
and she exploits it.
She's gonna fight you all the way
here. She's gonna fight and fight...
We fell in love fighting
over this hospital.
- We'll be okay.
- Yeah, except she's
not gonna stop.
All right? She's gonna
fight until she wins,
no matter the
cost. Don't let her.
Well, your father's
out of surgery.
His recovery is going
to be a long haul,
- but he will recover.
- Oh, thank God.
Okay. I can take you to see him.
What are you doing?
It's just that... Jim loves Dad.
- You're kidding, right?
Pam, it was an accident.
- Uh, which way?
- Oh, there.
How could you do that?
How can you do this to
somebody you care about?
Jackson, you need to
stop this foolishness.
What? I just need to know.
I need to know if business is really that
much more important to you than family.
This has nothing
to do with family.
Of course it has
to do with family!
Look, I get it, all right,
business is business.
If you need to fire someone
or replace them, do it.
But if it's someone
you love, you just...
Does that mean nothing to you?
Jackson, you and I are
two very different people.
Yeah, no kidding. I've never been
happier about that fact in my life.
You have never shown one
ounce of interest in this business.
- That's fine. Fine.
- Yeah, that's fine,
because you have
April now, right?
Yeah, 'cause you can
finally get that Avery
- that you always wished
that I was.
- No! No, son.
No, you've always
been your own man.
You've always made your own way.
Nothing could make a
parent more proud than that.
Nothing. I am so happy
with who you are. I am.
I just wish you were, too.
- Saved the baby.
- Oh. Excuse me?
The baby, the one
that Karev and I were...
- Anyway, the kid's alive.
- Oh, well, that's great news.
Okay, now you're
the one being the jerk.
Because Alex
was right about you.
Oh, yes. Of course.
'Cause everybody's always
in your ear, telling you
- what to think about me. Maggie...
- Nobody tells me what to think.
Okay, good. 'Cause I
don't want their opinion.
Okay? I care about
what you think.
About you? Actually,
I think a lot of things.
No, no, no. No
banter. No more quips.
I'll tell you what I think.
I think about you.
A lot. Okay? I can't stop.
I am telling you, I am in.
If you are. I am in this.
So I'm just... I'm just
gonna ask you outright.
What do you think?
Actually, don't answer.
Not till you know.
And when you do,
just... give me a call.
What time is it?
Did we fall asleep?
I don't know. I feel rested.
Oh, my God, that's
because it's almost morning.
Um...
So I guess we just
spent the night together.
I guess we did.
Oh, uh...
I'm sorry. Sorry.
War isn't civil.
You pick sides and
defend them. You attack.
You hurt people. You get hurt.
How was it today?
- Bad as you thought it would be?
- Kind of.
We need to talk.
We have to, but...
No, you don't. At
least, not tonight.
You weren't even supposed
to be here today. Come on.
You fight and you
fight and you fight.
To what end?
Come home.
What are we fighting against?
What are we fighting for?
Just get a good night's sleep.
I never wanted to come
between the two of you.
You and Jackson.
I never wanted that.
I know.
When is it time to just
quit all this nonsense...
Well, good night.
And simply...
surrender.
- That's one nasty throat tumor.
- Oh, God.
- En bloc resection?
- Maybe. Maybe.
Got a patient up at the
Avery hospital in Montana.
I might have to go
out there for a consult.
- Huh.
- "Huh" what?
I'm going to an Avery hospital,
now you're going
to an Avery hospital.
- Oh, come on, really?
- Yeah, it's not that.
Are you... are you
jealous? Is that it?
Jealous of my mom
manipulating you? No.
Oh, stop.
I'm not some puppet.
I have my own brain. I
have my own opinions.
Working with your
mom and the foundation,
it's full of
opportunities for me.
And I get that you never
wanted that, and that's fine.
- But she sees something in me.
- All right, I'm going to bed.
What is going on with you?
Nothing's going on with
me. Just leave it alone.
- Jackson, I...
- It's not your business!
Good night.