Previously on ER:
- Nice to meet you.
- Heh, heh. You too.
- And thank you for the hot dog.
- It's my pleasure.
- This is my brother, Chaz.
- How you doing?
- You moving in?
- Yeah.
Up at First Mission Baptist, Pastor
Watkins does a drug-exchange program.
What you're doing is dangerous,
okay? Not to mention illegal.
That TV news gal,
Courtney Brown, called again.
Oh. Channel 5 Courtney
Brown? What did she want?
She offered me a
job as a reporter.
It was about time someone
put something worthwhile on TV.
I called you the other night
and a woman answered.
Yeah. I can explain that.
Rise and shine, Mayday.
Too early to be taking a nap.
- Is it morning already?
- Yeah.
Has been for a while.
Crenshaw has been running me ragged.
I've been on since midnight Tuesday.
No wonder you haven't
returned my calls.
Surgery is not for sissies.
I wanna talk to you about our
mutual groping after the M and M...
Oh, yeah, it was a mistake.
Yeah.
You live with someone.
Yes, but not exactly.
And there's a little girl.
Right. Nice kid, not mine.
Her father was my friend.
In the Gulf?
Yup. After we came back,
he couldn't keep it together.
And I always told him that
if something happened...
I would make sure that Sarah
and Meg made it through.
That's a big promise.
I always say go big or go home.
Hello.
Gates, your DVT patient is still
waiting on a ride to Oncology.
Nurses started a pool on when
somebody will tap your ascites guy's belly.
All right, I'll go
take care of the...
The DVT guy first.
Ambulance on its way in.
Stab wound-slash-OD,
nine minutes out.
Wake me up in eight.
Whenever I move my
head, everything spins.
- Mm-hm.
- My nephew says it's a tumor.
Your neuro exam's
normal, ma'am...
so it's not a brain
tumor, it's not a stroke.
Stroke?
This is meclizine. Take one
every eight hours if you get dizzy.
When you run out, fill
this for a month's supply.
I take that to the pharmacy?
- Yes, ma'am.
- And I have to pay?
Yeah, but your insurance
will cover some of it.
- Dr. Pratt?
- There you go. Excuse me.
Ahh.
Yeah?
Mrs. Skinner's BP, 185/100.
- She take the Oretic I gave her?
- Sure, until she used up the samples.
Well, what about
the prescription?
It's $60 for a month's supply.
She's saving up, but hopes her son
will send her a check by Thanksgiving.
You know, I'm going out of my
way to get your people set up right...
you gotta help make sure
they stay on the program.
All I need is an extra 100 grand a year.
That'll cover costs for my congregation.
What? I need to figure out
a way to pay for all this too?
Hey, in for a penny,
in for a pound.
Who said that? Jesus?
Clemens Daniel III, my bookie.
Don't let me get wet,
Teller, the water burns.
- Gotta make sure they see him.
- Don't leave me.
We'll get in trouble.
Them demons come through
the sewers when it rains.
She's here!
- Bloody Mary.
- Let go. Let go! It's her!
It's okay. You know what to do.
- No, she sees us. It's too late.
- Do it, Paulie.
One, two, three, four,
Stay away forevermore
See?
She can't hurt us.
Stab wound to
shoulder, BP, 110/75...
Let's go, Teller. He's a doctor.
- Did she get Narcan?
- No response.
Teller, we have to go back.
What happened? To
his ear, what happened?
He climbed over a fence.
- Did he fall?
- I'll be good, Ma.
- Probably.
- Did he hit his head?
- Maybe.
We need a gurney, a
backboard and a C-collar.
Page Surgery, ENT.
- I'll come in as soon as I'm done.
- All right. Thanks, Mayday.
There be demons on the Hancock.
You can see them from the lake.
Shut up, Paulie.
They don't know.
Couple of Ativan
to calm him down.
- What do you wanna do about the ear?
- Unasyn, 2 grams.
Try 3. Irrigate
the hell out of it.
- Plastics will do a flap in O.R.
- Sats are good.
Pupils equal and reactive.
Pinpoint pupils. She had Narcan?
- Only 0.8.
All right, let's try 2 milligrams.
Sometimes they need more.
No wounds to the
anterior chest or abdomen.
Corneal reflexes are intact.
Chest is clear.
Belly soft, non-tender.
Tachy at 120. DUMAR:
Looks like you got her back.
- Oh, my God.
- Deep breath for me now.
In.
- Out. GATES:
One percent lido...
and update his tetanus.
It's gonna be okay, Paulie.
You're gonna be okay.
The blue lady's here.
Yeah, I was running around
all shift and I never got to it.
I was coming off an overnight,
I figured Gates could handle it.
He didn't and now he
can't. He's in with a trauma.
Well, it's just a paracentesis.
Maybe you could do it.
Look, you're an Attending, you
shouldn't have left this unfinished.
Look, I had
somewhere to be, okay?
What was so important you'd walk
out on a guy who'd been here all night?
Church, all right?
I had to go to church.
Pratt, you're a terrible liar.
Get back here and deal
with this right now, okay?
Hey. Hey. What are you doing?
You chipping in on the
water bill, because I need to...
Hey, Greg.
I thought you were at work.
This your brother?
Yeah.
- Get out of here.
- Greg, listen...
Hey, get the hell out of here.
You too.
By the time I get
back, I want you gone.
Let go. Why you wanna kill me?
- Stop it or she won't come.
- Are we charting this as a John Doe?
- I told you his name's Paulie.
- Paulie what?
Does he have any parents?
His father's locked up
in the tower by the water.
His mom was in the
shelter before she died.
Paulie left so they couldn't
send him to the Foresters.
Foresters?
The fake family that
don't ever love you.
A foster family?
- Where does he live?
- Under.
- Under what?
- How's it here?
Altered after a 10-foot
fall. No ID, history unknown.
C-spine and chest are
clear. Lose the collar, will you?
- Head CT films.
- I don't wanna stay here.
- Look. JARVIK:
Another two of Ativan?
No bleed or fracture.
What about drugs?
Tox screen negative
for alcohol, drugs.
- Fever? JARVIK:
Ninety-eight-point-six.
- I don't get why he's so altered.
- Doesn't seem like meningitis.
- Has he been acting differently?
- Since his arm started hurting.
Even before he fell?
- He only fell last night.
- How did he fall?
We was in the building
where nobody lives.
- Paulie got scared because of the bats.
- Bats?
- It could be rabies. Hope, page Kovac.
- Okay.
All right, put an
N95 mask on him.
If he does have rabies, his
saliva is extremely infectious.
I'll check for fractures.
No step-offs or deformities.
Full range of motion
at the elbow and wrist.
See, Paulie?
Told you she'd come.
Lunchtime starts at noon, so
I'll be there with the crew by 11.
You know, Courtney, this
isn't quite what I signed on for.
I thought I'd be reporting
on topical medical issues...
not doing puff pieces on
Botox and unsanitary manicures.
Hey, that one was strong.
People all over Chicago now think
twice before having their cuticles cut.
See you at noon.
This came for you
special delivery.
Baby gift?
Yeah. Yeah.
Charles Hadley, multiple
wounds after a bar fight.
He passed out on
the couch last night.
- This morning, I couldn't wake him up.
- Look at me, sir.
Pupils equal at 4 millimeters.
- You all right there, ma'am?
- It's nothing.
- We should take a look at it.
- No, no, no, I'm all right.
CBC, chem panel,
blood alcohol...
C-spine, head and facial CT.
Dried blood at the left ear
canal, positive battle sign.
- Have a seat.
- Chest is clear.
Abdomen soft, no
rebound or guarding.
- Did he do this?
- No. No.
He didn't know
what he was doing.
Are you saying your
husband hit you, ma'am?
It was an accident.
I was helping him down
on the couch and he slipped.
His elbow knocked me.
Pelvis is stable.
She's gonna need
a facial series.
Dr. Kovac, we've got a pretty
sick little boy in 2, no parents...
- Just keep trying to reach them.
- We think he's homeless.
Neela and Gates
are worried it's rabies.
You're good. I'll be back.
- Rabies?
- He was in a building infested with bats.
- How was the trauma workup?
- CT's negative, but he's altered, ataxic.
A river runs through the city.
On the other side's the good
streets, but we can't get across.
- How's he doing?
- Responsive but not making much sense.
He's not crazy.
The stuff he's
talking about is real.
- You're thinking rabies?
- What else could it be?
Encephalitis from
any number of viruses.
West Nile, Epstein-Barr,
mumps, measles, varicella, CMV.
- He needs a spinal tap.
- Can we do a rabies vaccine in case?
Well, if you're right, it's too late.
So let's first confirm the diagnosis.
The quickest way is with a
skin biopsy. Keep a mask on him.
If we intubate, you'll all need
masks, gloves and goggles.
- Tony, your buddy Cue Ball's leaving.
- What?
- He still needs an x-ray.
- He said he feels fine.
Will you handle this?
I'll be back in a second.
Are you gonna learn
me the hard song now?
Can you hold his
head for me, Teller?
There, you see, I'm just like a vulture.
I'm the guy that gets you out of here.
Cue Ball, where you going?
Home, man. They fixed me up.
Cue Ball. Hey, I knew your
parents, eight ball and highball.
Your lungs sound like
a bag of potato chips.
Oh, come on, it's nachos.
I was just translating.
- I'm taking you back. You need an x-ray.
- No, no. I been here since last night.
I got places to go,
people to see, baby.
Hey, sit down, Pancho.
- We'll wheel you back to Tijuana.
- I ain't Spanish, man.
He's a new volunteer.
We're still training him.
- Gates.
- Oh, here comes your pimp.
- I'm done with this.
- Cue Ball, get back here. Come on.
- Do one x-ray.
- Hey, hey, hey.
- What?
- Why didn't you tap my patient?
I was in trauma. What
was I supposed to do?
What I told you.
So I'm just supposed to
take all your scut, huh?
- Don't turn your back on me.
- I got stuff to do.
The only thing you have
to do is what I tell you.
You don't wanna do this.
- I don't wanna do what?
- Get in my face.
Then stop acting like you
don't hear me when I talk.
If you wanna have a job this
afternoon, you better stay where you are.
She can't cry.
There's only one dog.
Can you touch your nose for me?
Paulie, can you hear me?
If you can hear me, can
you touch your nose?
How's he doing?
Intention tremor
with worsening ataxia.
Bit my lip.
Skin biopsy came back
positive for rabies by DFA.
- Rabies is 100 percent fatal.
- Ninety-nine-point-nine percent.
There's a little girl in
Wisconsin, 2004. She survived.
- That was one case.
- We're gonna make it two cases.
- What's this?
- New England Journal of Medicine.
You need to order ketamine, midazolam,
ribavirin, amantadine from the pharmacy.
We're gonna induce a coma?
Titrate the midazolam
to suppress brain activity.
Lets the brain rest while
we administer antivirals.
Also, we need to call Neurology,
he'll need continuous EEG monitoring.
- There are no isolation beds in the
PICU. NEELA: He'll have to stay here.
This guy's taking a nose dive.
- I'm coming.
- Did you notify public health?
- They're bringing in CDC.
Okay, good. So
anyone else exposed...
needs rabies prophylaxis
vaccine and immune globulin.
Our party animal's more disoriented.
Head CT shows a basilar skull fracture.
- Intracranial hemorrhage?
- We got lucky there.
GCS is down from 14 to eight.
- Mr. Hadley, open your eyes.
- He's diaphoretic.
Are the labs back yet?
- No, not yet.
We need to repeat the head
CT, see if there's a delayed bleed.
- Sats dropping.
- Hundred percent non-rebreather.
Dr. Kovac, a guy called a couple
times, didn't leave a message.
- Did you get a name, Frank?
- He wouldn't say.
- Why are you telling me this?
- Thought you'd wanna know.
- It's probably a creditor.
- Great. Thank you. Thank you, Frank.
Doing an Accu-Chek?
He's not a diabetic.
No, but if he's a chronic
alcoholic who's not eating...
he might be hypoglycemic.
- There it is. Blood sugar's 34.
- That's pretty low.
Amp of D50 and
100 mgs of thiamine.
- He's a bigger drinker than we thought.
- He wasn't always this bad.
Advanced liver disease
diminishes his glycogen stores.
His body can't respond
to low blood sugar.
What the hell is going on?
Mr. Hadley, do you
know where you are?
Chicago.
You're in the hospital.
When's the last time
you had something to eat?
It's been a couple of days.
I guess I've been
on a bit of a bender.
Cancel the CT?
Yeah.
- Here.
- The hell is that?
Belly tap for my ascites guy.
Send it for a cell count,
culture and cytology.
Whoa. Hope didn't
get that hitting a patient.
Intern.
Why are you even here?
Paracentesis on a pass-on
Gates couldn't handle.
Uh-huh. Welcome
to being an Attending.
Wait, you... You
and Gates didn't...?
You know what, I
don't need to know.
Hey, how's the lip?
Better than your
hand. You hit like a girl.
Yeah, okay.
Look, sorry for blowing
my cool like that.
I was having a terrible
morning, but that's no excuse...
so if you wanna file a grievance
with Human Resources, you can call...
I was there too. It's not the first time I
let something like that get out of hand.
Have you tried getting into a
program to help you stop drinking?
Like I wanna hear
everybody else's problems.
What good is a lot of
talking gonna do me?
Not gonna bring my son back.
He died?
As a DUI.
He got his mother's looks. Heh.
And my alcoholism.
What about what
you're doing to your wife?
I don't know why she
hasn't left me before.
It should be... It
should be me, doc.
It should be me that's
dead and not Kenny.
She came here with an injury.
Did you hit her?
- What?
- Did you hit her?
I would never,
never hurt my wife.
But you did.
If it...
If I did...
It wasn't on... It
wasn't on purpose.
I love her.
Check his glucose in an hour.
Wait a minute, I love her.
I'll be back.
Do you think the concussion and
the low blood sugar contributed to this?
To what?
Well, I think he'd altered
and he hurt her accidentally.
We have to report it.
- If it's nothing, it will get dropped.
- The wife said he never hit her.
- The police will sort it out.
- Hey.
What? What? She's
got a bruised face.
So you wanna put
him in a locked facility?
You heard him, he won't get
any help unless he's forced to.
- It's time someone scared him.
- You might be right about this, but...
Look, let's try this.
You be the Resident, I'll
be the Attending, okay?
Okay.
- Can I help find something, Dr. Pratt?
- What? No.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Are we out of diuretics?
I think there are some
samples over here, but...
Free sample closet.
- Hope, you're a genius.
- Aah! Ha.
I thought...
- Aren't you not working this shift?
- Yeah, that's right.
Oh.
Well, then why are you...?
I'm running a little low on some stuff
for some people I'm helping at church.
Church? I didn't know that
you volunteered at church.
No, this is not gonna be enough.
Do we have anything anywhere else?
- Come on.
- There was a drug rep here earlier.
- Maybe they restocked?
- Drug rep.
She even brought pizza. Very
sweet girl from Dayton, Ohio.
My family's originally from
Akron so we had a lot in common.
I think her name was Dora.
Here you go, buddy.
- I'm not hungry.
- It might make you feel better.
And this soup is the bomb.
I'm serious, they
call it the bomb soup.
You eat this soup, you're
gonna fart like a cannon.
Ketamine's ready to go
at 2 mgs per kilo per hour...
with ribavirin loading
dose of 33 mgs per kilo.
When's Paulie gonna wake up?
I don't know. We're gonna make Paulie
sleep for a while, a couple of weeks.
Hopefully, his body can heal.
Amantadine needs
to be given by mouth.
All right.
Hey, Paulie. Can you hear me?
I need you to take a
little sip of water here.
Rabies are making it hard for
him to swallow. Drop an NG.
That's not why.
It's because Bloody
Mary saw his face.
Put a tube down his throat to help
him breathe. Ten of sux, 20 of etomidate.
Pulse ox is only 82.
GATES: Ambu-bag.
Yankauer suction on high.
Teller.
Teller!
What do you know about the
placement of the hernia mesh?
It must be parallel
to the peritoneal sac.
And?
The mesh covers
the abdominal wall...
reflects on the iliopubic tract and
covers several centimeters of the psoas.
Paulie can't breathe.
You have to come help.
- Who is that?
- You can't be in here, Teller.
You have to come help.
Paulie can't breathe.
Go back downstairs.
I can't come with you.
You have to.
You're the blue lady.
Please. Please,
just help Paulie.
You need to wake him up.
I can't. Paulie's very sick.
I saw you.
That other girl,
she was asleep...
and you woke her up.
You brought her back to life.
That was different.
You can't say no.
You can't.
I know your secret name: Mayday.
And one day...
One day, every day
is gonna be Sunday.
Diuretics, calcium channel
blockers, oral hypoglycemics.
Non-steroidal
anti-inflammatories...
proton-pump inhibitors,
beta-agonist inhalers.
Enough meds for 90
percent of your people.
That's fast work.
- How did you manage it?
- Sold my soul to a drug company.
Well, not exactly my
soul. Give me those.
I'll go lock them
up in the closet.
Greg's told me about
what you're doing here.
I'd love to be a part of it.
It's why I took my break
time to help out Dr. Pratt.
- Uh... Are you a med student?
- Hope Bobek.
I'm an intern.
It's the same thing as a first-year
Resident, but they call us interns.
I don't really know why.
Oh. I love old
churches like this.
- Do you?
- It's so big.
Yes, it is, isn't it?
It's estimated that between
10 and 20 percent...
of the youth in this
country are obese.
A condition which leads to
increased risk of diabetes...
heart disease,
high cholesterol...
- Lucy's choking!
- Somebody help.
Let's go. MAN: Yeah.
Keep filming.
Hey, sweetie? Honey,
can you breathe?
Can you speak? Okay, here we go.
- All right, I need help here. Look out.
- Kerry, what's happening?
Probably has a piece of
food obstructing her trachea.
Hang in there, Lucy. Here we go.
Oh...
Okay, get me a kitchen knife with
a sharp point and a drinking straw.
Now. Go.
Okay, this is gonna
hurt for a second.
Ready? One, two, three.
Ewww.
Oh, man, that's nasty.
She's cutting her throat.
Disgusting.
- He's still sleeping?
- Yes.
He's got peripheral IVs for continuous
sedation and antiviral therapy.
He needs a central line if he'll do
blood products and clotting factors.
Central line's too
risky with a DIC.
- We have to do something.
- What about saphenous cutdown?
Lily, Betadine.
Thanks for getting here so
fast. Thought we'd lose him.
She had to come.
10 blade, curved hemostat.
- He says I'm the blue lady.
- Ah.
When I was a paramedic, we used
to run into homeless kids like this.
- 3-0 silk.
- Survival.
They'd have to make up
a story about their world.
It helps them get through it.
It's not a story.
It's real.
God took a boat across the lake because
he couldn't fight the demons in Chicago.
There were too many of them
and they're always out to hurt you.
Like Bloody Mary?
Demons turn you into
druggies or whores.
One shot my brother
from his black SUV.
- 11 blade.
- What about good spirits?
- Any of those?
- The angels could save you.
They eat the millennium light
and stop the hawk from frostbiting.
So the blue lady can save
you if you're hurt or sick, huh?
She has to.
If you know her secret name.
Triple lumen catheter.
- Teller.
- Look, Ellie.
I told you not to stay.
I told you you'd
get us in trouble.
It's okay.
She's gonna fix Paulie.
Are you leaving?
I've tried to make him get
some help. He won't listen to me.
I've lost a son.
Now it looks like I'll
lose a husband too.
Well, not if you don't want to.
How bad does it have to get
before he realizes there's a problem?
Does he have to doze off with his
cigarette and burn the place down...
- or fall through a glass door?
- Well, alcoholism's a disease.
I mean, maybe the two of us together
can convince him to get some treatment.
I love him. I really do.
And he's a good man.
He just can't seem
to get over this.
I think he's starting to understand
that he needs to make some changes.
Okay.
Hemmerdinger's been D/C'd...
Winston is in Radiology
and Barnaby died.
- Now, listen, about the Hadleys...
- Abby.
Look, they love each
other. They're struggling...
- You're defending abuse?
- Don't think that's what happened.
- The guy's an alcoholic.
- Yeah, well, so am I.
I already reported it.
The cops are on their way.
Lucy Mokeler, criked for
upper-airway obstruction.
What happened?
I was doing a stand-up in a
middle-school lunchroom...
and she started choking.
I know you probably think that I
wanted to move in here because of this.
You told me that you
wanted to be closer to school.
I did.
I thought maybe we could be
brothers like we talked about last year.
Oh. Oh. So you just didn't
need a little bit more privacy...
than living with the
family could get you, huh?
It's not like that.
You lied to me, and
I'm not cool with that.
- I didn't lie.
- I'm not cool with it.
So, what, Greg?
What, if I'd have told you the truth,
then you would've been cool with it?
You think this is easy for me?
It's not like this has been
going on a long time...
it's just something
that happened.
I don't know, man, it's
like a phase or something.
Tsk.
He's bradying down.
- Mg of atropine.
- Where have you been?
- I was helping Dr. Pratt. Sorry.
Lost the pulse,
starting compressions.
I can do that.
- Call Kovac.
- Amp of epi.
It's hard to bag. There's
a lot of resistance.
- What's the rhythm?
- PEA.
Absent breath
sounds on the left.
Could've had a small pneumo that
converted to tension with intubation.
Still no pulse. GATES:
Looks like V-fib. Charge to 360.
The rabies can damage the
conduction system of the heart.
Charged. GATES: Clear.
There's no change.
The virus is too advanced,
GATES: Hundred of lidocaine.
I don't think he's
gonna make it.
- Hundred of lidocaine.
- Paulie.
Teller!
Clear.
- Hey, wait!
- Come on, let's go.
- Stop it.
- Please, let us help you.
You both need medicine so
you don't get sick like Paulie.
I thought you were gonna save him.
- It's not her, Teller.
She's just a doctor. Tell
him you're not the blue lady.
Please, you could have
what Paulie has. Please.
Neela! We need you inside!
- We got him back.
- What?
The rabies kid. He's got a
rhythm, a pulse and a BP.
That's not possible.
Tony put the pulse ox on his
finger. The kid grabbed his hand.
It's like a miracle, come on.
Hey. You're still here.
Well, I wanted to make
sure that she was okay.
And I got permission from her
parents to air what happened.
- Why?
- Are you kidding me?
If a male doctor pulled that off on
TV, he'd have his own syndication deal.
- Yeah, well...
- No, seriously, Kerry.
I mean, that was... That
was pretty incredible.
I'm still buzzing.
How do you come down
from something like that?
A glass of wine and a hot
bath at the end of the day help.
Mm. Sounds good to me.
All right.
Ketamine is at 2
per kilo per hour?
He's got spontaneous
eye opening.
That's a good sign, but we
need to deepen his coma.
Let's double up on the
midazolam drip. I'll check back later.
He's got goose bumps.
I'll go get a warming blanket.
He's putting up a fight.
Still has a long way to go.
Hope's right. It's a
miracle he's alive.
Maybe you are the
blue lady after all.
Well, if I was these kids, I'd
sure as hell wanna believe that.
If you believe in
something hard enough...
What?
Well, I've talked myself into things
that weren't true plenty of times.
What sort of things?
I don't know.
Like stuff about myself,
my job, people in my life.
Everything seems to be
a lot clearer now, though.
I have something to
do. I'll see you tomorrow?
- Yeah, okay.
- Okay.
Hey, you never told me
what your secret name was.
You're the one
that gave it to me.
Mayday?
Teller must have overheard you.
You never told me what it means.
She doesn't wanna press
charges, but the fact is he hit her.
- Can I talk to you for a sec?
- Just a minute.
- I need to get a statement from the wife.
- That's fine.
- I'm going to Ike's to get some dinner.
- Okay. I'll pick you up there.
Listen, before you do that...
there's something else I
need to ask you in private.
You okay, doc?
What is it?
It belongs to my son.
It was sent to me here.
See the initials?
C.A. Curtis Ames. He
was a patient of mine.
I think he's trying
to threaten us.
Maybe he just
wanted to return it.
Look, he followed my
wife and child to the park.
I'd like you to go talk to him.
Help me protect my family.
Okay.
Okay. Well, give him four more
ounces and I'll be back in a half hour.
All right, bye.
Cell phones.
- How did we ever survive without them?
- Sorry.
That was my babysitter.
Aren't you a little old
to need a babysitter?
For my baby.
Oh.
Well, aren't you a little
young to have one of those?
- Can I buy you a beer?
- No, thanks. I never touch the stuff.
So...
- A boy or a girl?
- Boy.
- Six months.
- Hmm.
- Ahh.
- Do you have kids?
- Five.
Yeah. Boy and girl of my own...
and three stepdaughters.
- Do you live in Chicago?
- Texas.
- Texas?
- Yeah.
- You're a long way from home.
What are you doing here?
Uh... Whew.
Well, I came up to see an old
buddy of mine in the hospital.
But I walked into the lobby, I
looked around, chickened out.
Why?
Well, you know, I buried a few
friends over the last couple years...
and hospitals make me queasy.
Yeah. Well, me too.
And I work in one.
You're a nurse, huh?
Mm. I used to be a
nurse, but now I'm a doctor.
- Really?
- Yeah.
- What's so funny?
- Oh, nothing.
Why are you laughing?
Uh... Heh.
It's just...
Well, the only
doctors I ever met...
were white-haired old guys with
glasses and necks like turkeys.
I guess I've got that
to look forward to.
- What do you do in Texas?
- Oil.
Tycoon?
Don't I wish.
No, I work the rigs. Machinist.
Ever seen an oil fire?
Seen one? Hell, I started one.
Can we have our chips please?
- What are you gonna eat in the movie?
- That's why we got the licorice.
- Think fast, horndog. Think fast.
- Oh.
- Good hands.
- Thanks.
- What do you think of this kid?
- Seems okay.
Polite, kind of quiet.
All the common
traits of a serial killer.
- Can't believe she's gonna be dating.
- Yeah.
Listen, Meg, there's been
something on my mind.
- Yeah, me too.
- Really?
Yeah, I've been thinking
about moving forward.
I think Sarah's old
enough to accept it now.
In fact, I think it
would make her happy.
What would?
Us making this permanent.
- We've danced around it long enough.
- No, no, no. That's not what I meant.
Meg, I can't do this anymore.
Us living together, but
not really living together.
Sleeping with each
other when we need to.
It's too easy. It's
like a placeholder.
And I think it's stopping us
from moving on with our lives.
What are you talking
about? This is our lives.
I don't want it to be.
We fell into this, Meg. I care about
you and Sarah, but I have to do my thing.
What's her name?
Come on, Meg.
What? So you wanna screw some
other girl. It won't be the first time.
They never last.
It's more than that.
You think you can keep what
you want and leave the rest?
Be part of our lives, but not commit?
It doesn't work that way, Tony.
I've committed fully for a long
time, Meg, and you know that.
We love you.
And you love us.
I know you don't
wanna blow that.
You know Chicago winters
can be pretty tough on asthma.
- You should get a flu shot.
- Ah. I hate needles.
Just come by the ER, I'll do it
myself. I promise I'll be gentle.
- Hey.
Luka, this is...
- Eddie. ABBY: Eddie.
You the husband?
- We're not married.
- Ah. Gotcha.
- Are you ready to go?
- Yup.
Well, Eddie, it's
nice to meet you.
And remember, flu shot.
Thanks for the advice.
And the company.
- Hey, nice meeting you.
- You too.
- Wanna talk about what's bugging you?
- No.
No, you don't wanna talk about
it or no, nothing's bugging you?
Something was,
but I took care of it.
Nothing to worry about.
Okay.
Dr. Rasgotra?
Sorry, I must have nodded off.
- You've been working a lot, huh?
- It's becoming up to 30 hours now.
- Do you want me to get you something?
- Oh, no.
I'm fine, thanks.
How is he?
He needs to be in a
coma for two weeks...
until increased levels of rabies
antibodies appear in cerebrospinal fluid.
And then we'll wean him off sedation,
see if any neurologic function returns.
I prayed for him
in church today.
I heard that his friends have a
whole story about demons and spirits.
Who are we to judge, right?
Everybody needs
something to believe in.
I will see you
tomorrow, Dr. Rasgotra.
Good night, Hope.