[LINE RINGING]
Come on, come on, come on.
Derek.
I need you.
Oh.
[GIGGLES]
Oh, you just...
You bring something out in me.
[SIGHS]
I like to think it's the best in you.
Or the worst.
[BOTH LAUGH]
[MOANING]
Oh, Archer.
Oh. Archer,
why are you being such a tease?
What are you doing?
[GRUNTING, GROANING]
Archer? Archer.
Archer.
Archer, okay.
You're okay.
[GRUNTS]
Okay, good, good, it's good.
- Plus-two station.
- Good.
Where's Naomi?
She promised she'd come.
We paged her. Hopefully she'll come.
But we promise you, Maggie,
you're in very good hands.
We have everything under control.
But she's my good luck charm.
Where is she?
ARCHER:
Don't give me that look. I'm fine.
You're not fine. You had a seizure.
ARCHER:
Blood pressure's 120 over 80.
Pulse, regular on 70.
Eyes? Equal and responsive.
- You know you need...
- No tests.
I don't even need to be here.
I told you that,
I told the paramedics that.
A healthy person your age does not just
have a tonic-clonic seizure out of the blue.
Actually, that's not true.
I'm the badass brain guy.
Yes, I had a seizure.
While I could lecture you on the fact
the brain is a complex organ,
firing off neurons
and electrical impulses,
which occasionally short-circuit
for totally benign reasons,
- instead, I'm signing myself out.
- But...
Against all medical advice?
Your medical advice,
which makes you my doctor.
So you have
doctor-patient confidentiality.
What? Wait, wait.
You want me to lie to Addison?
Yes.
[EXHALES]
- You know, you need to see someone.
- I'm fine.
No, you're a doctor. You know better.
You need to see Addison or Naomi
about the pregnancy today.
And you sound like crap.
Didn't know you're moving in
to be the pregnancy police.
I am your friend,
and I'm helping you out.
And I have the added benefit
of being a highly trained physician.
So as long as you're preg...
Sheldon.
[CLEARS THROAT]
Cooper, Violet.
- Together again.
- Look, we're not...
Oh, of course not. It was humor.
[CHUCKLES]
It just seems...
Oh, the office, the elevator, your house.
Together.
It's...
- It's nice.
- Yes.
It is nice.
- We're friends.
- Of course.
You called me the other day.
I'm sorry, I should've...
We're all busy.
You'll call me. When you have time.
[ELEVATOR BELL DINGS]
Oh, look, happy couple.
Hey, this has gotta stop.
We have to talk.
When you can explain moving in
with Violet, we will.
If you knew why,
you would see that it's actually right.
If I knew why, which I don't.
So right now, you are nothing but a guy
who moved in with another woman.
Aah!
Why is it taking so long?
Still at plus two, Addison.
- What's that mean?
- Means the labor's not progressing.
And the baby has variable decels.
We're gonna need to perform an assisted
delivery to help guide the baby out.
It's very safe. Dell, would prep
the vacuum extractor, please?
- Vacuum what?
- It's gonna be fine, honey.
- I've never done one of these.
- It's okay, I'll guide you through it.
Okay, place the cup
directly on the vertex.
DELL: Okay.
- Good. Maggie, when I tell you,
I need you to push as hard as you can.
And while you push,
we will take the baby out, okay?
Okay, ready?
And push.
[GRUNTS]
That's great, Maggie.
The baby's crowning.
- Take it out, take it out, take it out.
DELL: Okay.
[BABY CRYING]
It's a girl. It's a baby girl.
ADDISON:
Congratulations.
- The discoloration on her head?
ADDISON: It's a hematoma.
It happens sometimes
with a vacuum delivery.
- Her Apgar is low.
- Dell.
Don't worry.
She's fine. You did great.
Wait, wait, I thought you and Charlotte
were back together.
- We were.
- So, what happened?
Well, l... She's...
- It's complicated.
- Well...
- You know what I like about Sonya?
- She's not complicated?
- She says exactly what she thinks.
- Oh, be careful what you wish for.
Dr. Freedman?
Patty, I thought I was meeting you
at the hospital later.
Mom said we should come here
before surgery.
- Oh, where is she?
- She went to go get money.
And she's not back yet.
I have to go to the bathroom bad.
- It's right down the hall to your left.
- Thanks.
Oh, I forgot.
Mom said I should give you this.
What? What's wrong?
Her parents. Uh...
They dumped her.
They're not coming back.
- Hey, you're here.
- Oh, yeah.
I paged you, Jake and Maggie Klein
were asking for you.
They had their baby, Beth.
- That's wonderful, wonderful.
- You okay?
Yeah, I just...
I had a rough morning.
Look, if my brother's causing you trouble,
just dump him.
Come on,
that was supposed to be funny.
Yeah, l... You know what?
Can you excuse me a minute?
I hate lies.
- Something is wrong.
- I'm fine.
Close the door, I'll show you
how fine I am.
That's not funny.
If you were fine, you would've let
the doctor examine you today.
You would've let them run tests.
So, what is it? Is it an aneurysm?
- Or a stroke? Or AVM?
- Who's the neurologist here?
Well, you won't tell me what's going on,
and I'm thinking the worst here, Archer.
You don't know how scary it was for me
this morning.
- I'm sorry.
- Sorry is not gonna make me feel better.
Sorry is not gonna make me not worry.
You need to tell me what's wrong.
I can help you. Come on, we can...
We can figure it out.
[SIGHS]
It's a tumor.
A glioma
in the third ventricle of my brain.
- Can...?
- It's inoperable.
There's nothing they can do.
Hey.
There's something
I want to tell Addison.
- But I can't.
- You can't?
I was asked specifically by someone
not to tell.
You were asked
specifically by someone
not to tell Addison something specific?
Okay, up to a week ago,
I would've said Pete, maybe Coop.
But this definitely reeks of Archer.
It involves
doctor-patient confidentiality.
Which would apply if you were
Archer's doctor. You're not.
Unless he's trying to get pregnant.
I'm sorry,
you're not giving me much to go on here.
It's something medical.
Okay.
So, uh...
Do you keep a secret
for a man that you care about?
Or do you lie to your best friend?
- How's she doing?
- She isn't responding to the pacifier.
And she's barely cried.
And the bruise, it looks worse.
Well, her color's good. She's active.
Let's see those feet.
[BABY CRIES]
- She responds to stimulation.
- Maybe you should order a CT
or an MRI, just to be sure.
Dell, this is all within the range of normal
after an assisted delivery.
Yeah, but if there's a chance something's
wrong, l... Something you could...
- I just... I want her to be okay.
- I know you do.
And so do I, but this baby isn't sick.
[CHUCKLES]
[DOOR OPENS]
Patty's parents
aren't answering their phone.
And there's no contact information
for their work or their cells.
- How'd she hurt her knee?
- Car accident. She was 5, hit-and-run.
Internal injuries, which, you know,
she got over. Walking has been hard.
Had to wait for the bone to grow more
before we could reconstruct the knee.
And her parents just walked out
the day of the surgery?
Patty's out there
reading to her teddy bear.
I haven't told her yet.
Told her her parents were still at the bank,
things taking longer than they should.
Cooper, she knows something's wrong.
You know that.
Kids know when something's wrong.
You have to report this.
- Her parents are good people.
- They abandoned a sick child.
Child and Family Services
needs to be involved.
Yeah, and the police. Safe Haven program
is for babies. This is abandonment.
Her parents
are having financial problems.
They're just freaked out
by the surgery.
Just give me a few hours, I'll find them.
Surgery's elective.
If we turn her over to Family Services,
they won't pay for it.
And she needs the surgery.
- She needs her parents.
- Not all parents should be parents.
So if you want to, go look for them.
But let me talk to her first.
Let's make sure this family
is worth being put back together.
Okay.
So Dr. Cooper,
is he like your best friend?
Uh-huh.
What about you?
Do you have a best friend?
Uh-huh. Felix.
And does Felix live at home with you
and your family?
Uh-huh.
What does a family look like?
Can you show me with the dolls?
Well, there's a mommy.
And a daddy.
- And me and Felix.
- Okay.
So I'm gonna start a sentence
and I want you to finish it, okay?
So I'll say:
"I like it when my mommy..."
And then you say...
- Hugs me.
- Great.
And "I don't like it when my mommy..."
Gets sad.
And what about the daddy?
- What does the daddy do?
- A daddy comes home at night.
And what does he do
when he comes home at night?
He crawls into bed with me.
And what does he do
when he crawls into bed with you?
Sometimes he reads me a story.
But most of the time he just snores.
I need to tell you something.
Something good or something bad?
- Something bad.
- Archer asked me not to tell you, but...
- What did he do to you?
- Last night Archer had a seizure.
And it's not the first seizure he's had,
Addison.
It's cancer.
A glioma.
It's inoperable.
He says he saw everyone in New York:
CT scans,
second opinions, third opinions.
And he says that there is nothing to do.
- Where is he now?
- He's downstairs.
He says he doesn't wanna talk about it.
Right. Well, we'll get
his scans from New York.
We'll figure out exactly what it is
and how we fight it.
- Addison, you can't just start...
- Don't tell me what I can't do.
I'm his sister, I'm a doctor, and there's
always something that we can do.
[SIGHS]
- So?
- Well, everything she demonstrated,
concept of the family structure,
parent-child roles,
suggests the family life is healthy.
So if I can find them?
Go find them.
Hey, could I borrow you
for a few minutes?
It's kind of important.
[TYPING]
Addison, I am so sorry.
- I saw him yesterday, he was fine.
- Don't talk about him like he's dead.
- Have you talked to him?
- I'm trying to get his scans.
- I need ammunition.
- Addison...
If you give me some stages-of-grief crap,
I'm will throw something.
Okay, look, I don't need
the Super Friends here, okay?
I don't need moral support.
I'm fine, he's not, and I'm gonna fix it.
Well, Nai says he's taking it well.
You know what he's doing, Sam?
He's creating drama, like he always does.
- Secrets.
- I know he doesn't want help,
but he's gotta be scared.
I know I would be.
I mean, look at all of us.
None of us wants to think that...
- Yeah.
- Got it.
What, his scans?
They released them to you?
With 15 phone calls
to every hospital in New York,
ten calls to every neurologist,
and one very effective email
to the doctor who wrote the preface
to Archer's last book.
[EXHALES]
Addison.
You wanted a consult on...?
You convened a panel?
The doctor says it's operable.
One thought so.
Three doctors said no. They'd have
to tear through half my brain to get this.
- Chemo?
- Radiation?
Chemo's not effective
with this kind of lesion.
And radiation would fry all brain tissue
before it made a dent.
- I'd lose my sense of humor.
- You can't just give up.
I'm not giving up. At the rate
this is growing, I could have five years.
Five great years.
And I get to keep all my hair.
- I'll adjust my medication.
- What if it's not slow-growing?
What if, instead,
it's a couple of months?
- Or worse?
- When was your last CT scan?
You know her, she's not gonna give up
on this.
ARCHER:
These were my last.
They were taken, uh...
...three weeks ago.
Followed a set two months ago,
another set before that.
Wait, read that date again.
This time don't tilt your head.
What?
Yeah. He has an upward gaze palsy.
Sam's right. You can't look up.
But that's not consistent
with third ventricle glioma, is it?
Well, what else could it be?
We need to do another CT scan.
We need to do it now.
Laurie?
George?
[WHISPERS]
Hey.
Ahh. She's beautiful, isn't she?
Very.
How are you feeling?
Beat up. But happy.
Jake went home to take a shower.
Thanks for taking care of her
so I could get some sleep.
Has she...? Has she nursed yet?
No.
Is there something wrong, Dell?
No. Everything's fine.
Hey, here you go.
Here.
[BABY GURGLES]
- You should have told me.
- Addy.
No, what? You move to L.A. Because
you wanna be closer to me. It's a lie.
You lied.
You knew you were sick. You knew
and you didn't tell me.
What were you thinking?
- I wanted to make up for lost time.
- What, by lying to me?
When I can help you?
And then you tell Naomi.
- She saw the seizure. Didn't have a choice.
- Oh, please.
Whatever's going on, there's something
in my brain that can't come out.
And now that you know
everything's about me dying,
you got that look in your eye,
that underlying pity.
- It's not pity.
- It is. I didn't wanna come here
- and look at you every day and see that.
- You are my brother.
You're the only family I have.
The only sane family...
MAN [OVER INTERCOM]:
We're ready.
[SIGHS]
This is really gonna make
your knee feel better, okay?
It's okay. You don't have to be scared.
It doesn't hurt that much.
He is really brave.
- What's his name again?
- Felix.
Well, you know what, Felix?
We are...
...done.
So if your parents had trouble at the bank,
who do you think they'd call?
- I don't know.
- Well, do your mom and dad
have a good friend they talk to a lot, or...
My mom talks to Aunt Katie.
Is that your mom's sister?
- Do you know where she lives?
- Near Disneyland.
Mm-hm.
Did something happen to them?
- Did they get into an accident?
- No.
- Are they dead?
- No, no. God, no.
Your parents...
I think they're going through a tough time.
And they need to figure some things out.
You're lying.
It's almost twice the size.
Wait, there are two more lesions
on the cortex.
- A tumor wouldn't expand that quickly.
- No, it wouldn't. Is it metastatic?
Not in this position.
- Multifocal abscess?
ARCHER: No.
No fever. No source.
Then what?
Well, maybe it...
Zihuatanejo.
- What?
- Zihuatanejo.
I was there six months ago
for a book junket.
- What are you talking about?
- It's not tumors.
Neurocysticercosis.
- Parasites?
- Yes.
Parasites. I have parasites in my brain.
Forgot what it was like.
On this side of things.
Just being out here in the waiting room.
Oh.
- Hey.
- Blood-gas test confirms it.
- The mass is a parasitic cyst.
- Oh, my God.
- I'll call Derek, he can take them out.
- It may not be a tumor,
but it's still in my third ventricle.
Doesn't change that.
No, you thought you had five years. These
lesions are worm sacks in your brain.
Could burst at any moment
and you could die.
Or I could take anti-parasitics
and steroids to kill them.
They might. They could also send
your immune system into overdrive.
You end up with brain swelling,
more seizures.
Which would rupture
the remaining cysts.
Do you realize how lucky you were
last night that that didn't happen?
On the other hand,
drugs could cure me.
All due respect to your ex-husband,
even in Derek's hands, there's
a one-in-four chance I'm a vegetable.
Or I could die on the table,
or I could die from complications...
- Archer.
- Look, you're a surgeon.
It's your instinct to cut. Not mine.
- He has a right to make his own decision.
- Oh, come on, Nai.
What, you've been sleeping with him for
a few weeks, and now you're on his side?
It's his field. And it's his life.
Sam?
- It's risky, but...
- Drugs can work.
I'm sorry, Addison, Derek may be
your answer, but he's not mine.
This isn't your choice.
Hey, I delivered a baby today.
And I think I did something wrong.
And you wanna tell me about it.
Yeah, I'll just...
I placed the vacuum too low, I think.
I used too much force
and she's got this, like, red mark.
And I'm afraid it might be
bleeding in the brain.
- What does Addison say?
- That she's fine.
But she won't do a CT scan
and she won't check.
And now she's not even here.
You asked her for a diagnosis, she gave it.
She's gotta focus on her brother.
Who's getting every test under the sun.
Which is great, it's great.
But, you know, why can't the baby
that I delivered get just one?
You know what I think?
I think that you want her to run a test
to treat your anxiety and not the baby.
[SIGHS]
If Addison say's the baby is healthy,
then accept it.
Whatever you did worked.
[SIGHS]
You okay?
Yeah, no, it's...
Can I trust you with something?
I can't believe it.
You. Pregnant.
- I don't want anyone to know.
- What about the father? Does he know?
- It's complicated.
- You don't owe me any explanations.
It could be Pete or it could be Sheldon.
Keeping it local. That's cool.
Okay. Hey, look at that.
- I don't see anything.
- That's the heart.
- Is it beating?
- Strong.
Good cardiac activity.
Rate of 150. Everything looks good.
The cramping's probably
just from your uterus expanding.
It's nothing to worry about.
- Oh, my God.
- Ahh.
I'm actually pregnant.
That's a... That's a baby.
That's my baby.
That is a tiny human being.
Violet, your pulse is racing.
I need you to breathe, Violet.
- I'm... I'm pregnant. I'm...
- Okay, okay, okay.
Violet, you're having a panic attack.
Here. Concentrate on my breathing.
Okay. Slow and easy.
Deep breaths.
In and out.
[BREATHING DEEPLY]
- How did you find us?
- Patty told me about your sister.
It wasn't that hard to find the address.
You shouldn't have come here.
[DOOR CLOSES]
[SIGHS]
That's it? You see me standing here.
You got nothing to say?
I'm... I'm sorry.
You're her parents.
Maybe you lost your house,
and maybe things are bad.
And... And there are probably things,
I don't know, things that make your life
excruciatingly hard.
But Patty loves you.
And this surgery, she needs it.
- She needs you.
- We can't.
- You're good people.
- We're not.
I've known you
since your daughter was 6 hours old.
- Through the accident. Through rehab.
- All of that ruined us.
The bills, they never end. Day after day.
We don't have the money.
Our insurance is gone.
- I can talk to the hospital.
- It's too much, Cooper.
She's too much for us.
We can't do it anymore.
I know what you must think of us.
But we're done.
That's it, you're done?
That little girl is smart and strong.
And she survived a car accident,
and all the surgeries, and all the pain.
And for a kid like that, I would walk
over broken glass to help her.
You are done.
You don't deserve her.
[DOOR OPENS THEN SLAMS]
Looks like you're good at your job.
I'm not a doctor. But yes, I know
a thing or two about pregnant women.
- My cramps...?
- Aren't about the baby?
What are you talking about?
I have an alien being
growing inside of me.
That's not the only thing inside you.
I mean, keeping this a secret,
not telling Pete or Sheldon,
the guilt, the anxiety,
it grows. You know, it'll swallow you up.
- Dell...
- It's not good for you.
Or the baby. Okay?
You need to tell them.
I can't.
Not now.
Don't forget these.
[SIGHS]
When I was 7, I fell off my bike.
You remember?
We were in the vineyard.
And I just fell off.
We were going downhill
and my tire came loose
and I went over the handlebars.
And I scraped my whole face.
- Remember?
- Hmm.
We were about a half-mile from home
and you...
You picked me up,
you told me it was gonna be okay
and you carried me home.
You weren't even that big.
But you were my big brother.
And you knew I was scared.
And you carried me home.
Mm-hm.
Who's gonna carry me home if you die?
[CRYING]
I fix things, Archie. It's what I do.
I wanna fix this for you.
Some things you can't fix.
[ELEVATOR BELL DINGS]
Hey, Patty.
They're not coming, are they?
Oh.
I'm sorry.
I know it's not what you wanna hear.
It's not what I wanna be telling you.
But it doesn't mean
that they don't love you.
It just means that, right now,
they can't be here.
Okay.
I need a favor, Charlotte.
I need three more nurses, six more hours
in a day, mandatory martinis at lunch,
and to know why the man I was sleeping
with is living with another woman.
I have a little girl who's scheduled
to have surgery at St. Ambrose today.
- I need it to happen.
- The problem is?
Her parents signed all the pre-op forms
and all's good to go,
they then abandoned her.
That is what DCFS is for.
You call, they take the kid.
And then she never gets the surgery.
She was in an accident at 5.
She limps. She has back problems,
crushed her knee,
needs to be reconstructed.
Considered elective surgery,
DCFS won't pay it.
The parents are required
to sign their children in. Period.
- Risk Management requires it.
- And if we just assume that they did?
You waltz in here and expect me
to violate hospital ethics.
To essentially commit fraud. For you.
Who won't even break
Violet's confidence for me.
You're mad at me. I probably deserve it.
But there is a girl who's been sitting
alone in my office for 8 hours,
waiting for a surgery to change her life.
A surgery that she doesn't get
unless we skip a step in the process
and just let things progress
the way they're supposed to.
Please.
Okay, don't help me. Help her.
It's all right, Violet.
Just say it.
- Whatever it is, just...
- Right. Good.
Just say it.
[EXHALES]
I'm pregnant.
I know. It's crazy.
It's wrong. It's awful.
But I wanna be clear
that I have no expectations here.
I know neither of you want kids,
so you don't have to worry.
I actually don't know whose it is,
which is crazy, I know.
But whichever it turns out to be,
it is not your responsibility. It's mine.
And there's nothing that you need to do.
Cooper's moved in with me.
He's looking after me.
It'll all be taken care of.
So now you know.
Okay?
This is how you wanna handle this?
You think that this is how either of us
wants to handle this?
SHELDON:
Divide and conquer.
Isn't that right, Violet?
You don't want a conversation
about this.
You've decided what we want
and how we feel
and how we'll react and what we'll say.
So you just drop this bomb
in front of both of us.
- I didn't wanna say anything until...
- You decided on your own
without consulting anyone.
Anyone who... Who might...
So I take it that you're gonna keep it?
Yes.
I'm gonna keep it.
And now I'm gonna be sick.
ADDISON:
Oh, you are gonna love me.
A 1945 Bor...
[ARCHER GRUNTING, GROANING]
Archer? Archer.
Sam!
- Sam!
SAM: Yeah. Yeah.
Okay. Okay. Shh. Shh.
Call 911.
Okay, that's it, Archer. You're okay.
You're okay. You're okay. You're okay.
[MONITOR BEEPING STEADILY]
The paralyzing agent
has calmed his body,
- but the seizures aren't stopping.
- They'll stop.
Neurologist says they may not.
He's not your brother, but he's good.
He knows what he's doing.
How long before the seizures
cause permanent neurological damage?
There's no way to know,
but given the intensity and duration,
- I don't think we have a lot of time.
- Time for what?
He wants to use a general.
Induce coma.
Put Archer's brain to sleep.
It'll stop the seizure cycle.
He may not come out of that.
He's not coming out of status either.
The longer we let these seizures go on,
the bigger the chance
that everything
that makes Archer Archer
gets burned away.
I'll do it.
This is gonna help you, Archie.
It'll help you rest.
There we go.
[EXHALES]
He needs the surgery
to remove the parasite.
Addison, Archer doesn't want it.
- He was clear about that.
- That was before.
He went into status
because the parasitic sack shifted.
- Maybe. We don't know that.
- We don't have time to try the drugs.
- The drugs are too risky.
- If we started the drugs immediately...
Not fast enough. It'd take a week, maybe.
Ten days, even. That's what they said.
Addison, I am scared as you are
of losing him.
- But we have to respect his wishes.
- I'm tired of respecting him.
I want to save him.
- I wanna call Derek.
- Addison.
Archer said no.
- And if you go down that road...
- I will not accept
that we are supposed
to just stand by and watch him die.
It's my choice. I'm making it.
Make the call.
Come on, come on, come on.
Derek.
I need you.
[DOOR BLINDS RATTLE]
[SIGHS]
I know all about the five stages of grief.
I'm trying to figure out
the five stages of shock.
- I'm pissed.
- Yeah. Kind of. I don't know.
You don't know?
You don't know how you feel?
- Do you?
- Like I said, I'm pissed.
She kept it from
us.
But how do you feel about...?
She's gonna have a kid. Yours or mine?
Is it true? That you don't want kids?
I'm sorry. I had no right to ask.
I just...
I'm reeling.
Kids just don't seem to like me.
I wish they did. I've always liked them.
They just don't like me.
And maybe,
if it were mine...
I wanted kids a lot, a long time ago.
But I told myself it was better
that I didn't have them.
But it's not
better.
[SIGHS]
[BABY CRYING]
- She just woke up screaming.
- We can't calm her down.
What's wrong? Did we do something?
I think
she's hungry.
- Look at her.
- She's perfect.
She is.
- Hey.
- Am I better?
The surgery went well.
Went really, really well.
My knee won't hurt?
I predict that you will be dancing.
And anything else you want.
- Okay?
VIOLET: Hi.
Patty, I wanted to introduce
someone to you.
She's gonna make sure
that you're taken care of.
This is... This is Michelle.
And she's a friend of ours.
She's really nice.
And she's from a place
called Child and Family Services.
Patty, they take care of kids
when their moms and dads can't.
But what about you?
And Violet? Can't you...?
I'm sorry, Patty. I wish we could.
MICHELLE:
Hi, Patty.
I heard a lot about you.
I hear you're doing really well.
- I just wanna go home.
- I know.
Patty,
Michelle's gonna keep you safe.
She's gonna help you get through this.
You and Felix are gonna watch out
for one another.
I'll still be your doctor.
Thank you.
[SPEAKS INDISTINCTLY]
Thanks.
- Patty's...
- I heard.
Called Social Services
soon as she went under, and the police.
And Violet.
Charlotte.
It's been a terrible day, Charlotte.
I looked that girl's parents in the eye
and they do not care.
The surgery's good,
the surgery's gonna help.
But at the end of the day, that girl
doesn't have parents anymore.
And the only thing I can think
of that might make me feel any better
is being with you.
I know being with you
would make me feel better.
Violet's pregnant. That's the secret.
That's why I'm moving in with her,
because she's freaking out.
Are you...?
- Is it your...?
- No.
I'm not the father. I'm the best friend.
Violet has always been there for me.
She shouldn't have to do it alone.
What about me?
- I love you.
- What about me when I have our baby?
Your first child
was supposed to be with me.
Those moments
were supposed to be ours.
Enjoy your first child, Cooper.
They say there's nothing like it.
[SIGHS]
So you're gonna keep the baby?
- Yeah.
- Ha.
You know what?
I think I might be a pretty good midwife.
Yeah.
I think you are.
Okay, the medevac's gonna meet us
at Santa Monica Airport.
We'll be in Seattle
in less than three hours.
And in the OR 45 minutes later.
You're gonna be okay. You are.
You better get better.
Nai. Come with me.
He'd want you there.
I need you there.
Go. I got Maya. Go.
[SIREN WAILING]