Discharged the rule-out MI.
Last enzymes were normal.
And, uh, admitted the
pneumonia to Medicine.
Sounds good. Morning, ladies.
I understand we have a double
trauma coming in. Need help?
Just two minors,
Robert. We can handle it.
Well, while I'm
flipping burgers,
might as well flip
these too. Excuse me?
Ray Kroc. Started McDonald's.
Once a year he'd make
shakes, fry the fries, you know,
get back in the trenches
with the little people.
Ah, so today you're
working in the trenches.
With us, the little people.
Wanna make sure
the ship is shipshape.
Son of a bitch! You
started it! You started it!
The hell I did, boy!
Hey, cut it out!
Whoa, let's break this up!
That's enough. WEAVER: Hey, hey.
Get away from him.
That's enough. Hey!
Get your hands off
me, dumb-ass punk!
Dumb-ass punk. WEAVER:
Malucci, get out here.
What's open? Curtain 2!
I'll sue your ass!
Kiss my ass! You ran into me!
You cut me off!
You're crazy! Enough!
Settle down, bud.
Who you callin' "bud"?
Hey, that's enough!
Get off me, man.
You, actually, bud.
What happened here?
Road rage led to an MVA.
Which led to a fistfight.
Terry Waters, 46,
multiple abrasions,
bad lac to left arm. BP, 120/80.
Janes, 25. Multiple abrasions,
head lac. BP, 110/70.
Get soft restraints.
I didn't start it.
Tried to sideswipe me.
Settle down!
We need to treat you.
Thanks for
rear-ending me, moron.
That's it! Hey!
Call Security! Hold it!
You're the moron!
You son of a bitch!
Oh, my God!
Get him.
Down on the bed, Mr. Waters!
Oh, man! This is nasty!
Do something!
Hey, just settle
down. Settle down.
Is this what you mean
by "flipping burgers"?
Very funny.
Seems to be under control.
If you don't need any
of the little people...
Thank you, Kerry,
I'm sure I can handle it.
Shall I just, you
know, yank it out?
No, no. We gotta check for
damage to the facial nerve,
not to mention damage to my pen.
Worrying about your pen?
Oh, shut up.
Put it back on, Dad.
I don't need it.
It makes me want to sneeze.
And I don't need
you waiting around.
I don't wanna worry
about you taking it off.
You better get used to it
because I've made up my mind.
I'm not going to be doing
my dying in your cramped,
thin-walled,
second floor walkup.
Maybe we oughta
think about moving.
Stop, Mark, you
know what I mean.
Even if I stay in Chicago, I
want to get my own place.
How's that gonna work?
Well, I'll...
get somebody
to help if I need it.
No. You'll just ignore it,
like you have the last year.
I know you. No, you don't!
Y-you might know this disease,
but you don't know what I want.
I don't wanna have
this conversa...
Then don't.
Chest x-ray's clear.
Labs are normal.
Hematocrit of 32.
What's my potassium?
4.2. It's fine.
I figured it would be.
I just had that
dialysis yesterday.
So, what is it? A
man or a woman?
I believe it's a man.
What happened to him?
I don't know.
Must have been
an accident, right?
Isn't that usually the deal?
Yep. I think it was.
In Minneapolis.
They'll fly the
kidney in from there?
Yeah.
Our surgeon, Dr. Corday,
he's gone to procure the organ.
Yeah, they put it in a
cooler. That whole thing.
Man, I didn't ever think
I would make it to
the top of the list.
Yeah, you are lucky.
If I was lucky, I
wouldn't need the kidney.
But seeing as you do...
Yeah, yeah. I'm hungry.
I'm afraid you can't
eat or drink anything.
I've cleared you
for the surgery.
We just have to wait
till the kidney gets here.
I'm not going anywhere.
The kid was the
one that started it.
Then he rammed into my damn car!
I know, Dad, you
said that already.
Ah, damn it!
Mr. Waters, it's all right.
No, it's not all right.
I hate being clumsy.
It's no big deal.
Let's just finish
your sutures, huh?
No, you... You
need to hold still.
I think I know that. Okay?
Dad?
I'm sorry. It's just
been a crappy day.
Listen, can I get...?
Get some more water?
Yeah, sure. I'll go.
I'm, uh, just gonna
hit the ladies' room.
I'll be right back, okay?
What's going
on? Is he all right?
Well, I think he's a little
upset by what's happened.
I've never seen
him like this before.
Running into some car.
And h-he stabbed
somebody with a pen?
Has he always had
a temper? No. Never.
But this week, since
I've been visiting,
he just seems off.
He loses his balance
sometimes, lashes out at people.
Has he ever had seizures
or bad headaches?
Not that I know of. Is
something wrong with him?
Well, I wanna run some
tests and get a head CT.
Then we'll know more.
Um... Oh, ladies'
room is down there.
Thanks.
He's taking codeine
for his back pain.
Now he has increasing
abdominal pain.
Positive surgical
history for an appy.
I'm concerned about
a bowel obstruction.
Has my kidney gotten here yet?
I don't know. I'm Sorry.
Well, I'm still hungry.
I could've eaten.
Good bowel sounds. Any fever?
No.
Vomiting?
Nope.
No guarding or rebound.
Did you get an abdominal series?
Yeah, it just came back.
Excuse us one minute, please.
Mm.
Okay.
Well, no obstruction,
just a lot of stool.
So he's constipated
from the codeine?
Mm-hm.
I'd have him cut
back on his pain meds
and give him a laxative.
Also, have the pharmacy
give him bisacodyl,
10 megs a day.
Sorry. I thought it was serious.
Well, to him it is.
She's had trouble breathing.
Any fever?
Up to 102. Lots of secretions.
I suctioned her,
but she got worse.
She was diagnosed
with Sanfilippo Syndrome
when she was 2.
She has a seizure
disorder, G-tube, PICC line.
She's on O-2 at home
and BiPAP at night.
Can Angie talk?
No, she's severely retarded.
She recently lost her hearing.
She can't even feed herself.
What medications is she on?
Oh, Lasix, albuterol,
Robinul, Valium.
Phenobarb, cisapride, Bactrim.
Okay, she has rales bilateraly.
It's probably pneumonia.
She was in about a month
ago with pseudomonas.
Temp's 102.
Culture her PICC line?
Yeah, order a portable
chest, CBC, lytes,
sputum and peripheral cultures.
The doctors usually give
her Ceftaz and mucomist
when she has pneumonia.
We'll do the same.
I'm gonna run back home and
get her some dolls and things.
I-I think it makes
her feel better.
Don't worry, we'll
take good care of her.
Oh, um, is it possible
to get a TV and a VCR?
She loves to watch the Muppets.
Sure. We'll bring one in.
Thank you.
What do we got?
Eddie Bernero,
12. Two days of flu.
His dad found him
barely responsive.
Where's Dad?
Coming in his own car.
BP 90 palp, pulse 120, resps 28.
Not much response.
Could be encephalitis
or meningitis.
He's been in before.
Then pull the old chart.
Dr. Finch, the
nurse signed us out.
You said I need medicine.
Right. Go ahead, I'll be there.
Help them transfer that boy?
Sure.
Is the Grunwald prescription
back from the pharmacy?
Yeah, right here.
Once a day till the
constipation resolves.
All yours. Thanks.
Okay, let's get a CBC,
lytes and dip a urine.
He's tachy at 150.
Pressure's dropping, 70 palp.
He could be septic,
going into shock.
Mucous membranes
are as dry as a bone.
He's severely dehydrated.
Urine's positive for
glucose, no ketones.
Where's the old chart?
Does this kid have
type two diabetes?
It says he was in here five
months ago for gastroenteritis.
Do you have a blood
glucose? Almost.
Okay, let's bolus him with
normal saline, 10 cc's per kg.
Blood glucose is over 400.
What? Are you sure?
I checked it twice.
He's in a a hyperosmolar coma.
Start another IV,
regular insulin,
.1 unit per kilo per hour.
Let's get the bicarb
and potassium levels.
This kid's been
sick for a while.
What was his blood glucose
on his last admission?
They didn't do one.
You're kidding.
Did they dip a urine?
Nope. Doesn't look like it.
Who the hell took
care of this kid?
Carter.
Page him. Get him up here now.
Bloody flight took forever.
Unfortunately we have some time.
Had to ruled out
the first recipient.
What? I thought you cleared him.
I did but he developed
unstable angina.
He's not a surgical candidate.
Did you talk to UNOS? Yes.
They have another
Chicago person on the list.
She's on her way.
Okay, well let's
hope she gets here
while the kidney's
still viable. Yep.
Any family?
Dad's on his way. I'll send him.
Recheck his potassium and
bicarb levels in two hours.
Cleo, what's up?
Eddie Bernero, on his
way to the PICU, that's what.
Let me refresh your memory.
He was your patient
five months ago.
Sorry, I don't remember him.
Yeah, neither did I. It
took me a few minutes.
You called me in on the case.
Couch-potato kid,
type two diabetes.
Father was having
insurance problems.
So I guess you
doctored the chart?
What are you talking about?
He could've died of cerebral
edema or an infarction
'cause I rehydrated him
without knowing he had diabetes.
Hey, let me take
a look at the chart.
His electrolytes were so out
of whack, he could've died.
What the hell were you thinking?
Carter, your headache
patient's having a seizure.
Okay. If anybody asks questions,
don't expect me to lie for you.
Hey, Carter, nice hair.
Can you get me
Eddie Bernero's chart?
We sent it up to PICU.
I know. I said, just get it.
Henry is so excited.
Wouldn't you know
this would be the day
that he had to go to St. Louis.
He's on his way back? Oh, yeah.
I think he could fly
under his own power.
Oh, I did hemodialysis
for four years,
three times a week.
But three years ago
I switched to CAPD.
How often are the infusions?
Uh, four times a day.
Henry says it's like getting
my oil changed. A lot.
Yeah, but it gives
you more freedom.
Oh, yeah.
It is so great not to have
to go into that hospital
every other day.
And with the transplant,
I'll be able to...
Have you had any peritonitis?
Uh, a few times.
But not for at least six months.
Okay. Everything looks
good, Mrs. Bassett.
We'll wait for your labs
and then get you to the O.R.
Thank you so much.
Well, I haven't had
that much to do with it,
but you're welcome.
Mrs. Dwyer.
Angie, I'm back.
You're gonna be okay, sweetie.
Nurse Hathaway explain to you?
Yes. You have
to start another IV.
Yes, we've been trying,
but Angie is a very tough stick.
I know. She has a lot of
scarring from previous IVs.
That's why we thought
a central line's better.
It's really the best way to
give her fluids and antibiotics.
Yes, I understand.
Great, so could you just
sign this consent form?
Oh, I... I can't do that.
Oh, Mrs. Dwyer, it's
a very safe procedure.
I'm not Angie's real mom.
I'm her foster mom.
She's been in our care
for almost four years.
We wanted to adopt,
but we couldn't
afford the medical.
And her birth parents?
Well, they abandoned her.
She has a legal guardian
through, uh, DCFS.
Okay, Carol, see if you can
track down Adele Neuman.
Isn't there anything
else you can do?
We will keep trying
for another IV, all right?
Okay, Sweetie, here we go.
Mr. Bernero?
Dr. Carter, right?
How's he doing, Kit?
Much better.
Blood glucose is down to 380.
How are his lytes?
Potassium's normalizing.
He'll be here a couple of days,
but I think he's
out of the woods.
Do you have a minute?
Of course.
What happened, Mr. Bernero?
Well, uh, Eddie's
gettin' more exercise,
and, uh, we're workin'
on the diet issues.
What happened, Mr. Bernero?
You understood I
had insurance problem.
You understood that your son
had a very serious condition.
Yeah, I cut you some slack.
But you agreed
to monitor his food,
his exercise and his medication.
You know how kids are.
Yeah. Which is why
they have parents
to be responsible for them.
The insurance thing's
worked out now.
Eddie's covered.
At what expense? His life?
You know, he almost
died this morning.
You never led me to
believe it could get this bad.
Eddie's been doing just fine,
and then suddenly
this morning...
Oh, great.
Great, so you've got
no culpability here at all?
Is that right, Mr. Benero?
You're his doctor.
You said he'd be
fine for a few months.
I remember, that's
what you said.
Now, if you didn't
know this could happen,
how am I supposed to?
No, this is not an emergency,
but the child is
gonna need IV access.
Yes, we are aware of how
often she's been hospitalized,
but that has nothing
to do with this.
Her veins are sclerosed.
I can't get a thing.
Neither can I. This
is ridiculous. Here.
Give me the phone. Come on.
Steven Galbraith.
Hey, Mr. Galbraith, hi.
This is Kerry Weaver, and I'm
chief of emergency medicine.
Angie's PICC line is infected...
You should know
what a PICC line is.
You're her guardian.
Yes, I-I know that she
has an incurable disease.
But she's treatable
at this time...
No, it's not a matter
of life or death yet,
but it could be...
Mr. Galbraith, have
you ever seen Angie?
Have you seen her?
Because I'm looking
at her right now.
And I am see an eminently
treatable girl who would...
Well, thank you.
Thank you for nothing.
He said no.
She should be given pain meds
and made as
comfortable as possible.
There it is.
A heartbeat.
You're definitely pregnant.
I think you're about...
eight weeks along.
I wish Henry would get here.
Have you been
trying to get pregnant?
For almost two years.
With no luck. Until now.
This takes me out of
the running, doesn't it?
After the transplant,
you need to take
immunosuppressive drugs.
And they are
very, very powerful.
And it's likely they
would cause birth defects
or a miscarriage.
And if you choose
not to have the child,
then we can go
ahead with the surgery.
I'm sorry to pressure
you, Mrs. Bassett.
But we have only so
much time for the kidney.
We can't wait for your husband.
How could this happen?
I've waited so long for both.
Mrs. Bassett.
I wanna keep the baby.
Okay.
David, you been to
your appointment?
Yeah. Same old, same old.
Say, where is the
snack bar around here?
I'd like to grab a bite
before I head home.
If you don't mind
some company, I'll go.
No. Let's go.
His daughter says his
behavior's been unusual?
Erratic. Sometimes volatile.
Used to be a pretty
easygoing guy.
I was thinking maybe
some kind of mass or lesion?
No signs of that.
Any new stress at
home or at work?
Uh, he claims no.
So we've got
uncontrolled movements,
loss of balance and
personality change.
You get a family history?
Yeah, his mom's living,
but he doesn't know
much about his dad.
He died when Waters was 14.
So it'd make him early-mid-40s?
Probably.
What'd he die of?
Suicide, apparently.
We need to go talk to him.
I just wish you could talk
some sense into Mark.
Well, he's worried about you.
I know he is.
But he also thinks
that he can control
what's happening to me.
Hell, I wish he could,
but we all know he can't.
I know it's a cliché to
say you don't wanna be
a burden to your children,
but at my age, I don't
mind being be a cliché.
I don't want him to have
to deal with everything.
Well, he's going to,
one way or another.
Can you imagine your
mother allowing you
to take care of her?
She'd sooner push off in a
canoe and head out to sea.
Well, I don't need
to go to that extreme.
I do wanna check out
that... Uh, what do you call it?
Not quite a... A nursing home.
A hospice?
That's it. A hospice.
If I stay in Chicago, at least
that'll make Mark happy.
David, I don't think
there's anything about this
that's going to make Mark happy.
Huntington's Disease?
That's what we're thinking.
I never even heard of it.
Well, it's a progressive
neurological disorder.
It causes loss of
balance, mood changes
and jerking
movements of the body.
And progressive dementia.
You mean, like Alzheimer's?
Well, there are similarities.
Okay, um...
Now we know what
it is. What do I do?
I'm afraid there's no cure.
Well, how bad's it gonna get?
You'll need to discuss
this with a geneticist.
You're telling me that...
I'm going to lose control of...
Of everything
physically and mentally,
and there's nothing
I can do about it?
They're always
developing new treatments.
But at the moment, no.
I'm 46 years old.
How could I get such a thing?
It's genetic, Mr. Waters.
You inherited it.
It generally manifests
itself in your early 40s.
It could be the reason why
your father committed suicide.
That means I could've
passed this on to Jo.
There is a 50-50 chance.
Hyperosmolar coma,
no evidence of DKA.
This kid's got
type two diabetes.
I'd say. His blood glucose
came back from the lab at 980.
How far did you get?
Two liters of saline,
two units of IV insulin.
He's still altered,
up in the PICU.
And he was seen here five
months ago for gastroenteritis
Apparently.
If his glucose was 980 today,
it must've been
high five months ago.
You'd think so.
So why didn't anyone
pick up the diabetes then?
I really couldn't
say. Excuse me.
Dr. Greene, could you
take a look at this elbow film?
What's the problem?
Big anterior fat pad,
but I don't see a fracture.
Are you the Attending? Yeah.
Dr. Tillman, Century
Managed Care,
I'm admitting Eddie Bernero.
Oh, the diabetic coma?
Yeah. I was wondering why
no one picked up on his diabetes
when you guys saw
him in November.
Do you have the old chart?
Here's a copy.
Cleo, what was the glucose?
980.
No, not today. Back in November.
It should be in the chart.
No urine dip?
Not that I saw.
I'm gonna have
to look into this.
I'll give ya a call you.
Thanks. Dr. Finch.
Looks okay. An anterior
fat pad can be normal.
Thanks.
Is there something you didn't
wanna say in front of him?
About what?
The diabetic kid.
He was Carter's patient.
Mark. You're not in surgery?
We can't seem to
give this kidney away.
We're going through
potential recipients like...
Crap through a goose?
Yeah. That works.
Um, The Morgan Center's
going to be calling you.
Hospice or rehab?
The hospice.
What patient?
Uh, your father
asked me about it.
I think he's leaning
towards palliative care.
You went ahead
and called a place?
Yeah, well, he asked me to.
Whoa, whoa, whoa. What
the hell are you doing?
Mark, he asked me to help.
What would you have me do?
Well, tell him talk to me.
Well, he's a grown man.
Yeah, with a stubborn
streak a mile long.
The only other option
is your apartment...
I'm aware of my options.
With you looking after him.
A nurse's aid during the day.
I'll do the rest.
You talked to him about this?
I'm handling it, okay?
Or at least I was. Mark!
I didn't mean to interfere.
Then don't.
Is this what's best for
your father or for you?
Elizabeth, stay
out of it, please.
Fine.
I can send her up now.
Good. Thanks.
They can squeeze you in.
I can't see my own ob-gyn?
No. There's too many
potential complications
with your renal failure.
Dr. Kovac? Yeah?
This is Steve Maldonado. Oh.
The transplant candidate. Right.
You the surgeon?
No, but we'll get
you started here.
I-I was going to the movies,
and I left my pager at home.
And I went home to
get it, and it went off.
I had it on for
maybe 30 seconds.
Yeah. The nurses
need to draw your labs.
This way. Oh. Okay.
Good luck. Yeah, thanks.
You all right?
If I could have
both, I would be.
But I do want the baby.
Ask for Christine Collins.
Suite, uh, 4020.
Okay. Bye.
Bye.
Okay, Mr. Waters.
The geneticist is
Dr. Kevin Casey.
I've made an appointment
for you for next Friday at 11
to go over the results.
Uh-oh. I've just been ordered
to appear in court
Friday afternoon.
The incident... this morning.
I can make a day out of it.
Well, uncontrolled temper
is a symptom of Huntington's.
They might not
hold you responsible.
That's a pretty lousy excuse.
How is Jo doing?
She's meeting Glen
out in the lobby right now.
That's her fiancé.
Does she, um, want
to have the test?
I didn't tell her.
Mr. Waters, you have to.
I mean, if she has
the Huntington's gene,
she will eventually
get the disease.
Listen, my father didn't tell
me and I'm glad he didn't.
Well, she has a right to know.
If there's nothing that
she can do about it,
what's the good in her knowing?
But if she knows,
she can do something.
She can make different choices.
She might not want to work.
She might not want
to have children.
She might not get married.
Might not have a life.
She has to know that
she can pass this disease
on to her children.
Why? So she can
decide not have to any?
I love my daughter.
And I can't imagine
my life without her.
She's had a good
life up until now.
A happy life.
I'm gonna keep it that
way for as long as I can.
If you sign an
emergency consent,
I can overturn the
guardian's decision.
Doesn't DCFS have to appoint me?
Yeah, I already cleared
it with her, though.
I don't know, Kerry.
She's gonna die of
pneumonia sooner or later.
Her mother wants it.
Her foster mother.
She's had Angie for four years.
She might as well be her mother.
She hasn't adopted her
because she can't afford the bills.
But the state can?
How many hundreds of
thousands have been spent so far?
Mark. All right,
all right, I'll sign.
Thank you.
Let me know how she responds.
I will.
Can I help you, Robert?
My niece used to
watch Sesame Street.
Outgrew it when she was about 8.
Yeah, those are the Muppets.
Is there something
that you need?
I came in here looking for
Jevity and a Dobhoff tube...
By the way, we need to
discuss your supply management.
And I find this
girl's foster parent
conspiring with DCFS,
and apparently with you,
to circumvent
the state authority
and perform a
procedure on a girl
who has been a
gork most of her life
and has no chance of recovery.
Did I understand this correctly?
You're overstating it. Am I?
Yes, she has a potentially
life-threatening infection.
All she needs is a central line.
And her so-called
guardian has never seen her.
Well, I've seen her.
We have an obligation to
provide appropriate care.
All I'm doing is exercising
a safeguard that's
built into the system.
You're letting
sympathy for the mother
override your clinical judgment.
I disagree. But thank
you for your input.
This girl is not to
get a central line.
She's my patient. Hydrate
her through her G tube
and keep her comfortable. I
already have a second opinion.
I'm the final opinion. I'm
not getting in a pissing match
with the Welfare Department.
It's one bureaucrat.
And he is right.
It's hopeless and exorbitantly
expensive. Stop flogging her!
Frankly, I've come to expect
a higher level of
professionalism from you.
I'm supporting what I
see as a parental decision!
Angie is essentially
the woman's daughter!
She's her pet!
Look at this girl.
What kind of quality of
life do you think she has?
Robert.
Kerry, I'm serious.
No central line.
Has he always had asthma?
Yeah, since he was about 3.
I'm okay, Mom.
You are not okay, Troy.
I was sitting in the
audience watching,
and I could see his wheezing
getting worse and worse.
Breathe.
She came up and pulled
me right off the stage.
Oh, that's no fun, is it?
I don't ever wanna
go back to school.
Cleo, we got a bounce-back
from this morning.
Paramedics brought him in.
Collapsed at home.
Loss of consciousness.
Who?
Patient named Grunwald.
Grunwald?
He was constipated. Excuse me.
Pulse is down to 50!
He's unresponsive. Atropine.
Put in a liter of saline.
See if you can get a BP.
What happened?
He was getting off
the toilet, just fell over.
See if you can get first
aid labs, cardiac enzymes.
Pressure's 60 palp.
Mix up the dopamine.
He was your patient?
Yeah, abdominal pain.
Wasn't a surgical belly.
Well, we got ST elevations
in the inferior leads.
Any history of heart
disease? No, right?
You said he didn't
have cardiac problems.
His heart is fine.
Is he on any medications?
Codeine. A-and
what she gave him.
What was that? A laxative.
Uh, Bisopro... Bisoprol...
Bisoprolol? Yes.
No, no. We gave him bisacodyl.
Ho-ho, which one was it?
This is Bisoprolol,
but it's not what we gave him.
Hal. Hal, wake up!
Can you have her
wait outside, please?
Ma'am, could you come with
me? No, I should stay here!
We need to work on your
husband, Mrs. Grunwald.
Call the cath lab. Mary,
bolus 5000 units of heparin.
What are you doing? You
gave him a beta blocker?
I didn't. At twice
the starting dosage.
You dropped his heart rate,
pulse, and gave him an MI.
BP's improving, 80 systolic.
Up the dopamine.
Stand by with a nitro drip.
I didn't write the
prescription. You said you did.
I handed it to
him, didn't write it.
Well, who wrote it?
Dr. Kovac, Yeah.
The labs are back on
the transplant recipient.
Good. Get ready to move him.
No, no, you're gonna
wanna look at this.
You're kidding? Nope.
What do you want me to say?
It's okay to tell the daughter?
I think it's debatable. No,
his choice is debatable,
not your obligation.
I have information that
could drastically affect her life,
and I'm hiding it. I feel I
have an obligation to her.
Right, but she is not
your patient. He is.
All you can do is
try and convince him.
I did try. Then
you can't tell her.
Your renal failure was
caused by rhabdomyolysis.
Yeah. From muscle breakdown.
And what caused that?
I don't know.
I think you do.
I was in a car accident
a few years ago.
It crushed my leg. They
think that could've done it.
Not using drugs?
No.
You tested positive for cocaine.
I'm sorry. I didn't realize
I was this high on the list.
I don't do it all the time. I
went to a party, you know.
I was depressed.
The damn dialysis.
You better get used to it.
You're not gonna
give me the transplant?
The cocaine
destroyed your kidneys.
You're still using. Why
would we give you another?
I won't do it after the
operation. I'm not stupid.
You should have told
me. You wasted my time.
Please, come on.
I'm not an addict.
I need this kidney.
The organ is only
viable for a limited time.
I have less than an hour to
get a real candidate in here.
You mean someone
who deserves it.
Yes.
Dr. Chen?
Oh, one second.
Yes?
This is, uh, Glen, my fiancé.
Oh, how do you do? Good, thanks.
We were talking about Dad.
Glen thinks he might be
suffering from depression.
You know, the mood
swings and stuff.
Yeah, it might be the wedding.
We're married in a month,
and I know he
wanted to pay for it.
But it costs a lot of money.
Yeah, that would be tough.
I know, and Jo is
his only daughter.
All right, I'll get the car.
Nice to meet you, Dr. Chen.
Mm-hm.
So you think that's
what it is? Depression?
Uh, well, it's hard to say.
Are you ready to go, Dad?
Yeah, I am. I am.
Thank you, Dr. Chen.
Mm. Mm.
Thanks for everything.
You're welcome.
Kerry?
I thought Romano
said no to a central line.
He did.
But you're doing it, anyway?
I have emergency consent
from another physician.
That's all I need.
I've got this, Carol.
You're gonna need Opsite.
I said, I've got it.
But, Kerry... It's my decision.
It doesn't involve you.
Okay.
Well, looks like a
"P" to me. Bisoprolol.
It's a "C." Why would I order a
beta blocker for constipation?
What's that say, Carter?
Well, I can see how the pharmacy
could have read it wrong.
But they really
should've called. Sure.
Blame them, you coward.
It could have been
read both ways.
Hey, you, come here. I
need an impartial observer.
Come on, that's a faxed
copy... Quiet, Peter.
Is that a "C" or a "P"?
It looks like a "Q."
Someone else who can't read it.
I prescribed bisacodyl.
That's what I ordered.
That's what I wrote.
Why is he currently
undergoing an angioplasty
for a life-threatening
myocaridial infarction?
You heard me say bisacodyl?
Yeah.
Did you even bother to
read the pharmacy label
before you handed it out?
There was a trauma coming in.
Oh. Oh, a trauma came in.
Oh, well, then that
makes everything okay.
When traumas come in, we can
hand out any meds laying around.
Dr. Romano... What's
it have to do with you?
Nothing. So shut up.
Can I go? The growing level
of incompetence
around here is frightening.
Amazing we're not shut
down. It was an honest mistake.
No, it was tag-team negligence.
Okay, you are both prohibited
from writing prescriptions
until further notice.
How are we supposed
to treat patients?
I'm sure Dr. Carter or
one of the other colleagues
will be happy to
write them for you.
How long?
Until your penmanship improves,
and until you can read.
I know how to read. Then do it!
Ooh.
Thank you, Carter.
So you just gave
him a bottle of pills
without even looking at it?
Peter, what you
wrote wasn't legible.
I shouldn't be writing
your scrips, anyway.
I didn't ask you to.
He was your patient.
You always check the
label before you give drugs.
They teach you that
on the first day, Cleo.
You called UNOS?
I needed to get the
next person on the list.
Mrs. Nussbaum,
she is coming in
from upstate Indiana,
and she'll be
here in 40 minutes.
Well, that'll push me
past the 12-hour mark.
The new kidney might fail.
I thought we were at 10 hours.
Luka, We need to do a
workup, get preop labs.
She may have eaten a heavy meal,
in which case we need
to wait to anesthetize.
Let's assess her
when she gets here.
She's already on her way.
You should've talked
to me before you called.
We were in a hurry,
and we had to move on.
Look, you may not like this guy,
but we have a match in-house
who's ready for surgery.
Come on, you can't be serious.
I'd rather put a healthy kidney
in a questionable candidate
than no kidney in anyone.
The guy knows he's
on the UNOS list,
knows he can be
called at any moment,
and he's snorting cocaine?
He's not going to stop using
because he gets the transplant.
He'll burn his way
through another organ.
We've been through three people.
Your Mrs. Nussbaum
might not get here in time.
Or she might not qualify for
some reason. It'll go to waste.
Then let it go to waste.
I'd rather risk it
than give it to him.
It's not your risk to take.
The guy made his choice.
Give the next person
a chance to get here.
Thirty minutes. Then I'm
taking up Mr. Maldonado.
I'm not releasing him.
I don't need you to.
They've never gone
up a tree before.
No, they usually
just go out on a limb.
Okay. Well, it was a great show,
and I have certainly
had a good time.
She likes this
one, I guess, huh?
It's her favorite.
Most doctors think
she's just responding
to the light changes.
But I notice a difference.
At least I think I do.
Dr. Weaver put
in a central line?
I know you think it's too much.
But... I'm not ready
to give her up yet.
I understand.
Excuse me.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Strep throat in Curtain 2
ready to be discharged.
Did he get penicillin? Yep.
Curtain 3...
Were my instructions
in any way... unclear?
No, I-I think you made
your position known.
And you decided to ignore it?
I took it under
advisement. I see, okay.
Well, then you're suspended.
Sign out your
patients and go home.
Robert, let's... Right
now, Kerry. Right now.
Suspended?
Effective immediately,
and until further notice.
Carter, you going home?
Yeah.
I really wish I weren't, though.
My, uh, grandparents
are throwing
one of their dinner parties.
You have to go?
I'm staying there, so
attendance is kind of compulsory.
I have a question for you.
Shoot.
A 12-year-old presents
with abdominal pain, diarrhea,
low-grade fever,
no ill contacts.
What do you do?
Any vomiting?
No.
Probably gastroenteritis.
But that sounds like
a trick question to me.
So I'd probably order
a CBC and dip a urine
to rule out a UTI.
That's what I thought you'd do.
Do I pick up anything abnormal?
Nothing on the CBC.
And, uh, I don't
know about the urine
because... you didn't order one.
Eddie Bernero.
You saw him last fall.
Came back today
with... Type two diabetes.
Hyperosmolar coma.
Cleo told me. Uh-huh.
Is he gonna be okay?
Should be.
Would have been nice
if we caught it earlier.
Yeah, kid must not
have looked that sick.
What did I say? Stomach flu?
Yep.
Yeah, I really wish I
could remember him.
I feel bad.
Must've misdiagnosed.
He didn't have any insurance.
Really? What are they gonna do?
Well, they're okay.
They have it now.
Oh, good.
Is there anything else
you wanna tell me, Carter?
No.
I made a mistake, I'm sorry.
Have a nice party.
Thanks.
Hey.
Yes, Peter?
I didn't like how
we left things.
You mean, you screaming at me?
You mind if I come in?
Suit yourself.
I've got one more set.
♪ More to life than livin' ♪
You always work out
in your living room?
Beats the garage.
Uh, listen, I, um...
I was angry that I got
dragged into all of this.
It wasn't even a
surgical patient.
Cleo, I know it gets
crazy down there.
I just want you
to know that, uh,
you know, I don't blame you.
Oh, you don't?
No, I don't.
You want me to give you a hand?
No.
Come on.
Am I forgiven?
♪ 'Cause this is My life story ♪
Peter, that was
the lamest apology
I've ever heard.
I gotta hit the shower.
You coming?
♪ Oh-oh ♪
♪ This is my life story ♪
♪ And it's for you only ♪
♪ My life, my life, my life ♪
Mm?
♪ This is my life story ♪
♪ And it's for you only ♪
♪ My life, my life, my life ♪
♪ This is my life story ♪
♪ Ooh-ooh ♪
♪ And it's for you only ♪
♪ Ooh ♪
♪ Give you everything ♪
What's next on the
woodworking agenda?
The next project, I'm
going to build an airplane.
- An airplane?
- An airplane.
Out of wood? Dad?
Think it'll be ready by March?
I don't think so.
Well, thanks for letting us...
I'm wearing it.
I just didn't wanna
drag it to the can.
I didn't say anything.
You were about to.
Your backup oxygen's low.
I didn't notice.
I'll go to the hospital
and get you another one.
Well, it should get
me through the night.
I don't want to
take any chances.
Whatever you say.
I made some macaroni and cheese.
There's some extra
on the... On the counter.
Thanks.
Say, I saw Elizabeth today.
Yeah, she told me.
Did she say anything
about that... That...
That place, uh... The hospice?
I checked it out.
There weren't any
spots available.
Well, when will they
have one available?
I don't know. They didn't say.
There's a long waiting list.
Waiting list? What...?
What's the point of that?
I don't know.
Looks like you're stuck
with me for a while.
Yeah.
Luka! Huh?
What are you doing?
I think the grease from the meat
dripped onto the coals
and caught on fire.
Yeah, that's what
the water bottle's for.
You didn't tell me that.
Here. What's left of it.
Thanks.
Ah, it really cooled
off out here, huh?
Mm-hm.
Girls asleep?
One of them. The
other one's still fussing.
Let me guess. Kate.
You had a 50-50 shot.
No. She's the troublemaker.
Yeah.
Do you think
these are too thick?
They might be rare inside.
Well, don't worry.
If you blow it,
I think I have a steak and
kidney pie in the freezer.
Kidney, huh?
Very funny.
You know, the nurses
were about to take a poll.
Thought you'd actually
have to take it home with you.
I might as well have.
No, you probably
scared the guy into rehab.
Well...
What's wrong?
What? Is...? Is that snow?
Oh, man!
Hello! It's April!
We can finish cooking inside.
No, I came here to barbecue.
You wanna freeze?
Come on, it's a little snow.
I'm gonna get you a sweater.
I don't think your
sweaters will fit me.
I'll find something.