The human body is a
highly pressurized system.
The blood pressure
measures the force of blood
pulsating through the arteries.
Great! What the hell
am I gonna do now?!
It's important to keep
this pressure regulated.
Damn it! Damn it!
When a heart wasn't
available, I opted to continue
with Roy Henley's
lung transplant...
Low or inadequate pressure
can cause weakness or failure.
- It's all in your head.
- My name isn't on the OR board.
I checked the schedule,
nobody wants to work with me
- because I'm not
on anybody's service.
- It's an oversight.
- Just ask around.
- Do you know how many things
I've screwed up
- in the last month?
- Stop it. I'm serious. Just ask around,
and get on someone's
service and get back to work.
You smell like you're sweating
booze. Where have you been?
- I want the weekend you had.
- What happens
in Vegas, you know?
Hey, who's Stark? I'm supposed
to be on Stark's service today.
Oh, me, too! He's the new Peds
attending, since Robbins left.
Crap. I can't handle a bunch
of sick kids today. I can't do it.
- So was it a bachelor party?
- Sh. They're talking
about Cristina.
Oh.
It became clear to Dr. Yang that they
were gonna need to switch modalities.
- The patient was put on...
- - It's when the pressure gets too high
- that problems really occur.
- And why did Dr. Yang opt to
use the intra-aortic balloon
pump over an RVAD?
I, um... I can't
answer for Dr. Yang.
- And why isn't she here?
- She, um...
She quit. She left the program.
I'm sorry, what? She what?
Dr. Yang cleared the balloon
pump with Dr. McQueen,
who agreed that
it was the best...
Go back. Go back.
- Yang quit the program?
- Where have you been?
It's the first I've heard of it.
Hunt, what the hell happened?
- She told the chief she quit.
- Richard.
- If we could finish the presentation...
- - I have a question.
Can you tell us about your decision to
put Dr. Yang in charge of this patient?
- Sorry?
- But she didn't
"quit" quit, right?
Grey?
You're joined at the
hip, what'd she say?
She hasn't spoken
to me about it.
If the pressure
continues to increase,
a closer examination
is called for.
Stop looking at
me. Look up there.
Does Torres know
anything about this?
- I'm calling Torres.
- Can we please just...
I guess I'm asking you, why
did you choose to put Dr. Yang
- under so much pressure that day?
- - I didn't.
I intended the opposite. I gave her a
simple pre-op checklist on a stable patient.
Stable patient?
- The patient almost died twice.
- I couldn't have
seen that coming.
I'm sorry, is this a, uh,
a patient presentation,
or a post-mortem on Dr. Yang?
Well, you saved the patient.
Because it's the best indicator
that something is
going terribly wrong.
Hey, Mark.
No, no, I was, um, I was
actually on my way out. What's up?
She what?
I don't know what
Shepherd's problem is.
What the hell was that?
How is she doing? Is she...?
We're... I don't know.
She's... We're good. We're fine.
It's like nothing's changed. Yet
she refuses to talk about work.
I bring up work,
and she goes blank.
Altman, Hunt, emergent
patient, ten minutes out.
- Can you meet me
in the VIP wing?
- VIP wing? Who is it?
You'll find out
when we get there.
Listen, Hunt, I'm required to send a
letter to the American Board of Surgery
declaring that Dr. Yang has
officially left the residency program.
I have to let them know. I'm
asking you, is there any reason
I need to hold off on
sending that letter?
- Yes!
Please, don't mail it. Just
give us a little more time.
OK. Let's go.
- Grey, who are you with today?
- Shepherd.
Damn it! I've already blown it
with Shepherd, I can't ask him.
Uh...
Bailey, I haven't
blown it with her yet.
- Thinks no one
wants to work with him.
- Are they saying that,
- or are you saying that?
- Who are you with again?
- Karev. Uh, I mean Stark.
- No, you meant Karev.
And you don't want to go there.
You don't know where I'm going.
He's right, don't
want to go there.
I'm not going anywhere!
He's not the guy for
you. OK? Trust me.
And don't be paranoid.
Trust me on that, too.
Oh, but it's OK
for you to go there?
I'm a guy, I live there.
I gotta find Bailey.
Hello? Cristina?
Oh, hey. Hello?
Hello!
- Hello!
- Ah!
- Uh, what are you doing here?
- I'm not back until next week.
So it's true? You guys
broke up? She's in Africa?
OK. Sloan told me that you quit.
Hey! What are you doing?
- This! Go away!
- OK, this is disturbing.
Hey, stop!
Look, I was unpacking,
but then I didn't enjoy it.
- What are you doing?
- What do you mean?
You don't have a job to go to.
You don't have a girlfriend telling you
you have to go to Africa. You're
completely free, do whatever you want.
The world is your
oyster. Make lemonade!
I'm trying. I was gonna
get my hair cut today.
Like, make a radical change.
But then I thought, hm...
maybe you shouldn't do radical
things right after a blond woman
has ripped your heart out of
your chest and stomped on it.
What are you...? Oh, my
God! What are you doing?!
Are you insane?!
Let's make lemonade.
Oh, my God.
Uh... Ninety-seven-point-six.
Stick out your tongue.
- Ow! Cut it out.
- We'll have fun today.
Stark's got a four-month-old biliary
atresia patient who just found a donor.
A liver transplant on an infant?
Enough with the
damn ping-pong balls!
- Jerk-face!
- Whoa! Inside
voices here, please.
So you must be Dr. Karev.
You missed my rounds today.
Ugh! Sorry I... I
had car trouble.
Well, there's a classic. So, what,
you're here just to yell at my patients?
I'm sorry. Look, Dr. Stark,
I am feeling very sick today. So
I think since you have Kepner...
Well, let's see here.
No fever. You don't
seem to be vomiting.
- You retaining control
of your bowels?
- Ew.
- Yes.
- Well, since hangovers
are not contagious,
I'd say you're working.
And you can start by
prepping my atresia kid.
She's only a few months
old, so try not to be a jerk-face.
Give me that!
Dr. Webber? Ronald Dace, State
Department. We spoke on the phone.
- These your surgeons?
- Uh, yes, this is Doctor...
Right now, we need to limit access
to this area to only essential personnel.
- Why is that necessary?
- - No one can know this man
is being hospitalized. No one
can know he's in the country.
Everyone, stop!
Give me the paddles.
I need a reading.
- Stay back.
- He's in v-fib, charge to 200!
And from a global perspective,
it would be great if he didn't die.
Clear.
Clear!
They faxed more of his records.
- These are all in Arabic.
- Clear!
- There was a car accident?
- The emir's car
was hit by a truck
- as he was leaving the meeting.
- What's he doing in Seattle?
He's not. Let it suffice
to say, if he dies,
we've got a serious
international incident.
Not to mention, his people are supposed
to see their first elections, right?
- I'm not at liberty to...
- Unless he dies,
in which case the door is
open for Al-Qaeda to move in
and then your secret
meeting was for nothing.
You don't just skip to
the crossword, do you?
- I worked in that
neck of the woods.
- I know, Dr. Altman.
Three years in Baghdad.
Two years in Landstuhl.
- Wow, you guys are fast.
- We are.
Our best outcome here is we get him
stable enough to be put on a plane home.
Our best outcome is we save him.
He takes two medications, one for high
blood pressure, one for his cholesterol.
Uh, he was hospitalized
late last year for exhaustion.
- Did he receive
any treatment then?
- No, just rest.
Working too hard.
He works very hard.
He has a wife, four children.
Five, if you count me.
He's more than my
boss, he's been, um...
He's given me
everything. So, please...
We'll do everything we can.
- He's in v-fib! Alright, charge to 300!
- Clear!
- We'll bring your baby up soon.
- Lisa. Her name is Lisa.
The donor was an adult, so
the liver will actually be split
- between your baby...
- Lisa.
Sorry, we read that
if the doctor knows
your baby's name, it helps you to kind of
bond with her. We read that's important.
Will Dr. Stark be
splitting the liver in situ?
We that know ex
vivo takes less time,
but we also read that in
situ gives better results?
We're not trying to tell
you how to do your job.
No, of course not. Please don't
apologize. We'll find out for you.
One second.
- Blow up as many
of those as you can.
- Dr. Stark.
- You got it. You got it.
- Dr. Stark?
Can you come talk to the Collises,
please? They've got a lot of questions.
Yeah, I gotta check on
that kid's harvest team.
- Did you ever hang glide?
- What? I... No.
It's apparently a very good
way to become a liver donor.
Sir, are you splitting the liver in the
body, or ex vivo? Parents want to know.
OK. Those folks have been
spending a little too much time
consulting Dr. Internet.
Listen, just hold their hands.
Let them feel smart. Tell them
I'm busy getting their baby a liver.
Her name's Lisa.
I said I don't need any
help. I've got an easy day.
Two laparoscopic
surgeries. I can't use you.
- Maybe I could...
- I'm sorry, ma'am,
I can't admit you.
You don't need to admit me.
I'll just walk in there myself.
I do it all the time.
Uh, Chief Webber
paged me in there.
- I'm sorry, ma'am.
- Well, who's in there?
Is it the president?
Or the vice president?
- Is it Bono?
- Bono?
- Ma'am, I'm sorry...
- Bailey.
Can you take my patients
today? I got a situation in here.
- Oh, of course, sir.
- Louise Cortez is a readmit
after surgery for chronic pancreatitis.
CT showed a pancreatic fistula.
- And she spiked
a fever this morning.
- Right. Sir...
- You put in a drain?
- Yes. Just keep a close eye.
Sir! Is it Bono?
Come on, Avery, I can use you.
OK, but I don't understand,
I'm on your service.
I don't need you. The
craniotomy's been cancelled.
I don't have anything
for the rest of the day.
- So, what am I supposed
to do now?
- Go study.
- Study what?
- I don't care, Lexie.
Go somewhere else. Oh, my God.
- How do we have time for this?
- We have to make time for this.
- Should I call her?
- Call who?
- Cristina!
- Why?
Because she quit and I feel
like I should do something.
That's not your fault. You
didn't do anything wrong,
no matter what she says. OK?
- You just need
to make time for this.
- But...
Oh, my God. Lexie.
- What?!
- I'm looking
for Dr. Meredith Grey.
What did you do?
How's it going?
- Can I see?
- Fantastic, shut up.
OK... You know what you need?
To get this place done? You need
to throw a housewarming party.
Put a little pressure
on yourself.
We should throw a
housewarming party!
Oh, my God!
- Oh, my God. No!
- Tonight! I'll text everyone!
- No!
- Yes! I have
several credit cards
- and nothing to do.
- OK, this is not what I wanted.
I look... I look injured.
Do you even cut hair?
- I need furniture!
- Look at my hair!
Yeah. I sort of can't
believe you let me do that.
- Cristina!
- It's OK, we'll go to the mall!
You might want a hat.
Clear!
We need to get
him to a cath lab.
If he'd stop coding long enough.
I'm inserting a pacemaker.
- You paged?
- Yeah, Grey, grab
me a pacemaker kit.
Hey, Hunt, you're throwing a
housewarming party tonight?
- Tonight? I am?
- Well, your wife is.
- That's a good sign, right?
- It's a weird sign.
But maybe it's an opportunity. I
mean, maybe I could talk to her.
Better yet, maybe
you could, Grey.
We all could. I mean,
it's gonna be hard for her
to walk out of a
room at her own party.
- How bad is it?
- I'll tell you when I know.
Maybe a little less
party planning...
Hey, I don't tell you how to...
- polish your sunglasses.
- Look, between you and me,
he's a good man, and it'd be a
shame if something like this screwed up
- what he was trying to do.
- Wow. Every time I talk to you,
I feel a little more relaxed.
The last thing Cristina
wants is to talk to me.
I have to just give
her some space.
We don't have time
to give her space.
She's gonna be locked
out of this program.
And I do not believe that,
that is what she wants.
I mean, do you think
that's what she wants?
I'm asking you, Grey.
I still don't understand
what I'm doing back here.
Dr. Webber said
something about a fist?
A fistula. It's a complication
from your surgery
that's leaking pancreatic fluid.
The drain takes the
fluid out of your body
so it won't go where
it's not supposed to.
OK...
The pancreatic fluid is
made to digest your food.
If it leaks in your body, it starts
to digest your other organs.
- That wouldn't be good.
- Exactly.
But not to worry,
yours is looking just fine.
I just want to keep a
close eye on you, OK?
Seems like I just was
home, and here I am again.
- You know, I say
that every morning.
- Dr. Bailey, the OR's ready.
OK. Um, Ms. Cortez, your
temperature's still a little high,
so you just rest and we'll
get you home in no time.
OK.
- OK, you're not scrubbing in.
- I'm not?
No. Watch Mrs. Cortez. If the fluid in
her drain changes color, you page me.
If her fever goes up
one digit, you page me.
- 'Cause the fever could mean...
- An abscess, early sepsis,
pneumonia, any number of nasty things.
Remember your first rule of residency:
"Eat when you can,
sleep when you can..."
"Don't screw with the pancreas."
So much for my easy day.
Nice anastomoses.
No leaks.
- How are we doing? Are we good?
- It's not...
It's not quite fitting, is it? There's not
enough room in the peritoneal cavity
- for the graft.
- The liver's too big?
Or the baby's too small.
BP's 64 over 40.
It's compressing
the hepatic vessels.
Sponge. No, no, no. Larger,
larger, larger. There we go.
Let's get this sponge up under
there, take the pressure off the vessels.
And... Yeah, that's
doing the trick there.
All right. I think we're done.
- But the liver's not gonna fit.
- We're not gonna
close her up today.
Just wrap her. This
happens with adult split livers.
You just gotta sit tight and hope
that the swelling goes down enough
- so you can close her up.
- Well, how long will that take?
As long as it takes, Karev.
Thank you all, great work.
This graft is big. The swelling
is going to take a lot to go down.
How long can it stay like
that with that sponge in her?
- I don't know.
- - Isn't it gonna start to deteriorate?
She could get infected. And what if
the swelling doesn't go down enough?
The liver will die and she'll
be back on the donor's list.
- Geez, how is this a solution?
- It's not.
Um, how can you not talk to Meredith
about this? She's your best friend.
- Ooh, I love that lamp.
- You can't just
cut yourself off
from a person, pretend your
whole relationship never happened.
I mean, you can, but it makes
you a heartless, soulless monster
- who I thought I knew,
but really didn't.
- With wheels on her shoes.
Oh, God, how was I OK with that?
I used to be a lot cooler than that.
- I was a lot cooler
when I was single.
- You were hardly ever single.
I know. I know.
I'm actually excited to
spend time on my own.
OK, I thought we were
going to a hair salon.
- Next. We're doing me now.
- Can I help you find something?
Yes. I will take that.
- That sofa?
- That room.
All of it. I'll take it. You do
same day delivery, right?
- Great.
- So it went very well.
Baby looks good,
liver looks good.
- And we can all
exhale a little bit.
- When can we see her?
Soon. We'd like to
keep an eye on her.
There's a little bit of swelling,
and I wanna see that go down,
- but, uh, we'll let you know.
- Thank you.
Thank you so much,
Dr. Stark. Thank you.
Yeah. My pleasure entirely.
You aren't gonna tell
them any more than that?
What would you want
me to tell them, Karev?
That there's a chance of infection,
that if the liver doesn't conform,
they could be back on the donor's
list? I mean, they're smart people,
they want to know
what could go wrong.
Make them more
worried than they are?
I think you're not
worried enough!
- Tell me a better solution.
- I, uh...
Can you give me
a better solution?
- No.
- Well, then
keep your mouth shut,
and go do something you can
do. You can start with my post-ops.
You tried.
Ow! OK, since when is it OK
to shoot people in this hospital?
- Now Bailey's
given up on me, too.
- You're on her service!
- Why are you still
freaking out?
- No, Bailey's in surgery.
She trusts me to watch a post-op
drip fluid in a bag every ten minutes.
- Ow!
- Inappropriate! You should relax.
You get an easy day, you
take it. Shepherd didn't need me,
so I took a nap in
the research library.
Give me... Give it to me.
- Jerk-face.
- He's having a rough day.
- New Robbins is no Robbins.
- Check this out.
- Armed escort to get a yogurt.
- OK, who is it? Is it Bono?
It's totally Bono. It's
all over the hospital.
- It's not Bono.
- Are you going
to Cristina's tonight?
I don't know.
OK!
- Not OK.
- It's addicting.
Put it away before my guy
wrestles you to the ground.
- Give me that.
- No.
- Give me the ball.
- No. Get...
- What's his problem?
- He's having a rough day.
Jeez, I'm coming.
The Emir's cath confirmed that he
has a tear in one of his coronary arteries.
We've stabilized him
with a balloon pump,
but I am gonna have to perform
open heart surgery to repair the tear.
Doctor, doctor, please.
- Was the tear in his...?
- Quiet, please.
Was the tear in
his artery an injury
- sustained in the car accident?
- There is no way...
- Doctor, don't answer that.
- There's no way of knowing
- if that was the cause.
-
Can we have assurances
that your finest surgeons
- will be operating on His Highness?
- - Yes.
These are the chiefs of my
cardio-thoracic and trauma departments.
Sorry. He was asking
your State Department.
He didn't mean the finest
surgeons in this hospital.
Which is why you might be
more comfortable travelling
to your own country,
where he can...
All right, quiet! Quiet, please!
Quiet, please. Thank you.
I understand that there are a lot
of concerns and agendas here,
but we all have the same goal,
and that is to see this man live.
Now, we are out of time, which
means we are out of options.
I am your only shot,
and you have to take me.
I can only say that if
you knew me better,
you'd feel pretty good
about your chances.
Dr. Hunt and I are
going to operate.
And we will update
you as soon as we can.
Good luck.
You have to tell them to stop.
- Tell them they can't operate.
- Why? What's the problem?
Come with me.
He didn't want anyone to
know. He made me swear.
- Just tell him
what you told us.
- Four months ago,
the Emir was diagnosed with
an unruptured cerebral aneurysm
- in his left temporal lobe.
- He's in CT now?
His first neuro came up clean,
but now he's got a blown pupil.
- So we think it's burst.
- Scans should be up by now.
I swore to him, I wouldn't say
anything until after the election.
I'm still not sure I should have told
you. I might be costing him everything.
You're trying to save his life.
He's trying to save
seven million lives.
To make it so seven million
people can walk the street
without the fear of being
murdered by the extremists.
He doesn't, um... He risks his life
every time he steps out his door.
You're trying to protect him too,
and I'm sure he'll understand that.
- He was headed to surgery?
- Yeah, we're going on
- dissected coronary artery.
- - Yeah, that aneurysm's blown.
- Damn it. That's a huge bleed.
- Well, not surprising.
He was shocked seven times and given
a blood thinner, which is unfortunate.
He presented like an MI. I
treated him appropriately.
I couldn't have
seen this coming.
You've been saying
that a lot today.
You know what, Shepherd?
I don't need crap from you.
Apparently, I hold the whole fate
of the Middle East in my hands.
Apparently, now I do, too. Book an OR.
We'll gonna have to work simultaneously.
Can't wait.
Cristina's having a
party? Cristina Yang?
Yeah, I know, but I'm gonna go.
We're all gonna go and talk to her.
You should come, too. You quit
once. You walked away and came back.
So maybe you have
something to say that could help.
- No.
- No?
Do you remember when you came
out to talk to me about coming back?
Do you remember when I hit your
engagement ring with a baseball bat?
- Oh, that was a great day.
- She's already lashing out.
Don't go and try and confront her.
No intervention of Cristina Yang.
Do you hear me? It's a bad idea.
What are you sterilizing?
You're kidding me.
- What was so important?
- Uh...
Sir, I was out of line earlier.
But I think I found a
solution for Lisa Collis's liver.
- What is that,
a ping-pong ball?
- It's the perfect shape
to keep the liver from
compressing her blood vessels.
It's made of celluloid, not plastic, so
it won't break down, like a sponge will.
It's gas-sterilized, so
there's little risk of infection.
You could leave it in there forever.
Her liver will just grow around it.
I think it's...
- You think it won't work?
- No...
I was thinking I left
you to do my post-ops,
and here I find you
playing with balls.
I don't know, Karev.
Am I gonna have to talk
to your chief about you?
Yeah. Right.
I want it sort of like bad-ass, you
know? A little dangerous, unpredictable.
- Did you bring a picture?
- Mm... It's more of a feeling.
What do they do all day, the
mall people? Look at them.
They move so
slowly. They all mosey.
- Look!
- Yeah, I can't turn my head.
Do they just eat things and buy things
and complain about their breakups?
- Yes.
- Fantastic. Look at that lady.
She's just gonna eat that
pretzel. That's all she's gonna do.
So, what are you gonna do? You're
just gonna become a mall person?
- Shop and eat?
- This yogurt's pretty good.
I'm serious.
I'm getting a pretzel.
- Avery, how's our patient?
- No change.
That's what I like to hear.
I'm going into my colon.
So you still don't
want me to scrub in?
- No, I need you to watch...
- Ms. Cortez.
Right. Like I said, no change.
Avery, I need you where I
need you. I don't have time.
No, ma'am, that's fine.
I get it.
I'm saying with this letter,
there's a timeframe now.
You're content to stand
back and watch Cristina
- lose her spot in this program?
- I'm saying an intervention
is not a good plan. Suction.
It's not an intervention,
Shepherd. We just thought,
- since we were all together...
- Torsades!
Damn it. He's in v-fib.
Shepherd, I need you to stop.
- We have to shock him.
- - No, wait, I'm right in the middle of...
- Internal paddles.
- Charge to ten.
Hold on, hold on!
Shepherd!
OK. Clear!
Sinus tach.
Hey. Did Stark ever
respond to my page?
He's got three discharges, one of
them's been here since yesterday.
Dr. Stark's in surgery. He
went back in on Lisa Collis.
What?
It's a great idea. So simple.
Let's see if it works.
It is the right shape.
It's celluloid so it
won't break down.
And the liver
will conform to it.
- It's a great idea.
- Whose idea was it, Dr. Stark?
Originally? Was it
yours or Dr. Karev's?
Let's just see if it works.
And I'm back, Ms.
Cortez. Did you miss me?
Could you please let the dog
out? He won't stop barking.
She's delirious. Pulse is thready! I
think she's in shock! Get her vitals.
Oh, no, no! Damn it! Get me a
monitor in here! Call Dr. Bailey now!
- Right away, doctor.
- Come on.
I'm almost done here.
Get her into an OR, open
her up and wait for me.
- I'll be there.
- Open? Did you say open her up?
No word from Dr. Bailey?
OK. Ten blade.
The artery is at the
base of the heart.
Bypass would be so much better.
I cannot manage
this bleed on bypass.
OK, good. I can
clip the aneurysm.
I need you to stop
what you're doing.
I am trying to do a coronary
graft on a hemorrhaging heart.
- What do you suggest I do?
- Do it faster.
All right, I need you to
stop making this my fault.
Pack that. I tried
everything I could for Yang.
I encouraged her into the
OR, I kept her out of the OR.
I don't know what else I could
have done differently. Hold pressure.
More! OK, good. Go.
Yang was my student. Don't
you think that I wanted to help her?
I have no doubt that's
what you wanted to do.
But you're saying that I failed.
I'm saying that we all failed.
- So now it's time to back off.
- No, Shepherd,
you need to back off. She's my
wife. I'm not gonna give up on her yet.
All right! It's clear we all have
the same goal. We want her back.
Done. I got it.
I'm sorry.
I have a personal
stake in this, too.
I would not be standing
here if it wasn't for her.
Right.
But you're asking us to do
nothing, and we can't do that.
- I can't do that.
- OK.
Let's start closing.
Damn it! Time of death, 7:41.
Son of a bitch!
This is not my fault!
She got a fistula, they
got delayed hemorrhage!
Post-op pancreatectomies always
get fistulas! I didn't screw this up!
- Avery...
- No, you listen! They always get fistulas,
then they get severe
complications, and they die!
I did what you said! You told me to
open her up, and then you weren't here.
- I tried to fix it.
- Avery.
- This is not my damn fault!
- Dr. Avery!
Step out of my OR.
We are awesome.
I can't believe we did all this.
Uh, I did all this. You
opened one bottle of wine.
- Could you find
where the napkins are?
- Hello?
- Damn it. Uh, not ready!
- Hi.
Hey, if you're here for the
party, you're like way too early.
I'm not here for the party.
- Are you here
to tell me to come back?
- No.
But a bunch of other
people are coming to do that.
Oh, God.
Are you OK?
I'm sorry. I tried to find you.
He is awful! He tried
to take all the credit.
- Is the kid OK? Is it gonna work?
- Yeah!
Of course it's gonna work. It's
brilliant. I'm gonna talk to the chief.
Because it is so unfair. You
did every single thing right today.
You covered that
attending's ass and you got...
You got crapped on
every step of the way.
The chief should
know that. No, no.
You're so...
What you did today was so great.
You know, you don't
deserve this. I just...
I wanted you to know
that somebody knows that.
That I know that.
You know, I'm,
uh... I've never, um...
- This is my first time.
- I know. You want to stop?
No. No, I don't
wanna stop. I just...
- Can we just go, uh... slower?
- What?
Can... Can we please
just go a little slower?
It's just... I need...
You need what? What do you
need? What do you need from me?
You wanna screw? Let's screw.
You don't? Then get out!
I'm not gonna hold your virgin
hand and walk you through it, damn it!
You're not a child! I
can't take care of you!
I can't take care of
everybody in this friggin' place!
- Hi.
- Hey.
Uh, I usually do a
post-op exam right now.
Yeah, well, he's on a C-130
halfway across the
country by this time.
So I don't get to
check on his recovery?
He's being well taken care of.
- You did a good job.
- Oh...
I can tell you that.
What are you doing
hanging around?
Well, I wanted to say thank you.
And that it, uh...
It was nice meeting you.
I'd say the same,
but you were never here.
Welcome.
Wine's on the table,
beer's in the fridge.
- I have a fridge?
- And since you
actually live here,
I'll hand over the
hosting duties to you.
- Where's Cristina?
- Haven't seen her. Which is sort of rude.
Torres might know, hang on.
Callie, Yang say
where she was...?
Oh, um...
Can I move in with you?
That might be the
rebound talking.
Not like that, not that. Just till I can
get rid of the sub-letter in my place.
I'm starting from scratch.
And I don't want to do it alone.
Can't we be alone together?
Isn't it easier to be single in pairs?
This a riddle?
No, I'm drunk.
- Come on. Can I?
- Sure.
Yay!
- Your hair is hot.
- Right?
Oh, hi. Um...
I... Sorry, I didn't...
I know I should bring a gift. Like a
housewarming gift to things like this,
but I didn't really have
time to bring anything.
- So I'm... really sorry.
- It is really... It's no problem.
What happened? April? Hey, hey.
Come on.
Has anybody seen Cristina?
If you're asking my
opinion, I think you should.
I think you absolutely have to.
You should keep and
refinish the original floors.
Why do I have to? I mean, you guys
did what, like, bamboo or something?
We're building our house from scratch,
we can put down whatever we want.
- You have original oak floors.
- Yeah, but, what if
I don't like it?
- I mean what if I hate oak?
- Doesn't matter. You have to do it.
The building's historic.
I know.
God! OK. OK. OK!
Every pressurized
system needs a relief valve.
There has to be a way to
reduce the stress, the tension...
I got there as fast as I could.
It was a grade-C fistula
with a ruptured splenic artery.
You did everything
you could. Avery, too.
- Why don't you go home.
- Yes, sir.
- Bailey look...
- Why do we see so
many post-op fistulas
after pancreas surgeries?
Your operation is flawless.
It doesn't matter, we still see fistulas
in... What, 20 percent of patients?
I think there's a way to bring that
number down. I just got to find it.
- Miranda...
- I needed a win, sir.
I've got a string of big losses.
I could use a win, that's all.
Yang.
Yang was the one I
didn't have to worry about.
I know.
Before it becomes
too much to bear.
Look into the pancreatectomy
patients. Figure it out.
- And then let me
know how I can help.
- Uh, can I use Avery?
He actually gave me the
idea. He was great today.
Well, that's good to know.
You know, Alex Karev saved a
baby's life with a ping-pong ball?
- Ping-pong ball?
- Yes, he did.
Alex Karev.
There has to be
a way to find relief.
Because if the pressure
doesn't find a way out...
it will make one.
Listen. Let me talk to her.
All right.
Come here, come
on, here. Come on!
It will explode.
OK, OK. Let's go. Outside.
It's the pressure we put on
ourselves that's the hardest to bear.
You think it was hard for
Yang? To quit, to just walk away?
Oh, don't be stupid.
You're not quitting.
Besides, you might have
just gotten yourself fired.
- Or arrested. Probably both.
- Yeah, well,
April is the only friend
I have left here. So...
Don't be stupid.
The pressure to be
better than we are.
What the hell were you
thinking? She's a virgin.
- Why would you do that?
- I know. God. Ow! Ow!
If you needed it that bad, Alex,
you should have gone back to Vegas.
- There's a whole
industry there.
- I didn't go to Vegas.
- I went to Iowa.
- You went to Iowa?
I went home.
- My brother, remember Aaron?
- Yeah.
Doctor said...
He got diagnosed schizophrenic.
Just like my mom.
You know how they figured it
out? He tried to kill our little sister.
She's 16. She's a kid. And
her brother tried to kill her.
And my mom didn't do anything
'cause she's off her meds and...
Anyway, I was in Iowa.
That's where I went.
To my brother's commitment
hearing. I had to commit him. Whatever.
The pressure to be better
than we think we can be.
- Well, it's good
that you were there.
- I wasn't there.
I wasn't.
I showed up, I held my sister's hand
in the hospital for like ten minutes,
I shoved some pills
down my mom's throat,
I signed my brother
into a nuthouse.
Then I got the hell out
of there as fast as I could.
I wasn't there. I'm the ass
who can't stand to be there.
It never, ever lets up.
I should go down there.
I have to go down there.
Yeah, I should go.
You good?
Anything else you
want to talk about?
- What are you doing
for bathroom tile?
- Oh. Bathroom tile. Um...
I don't know yet. I
think I'm going to...
It just builds
and builds and builds.