Previously on ER:
- Who are you?
- Victor Clemente, your new Attending.
And congratulations,
doc, you just killed me.
I know what happened in Newark,
and I really do not want a repeat here.
Hear you're getting out.
It stunk to work here?
Try being a patient.
- Zoe.
- Yes?
- You know what you're doing?
- I know what I'd like to.
- I'm your half-brother.
- Good to meet you.
This is my wife, Evelyn,
and my daughter, Jocelyn.
Uh, this is Greg. My son.
You don't wanna have
anything to do with me.
- But what about your brother?
- Don't use him like that.
- I'm trying here.
- Then stop.
- Getting ready for a roast?
- We gotta clean this place up.
- Gallant won't be here for three days.
- It's gonna take a week to disinfect.
I want it nice for him.
He's been there a long time.
Come on, we're gonna be late.
Oh. Hi, I'm Zoe.
Yeah. I remember.
You have a cool place.
Thin walls, though.
Oh, sometimes we
really get it going.
Have you seen my... toothbrush?
Sorry.
Keep it. I have gum.
- You're just leaving her here?
- Afraid she's gonna steal something?
- She already took my toothbrush.
- Don't worry. She'll lock up.
- You gave her keys?
- It's different with Zoe.
There's something
real between us.
Yeah. Real loud.
Wouldn't admit him because what?
Too young?
Yeah, we got a NICU...
but it's not exactly SOP.
"SOP"?
Standard operating
procedure. It's military talk.
- Ah. That must mean you like him.
- Ha-ha-ha.
It's gonna take a
little more than that.
All right, all right.
But you owe me, man.
- Lockhart?
- Abby.
Incoming. I need a room with a warmer
set up for an infant, Miller 1 and a 2.5.
2.5? What's it, a preemie?
Yeah, but... We got it, thanks.
You can see it in his eyes. It's
starting to sink in on the poor sucker.
What is?
- That he actually works here.
- Hmm.
This is a special case. Needs to
be treated on the DL, you follow?
- Is it your illegitimate love child?
- Try to be cool, okay?
Nine-week-old, two days
vomiting, diarrhea, fever.
- Vitals?
- Tachy. Couldn't get a BP.
- How about a sat?
- Probe wouldn't stick to the fur.
Easy, easy. Lockhart,
this is Darwin.
That's the ugliest
baby I've ever seen.
Okay, folks, the good news is
the hospital has approved 4:1 ratios.
- Finally.
- That means extra full-time equivalents...
and zero, zero, tolerance
for excessive OT.
Let's hope we have enough
people to fill those shifts.
Sam, you got a haircut.
No. It's just highlights.
Good morning, ER staff.
So it's true. We're not alone.
What's going on?
Well, this device was designed
to offer remote surgical consults.
So since I'm still at
home recovering...
thought I'd give
it a test drive.
Okay. Meeting's over.
Nurses, for the sake of the
trial, I'm gonna need a few things.
- I miss the Bronx.
- This is why I don't have cable.
- How are you doing that?
- I have a joystick in my lap.
All right, that is too
much information.
- Sam, we're gonna be in sutures.
- You need help?
- No, that's okay. We got it.
- Morning, Dr. Lockhart.
- Some kid in triage asking for you.
- Tell him to take a number.
He says he knows you.
Oh, yeah. Set him up in 2, okay?
Okay.
Haleh, walk with me.
- You sure like to walk.
- Remember that little chat we had?
No more OT. I did
what I promised.
You're picking up extra
time by taking shifts in ICU.
You never said I couldn't.
I also didn't say you couldn't flip
burgers or turn tricks in Lincoln Park.
Excuse me?
It's overtime. You know
what I'm talking about.
I'm sorry. It won't
happen again.
Okay, his temperature's only 94.
I must have skipped school the
day they taught monkey veins.
Word is you give good neonate.
Human neonate, Dr. Moreau.
Bet you didn't know chimps and
humans share 96 percent of their DNA.
I know, it's fascinating.
So this is what happened:
Darwin's handler calls me up and
tells me that the vet's kind of nervous.
He figures this little
guy's best shot is with me.
- Oh, of course he does.
- Tachy, carotid's weak.
This handler, he knows you because
you went to clown school together?
How did you guess?
No, I'm serious. I was at NYU
while he was at Ringling Bros.
- I had kind of a circus thing.
- Okay.
We need access, Lockhart.
Right. Abby. I'll try to
find a transilluminator.
- Is there anyone else we can trust?
- What are we doing?
I'm an attending. I can't
spend all day with a chimp.
I know. So, what are we doing?
Go, go, go. Okay, okay, go, go.
Don't forget to knock, okay?
Please, go.
I heard you have a baby
there. You need help?
No. I... We got it.
- Is it cute?
- Yes, it's a hairy little monkey.
I love babies. Babies love
me. I have a way with them.
- Can you get me a transilluminator?
- I'm like the wind.
Oh, hey, Neela. Do
you have a minute?
- We could use an extra set of hands.
- "We"?
Clemente and I have a patient.
Sure.
Come on. Hurry up.
- Transilluminator was MIA, but I...
- Forget that, I got a 24 in the antecube.
Wait. What?
- You two do realize that's a monkey.
- Chimp, actually.
Ninety-six percent
human. Who knew?
So how did this happen?
I was just horsing around.
Looks like you did
a bit more than that.
I got in a fight.
Where? At school?
No, at home. With Dad.
- Did he hit you?
- No, man, he doesn't do that.
So, what were
you fighting about?
I always felt there was something
going on in my house I didn't know about.
Then I met you, and I got it.
It was like... It was
like a cloud was lifted.
But the cloud came back.
- You mean, because I cut off Charlie?
- Not just him, man, you cut me off too.
I don't want it to be like that.
I mean, ain't we brothers?
This may be worse
off than it looks.
Sounds like they need this
room for an actual patient.
Thing they share with humans is a
tendency to get sepsis as neonates.
So let's go with a CBC, D-stick, cultures,
portable chest and 20 cc's per kilo bolus.
Oh, that's all? No Foley, no LP?
Tap might be jumping the
gun, but Foley's not a bad idea.
Hold on a second.
Hello, Dr. Clemente?
- Yes, Eve.
- We're over here in Trauma 2...
with our friend Jessie...
who has multiple
fractures from a fall.
We were just wondering if it would be
possible for you to get your ass in here.
All right, all right, all
right. Shake a leg, okay?
Because if this chimp gets sepsis,
he could crump at any minute.
And lock the door.
We should take core temp.
I'm not sticking anything
up this monkey's ass.
If I had a nickel for
every time I said that...
How about we flip for it?
- Fine.
- The transilluminator's missing a bulb...
but I thought I'd give you a
little help with this sweet little...
Hah! By all that
is good and holy...
what diabolical spell
have you cast on this child?
Dr. Pratt, can you
sign off on this chart?
Who's it for?
The kid in 2, got
into it with his father.
- Wait. What?
- Social work's in with him now.
- You weren't supposed to do a chart.
- I have to.
No, it's not like that.
Eve's strict with this stuff. Suspicion
of abuse, I have to call them in.
- I don't need any help. I'm fine.
- That's not how it looks.
Why do I gotta go
through this with her?
- I'm Dr. Pratt.
- Liz Dade, social work.
- Can I talk to you outside?
- When I'm finished.
- The thing is...
- I'm not finished yet.
Well, I think you should be.
Look, the nurse jumped the gun, okay?
I know this family. It's a stable home.
It's an innocent argument.
The kid got a little too steamed.
- Is that so?
- Yeah.
- And nobody hit anybody?
- I just got real mad at a chair.
That's not gonna do it.
Okay, look here, all
right. He's my brother.
- Okay?
- His brother?
Yeah. Same last
name, check it out.
Why didn't you just say so?
I'll do a follow-up phone call.
- Sally.
- Tom Cruise? Retarded.
- Sammy Sosa's retarded.
Son of a bitch.
- Sam.
- Ah!
- Yeah, I just...
- No, that's all right.
How retarded was that, huh?
Listen, I overheard
you talking to Inez.
Oh. Sorry about that. It's just
sometimes she needs a little guidance.
No, that's okay. I'm
actually really impressed.
You have fantastic
interpersonal skills.
The younger nurses respect
you, the older ones trust you.
Oh. Thanks.
So I think it's time you
moved up the ladder.
What ladder?
Nursing administration.
- I'm pretty happy doing what I'm doing.
- Job wouldn't change much.
You'd help out with staff education,
implementing policies and procedures.
- Sounds like a lot of work.
- There'd be a big pay hike.
- How big?
- Shopping-on-Michigan-Avenue big.
Well, if you put it that
way... When do I start?
Right away. First thing I
need you to do is fire Haleh.
- Hold on. What?
- Welcome to management.
Eve.
- Is it done?
- No.
Inez, how's that pulse
ox probe working out?
Fine.
I'm not gonna fire Haleh.
- Hey, management's a bitch.
- Yeah, not the only one.
You know, Haleh's been warned
three times, twice in writing.
- She has?
- With all the OT she's doing...
we could hire two nurses and still
have enough for a wet bar in the lounge.
Well, then let's counsel her.
Yeah. You're confusing
me with Oprah.
Dr. Clemente, did you sign
in this patient in sutures?
No, no, no. VIP.
What, is he the reincarnation
of the Dalai Lama or something?
No, no, it's a privacy
issue kind of thing.
Well, he still needs to be tracked.
Give me a name, any name.
- Darwin.
- Darwin what?
Magilla.
Are you gonna need a NICU bed?
No, no, because we were transferring
him back to the referring facility.
It's closer to where he lives.
The mom doesn't drive.
I'm not doing it. I don't
need the job that bad.
- Either way, Haleh's gonna go.
- But she's a great nurse.
- You've never fired anyone before.
- No.
All right, okay. It's a new
skill, it needs to be developed.
We'll do it together.
- What?
- Cheer up. It won't be so bad.
Listen, my EMT trainees are
waiting for their 12-lead class.
I'll come find you after.
Hey. Hey, you
left the door open.
All right. So, doctors,
what's the status report?
Heart rate's down. He's
on 100 percent room air.
Took 8 ounces PO.
Oh, that's great. Good
little guy. Good little guy.
Let's ship him out before
they put us on a psych hold.
Shouldn't we keep him a while?
- Yeah, for observation.
- He's awfully young.
Guys, guys, it's just a
bad viral GE. That's all.
We should recheck the cultures.
- A vet can do that.
Well, he's gonna need
another round of antibiotics.
I thought you
didn't like monkeys.
- I never said that.
- And anyway, he's not a monkey.
Okay. I don't know if I'm touched or
if I'm nauseous, but you know what?
We're done here. So D/C the
lock and let's get a move on.
There's a giraffe out
there clogging up triage.
Twelve-year-old
crushed under scaffolding.
- What's your name, little man?
- Barry. Is my pop all right?
Chest injury, respiratory
distress, vitals stable.
- What happened to his father?
- Everything fell.
- Had an MI trying to dig him out.
- Ray, that's you.
- I'll check on him. PRATT:
Both lungs up. Let's go.
- Cardiac arrest during exertion.
- Downtime?
Maybe 12 minutes. Shocked him
three times with epi and atropine.
Full compressions.
Pulse is V-tach.
Let's go, let's go.
Okay, kiddo, deep breath now.
- It hurts.
- A little bit of stridor here.
Pulse ox 92.
Chest, C-spine, pelvis, CBC.
- You hang in there, Bar.
- Thank you, ma'am.
Chem-7, UA, type and screen.
Five hundred cc saline bolus.
Okay. Simon says
squeeze my fingers, pal.
Good man. Now
wiggle those toes for me.
- I'll be right back.
- Oh! I didn't say "Simon says."
Shock again at 360.
- Rhythm.
- I got a pulse. Check the BP.
It's hard to keep track
of the Splenda in here.
- Pupils sluggish but reactive.
- Let's hope for neurological function.
- God.
- What, no response?
- No.
- BP's 100 over 70.
His GCS is only 3.
Fellas, if we save the heart and lose
the brain, we might as well go home.
Worsening respiratory distress in here.
- Okay, I'm coming.
Pop! Pop!
We need to paralyze
and intubate. 6.5 ET tube.
- Yeah, hold on.
- Is he okay?
He will be. Why
is he so stridorous?
Laryngeal injury?
No. No neck injury,
no midline shift.
Okay, give me some
lido and a towel clip.
- Clavicle's displaced?
- I think it's compressing the trachea.
He needs an airway right now.
Draw up etomidate and sux.
- Don't push anything yet.
- Pratt.
So, Barry, what's
your dad building?
Our dream house.
Oh, yeah?
It's for my mom.
That sounds nice, buddy.
Okay, buddy, you're
gonna feel a little stick here.
I'm helping.
Pratt, push the etomidate.
Hold on. I just need
to get a good grip.
Okay. So, Barry, what
kind of house is it?
Craftsman. Ah!
Is he all right?
Sats coming up.
Pulse is normalizing.
Vitals are stable,
tenderness over the lower ribs.
Get a CT abdomen and
chest. What's next door?
V-tach arrest. We got him back.
Is that a robot doctor?
Oh, yeah. We're
very advanced here.
- How's it going?
- He's not waking up.
- We've got ROSC without RONF.
- Come again?
Return of spontaneous circulation
without return of neurologic function.
- The downtime was over 10 minutes.
- Not good enough for brain cells.
- Cath lab?
- No, I don't think so.
- All he's got is a little ST depression.
- I think ICU.
No, no, not yet. We're gonna
go with a portable chest...
- and a cardiac echo.
- What for?
A little ditty I like to call "induced
hypothermia." I'll be right back.
How you doing?
Me? I'm okay.
The board's not too backed
up. You need anything?
No. I'm good.
I kind of like this new energy.
You mean Eve?
She's tough, but it's gonna be
good for all of us in the long run.
Yeah, I hope so.
This new nurse manager's
working out, huh?
She's a terrorist, Neela.
- Zoe.
- Hi. Heh.
Are you looking for Ray?
Oh, no. Actually, I was
hoping you could help me.
Where did you get this thing?
I stole it from the last place I worked
at. Hey, but that's between us, okay?
How cold do you set it?
- Thirty-three degrees centigrade.
- Ninety Fahrenheit.
- Which many consider dangerous.
- We're decreasing his metabolism?
Six percent per degree centigrade.
Might get his brain started again.
What about effect on oxygen
demand in low-flow regions?
The studies show a 23 percent
improvement in neurologic outcome.
Yeah, I'm familiar
with the literature.
Okay, that's it. I'm done
arguing with a television set.
It's believed to suppress
radical formation...
Did you just call me a
television set? That's pretty funny.
This isn't surgical
consult, my friend.
It's believed to suppress
radical formation...
If you can't come to work, I don't
see why we should listen to you.
You little mechanical bitch.
It kind of burns when I pee.
It sounds like a
bladder infection.
Oh, I figured.
You can get it from many
things, like having sex. A lot.
I've been doing that.
Don't I know it.
Look, I hope you don't mind. I just
didn't wanna ask Ray to do this, you know.
It's fine. I'll need a urine
sample and run some tests...
but first I'll need to
get some information.
Name?
Butler. Zoe Butler.
Okay. Address?
1226 Parkington Road.
Okay. Date of birth?
December 12th...
1990.
- Sorry?
- December 12th.
No, I know...
1990.
1990. So you're... 14 years old?
Almost 15.
My birthday's coming up. Heh.
When will he wake up?
Soon, we hope.
He cheated.
On a business trip, with
some lady from work.
When my mom found out, she
wouldn't let him come home for a month.
He lived in a hotel.
You know, parents
make mistakes too.
He's trying to
make it up to her.
Is that what the house is for?
He wants everything
back the way it was.
Barry. Are you okay?
Yeah, Mom. I'm okay.
He's got some broken bones
and a small injury to his liver...
but we don't think
he'll need surgery.
And Paul?
Your husband's
had a heart attack.
His brain's been
deprived of oxygen.
We're doing our best
to help wake him up.
Excuse me.
- What's the big hurry?
- Zoe's here. She's in Exam 2.
- She is?
- Yes, she is.
Oh, and I almost forgot,
she's 14 years old.
- Shut up.
- She was born in 1990, Ray.
What?
That's the decade immediately
preceding the one that we're in.
- Are you for real?
- Yes.
And in prison math, I
believe 14 equals five to ten.
- Where is she?
- Exam 2.
- Okay.
- And here's the kicker, Jerry Lee:
Your prepubescent
penis pal has chlamydia.
I had no idea she
was that young.
Young? She's still teething.
Although, I don't know,
maybe you enjoy that.
She didn't say anything.
How was I supposed to know?
Take her out for a coffee,
converse with her a bit...
before you start boffing
and handing out house keys.
- I don't card my dates, okay?
- Maybe it's time you started.
- 1990?
- It was a very good year for chlamydia.
Hmm.
Why didn't you tell me?
I thought it was a bladder infection
from all the sex we were having.
No. God, not that.
Why didn't you tell
me how old you are?
Well, you never asked. Heh.
- You said you were a student.
- I am.
In what, ninth grade?
Eighth.
But I didn't think you'd
like me if you knew.
Well, you know, you're right.
Because I also don't like
courtrooms and prisons...
and men named Hank
who'd make me their bitch.
What is the big deal?
We like each other.
It's fun. Wait, who's Hank?
Zoe, I'm gonna give you a prescription
for doxycycline for the chlamydia.
You're gonna need to be tested
for a bunch of other STDs, okay?
- Like gonorrhea, syphilis, HIV...
- Sure, whatever.
And under the circumstances,
no parental consent is required.
- That's good.
- Thank God.
Wonder who I got it from.
Not me. Heh.
Whoa. Uh...
- How many other candidates are there?
- Wait, were we being monogamous?
- Starting to shiver.
- All right, try 25 of Demerol, IV push.
- Is his wife coming in?
- Not just yet.
Sam. Ready?
- For what?
- Haleh's in the family room.
Go ahead, I got this.
I'll push the meds.
Wait a second. Wait a second.
- Can we not do this? It's wrong.
- You think I find this enjoyable?
Firing Haleh will send a
message to every nurse in this joint.
Joint? We're not in jail, Eve.
No, but it should
feel like we are.
Haleh.
Is something wrong?
Well, we've had quite a few meetings
about your overtime, right, Haleh?
- Uh-huh.
- And I've discussed...
those meetings with Sam.
Right, Sam?
Yeah, I guess.
Haleh, uh...
you are a wonderful nurse.
And I'm sure that you're
gonna continue to do great work.
But...
It's gonna have to be
at some other hospital.
Excuse me?
It's just that you've been
warned three times and...
We're gonna have to let you go.
You're not serious.
Is she serious?
You can report to HR tomorrow.
You can't do this.
And you can turn in your badge
and you'll collect your last paycheck.
Sam.
Oh, Haleh, I'm so sorry.
- You just getting out?
- Yeah.
I read some magazines.
Never realized a human
esophagus could be so complex.
Hey, look, man. You know,
I'm sorry about all of this.
But you got to understand, it's like this
because of the choices that Charlie made.
It's not all me.
Dad's a hard guy to figure.
I think maybe some stuff
happened that he never talked about.
Maybe so.
I think there's some stuff
you don't know too, Greg.
Some stuff that maybe your
mom didn't tell you the truth about.
Is that what he told you?
Yeah.
Radiology faxed
down these results.
I just got here,
Frank. What patient?
It's me, actually.
I had a mammogram
last week. It's normal.
- Oh.
- Hey, congratulations.
I'm out of here.
The kid in 1's stable.
- You watching the dad?
- Yeah, I'm on the case.
Frank, will you forward
anything for me to my house?
Of course.
We're all really sorry, Haleh.
Thanks.
I'll try to come
by for a visit...
when I'm up to it.
- Take care.
- Bye, Haleh.
What? ALL: Nothing.
- What happened?
- Sam fired Haleh.
Oh, screw you, Frank.
Eve fired her. I just...
Helped?
I'm sorry. That's the
word on the street.
- Eve's making a statement?
- And all the words are dirty.
- Lockhart.
- Abby.
Code banana. Our
VIP's bouncing back.
Haleh.
Wait.
Haleh, I feel
terrible about this.
Who covered for you all those
times your kid was in trouble?
How many shifts were you
late or had to leave early?
And now you're gonna fire
me for too much overtime?
For what, Sam?
A couple extra
hundred bucks a month.
You calling her a liar?
- I don't know who you mean.
- My mother.
Isn't that what you said?
- Slow down, son.
- Don't you ever call me that.
Ever.
You wanna talk about
why you're upset?
I'm not one of those
little CeaseFire punks...
you've convinced you have
wisdom. Don't forget, I know you.
You're not a lesson or a
role model for anybody.
You don't know everything. How it
all went down when you were little.
- I don't wanna talk about it.
- Then why the hell are you here?
You've already lost one son. Don't
make the same mistake with Chaz.
- You come to give me advice?
- Don't bring him into this.
Okay? Don't talk
to him about it.
He asked. He needed to know.
Know what? Know
what, how you spin it?
Some nonsense about a dead
woman who happens to be my mother?
She wasted her life away taking
care of me with no help from you.
- Nothing.
- I tried to come back.
She wouldn't let me.
Look. I can see we
both had rough days.
- Let's not do this tonight.
- Hey, don't turn away from me.
You can come by the
house some other time.
There's something of your
mother's I think you should have.
You've got something of hers?
It belongs to me and her.
Maybe they belong with you now.
Whatever it is, I want it.
You heard what I said. You
can come by the house...
Right now.
He started breathing hard again,
so I brought him right back here.
- I thought you said he was okay.
- He was, Alonzo.
He looked great after the bolus.
He was drinking and playing.
- Bag him. He's not moving air.
- Maybe you should've kept him longer.
No, he seemed buffed after the fluid.
We thought it was just dehydration.
I promised Cookie's
owners he'd be okay.
- Who's Cookie?
- Darwin's mom.
She belongs to this super-nice
couple from Evanston.
- I also keep their llama.
- BP 66 over 25.
He's got hypotension with
a widened pulse pressure.
- Sepsis.
- Dopamine at 10 mics.
He's got a bacterial
infection in his blood.
- But you gave antibiotics.
- Which rupture the bacteria...
releasing endotoxins which
can make things worse.
- Suction.
- I'm so sorry, man.
I thought he was doing
too well to be septic.
Suction.
Okay, tube. PVCs.
Maybe you could
put him on a vent.
We're doing the best we can.
Okay. I'm in.
- My God, I lost the pulse.
- V-tach.
Please don't stop. These
people really love this little guy.
- I think you should call it.
- Charge to 10 joules. Starting CPR.
Don't you wanna come in?
No.
You don't have your keys?
- Hey.
- Chaz, you okay?
Yeah, Dad.
I gotta get
something for your...
For Greg.
- Hey, what's up, man?
- What's up, man?
I just wanted to go talk to him.
- Because of me?
- It's fine.
Chaz?
- Why don't you come in?
- No, I...
Chaz, dinner's on the table.
My mom's mac and cheese.
But I swear to God, it's the
best you ever tasted in your life.
- Heh.
- Come on, man.
Hey.
I'm sorry.
Why? Because I talked
myself into liking some groupie...
who turned out to be
Hilary Duff with an STD?
- I know you liked her.
- Mm.
I'm an idiot.
The bright side is your urine dip
came back negative for chlamydia.
Oh. Well, she must have gotten it from
another rock star she was partying with.
Probably one with
a recording deal.
I should probably
still swab you.
I used a condom, Neela.
Did you also use a dental dam?
Well...
Neela, your top-secret baby's
back. Abby needs you in sutures.
Okay.
Going again. Clear.
- Still V-tach.
- What happened?
- I don't know. Resuming compressions.
- Septic shock.
- How long since the last epi?
- Two minutes. Another round of lido?
- No.
- Are you sure you don't want another?
We've been doing this for 35
minutes. His brain's gotta be fried.
No. Keep going.
He's been through
enough. I... We gotta stop.
His heart's still beating.
It's more like a twitch.
It's not actually pumping
any blood to his body.
So that's it?
Just about.
He's fading.
Then I'll go get Cookie.
- Sorry?
- His mother.
If he's dying, she
should be here with him.
Her baby was taken from her.
She needs to understand why.
Anybody says "next of
kin," I'm gonna lose it.
I think you've already lost it.
Because I tried to help a
guy and it didn't work out?
Just game over, that's all.
In it this far, why
not let the mother in?
There's no need.
There was no need to treat
a chimp, but here we are.
The chimp was sick. Mom
is a little depressed, maybe?
It's the humane thing to do.
Forget it. You guys are
getting carried away with this.
Oh, come on. You're the one that
started this whole monkey business.
I didn't mean to say that.
Thank you, Lord, for the
blessings we are about to receive.
Look over those now
who cannot be with us...
including the countrymen who fight
to protect us in an overseas war...
founded on lies told to
us by our government.
- Jocelyn.
- And we welcome Greg...
and thank you, Lord, for bringing
him into our home and family.
Amen.
- Amen.
So why do you have that walker,
if you don't mind me asking?
I had a little fall.
Broke my hip.
Little? I was so scared when I
found her, I thought she was dead.
She was laying there:
I still have a ways to
go with my recovery.
Where'd you get your surgery?
County.
Must be downstairs.
It'll only take a minute.
Um, excuse me for a minute.
Why didn't you tell
me about Evelyn?
That she was the one at County
that day. Maybe I could've helped.
You didn't seem in
the mood for helping.
Here.
A bunch of things that
I sent your mother...
that she sent back.
A few notes she wrote me.
And this.
Hmm.
An act of mercy, her
sending me that picture.
I don't even remember
when this was taken.
I made mistakes, Greg.
I never denied it.
Got busted for some stupid petty
stuff and went away for a while.
Regretted it ever since.
But life is more
complicated than you think.
No respiratory effect.
Yeah, well, it
won't be long now.
Is he in pain? - No.
Ahem. I'm gonna give another
milligram of morphine just in case.
What? I just wanna make
sure he's comfortable.
Okay, I'm sorry. No, no, let go.
Thanks.
GCS is up from 4 to 11.
He's blinking on command,
starting to move his fingers.
See, sometimes you're good
and then sometimes you're lucky.
- Which one is this?
- This is "sometimes you're not sure."
- We're waiting on ICU.
- Good, good.
Hey. Why don't you
go bring his kid in?
Yeah.
Hey.
You know, patients come and go.
And some days, some of
them don't even register to me.
So how is it that a hairy little chimp
crumps on the table and it's like...?
In any case, it sounds
like you'll forgive me.
- For what?
- Well...
There's gonna be some
kind of disciplinary...
suspension.
- What, did Eve found out?
- She's not an animal lover.
No, more like an
animal strangler.
It's funny, because when I was a kid, I
always wanted a robot and a monkey.
- That doesn't shock me.
- No, no, I'm serious.
- Me too.
- Well, I'm over it.
Spontaneous eye movement.
That's a very good sign, Lockhart.
My name's Abby.
Yeah, I know.
Jodie. Jodie, if you call me
one more time, I swear to God...
Well, you just gotta
stop that nonsense.
No, I'm not in New York. Why
would I tell you where I'm at?
Yeah. Why would I tell you?
Yeah, because you're...
Every time that...
You're the... Hey.
Hey, hey.
You sure are getting
good at finding me.
Yeah.
I talked to Olivia.
This was our house.
I used to play out here.
She would watch
me from the window.
So you tried to come back.
She pushed you away.
She lied to you. She lied to me.
And no, I didn't know any of it.
But the question is, what did you
do to make her hate you so much?
I got into trouble.
Maybe she felt she
was protecting you.
When I got out of the pen,
I wanted us to be a family.
I was still a kid when she
died. What about then?
I was living in
Gary with Evelyn.
I came here to find you.
But they told me you had gone to
Detroit with your cousin's people.
So you gave up?
That was the
biggest mistake of all.
But I had a second life that
I was trying to hold together.
I've done my penance.
I do it every day.
But there's only one person
I still need forgiveness from.
Tsk.
I hear you.
I hear everything that you say.
But you and me, we're here now.
None of that other
stuff matters anymore.
Because even if the
story's more complicated...
than the one I spent the
last 20 years believing...
you still were not there for me.
And I don't give a damn
why or who said what.
- Hey, Greg...
- You were not here.
Please listen to me.
And we can never change that.
We can fix it.
Never, man.
But...
Never.