Previously
on "New Amsterdam"...
I love you.
They keep hammering on
at you to open up,
but that has to go both ways.
And even though my body
is telling me
to just let go and jump,
I can't.
Not even for you.
I gave Chance everything.
I just wanted him
to get better.
But it was never enough.
If you don't
have to fight for it,
it's 'cause it's not worth it.
♪
Leave a message
after the tone.
Hey.
It's, uh, me.
I... I miss you.
I can't get you
out of my head.
It's, uh,
it's very distracting.
Um...
We said things to each other
that were just the beginning.
And we never quite, um...
Anyway, now you're gone,
and it just feels like
it's been forever.
And I really need...
I need to see you.
I need to talk to you.
I need to be with you
in all of the ways
that I've been dreaming of.
And we're done.
All right. Easy enough.
Everything looks good,
Dr. Goodwin.
Fantastic.
- Thank you so much.
- See you in six months.
Is everything okay?
Have you seen my wedding ring?
Sure haven't.
I need to see you.
I need to talk to you.
I need to be with you
in all of the ways
that I've been dreaming of.
And this one's too tight.
Everything looks terrible
on me.
- Oh, stop that.
You're just nervous.
- Wonder why.
It's only the beginning
of the rest of my whole life.
Hey. You've reached Max.
I can't take your call,
so leave a message.
Hi. Um.
I very much
enjoyed your message.
My flight's not till tomorrow,
but, um...
I've been doing
some fantasizing of my own.
Okay.
I'm ready. I think.
- You can't be serious.
- Oh, don't sound so surprised.
I was never gonna
stay here forever.
- But today?
But today?
I'm gonna try and catch
a standby flight.
But I wanted you to come back
to Cambridge with me.
I know.
I've had a wonderful time.
But you're all set up
in the halls.
You have an amazing dress.
And most importantly,
you don't need me anymore.
I'm so proud of you.
You took me into your home.
You never gave up on me.
I don't know how to thank you.
You don't need to.
We're family.
And text me when you're
at the airport, okay?
I will.
I just have
one more stop to make.
Sorry I'm late, Mum.
Now that you're here,
we can leave.
I made you some red-red.
No use spending hard-earned
money on beetroot foam.
Well, let me
do this for you, Mum.
It's a meal.
And it's really good
to see you.
Glad you found time
to fit me in.
Yeah, uh, Nina got
into King's College
in Cambridge.
It's been a busy week.
I wanted to help her
get set up.
So, the truth comes out.
Mum, she is wonderful.
She's smart, she's driven,
and she is family.
And since I'm going back
to New York,
I put you down
as her emergency contact,
and I think that
if you would just meet her...
- Not on your life.
- Mum.
You say no all the time.
No to London,
no husband, no baby.
Why must I say yes?
But please, daughter, give me
that other woman's grandchild.
We are blood.
And since Baba
was kept away from me...
I didn't keep
your father from you.
He cut off ties.
He went home to Tehran
and found his ready-made
Persian wife.
He abandoned us.
Okay, so now what?
Hmm?
We abandon her?
You spent the past week
ignoring your own mother
for that other family.
Turns out you're
just like your baba.
Mum, how long have you
had that cough?
A few weeks.
Or more.
You'd know if you ever rang.
- Come on.
We're gonna go, Mum.
Come on.
This is your old clinic.
Yes.
It's certainly seen
better days.
Excuse me. Hi.
Hi, I was hoping to get my mum
in today for some scans.
She's had a persistent cough,
and today we found some blood.
We're booked solid,
I'm afraid.
I could maybe get her in
early next week.
This is why
I never bother with doctors.
No, Mum, wait, wait.
Uh, sorry. Excuse me.
My name is Dr. Helen Sharpe.
I used to volunteer here
when I was in college.
I started behind the desk,
just like you,
but this clinic
is where I found my passion,
and now I'm pleading with you.
I need to make sure
that my mum gets seen.
I can move things around.
Thank you. Thank you.
No, I don't want
any special treatment.
I don't like my daughter
pulling strings
just so we can jump the queue.
Mum, we are taking
the opening
whether you like it or not.
End of discussion.
- Right this way.
I'll take you back.
Thank you.
No, I don't need you
to come with me.
I can do this all on my own.
Helen?
As I live and breathe.
Elinor.
I didn't know
you were still here.
- There's still work to do.
What's your excuse?
No more New York?
- My mum's sick.
She's getting seen.
Can I just ask? Um...
This place... what happened?
We started hemorrhaging staff
due to Brexit.
And then we lost the funding
we used to get from Cambridge,
and it all started
to fall apart.
Last month, our medical
director packed up and left.
Now we're fighting to hold on.
This place is too special
to just...
Dr. Sharpe, can you join me?
It was good
to see you, Elinor.
- Oh, you too, love.
- Mm-hmm.
Thank you.
I'm right here, Mum.
I'm not going anywhere.
So I just wanted you
to see what we found today.
Run blood tests on Bay 26,
and let's send her up
for a stress echo.
Why hasn't Bay 9
been discharged?
- Because I possibly forgot.
On it.
Hey, have you, uh,
have you heard from Iggy?
Uh, no. Not in weeks. You?
- Radio silence.
I've been thinking about him.
But... uh, what's up?
- Nothing. Stupid.
I lost my wedding ring.
- Yikes.
- Yeah.
But it's okay. No big deal.
I mean, it's not like
it's worth
a ton of money or anything.
It's just a little silly ring,
you know?
But it's gotta be in here
somewhere.
Okay, who loses one shoe?
Well, where did you
take it off?
I... I don't take it off.
- Not even at night?
- No.
- Well, what about to scrub in?
Not even when you were
dating that woman?
- Never. Okay?
I never take it off.
26-year-old. Tachy at 148.
100/56, respiratory rate 14
from an abdominal stab wound.
- From Excalibur?
- Cosplay gone horribly wrong.
Oh, that's a ton of blood
for a wound in that area.
Let's page Reynolds now.
Trauma one.
Gauze.
Gauze. Gauze. Gauze.
Damn it, keep them coming.
The puncture's bad,
but it shouldn't cause
loss of consciousness.
Dr. Bloom, look at this.
Negative P waves?
And negative QRS,
and T waves, plus low voltage?
What the hell?
Dextrocardia.
Her heart's on the wrong side
of her chest.
Boy, do I have
a great case for you.
Dextrocardia doesn't explain
the excessive bleeding.
Unless she also has
complete situs inversus.
Not just her heart, but all
of her organs were flipped.
Then her spleen
is on the right side.
Which means the dagger
is going right through it.
But that doesn't
explain the LOC.
Stop for a head CT
on your way to the OR.
Good idea.
- Hey, you.
What's going on?
The residency match list
came out.
I got a spot.
- You did?
Oh, that's amazing.
I honestly can't believe it.
Well, don't look
so surprised.
- Have you met you?
- Stop.
You know how competitive
these things are.
And it was my very first try.
And I'm
a foreign-trained doctor.
And you blew them all away.
Well, not all.
I didn't get a spot here.
But we knew that was
gonna be a long shot.
Wait, you didn't
get a spot here?
- Spokane.
Washington.
- Wow.
That's incredible.
It is, isn't it?
I haven't even told my mom yet.
Well, what are you
waiting for?
Give her a call.
Let her be a proud mama.
She's gonna explode.
So, you just chose
to ignore
my residency recommendation
for Leyla Shinwari.
I have been on the phone
all morning with board members
and angry doctors
just like yourself,
all astonished
that their personal recs
didn't open the doors
for their hand-picked proteges.
No, Dr. Shinwari is one of
the most promising candidates
we've had in years, okay?
She deserves to be here.
Yet her application
says otherwise.
Khyber Medical University?
One of the best
medical schools in Pakistan.
That has no
international standing.
She practiced medicine
in refugee camps, Hank.
Okay?
The fact that she even
has to redo her residency
is offensive.
Well, even if I agree
with you, what can I do?
I... I can't rescind an offer
that's already been made.
I can't make another spot
just magically appear.
- Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Well, what about two years ago?
Huh?
A fifth spot just magically
opened up in general surgery.
It was hardly magic.
Well then,
what the hell was it, Hank?
You want Dr. Shinwari
on your ED?
You want a fifth spot?
The dean of medicine
has been known
to make allowances
for the right price.
Are you talking
about a bribe?
What do you want me to say?
That is a federal crime,
Hank.
I could lose
my medical license.
I could go to jail.
I'm just telling you
what I've heard.
Not suggesting you do it.
Of course,
I am not gonna do it.
Dear God...
Grant me the serenity
to accept the things
I cannot change,
the courage
to change the things I can.
Dear God,
grant me the serenity
to accept the things
I cannot change,
the courage
to change the things I can...
And the wisdom
to know the difference.
This is just...
Thank you.
Congratulations.
Look, I have been
feeling guilty all day.
Why?
I was just so excited.
I didn't even think about what
you must have been feeling.
And I want you to know that I'm
not excited to be leaving you.
- You're everything to me.
- Leyla.
I can make this work.
I can.
I don't have a choice.
I'm in love with you.
No, you should...
You should get that.
- Are you sure?
- Yeah. Yeah.
Hello?
Yes, this is she.
Okay. Okay.
Are you serious?
That's...
I don't know what to say.
Yes! Yes. Thank you.
That was the residency director
from New Amsterdam.
The dean just opened up
a fifth spot in the ED.
And they offered it to me.
- That's amazing!
Congratulations!
Did you have anything
to do with this?
- What? No.
No, of course not.
No, this... this was all you.
Oh.
It was all you.
I moved across Lenox,
not the country.
I'll still see you
all the time, Mama.
Okay, yeah, just...
Try to remember I'm not
a little boy anymore, okay?
House special.
- Oh, what?
- Bam.
Oh, my gosh.
Mmm.
If I didn't know any better,
I'd say you're trying
to get me to move in.
Would that be so bad?
Mm, all right. Okay. Okay.
- What?
- You know the rules.
I also know that rules
are meant to be broken.
And we have.
You get one stay.
Somewhere along the line,
this turned into Thursday.
- Okay.
Look, look, I get it.
I tried to resist you
for months, right?
Finally had to give in.
Now look who can't resist.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Of course I'd fall
for two alpha males.
Oh, okay, hold on.
No, I got a rule, too,
all right?
None of that husband talk.
Come here.
- Floyd.
- Yeah.
This is the arrangement.
We can never be more than this.
Tell me you know that.
Yeah, I know.
I am going to take a shower.
Dextrocardia doesn't explain
the excessive bleeding.
Not just her heart, but all
of her organs are flipped.
Then her spleen
is on the right side.
Which means the dagger is
plunging straight through it.
But that doesn't
explain the LOC.
Stop for a head CT
on your way to the OR.
- Good idea.
All right.
I'll need the largest OR
that's empty
and every unit of O-neg we got.
Already ordered
and waiting for you.
- Okay, good.
We'll also need a fresh staff
that can work
at least 12 hours.
This one's gonna be a marathon.
- I'll round them up.
- I've got a full craniotomy
- set up on order for you.
- Oh!
Perfect timing.
I'll take her from here.
- Wait. What?
- Dr. Salaita.
The CT showed Ms. Madera
threw a clot from her abdomen
up through her poorly-formed
heart to her brain,
where it caused
a hemorrhagic event.
You'll need to drain the blood
from her head.
Our team's waiting,
Dr. Baptiste.
Okay, get a scanner in here
so you can do a real-time,
image-guided surgery.
They'll never let me have
the IGS system, sir.
Tell them
the chief of surgery
personally authorized it.
Dr. Flores, gather your team
for the septal reconstruction.
You'll be last,
so just wait in the obs deck.
- Will do, sir.
- And you.
You're the associate
ED trauma surgeon?
- Dr. Reynolds. Yes, sir.
- Let's see what you've got.
- All right, here we go.
Get the lap pads ready.
- Dagger's out.
- Replaced by blood.
There's gotta be a bleeder
in here somewhere.
- Whew.
- Another lap pad.
- Still can't see it.
Come on.
Come on. Come on.
Got it. Suture.
Monitor the systolic pulse...
With situs inversus,
we got small mini-spleens
all through her abdomen.
Once I get this under control,
I can remove them.
No need; I'll do it myself
during the brain surgery.
Did you get a CT angio to
locate the accessory spleens?
Scissors. I did not.
You know what they say:
death begins in radiology.
standing by.
That should hold.
I can assist
in the splenectomy.
You're dismissed.
Where's my neuro team?
You guys are up.
Make sure
there's enough blood...
Switch up.
Do you dry clean?
Got a couple of shirts
that could use a press.
- Lost my wedding ring.
- Oof.
Well, you didn't have it
on this morning, if that helps.
You notice who's
wearing a wedding ring?
Recently.
I have looked
everywhere for it.
I'm gonna be sifting through
medical waste pretty soon.
I guess I just assumed
you took it off on purpose.
No.
I don't know.
Still means something, I guess.
I mean, it's everything we had,
you know?
It's like... come on,
it can't just be gone.
Actually, uh, I felt
the same way about Evie's ring
after we, uh, you know.
So what changed?
Well, I realized I wasn't
hanging on to Evie's ring
because she still had
a big piece of my heart.
I was hanging on to it
because she didn't.
And the ring wasn't
about our love anymore.
It was about my guilt.
Dr. Reynolds, Dr. Flores
needs you in the OR, stat.
- Flores?
- I'm trying to pull off
a triangular patch
reconstruction
of the ventricular wall.
You've done one?
- Several times.
- I just can't get it to hold.
- All right. I got it.
- BP's still dropping.
We need to increase
patch adhesion
to seal
microcirculatory leakage.
Go ahead and clamp
the inferior vena cava.
I'm gonna apply
direct pressure.
On my signal,
I want you to squeeze
the largest piece
of spleen you can fine.
- Mm-hmm.
- All right?
Ready. Now.
Okay.
All right, so go ahead and
slowly release the vena cava.
All right.
Now increase the flow.
Gently. Ah. Slow it down.
Okay. And all the way.
- I don't see any leaking.
- Nice save, Floyd.
We'll close her up.
Dr. Reynolds.
After surgery,
may I have a word?
Get another blanket
on her leg.
- Custodial services, 224.
Custodial services, 224.
I've only been here
a little while, so tell me.
How'd you end up buried deep
in the ED...
Please, please, have a seat...
Associate trauma surgeon?
It's the only spot
I could get.
You never mentioned
you used to be
the chair
of cardiothoracic surgery?
So what happened?
Well,
I left about a year ago.
Poached?
Engaged.
Yeah, my fiancée got
her dream job in San Francisco,
so I followed.
Long story short, I'm back.
We got a lot in common.
I followed my girl
out here too.
But one big difference: my job
makes full use of my talents.
- Yours doesn't.
- Well, I'm not complaining.
And I'm not insulting.
I'm offering you a promotion.
Deputy chair of surgery.
That's a big promotion.
Bigger than
chair of cardiothoracic.
To say the least.
- Is that a yes?
- Oh, yes, it is. Thank you.
I... I don't know what to say,
but thank you.
- You're welcome.
You're welcome.
Knock, knock.
Hey, sweetheart.
Hey.
Dr. Reynolds, Dr. Lyn Malvo,
my wife, the one who lured me
to New Amsterdam.
Nice to meet you.
Floyd's gonna be
my new right-hand man.
Wow. Congratulations.
♪ 37 bottles of juice
on the wall ♪
♪ You take one down,
pass it around ♪
♪ 36 bottles
of juice on the wall ♪
♪ 36 bottles of juice
♪ You take one down,
pass it around ♪
♪ 35 bottles
of juice on the wall ♪
Air guitar version!
♪ 35 bottles of juice
on the wall ♪
♪ Take one down,
pass it around ♪
♪ 34 bottles of juice
on the wall ♪
And cut. Papa needs a break.
No, guys, let's sing
some harmonies, come on.
Or we can enjoy
the meditative silence
of a solid 45 minutes
of screen time.
Yes!
Boo. Boo.
All right,
dinner is in one hour.
Tell your brothers and sister.
- Okay, when I'm done.
- Oh, "When I'm done."
When she's done.
- She sassing you?
- Yeah.
Gosh.
You know, I hate to say it,
but I think, um,
I think we've been
COVID-blessed out here, babe.
- Yeah.
- You know, look at us.
We're out here being a family,
camping, making slingshots,
she's giving you sass.
I love it.
Kind of begs the question,
why don't we just
stay here indefinitely?
Uh, Iggy.
I'm just having
a little fantasy.
- Let me have my fantasy.
- All right.
Look, the kids are going back
to in-person learning
full-time.
I need to get back
to my practice,
and you need to get back
to the hospital.
Yeah, well, what if
I'm not ready to go back?
So, uh, we're gonna live out
of a rented RV
- in upstate New York?
- Pfft, no.
I thought maybe we'd live
out of a rented RV
in upstate Vermont next.
What?
You can't just
keep running, Iggs.
I'm not.
Help! Help!
Ah!
Dad!
What happened?
- Come on. Come on.
- Dad! Dad!
- Please!
- Father!
- Ow.
- Slow down. Slow down.
Splinter.
- Show us.
- Oh. Oh. Whoa.
Mamacita, you took
some shrapnel there, buddy.
Okay, but fortunately for you,
our crack team
- of surgeons are at the ready.
- Yeah.
Harper, bring me
the instruments of abscission.
- What?
- That old rusty saw
we found by the dumpster.
- You know what they are.
- Dad!
Saleem, bring me a towel
for all the blood
and a bucket to put
the severed limb in, stat.
- You got it.
- Dad, be serious.
- I... kid, I am being serious.
This is war, all right?
Here you go.
I promise you it'll be over
in a couple seconds, okay?
Harper, look away.
Nobody move. Nobody breathe.
Except for me.
I have to breathe, obviously.
I'm the doctor.
Here we go. Almost there.
- Yes.
- Oh!
- Victory.
- Look at that beast.
Whoa.
- Look at that thing.
That was inside your finger.
- Disgusting.
- I'll say.
That is a serious
piece of timber.
Actually, don't throw
that away.
We might want to ride that
down the Susquehanna later.
We're a big family.
Probably sink with all of us.
- Oh yeah, right.
Not with me as a captain.
- We have five family members.
- You are brave, private.
Sameera?
I need you
to bandage this soldier.
- Sameera.
What, did she go back
to the car?
- Uh, I don't know.
Did you guys see Sameera?
Sameera.
- She was just here.
She couldn't have gone far.
- Sameera!
Sameera.
All right, um, you take
- everybody back to the RV.
- Hon.
No, no, I'm gonna
go look for her.
You find out where the nearest
ranger station is, okay?
- Guys, guys, stay close.
Stay close.
- Sameera.
- Sameera!
Sammy!
Sameera!
Sameera?
Sameera, baby!
Sameera!
Oh, God.
Oh, God, no.
Sameera!
Sameera?
Sameera, honey.
I'm coming.
Sameera, honey?
Sameera, if you can hear me,
answer me, baby.
Sameera!
Sameera.
Oh, my God.
Did you... baby, did you not
hear me calling you?
Why didn't you answer me?
Sameera, honey, say something.
I don't want to go back.
You don't want... you don't
wanna go back where?
You don't want to go back
to the campsite?
You don't wanna...
Back to normal.
Back to normal?
What is it?
Is it school? Are you...
I like school better
on the computer.
I learn better.
Yeah.
Yeah, but what about
your friends, baby?
What about all them?
I'd rather be here
with you and Papa,
eating lunch together,
playing together.
Everything's easier at home.
Yeah.
Yeah. I like it too.
So why do we have
to go back?
Well, because...
Because it's not
supposed to be easy.
You know, asking your teacher
for help over and over again,
that helps you become
more resilient.
Navigating tricky friendships,
even though it's a pain
in your butt,
that builds self-esteem,
you know?
Life is starting again.
We can't stay here
where it's easy.
Make sense, kiddo?
Well, that was
quite the adventure.
- Oh, my God, that one...
- It's roasted.
- You okay?
- Oh, my God.
Yeah, yeah.
You know,
when Sameera went missing,
I just had
these visions of Chance.
Hurting her.
- Iggy...
- I know. I know.
I know it's irrational.
I know that in my heart.
There he was, you know,
clear as day.
Yes! It's golden.
And why not?
You know, day after day,
I just absorbed his despair.
It all just became
a part of me.
All my patients,
all their despair,
it just... it just becomes
a part of me.
But it was all worth it,
you know,
because at the end of the day,
I can just trade
my peace of mind for
the self-esteem it brought me.
Easy-peasy.
I don't wanna
make that trade anymore.
I don't... I don't need to.
Look at this.
Look at what we've done.
Martin, you give me
everything that I need.
Our family gives me...
Everything.
We can go home
whenever you need to.
No more running. I promise.
But I am not going
to see patients anymore.
I'm done with that life.
Watch it... I got mine on fire.
I knew you hated
budget meetings,
but this seems extreme.
I lost my wedding ring.
Max. Come out from there.
- I can't do it.
- Come on.
Mm-mm.
I mean, rings do hold
a certain amount
of symbolic power over us.
- Don't they?
- Yeah.
- I should know.
I've had three.
Three. You get it.
Oh, Max, I get it.
You feel like you're losing
a limb.
Part of your life.
And if it can be lost
that easily,
then what does that say?
Says you didn't deserve it.
All right,
come out of there now.
- Come on.
- Do I have to?
Yes.
If I've learned anything...
It's knowing
when to let them go.
When to move on.
I want to move on. I do.
But I didn't get
to make that decision.
That choice was taken from me.
She'd understand.
Max.
Look at me.
She'd understand.
I almost took it off.
On the anniversary of her...
Why didn't you?
Because when I look at Luna,
I don't even
see Georgia anymore.
I just see my little girl.
And when I look inside,
Georgia's not there either.
That ring...
It's all I have left...
Of our whole life.
Well, it didn't just
slip off your finger.
There's a reason
you took it off.
Maybe you should trust
your subconscious.
- Yeah.
Yeah.
Like I'm trying
to tell myself something.
- Found it.
- What? Really? Wow! Yes!
You're amazing. Thank you.
I gotta go.
Sorry. Wow. I... thank you.
Thank you,
Sandra Fall from billing.
Where did you find it?
- Your office.
In the pocket of your lab coat.
Oh, many lives were
saved today in this building,
but nothing as heroic
as what you just...
Yeah, I'm aware.
Sorry.
That was almost a pile-up.
Um...
- You're... you're here.
- Yes.
Six hours in a middle seat
that wouldn't recline.
- Oh. Rough.
I'm... I'm glad that you're back.
- Though a bit wrung out.
- Same.
- Why? Did something happen?
- No, no.
I just... I lost my wedding ring
for a minute, but...
Ah.
Kind of freaked me out,
but found it, so...
I see.
I spent the day with my mum
in a cancer clinic.
Oh, God, Helen.
No, no, she's fine,
but for hours,
I thought it was lung cancer.
But turns out it was just,
um, severe bronchitis.
That's a relief.
Do you want... do you wanna
walk with me?
You can tell me
about your "mum."
Did I say that right?
Came out weird.
I'm a little bit talked out
today, I think.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
Yeah.
Me too, to be honest.
Maybe too much
was said already.
Helen.
Can I just walk with you?
We don't need to talk. I...
♪ Maybe there's
another way around ♪
♪ So we can
live this upside-down ♪
♪ It's hard now
for an honest man ♪
♪ Is that what I am?
♪ An honest man?
♪ You're the kind who seems
♪ Too beautiful
and out of reach ♪
♪ For me
♪ I'm in
♪ I've got you
underneath my skin ♪
♪ I fall apart
♪ To look away
is getting hard ♪
All right.
Well, here I am.
♪ Maybe we could just
let go ♪
♪ And say yes
♪ When the signs say no
♪ Breathe in
♪ Lean to kiss your lips
I should go.
♪ Then my eyes eclipse
Okay.
- Night.
- ♪ And it all goes dark
Night.
♪ You're the kind
You said that.
Okay.
♪ Too beautiful
and out of reach for me ♪
♪ I've got you
underneath my skin ♪
♪ I fall apart
♪ To look away
is getting hard ♪
♪ Oh, you're the kind
♪ Who seems
♪ Too beautiful
and out of reach ♪
♪ For me
♪ I'm in
♪ I've got you
underneath my skin ♪
♪ I fall apart
♪ To look away
♪ Is getting hard
♪ Oh, you're the kind
♪ Who seems
♪ Too beautiful
and out of reach for me ♪
♪ I'm in
♪ I've got you
underneath my skin ♪
♪ I fall apart
♪ To look away
is getting hard ♪
♪ Oh