You don't have
to leave. It's okay.
Well, do you want
some breakfast?
You don't have to do this.
I'm sorry. I know
I'm not supposed
to sleep over. I
was just so tired.
I thought I was gonna
close my eyes for a second.
It's okay.
It's not. I totally
agree with you.
This is casual. It's not about
snuggling in the morning.
It's easy. That's me. Easy
peasy lemon squeezy.
Leah, I was gonna order some
food, so if you want some...
I'm fine. I gotta
go find a costume
for this thing at
Joe's tonight, so...
That's right. It's Halloween.
Happy...
Every Halloween,
we make a choice
about what kind of
costume we're going to wear.
Something sexy...
Morning. Oh, good.
Can you take these?
There's a rip in
the bottom left.
Oh. I just finished an APPY,
and I was going to
do it in the 20 minutes
before my lap chole...
Mmm-hmm. But I
need to get on the phone
and order a 3D printer.
Your grant got
approved? That's great.
Yeah, it is, except it's a conflict
with a butterfly wing repair.
Well, I need to solve
my array problem today.
If I can figure out how
to shrink the craniotomy,
I should be able to avoid a lot of
the infections that we're getting.
Okay, well, this will only
take you four minutes.
I know. I'm just telling
you about my day.
Oh, well, I did not factor
that into the schedule.
And trick-or-treating
still on tonight?
Uh, of course, of course.
Maybe we'll be someone scary...
Alex, did you get the
house ready? Yep.
Okay. Candy? No.
Did you get the pumpkins? No.
Did you put up the
spider webs? No.
Then how is the house
ready? I got the keg.
Oh, you're having a
party at the house?
Um...
Yeah. Alex is letting us use
the house to trick-or-treat from,
because we have no
neighbors where we are,
so I invited a bunch of
families from the daycare.
He didn't tell you? No.
Oh, you should come.
It's fine.
Right. Well, you don't wanna
be around a bunch of kids
hopped-up on sugar
anyway, right? Right.
'Cause I hate
children. Cristina.
But I love your kids.
I should have invited you.
I'm sorry. I just thought...
But you should come
for a drink. It's at 7:00.
She's gonna be a butterfly.
I have to go. I
have a lap chole.
Or you could be a superhero,
which is what I'm trying to be this year.
How many fingers?
Three. Hangnail
on the index finger.
No side effects?
My uncle had LASIK,
like, three years ago.
He still has
horrible facial pain
and he's basically
addicted to painkillers.
Leah. Well, your uncle probably
came back to work too early
and didn't take the two days
off that the doctor recommended.
I am a second-year resident.
Sixteen hours is already more
recovery time than I can afford.
Go work. Leave me alone.
Bye.
How's it going with Alex?
Radio silence.
Still? I think it's over.
Well, I don't believe that,
and I have extraordinary vision.
Literally and figuratively.
Come on. Time to
go round on Webber.
Ow!
Are you sure you
don't want to go home?
Okay.
Hey, kids. You got Halloween plans?
- I'll take it.
Yeah, Matthew's having a
thing. I'm going as a bunny.
Ooh. Playboy? Uh, Velveteen.
Needs work.
How about you, Lone Ranger?
Are you and Emma going out?
Uh, Emma and I
are no longer a thing.
What? Why?
Well, it's just too
soon. I'm not ready.
Yes, you are.
Emma doesn't think so,
because I never mentioned
being married before.
She said, "Call me
when you're ready."
You're ready. Don't
you think he's ready?
Well, maybe he's ready,
but he's not ready to call.
What's the difference?
He's ready. You should...
Hmm.
He's not ready. Not ready.
Hey, um, I have the costume in my
car. What time do you wanna meet?
No, I have the costume.
Oh, please, don't tell me we
have two astronaut costumes.
We don't. We have a princess.
What? Yeah.
That's what you... You want
her to strive to be a princess?
No, it's what she wants.
It's what she asked for.
No, no, no. She told me she
wanted to be an astronaut,
and that's why I spent
three hours last night
sewing patches on
a little, tiny flight suit.
Yeah, well, I spent the
night gluing daisies on a tutu.
Fine. We can hold
up the costumes,
and she can decide
whose work she loves more.
You know what?
Forget it. You take her.
I'm not doing this.
- Are you serious?
- As the grave.
That is amazing.
What's amazing?
Dr. Webber wants one of
us to do his surgery today.
Oh...
Not you. No offense,
but I heard you walked
into a wall this morning.
Uh, why not me?
Well, you can supervise.
They know this
procedure inside out.
They're ready. I beg to differ.
How do you do a
transgastric approach?
Anterior gastrotomy for access
and cystogastrostomy creation
through the posterior wall.
What about the
posterior approach?
That is a single gastrotomy in
continuity with the pseudocyst.
Very nice, and which
is the easiest approach?
It'd have to be the
intraluminal approach.
Unless you're a fan of
intraoperative bleeding,
in which case, do what you like.
I thought I wasn't seeing
you until the weekend.
Ah, I couldn't miss
trick-or-treating.
Just didn't seem right.
Good man.
That's a bold move,
letting the second years
try a procedure like this on
you. How you gonna pick?
Bailey, watch them
in the ER today.
Tell me which one deserves it.
None of them do.
And I don't need to
spend a day in the ER.
Dr. Bailey, that's all.
Get out of here. We're gonna
review an intraluminal approach.
Come on.
Okay, so, you, me, and Tuck.
We should think of costumes
that have three parts,
like the Three Stooges.
I have a witch's hat. I put it
on every year and call it a day.
And my day is gonna be about
which of those three residents
is gonna kill the most
important patient I've ever had.
Halloween was kind
of my family's thing,
and I want it to be our
family's thing, so go work.
I'll figure it out.
You just come at the end
of the day with that face
and that body and the...
I'll figure out
what to put on it.
It's a holiday for
children, you know.
Victor Brown, 30-year-old male
mauling victim. Vitals are stable.
Let's get him to Trauma.
What mauled him?
He just attacked me.
He came out of nowhere.
Wait. Who is "he"? The guy.
He was snarling and growling.
I'm sorry. A person
did this to you?
He started eating my
face, like some sort of...
Watch your back.
Zombie?
Murphy? Edwards?
It's the biter. Multiple
GSW's to the chest.
BP 90 over 60.
Pulse in the 120s.
He's on something.
How is this guy stable? He's
got two bullet holes over his heart.
Cops shot him before he ate
that other guy's whole face off.
And he had four lorazepam.
Barely slowed him down.
I want him sedated now.
Push two of lorazepam
and five of Haldol.
This guy should not be alive.
Guys, I can barely hear his heart.
Ow!
Sorry. It's pretty deep.
Just patch me up.
There's no way I'm missing
out on Webber's surgery
because of a little neck
lac. Oh, yes, you are.
God!
Where did you come from?
I'm everywhere, and you are not
going into an OR with an open wound.
You need to get yourself tested
and run an infectious panel,
including rapid HIV on him, and
whoever's blood was in his mouth.
Hold up.
Ow!
Is that... A tooth.
One down.
What?
Say "trick-or-treat." No.
God, you're no fun sometimes.
Trick-or-treat.
What? A treat for you.
Well, first of all, the
X-rays are backwards.
No, they're not. The organs are.
No way. Mmm-hmm.
He has situs inversus?
All his organs are
completely backwards,
mirrored to the normal position.
This guy was shot
twice in the chest.
He didn't die. Murphy
could barely find a heartbeat,
but it turns out his heart
was on the other side.
I have wanted to see
this since med school.
I know that. Happy Halloween.
It started last night.
She loves Halloween.
She's been in this
costume for days.
And I have to go
out of town today
for work.
Last trip was Brazil.
I got to go, too.
And I couldn't take
her with me on this one,
so we had Halloween early.
We watched part
of a scary movie,
and...
Poltergeist. It was awesome.
I paged Dr. Robbins.
No, you paged Peds. You got me.
Taryn, I'm Dr. Karev. So
you have a stomachache?
You don't know any
magic spells to fix it?
Well, we had some candy
last night during the movie,
and she got sick a few times.
Candy for dinner. Nice.
Ow.
All right, she has some
guarding and a fever,
so it's probably not the candy.
I'd like to do further
testing. Draw labs.
I still get to
trick-or-treat, right?
Are you kidding? The best
trick-or-treating in Seattle
is right here on the Peds floor.
You go around with
these huge pillowcases.
Everyone hands out as
much candy as you can carry.
He didn't die.
They shot him in the heart
twice, and he didn't die.
I thought he was just crazy.
He was just crazy.
Then why didn't he die?
I've got a needle
right next to your face.
I need you to
calm it down, okay?
Is there any pain elsewhere?
It's just sore.
And stiff.
Oh, my God.
Is this rigor mortis?
Victor, zombies aren't
real. We know this, right?
You... You should quarantine...
Victor, squeeze my hand.
Did you hit your head
when he attacked you?
You should quarantine...
Can you smile for me, buddy?
Uh... JACKSON: No,
he's having a stroke.
There's pulsatile mass.
Could be damage to the carotid.
Maybe a pseudoaneurysm.
All right, get the ultrasound.
I'm gonna book an OR.
Mrs. Wiltern?
Uh, Walker. Marge Walker.
Take me home, Philip.
Mom? Uh, Sorry. She's
a little afraid of hospitals.
Oh, well, in that case, I'll
be very, very gentle, okay?
It says you hurt your leg?
She says it was a bug bite
or something that got infected.
And then she said
it hurts like heck.
She's been popping
ibuprofen like it's candy.
I had to drag her in here.
It's fine. Philip, take me home.
Mom, no. Not until
you let her check it out.
Just try to relax, okay?
I'm gonna take a look.
Uh, when did this happen?
About four months ago.
Four months ago?
Maggots.
Gross. Writhing and pulsing.
We know what maggots are.
At first, they were
a little bit blurry
because my eyes... I
just had eye surgery.
What? What? What
are you doing here?
I'm fine. You shouldn't
be seeing patients.
But I wanna be helpful.
Well, great. Then
you can go to the store
any buy some Halloween candy.
Name brands, none of
those Smarties or candy corns.
But I'm not supposed to drive.
Luckily, someone
invented the bus pass.
Come on, Grey. You're not
gonna make her take the bus.
Thank you, Dr. Torres.
There's a shop just up
the street. You can walk.
You're looking for what again?
You know, one of those little
head mirrors that doctors wear.
Ben, you are a doctor.
Have you ever worn one? No.
Because they stopped using them
a century ago.
What are they teaching
you down there?
Tuck wants to be a
mad scientist tonight.
He should have one of
those little head mirror things.
Well, I have a brain in a jar.
But I wanna give him a
costume, not a nightmare.
What did he do to you?
Torres and I are working
on thought control prosthetics.
I'm trying to figure out a
way to insert the sensors
through a smaller craniotomy.
Aw, you should be
ashamed of yourself.
I'm sorry? Well,
that's for Zola tonight.
It was ripped. I fixed it.
Yeah, if you call this "fixed."
I mean, I could do a
running whipstitch so smooth
the butterfly would never even
know there'd been a rupture.
What are you teaching up here?
I would like to take a biopsy
to see if the infection's
gotten into the bone.
And we are gonna need
to take you down to the OR
to clean the parasites
out of that wound.
No! No! Take me home!
Mom.
Take me home! Mom. Mom. Mom.
All right, we can give you a
sedative to ease the anxiety.
No! No needles! No
needles! Just go away!
Just leave me alone!
Don't! Just go away! Don't...
She's always hated doctors,
but it's gotten out of
control since my dad died.
I don't want to sound cruel,
but can't you just
put her in restraints
and give her a
sedative or something?
Well... I have an idea.
I'm going to the gift
shop. I'll be back.
Put her in bed three.
Get an X-ray of the ankle.
Bed five should be empty.
Get a rapid influenza.
Could be the flu.
Right away, Doctor.
Uh, ma'am?
I'm waiting for my doctor.
Well, I'm your doctor now, so...
What's your doctor's
name? Maybe I can find them.
Dr. Brooks.
Heather Brooks.
I'm sorry. She's not here.
Yes, she is.
She's always here.
She said she'll only
see Heather Brooks.
Can I tell her about Heather?
You wanna tell a sick old
lady her favorite doctor is dead?
That seem like a
good idea to you?
No. It's just, she's pretty
insistent on seeing Dr. Brooks.
Then tell her it's not
possible and treat her yourself.
Um... Where is she?
I don't know. She was
right there a second ago.
Uh, Murphy's bitten, Edwards
is blind, and you're bonkers.
No!
Another one down.
Holy...
Ma'am, I'd like to get
you started on medication.
I need to know your name
so we can get you registered.
No, I'll wait for Doctor...
Dr. Brooks isn't here. I am.
Just tell me your name.
If you don't, I'll have to go
through all Dr. Brooks' charts.
How about you save me all that
trouble and tell me your name?
She'll come.
Okay, I'm tracking
one of the bullets
through the accessory lobe.
That's the middle lobe.
Right. Right.
It's the right lung.
Mmm-hmm.
This is like driving in England.
You know, I have to keep thinking
about every move that I make.
It's gonna take twice
as long as it should.
Okay.
You got plans tonight?
Meredith semi-invited
me to this baby fest tonight.
But I can't tell if she
really wants me to go
or if she just felt
she had to ask.
It's so complicated. Right?
She and I used to just know
what the other one was thinking.
I meant this.
There's still bleeding
in the upper lobe.
I need more proximal control.
Duval lung clamp.
Straight vascular clamp, please.
Okay. Oh, watch
out for the SVC. Ah.
Nicked the SVC. It
shouldn't even be there!
I got you this so you don't
have to shut your eyes so tight.
And you don't have to
see. You wanna try it?
There.
So let's forget
we're in a hospital.
Let's talk about
Halloween. Okay.
Do you get a lot of
kids at your house? No.
Oh.
Too bad.
All of the kids in the
neighborhood are Philip's age.
They're all grown up and gone.
But when he was little,
it was nuts.
A real madhouse, huh?
Yeah, kids everywhere.
Philip loved it. His
favorite holiday.
He always needed a costume
they didn't sell in the stores,
and I always
needed to make it...
What's happening?
It's okay. We're just...
We're gonna take a little walk.
We're gonna go down to
the OR and get you a gown.
Is that okay?
Yeah. Yeah, but...
It's okay. It's gonna be okay.
So you made all of his
costumes from scratch, huh?
What did he go as?
Well, one year, he
went as an aardvark.
Taryn's labs show a
slightly elevated white count,
and some of her
electrolytes are off.
Um, is she gonna
be here overnight?
It's just that her
dad wants to know
if he should change his flight.
Yeah, his eight-year-old has
a potentially surgical abdomen.
She needs a CT. She's in
pain. He should change his flight.
Dude, what is your problem?
I know you think he's
an ass, but he's not.
He's not your dad.
Don't even... What?
Pretend that you're not angry
and hurt and about to explode?
I've been doing
that. It's not working.
Tell me what I can
do to make this better.
Just get a CT.
So I thought the second
one would be easier,
but it's just like having
one all over again,
except now there are two.
So you're twice as exhausted.
Okay, we're all set.
Okay. Okay, Marge,
we're in the OR.
And we are ready to operate.
You'll be here the
whole time, Meredith?
The whole time.
Okay. Yes.
I'm ready.
Okay.
You know, if you
segmented the wings,
then she'd flap when she moved.
She just has to
look like a butterfly.
She doesn't
actually have to fly.
How'd you swing the time off?
You know, I just made it happen.
Halloween was always
my favorite night as a kid,
and I just wanted to spend
it with my family, you know?
You're so domesticated.
You're suturing a
butterfly costume.
You know...
You know, if we attach
this to her wrist with strings,
it'd sort of fan out.
That's a brilliant idea.
Right. It's totally worth it.
Yeah, keep stitching.
They're incompetent.
It's not their fault,
because it's how
they were raised.
These days, parents think
all of their kids are geniuses.
And everyone gets a trophy
just for being on the soccer team.
They're not the problem.
You are.
I'm trying to teach them,
and you won't let them learn.
I can barely get
out of this bed.
I can't operate.
Who knows if I ever will?
The only thing that
gives me some meaning.
Hell, some days the only thing that
keeps me going is teaching them.
And you're standing
in the way of that.
So I'm gonna have
someone else supervise them.
You're not kicking
me off this case.
Yes, I am.
This is why when I fire someone,
I like to do it in their office.
So I can walk out.
Walk out, Bailey.
Now.
Wow, there is barely
any necrotic tissue here.
The maggots might have
actually saved her leg.
Well, remind me to
send them flowers.
We may actually make
trick-or-treating tonight.
Yeah, about that,
I'm bowing out tonight.
Arizona and I can't be in the same
room for more than five minutes
before everything devolves
into gunfire and screaming.
Sofia has been so
excited about Halloween.
I'm not about to let her
mommies' bickering ruin it, so...
Taking one for the team.
Are you sure? There's
gonna be a pinata.
Shut up. And pin the
head on the skeleton.
Damn it! They're so cute
when they're blindfolded.
Bobbing for apples. Aw!
They're even cuter
when they bob!
I'll take pictures.
Dr. Grey, it's Dr. Webber.
He's asking whether you
have room on your schedule
for a cystogastrostomy.
Maybe Derek can take pictures.
Did you get your labs back?
Nope.
The post exposure counselor
gave me this cheerful little pamphlet
on anti-viral drugs to
read while I'm waiting.
She said in case I do have HIV,
it might not be a bad idea
to start taking them now.
You probably don't have HIV.
I might.
I might never see again.
You probably will. My uncle can.
You said he's in constant pain.
Horrible pain.
He had to give up his accounting
practice. He can't do math.
I'm not gonna be able
to be a surgeon anymore.
The counselor
said there are plenty
of other health
care jobs available
apart from surgery.
Like what?
Like post-exposure counseling.
But I won't know which
pamphlets to hand out
if I can't read them.
We're screwed.
So screwed.
Ugh! That's one
jacked up carotid.
Yeah, let's go ahead and
prep the synthetic graft.
Okay. Starting it now.
It's yours, Dr. Avery.
From Dr. Edwards.
She wants to know if
you think she should
call the lasagna pleasant?
That's, like, her
15th misspelled text.
She's scared.
Tell her not to call,
everything's gonna be fine,
and to keep using her eye drops.
You know what? And
tell her that she's beautiful.
What? Who are you?
You were never that nice
to me when I would spin out.
Well, maybe I am trying to
be a better boyfriend now.
No, no, it helped
that you were an ass.
It made me get my act together.
I'm getting married, and I'm
saving this guy's life and his face.
And that's all because of me.
Damn it. I mean, this was
supposed to be fun, and now...
You're overcomplicating it.
Just tell your left hand to do
what your right hand usually does.
Haven't you practiced
operating with both hands?
Yeah. Upside down? Underwater?
In a straitjacket?
Yes, I have practiced
with both hands,
but I can't just... Cut.
See?
Simple.
I'm sorry. I can't do it.
Meredith, I just need
you to observe while a...
I understand what you're
asking me... Meredith.
Page the general
surgeon that's on call.
I don't have the time.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry for saying that
you were the wrong choice
to be in charge of my care.
For saying that you
should have let me die.
I'm sorry for ever
feeling that way.
Because I've remembered
what there is to live for.
I would have never gotten
here if it hadn't been for you.
So I'm sorry.
Meredith, please.
Help me teach them.
What is that, a fan?
Yeah, exactly.
The array is a fan.
Now if I can get the fan
to go in through a burr hole
and open up under the skull,
the whole area would be covered
with a fraction of the exposure.
How has no one ever
thought of this yet?
How have I never
You don't look like
you're regretting
stepping back
from surgery at all.
Well, it's only been
a week, but, uh, no.
What's the rush?
I got the kid's CT.
You wanna fill me in?
Adrenal glands are
enlarged, coupled
with high potassium,
low glucose,
adrenal insufficiency.
Her body's not producing
enough adrenaline?
I'm glad you can read.
But there's no tumor.
Unless it's an infection,
maybe blastomycosis.
Oh, God, her dad mentioned
that they just went to Brazil.
What, are you kidding me?
You didn't think you
should put that in her chart?
What the hell? MR. DAVIS:
Thanks for your help, and I'm sorry
about the last-minute
cancellation.
Where is she?
She was just here.
She was asking about
trick-or-treating around the hospital,
and I just stepped
out to change my flight.
You couldn't keep an eye
on her for five minutes?
What's going on?
Taryn's body isn't
producing adrenaline.
You know what adrenaline does?
It keeps your organs from going
into shock and shutting down
when you get hurt or
traumatized or scared.
You said that she started
to feel sick last night
watching the scary movie?
She wanted to watch it.
She's wandering through
the hospital on Halloween.
Look, if something frightens
her, she could go into shock.
She can get scared to death?
We gotta go find her.
I'm looking for a crazy
lady with weird eyes.
Too soon, Shane.
No, seriously, she
disappeared again.
She was Heather's patient,
and she won't tell me her name.
And there's no record
of her anywhere.
And every time I go
to find her, she's gone.
Oh...
Well, maybe she's a ghost.
Forget it. Stop.
She's probably a stray.
Heather was always taking them
in. The homeless, the uninsured.
Trick-or-treat.
Get me D10 normal saline
and bring a crash cart right away!
I'll get it.
Taryn, can you hear
me? WOMAN: Dr. Karev?
Give me that gurney!
Right away, Doctor.
She's in shock
from adrenal crisis.
Get me her blood pressure,
and get those fluids started.
I'm on it.
Let's get her legs elevated.
Expiratory wheezing,
get her on five-liter O2.
Systolic's 60.
I need an IV hydrocortisone
and a central line kit.
Have the PICU get a bed
ready, and get her to the ER.
Right away.
This doesn't look
like a hospital.
We've taken all
of the unnecessary
medical equipment
out of the room.
And Philip is bringing some
more of your things from home.
And I've even put
a sign on the door,
so all the doctors and staff
will respect your privacy.
Okay... Um...
Do you want me to stay?
Don't you have kids
to get to for Halloween?
Yeah, but, you know,
it's okay. Oh, no.
You don't want to miss it.
You only get 10
before they go off
on Halloween with their friends,
getting into trouble.
You gotta enjoy
it while you can.
That wasn't so bad, was it?
Yeah, and you can
make it to your party,
if you're going.
I Am. You know, I'll show up,
I'll have a beer,
Mer and I will talk,
and we'll move
past this whole thing.
Good.
Oh, it's Meredith.
"If you're coming to the party,
could you bring cupcakes?
"If not, no problem."
What does that mean?
It's no problem if I don't go,
or no problem if I
don't bring cupcakes?
And if I don't go, then
there's no cupcakes?
Or will someone else bring them?
And if someone else is bringing
them, why is she even asking me?
Don't overcomplicate it.
Just go.
The cortisone will prevent
another adrenal crisis.
Taryn should
make a full recovery.
I never would have
taken her to Brazil with me
if I had known
she could get sick.
I know. And the movie...
She loves scary movies.
It was one bad call.
That's all it was,
just one bad call.
I'm a good dad.
Don't let what Dr. Karev said...
He's just...
He's so good with kids
but just so crappy
with other people.
He knows you're a good dad.
Is my face fixed?
Not quite yet.
Our first priority
was repairing
your injured carotid,
which was damaged
when you were attacked.
Oh, God.
The zombie, where is he? - No.
He's not quarantined?
Is that where this is?
I've been
quarantined, haven't I?
Oh, God, I knew it.
I saw this thing on cable
about these rituals in Haiti,
and I thought they were all crap,
but you've got me quarantined.
Except you're not
quarantined. This is the ICU.
Which means you wouldn't
tell me the truth anyway.
They've got you on a
gag order, don't they?
Because that's what
they do, the CDC. Okay.
They don't want you
to tell me the truth.
Hey, Victor! Victor!
Hey, hey! Listen to me!
Victor, you are not
under quarantine.
You are in the
ICU, which is where
we take patients after surgery.
You were attacked by a normal
guy who took a bunch of drugs,
lost his mind, and attacked you.
He didn't die when he was shot
because he's got a
condition called situs inversus,
which put his heart on the
opposite side of his chest.
That's random.
Yeah, completely
random, and also
not in the least
bit supernatural.
And really, honestly,
when you think about it,
isn't that, like, 100 times scarier
than some zombie apocalypse?
Yeah.
Yeah, okay, I guess it is.
Okay.
See, someone
starts spinning out,
you just shut it down.
But, you know, you can still
tell him he's pretty, if you want to.
Fix the wings?
Yes, and changed
the future of science.
I figured out the sensor array.
I insert it into a
two-centimeter burr hole.
Great!
Well, I have to find a resident
to do Webber's pseudocyst,
or I'm not even gonna
make it to trick-or-treat.
Go. See you at the house.
Okay.
Dr. Mahoney to the ER.
Shane. You win.
Webber's pseudocyst.
- Let's go, Shane. Suit up.
- Big leagues.
I have a patient.
Could I talk to you about Alex?
Yes, I know a place we can
go where no one will interrupt us.
Trick-or-treat!
- Trick-or-treat!
- Thank you.
Hey, kids, slow down!
That house! Hurry!
Boo!
Oh, my goodness.
Welcome to my laboratory. Ah!
It's great.
Mommy, Ben did all this.
Look, there's even smoke!
Oh, I see!
Well, I had some help.
Well, look at you,
Dr. Crazy Person.
You look so good!
Okay, go and get your
trick-or-treat bag now.
Huh?
I told you, this is my holiday.
You are amazing.
He's so happy.
We had fun. You know, we should
do stuff like this all the time.
Yeah, he'd love that.
I would, too. Right?
I mean, this holidays
and weekends crap...
I want to be back here
in Seattle with you guys.
Yeah, I know.
But, well, you can't drop
out of residency in the middle.
In a few years,
we'll... Um, I did.
I quit.
You what?
Hey, have you seen Wilson?
'Cause I need to get an update on...
What's wrong?
Nothing's wrong. I'm fine.
You're crying.
It's nothing. I'm fine.
I got bit by a delusional,
psychotic drug addict
who think he's the undead.
And I'm waiting for
the guy's HIV results.
Why didn't you tell me?
I'm trying to be easy peasy.
My first needle stick
happened on a Tuesday.
It was the second
month of my third year
in my internal
medicine rotation.
And my patient was
suffering from end stage AIDS.
We had just switched over
to these retractable needles.
And when I went to put his
into the hazardous waste,
I didn't retract it right.
And it jammed
right into my palm.
And my whole body went cold.
And I had never felt fear
like that in my whole life.
Right now,
it's not the time
to be easy peasy.
She's dead.
Dr. Brooks died
three months ago.
Well, that can't be true.
You're not in the charts.
She was treating you
under the table, right?
She was giving you
these for your asthma?
I didn't want her
to get into trouble.
When you run out,
you come back, you find me.
I'll be your doctor now.
She was a very good doctor.
Are you as good as she was?
No.
But I will be.
So there's the wall
of the pseudocyst.
Now what do you do?
Enlarge the incision with
a dissecting instrument
and use a stapler to
create the anastomosis.
Good. Carry on.
Faster, but take your time.
Can I tell you a
thing about Alex?
He doesn't want me to tell
anyone, but I don't know what to do.
He keeps pushing me away.
And you know
him better than I do.
Can't tell me.
I can't?
Telling me is the worst
thing you could do.
If he told you, he trusted you.
So whatever it is, you have
to be the one to deal with it.
I mean, of course he's
gonna to push you away,
because he hates
being vulnerable.
But that's when he's gonna
need you to stick with him the most.
I'll keep trying.
We'll, you're gonna
have to do better than try,
because my plate is full.
I have too many kids
and too many patients,
and I can't handle a
broken Alex right now.
You can do it.
Is it out of the question to get a
little consistency in this family?
What consistency?
I never see you.
Trick-or-treat!
Oh, trick-or-treat.
Look at you. You're so scary.
Here.
Thank you.
You started the program.
No, you upended
our lives because
it was extremely
important to you.
It's not working.
You are my family, and
I want to be with you.
Trick-or-treat! Oh,
Cleopatra and a ladybug.
Thank you.
Trick-or-treat!
My life is happening,
and I'm elsewhere.
You don't love it?
You? Of course I...
No, not me. Surgery.
You left town a week
after we got married
to learn surgery, because...
You were in love with it.
Yeah. But I am in
love with you more.
You really gonna tell me
that's the wrong answer?
I'm just...
What?
Miranda, what?
Disappointed.
In you.
Can we go trick-or-treating now?
You are so cute!
Oh...
Okay. Let me get my coat.
This is Emma Marling.
Please leave a message.
Emma, Owen.
Uh, Listen, um...
I wasn't ready to talk
about Cristina before,
because things between she
and I were always so complicated.
And I can't... I can't do
complicated right now.
I don't even want to
think about complicated,
and that is what is
so great about you,
is that you're, you
know, you're so easy.
God, that came out wrong.
I don't mean you're easy.
I mean you're simple.
Delete this.
Emma? Hi.
Hey.
How'd she do? Fantastic.
Almost as if she
had a great teacher.
Take me through it. I
want to hear every detail.
Well, in the interest
of education,
why don't we let
Dr. Wilson do that?
I like the way you think, Grey.
Okay, well, we started
your incision using...
No, no. Start from
the very beginning.
Where'd you place the ports?
Well, um, we took a look
at your previous incision
and decided to place
the xiphoid port lateral...
Halloween is not
for the faint of heart.
There's a surprise
around every corner.
Rapid tests negative!
Good for you.
I have to go back in six
months to get tested again
to be sure, but
it's looking good.
What's wrong? You still blind?
Bummer.
Mmm!
Also, no hepatitis.
What are you doing here?
Dude, I'm waiting for my...
Hi.
Jackson?
Oh, damn it.
I'm screwed! I'm so screwed.
I really might never operate
again, and it's my fault.
I went and had
surgery on my eyes
because my glasses were
just a little bit annoying,
and then I went
back to work too soon
because I thought I
might get a little bit behind,
which is so stupid.
Yeah. Pretty stupid.
What?
You knew that I was gonna take
the whole day off with you, right?
We could have spent
the entire day at home
on the couch while I
made you chicken soup
and you watched
movies and slept it off.
But, no, you had
to come to work.
You had to stress yourself
out and strain your eyes
and make yourself miserable,
which I told you was gonna happen.
Can we do it tomorrow?
We're gonna do
it right damn now.
Come on.
Some of the surprises are good.
Hey! You made it. Hey, yeah.
The party was great, and Sofia
is a champion apple-bobber.
The wings look great!
Hey, look at the little
space princess! Look!
Hey! Go to mommy.
Hi! You want your wand?
I don't hear any gunfire.
Yeah, well, we'll only
get about 10 of these
before she starts wanting
to wear slutty costumes
and run off with her
friends, and I'm not
about to cut that
number in half.
It's the first thing Arizona and
I have agreed on in months.
Hey.
Who's ready to
go trick-or-treating?
Time for blast-off!
Whoo-hoo-hoo!
All right, let's go! Whee!
Yay!
Um...
And some of the
surprises are bad.
Are you gonna stay
here and hand out candy?
No, I'm gonna eat candy in the
dark and pretend like I'm not home.
Alex...
I'll pass out your
freakin' candy. Relax.
What's important is that you
can't let the fear of the surprise
stop you from
getting dressed up.
And wandering up
to a stranger's house
to ask the question.
What are you supposed to be?
Sexy
witch.
You didn't have something
else to do tonight?
I had many options, Sharky.
But this seemed the most fun.
Can I buy you a drink?
Tequila.
Two tequilas.
Lights are off!
I was wrong about your dad.
I made a bad call.
I should have let you walk away,
but I never would have
pushed you towards him
if I thought that
you'd end up hurt.
I didn't see it coming.
You did, and I am so sorry.
But it was one crappy call.
That's all.
So what'll it be?
Trick?
Or treat?
Get in, before the
trick-or-treaters think that I'm home.