You think
this is a good spot?
All right,
I'll see you inside.
Remember, if you get
any central lines today,
I'm your man.
And if I don't?
Hey, you're still bleeding.
Hmm.
Yeah, I think I'll be doing
those central lines myself.
Give me a break. See you.
The coast is clear.
Save some lives today,
Dr. Halstead.
I'll try, Dr. Shore.
And you down in path,
enjoy your day with the dead.
Always do.
Hey, you look cheerful today.
Well, you know,
I like to see
the ED as half-full.
Dr. Halstead, Dr. Manning.
Clarke.
So, how you two doing?
What?
You and Jeff.
What are you talking about?
Natalie, everyone knows.
It's good. It's...
You know, you seem
a lot happier lately.
It's nice.
Okay, but when
you say everybody...
ED staff,
ambulance drivers, EMTs.
You know,
the crazy guy out front
who thinks he's Jesus.
Okay, so about the same people
who know about you and Nina.
Wait, seriously?
Incoming.
Dr. Choi.
We're going to room two.
Edward Hall, 82.
He passed out
in his apartment,
was awake when we got there,
vitals stable.
Mr. Hall, how are you feeling?
Head hurts.
You got an aspirin?
He's never done this before.
He was just
walking to the bedroom,
and he fell down.
We're gonna take care
of you, Mr. Hall, okay?
On my count. One, two, three.
Okay, let's get an H and H...
Okay.
Get Dr. Rhodes.
Have you experienced
any recent neck pain,
trouble swallowing?
Swallowing?
Your neck is swollen.
How long has it
been like that?
I don't... Swallowing?
He's in and out mentally,
mostly out,
but I take care of him.
Are you his daughter?
No, I'm his girlfriend.
It's okay, Eddie.
You're gonna be all right.
What do we got?
Neck swelling with a bruit.
I'm thinking
there's a compressive mass
in his chest,
possibly a tumor.
Oh, my God,
do you think he has cancer?
Could be.
If it's pressing on
his heart or carotids,
that would
explain his passing out.
And if that's the case,
we're gonna have to
operate to remove it.
Well, just do whatever
it takes, please.
Just take care of him.
Tell radiology we're
on our way up
for a neck and chest CT
with contrast,
then up to the OR.
Okay.
Whoa! Please, stop.
Don't take him anywhere.
Excuse me, sir,
can I help you?
This is my father.
He doesn't want any of this.
And that bitch has no right
to make any decisions
about his health.
Fact is, my father
doesn't want
any extraordinary
measures taken.
He never said that.
When his mind
first started to go,
he made his
wishes clear to me.
Dr. Choi, what are
Mr. Hall's options?
The scan suggests
he has a thymoma.
If we treat supportively,
he'll probably have
four to six months.
But if we excise
the tumor,
we can prolong his
life significantly,
as I'm sure our surgeons
can attest.
Surgery's definitely
an option.
Yes, though surgery
does come with risk,
a successful operation could
result in a total cure.
He's 82 and demented.
You want to put him
through an operation?
For what?
They just said
he could live.
Yeah, and he could
be left hooked up
to wires and tubes
for who knows how long.
No.
You can't do this.
You can't just
let him kill Eddie.
I am trying to honor
my father's wishes.
All right, enough.
Look, we all understand
this is a very
sensitive issue,
but what matters here
is who has the legal authority
to make Mr. Hall's decisions.
Well, as far as
the hospital's concerned,
with no advance
directive in place,
the surrogate
decision-making power
goes to the next of kin,
which, in this case,
is Mr. Hall's son.
No.
Thank you.
Ms. Goodwin, all due respect,
but my job is to do whatever
it takes to keep
my patient alive.
Dr. Choi, you heard him.
Our hands are tied.
So that's it?
You're just gonna
let Eddie die?
I'm sorry.
Hey, you got
a bounce-back in three.
Hey, Hayley. Back so soon?
I was afraid you'd miss me.
Always. You still throwing up?
No, that's all better.
Right after we saw you,
what, three days ago?
She started getting
a fever and chills.
We tried ibuprofen,
but it didn't come down.
You did the right thing.
When did you finish
your last round of chemo?
Yesterday.
Usually the chemo
fevers don't last this long.
Or get this high, 103.
Do you think
something's wrong?
Hard to say. The cancer meds
do knock down
her immune system,
so I wouldn't be surprised
if she got some
sort of infection.
But probably nothing
to worry about?
Probably not, but I would like
to start her on
some antibiotics
and get labs and
cultures just to be safe.
Looks like we'll be spending
a little more time together.
I'll be back shortly.
Ready to head to the Farm?
Nurse, can you please
come here?
Sorry, I'm slammed.
The Farm?
Uh-huh.
You want to come?
Sure. What's the Farm?
You'll see.
Please, I need to leave.
Okay.
No, I gotta go.
Can you just take
this tube out of my nose?
Mr. Jones...
Everything okay?
He wants to leave.
Bowel obstructions,
even partial ones,
can become
life-threatening situations.
We can't discharge
you until it's cleared.
It doesn't hurt anymore.
Look, I understand,
but your output
is still too high.
Let's see if I can feel any...
No!
I just...
I don't like to be touched.
How're we doing in here?
Give the tube
a little more time.
I promise,
we'll get you home
as soon as possible.
He was found passed
out on the street.
KUB showed a massive
stool in his bowel.
Wow.
Passed out?
Yeah.
It must have been pretty bad.
It's starting to clear,
but he's been combative,
fearful ever since
he got here.
You want a consult?
Sure. He won't talk to me.
Oh, look, here's somebody
he might have an easier
time relating to.
They call this
a Vent Farm?
Dark humor.
Keeps you sane if you're gonna
spend some time here.
Hey, good to see you.
So this is where
all our comatose patients go?
Mmm-hmm.
A lot of these
people didn't have anyone.
They just got
appointed a case worker
who decided to keep
them on life support.
Others have families
that are still
holding out hope.
Either way, they're just...
Nothing that can
be done, right?
Nothing medically.
So, what? We're here to check
some culture results?
Nope.
Pronounce someone dead?
Uh-uh.
So what are we doing?
We're here to paint
some nails.
What's going on?
You remember
my cancer patient,
Hayley Kline?
Sweet young girl?
Yeah.
This just showed
up in her cultures.
Oh, God.
Colistin-resistant
Enterobacter.
She can barely fight
off infection as it is.
Now she has an
antibiotic-resistant superbug?
This is really bad news.
Natalie,
it's worse than you think.
What do you mean?
This is Erik Tillman,
just came in.
He has CRE too.
The same bug? Are you serious?
Labs just confirmed it.
So we could be looking
at an outbreak that might
not have a cure.
Dr. Halstead, Dr. Manning,
this is Robin Charles,
the newest member of our
epidemiology department.
It's a pleasure.
Top of her class,
DuPont Scholar,
and she just happens
to be Dr. Charles' daughter.
What can I say?
Nepotism is alive and well.
So I hear we've got
colistin-resistant
Enterobacter?
In two patients.
Did they catch it
in this hospital?
I don't think so.
There's no record
my patient's ever been here.
Well, he's here now,
which means every
immunocompromised
patient in this place
is at risk.
Do we have final
culture sensitivities yet?
We're still waiting.
I'll need to talk to
every one of your
patients' contacts,
get detailed histories,
find out what
the connections
between these people are.
I'll be in touch soon.
Actually, um, wait.
I think it's my fault.
Hayley was here
three days ago.
I missed the diagnosis.
You don't know that.
She could have just as easily
contracted it after she left.
I saw her records.
You treated her exactly
how you should have.
What if I sent her back
into the city
with an infection
and she gave it to Erik
and who knows how many others?
Natalie, it's a city of
almost 3,000,000 people.
This could all just
be a coincidence.
Actually, I don't
believe in coincidences.
Sorry.
I'll be in touch.
Hi, honey.
This is Jeff Clarke,
fourth-year med student,
little rough around the edges,
but it's so hard to find
good help these days.
Hi.
How do you know her?
She came into the ED
late one night, alone,
burst an aneurysm,
massive hemorrhage.
By the time we got her,
we knew it was too late.
She kept on asking me
to talk to her, so I did.
Thing is,
my mother had just passed.
And when she used
to put me to sleep as a kid,
she used to call
me "Maggie-Pie"
from a nursery
rhyme about a bird.
And I don't know,
maybe Cindy had heard
that rhyme before.
She must have seen
my nametag, and...
'Cause in her last moment,
she squeezed my hand,
and she called me
Maggie-Pie, too.
Anyway, CPD looked,
but there was no family,
no friends,
no one to speak for her,
so they brought her here.
Now I check in on her.
Every week.
Tell her what's
going on with my life.
I don't know.
I figure she's got
one foot in this world,
and another in the next
where Mom is.
Yeah.
So why would a 19-year-old
have a bowel obstruction?
Good question.
All his other
tests are normal.
It could be stress, right?
Could be.
Stress can present
a hundred different ways.
But you think
it's something else?
Don't know.
That's what you're gonna
find out.
Hi. I'm Dr. Reese, Sarah.
Can I come in?
I really want to leave.
I don't blame you,
but it sounds like
you're gonna be here
a little bit longer,
so maybe we could talk?
Or I could just sit here.
Is that okay?
Why?
I don't know. I just thought
you might want some company.
Are you from Chicago?
I've been here five years.
I'm from Connecticut,
and I still totally dread
the winter.
I mean, I thought I knew
what cold was,
but this is like
National Geographic,
Frozen Planet cold.
I carry around
those hand warmer pads
just in case my
eyelids freeze shut.
I hate the cold.
Yeah?
Where are you from?
Phoenix.
Okay.
I have a sister named Sarah.
No kidding.
Uh-huh. Yes, and have Monica
call every patient
that's been to the infusion
center since Monday.
Mmm-hmm. Yes, anyone
with fever, chills, headaches
or nausea gets a blood draw.
Yeah, okay.
How you doing? How's it going?
You know. Busy but good.
Nice people in that
department, right?
Yeah, they seem great.
So, you get my text?
When are we having coffee?
We will, Dad. I promise.
Just got a lot on my plate,
first couple of weeks
of work and all.
Of course you do.
You're sleeping,
though, right?
Are you sleeping?
Dad, come on.
Hey, new job, new city.
I'm sorry.
You know,
could be a little stressful.
I'm fine, Dad.
And really,
you're not my therapist.
Oh...
I'm just...
I'm glad you're here.
Proud of you.
Mr. Hall?
We found a tumor
that's compressing
the large vessels
in your chest.
We could remove it
with an operation.
Are you a doctor?
Yes, I'm Dr. Choi.
I'm your doctor.
You're Chinese.
I saw the Great Wall.
Mr. Hall...
I really believe
that surgery is
your best option.
Do you give us permission
to perform the surgery?
Permission?
Yes.
Are you a doctor?
What's going on?
I'm just explaining
to your father what's
happening in his chest.
Explaining? Looks to me like
you're trying to coerce him
into a procedure
he doesn't want.
I'm sorry, but I'm gonna
have to ask
that you not speak
to him alone again.
I'll check back with you soon.
Check back?
Echo to get a better idea
of her cardiac output,
and then we'll
take it from there.
Dr. Latham, about Mr. Hall,
the three of us need
to approach his son
as a united front.
Why?
Perhaps together
we can convince him
to let us save
his father's life.
I don't understand.
Well, I think what Dr. Choi
is suggesting is that
if we explain the surgery
again in more detail,
then maybe...
Our job isn't to solve
family problems.
Our job is to fix ailments,
and until the Halls
ask us to do that,
there will be no surgery.
This is distracting.
Cute shoes.
I could see my boyfriend
in those.
They're okay,
too tight in the toes.
These are pretty comfortable,
not the cutest.
I had to order, like,
50 pairs to find
the right one.
Are you okay?
I... I gotta go. I gotta go.
Hey, it shouldn't
be too much longer,
but let me check
with Dr. Choi.
Call Dr. Choi.
All right, this might
just be from the obstruction.
Is anything hurting?
He's tachycardic.
Abdomen's far less distended.
I'm gonna throw up again.
No sign of infection,
no fever.
Hey, has anything like
this happened before?
I am just here to help,
but I need you to tell me
if there's something
I should know.
Danny.
I am on your side.
Heroin.
What?
Are you... Are you on heroin?
He is in withdrawal.
Give me 10 milligrams IM
of methadone
and one of Ativan.
Got it.
Hey, I am right here.
It is going to be okay.
You know,
I couldn't stop
thinking about Cindy.
No family,
alone in that room,
month after month.
Yeah.
So I called a friend of mine
in the State Bureau
of Identification
to look into it.
It turns out that Cindy
has a sister in Spokane.
Really?
Yeah.
Gave her the number
of the hospital.
I don't know.
Maybe this means
Cindy will have
another person in her life.
That'd be great.
It would, right?
Yes, of course.
O2 sats are dropping.
Arms are swelling.
He must be hemorrhaging
into the tumor.
It's compressing his SVC.
Save me.
He said, "Save me."
What's going on?
Where's his son?
I don't know, but I heard him.
Let's bag him.
Let's go.
Sats still dropping.
Okay, let's get him to the OR.
What are you doing?
The patient expressed
his wishes.
We're taking him to surgery.
Are you kidding?
He's demented. He can't
express his wishes.
I heard him.
Doctor,
we're ready to go.
Okay, let's move.
You can't do this.
How is it having
her back in town?
Oh.
It's great. It's great.
Yeah.
Yeah, haven't shared
a zip code since she was
in high school.
You been spending
some time together?
Yeah. I mean,
haven't really hung out yet.
You know,
she's got a lot on her plate,
like new job, new apartment.
I mean,
just getting cable installed.
Like, come on, that's a bitch.
So, after she's got cable?
Yeah.
Daniel.
Sharon, look, she's never
gonna forgive me.
For divorcing her mother?
Yeah, that and I don't know...
All the time I was there,
wasn't really there, you know?
You remember.
Yeah, I remember,
but I'm sure she...
Dr. Charles?
Yes?
I am sorry. Are you available?
Will you excuse me? I'm sorry.
You were right.
There is something
going on with Danny.
Tell me.
He told me he's addicted
to heroin.
He started going
through withdrawal,
he's stable now,
on methadone and Ativan,
and I know detox
is a long road,
but maybe we can help.
Could work.
Let's see what we got.
Okay.
Oh. Hi.
Hi, I'm Dr. Reese.
And I'm Dr. Charles.
It's nice to meet you.
I'm Tina, Danny's mother.
He just told me
what's going on.
I had no idea.
Well, it's a lot to take in.
How you feeling, Danny?
He's embarrassed,
and he should be.
It's just so confusing
why he would do this.
We've tried so hard
to be good parents.
Well, fortunately, Dr. Reese
has a good plan about how
to move forward.
Please, tell me what to do.
So, as long as you continue
to tolerate the methadone,
I want to switch you to orals.
Then we can talk about rehab.
But first,
how are you feeling?
I appreciate all this,
but I know he wants
to go home.
That's totally understandable,
but Danny is gonna have
to finish his IV first,
and that's gonna
take a couple of hours,
so you might want
to go get a cup
of coffee or...
He is still gonna
be here for a while.
Right now, I don't think
Danny wants me to leave
his side.
Do you, honey?
Okay, makes perfect sense.
Why don't we check
back with you in a bit?
I don't know what happened.
He's totally different.
Well, it's gonna
be a little tense with Mom
in there, right?
But it's like
a switch was flipped.
He wouldn't even
look me in the eye.
Something is a little off.
What... How long
till he's discharged?
Well,
his obstruction's cleared,
and now that we know
it was caused by the heroin,
there's no reason to keep him
once his IV's done.
Let's ask Dr. Choi to order
a lactate level
and an iron panel.
Why would we want those?
Buy us a little time.
We got to separate them,
see if we can find
out what's what.
Hmm.
This was the right
thing to do.
Hmm?
The surgery.
Absolutely. Why?
Well, you seemed against it.
The son said, "No,"
so it was a no.
The patient said, "Yes,"
so now it's a yes.
Is there more to it than that?
Guess not.
I'm not good with ambiguity,
Dr. Rhodes.
I want you to watch
how I elevate
the caudal portion
of the right inferior horn
while still attached to
the pericardial fat pad.
It's an easier method
to divide and ligate
it like that.
Mr. and Mrs. Kline?
I have some news.
The lab tested Hayley's
CRE culture against
every antibiotic,
and it turns out it's
sensitive to just one.
A drug called
ceftazidime-avibactam.
So there's a cure?
That's fantastic.
Yes, but the thing is...
The bug is sensitive
at a very low rate,
which means it works best
for patients that
we catch early.
So... So Hayley?
We won't know anything
until we try the medication.
I waited too long, didn't I?
No.
No, I should have
brought her in sooner.
No...
Mrs. Kline...
I am usually so on top
of this, but I just...
I can't tell what's
an emergency anymore.
She's always so sick.
You cannot blame yourself.
Please,
this is not your fault.
I promise you, we are gonna
do everything we can
to help her.
Okay. Thank you.
How is he?
They're just getting
in the chest.
When he was crashing,
did you hear what he said?
No.
We're here to save lives.
You're doing what
you're supposed to do.
Yeah.
Someone help!
She can't get a breath.
I need to intubate.
Ma'am, please move.
Five of Versed.
What's going on?
She could be in septic shock.
I don't know. Pressure's fine.
Pulse is strong.
You're good.
What's going on?
Please, come with me.
Hayley... What...
It's okay. It's okay.
I can't get the tube in.
It's like
something's blocking it.
Did she eat anything?
No.
Damn it.
Sats down to 50.
Doris, give me the ultrasound.
Got it.
I need a cric kit.
What?
We need to make
a hole in her trachea
so she can breathe.
Oh, my God.
Wait, you're right.
Her airway is blocked.
It's an abscess.
The infection's
spread to her pharynx.
I'll page ENT.
No, no time.
Give me a minor
tray and a knife.
I got it.
It's okay, I can do it.
No, I got this.
Sats down to 50.
Hold her arm, please.
Nat, I have to cric her.
Hang on.
Nat.
I got it.
Oh, my God.
Dr. Manning,
thank you so much.
Lung's clear.
Baby.
How's she doing?
She's stable for now,
but the abscess was
caused by her infection.
It's only a matter of time
before she gets more.
What's going on from your end?
Bad news, I'm afraid.
East Mercy just got
a new CRE patient.
Intubated,
can't get any info yet,
but we're working on it.
And they're sure it's CRE?
That's three.
It's a pattern,
not a coincidence.
Okay, but just because
another person has it
doesn't mean it's your fault.
Well, there's only
one way to find out.
We need to extubate Erik.
No. It's too dangerous.
We've tried everything else.
His social media,
his contacts.
In order to find the source
of the infection,
we have to figure
out how he is connected
to Hayley and this patient
at East Mercy.
We need to talk to him.
Well, that's if you can
extubate him.
He may not even tolerate it.
We will go as slowly
and safely as possible.
That's not a decision
you can make.
No, it's not, but he can.
Okay.
I'll turn down his propofol,
and he should be awake
in a few minutes.
Make sure you separate out
the recurrent laryngeal nerve.
Copy that. Do you see it?
Should be right... Here.
Pull harder.
Did you see The Force Awakens?
Got it...
I'm sorry, did I see what?
The Force Awakens.
Uh. No.
When Rey defeats Kylo Ren,
the glove falls off
of his left hand,
but when he sits up,
it's on again.
These are professional
filmmakers.
It's unbelievable to me.
O2's in the high 80s.
That's the best we can get.
Okay.
Erik, I'm Dr. Manning.
You are in the hospital
right now with a very
bad infection,
and we're concerned
that other people
might be getting
this infection as well.
A lot of people.
If we don't find them soon,
it may be too late.
But in order to do that,
we're gonna need
to ask you some questions.
Now the problem is,
if we take your tube out,
we cannot guarantee you'll
be able to breathe
on your own.
And once it's out,
we may not be able
to put it back in.
What we are asking you to do
won't help you directly,
but it could save
a lot of lives.
You don't have to do this.
Do you give us permission
to take out your
breathing tube?
Thank you.
Okay.
He's still in the high 80s.
How are you feeling?
Are you okay?
Yeah?
Okay, okay, good.
Okay, now, Erik,
we're gonna ask
you some questions.
Danny, I thought we could
spend some time
looking over
a few rehab centers.
Thank you,
but I made some calls.
We're already booked
in a private facility
for as soon as
he's discharged,
which should be
any minute, right?
Are you sure you're
feeling well enough
to leave?
Ah, well, if you ever
want to talk.
Thank you.
Danny, are you okay?
Yeah.
We should get going.
Because bowel obstructions
can lead to irritation
in the diaphragm
if they aren't fully resolved,
I feel like I should keep you
for some more observation.
You know, if it gets worse,
we'll have it checked
at rehab.
There are doctors there.
We should do a chest X-ray.
Yes, yes, we need
a stat chest X-ray.
Could you take Danny
over to radiology?
I'll get a wheelchair.
Really,
I'm sure he'll be fine.
We're on a schedule.
Mrs. Jones, I see
how concerned you are
for your son,
and I want to make sure
he gets the best care.
I promise we're gonna
make this quick.
So it turns out Erik's
roommate was seen
here up in GI three
days ago for a bleed.
But Erik wasn't here with him?
No, but he's immunocompromised
from rheumatoid
arthritis meds,
which means even
if his roommate
was just a carrier for CRE,
Erik could easily
catch it from him.
And the patient in
the ED at East Mercy?
Was upstairs Monday
to see his hematologist
for chronic anemia.
So with Hayley,
that's three patients.
All within the last few days.
We are checking
the hospital records
line by line
to see if they have
anything in common.
Staff, location,
food, supplies.
I think we're almost there.
Maggie?
Hey, what's going on?
The hospital just received
a set of legal papers.
They're from Cindy's sister.
She got in touch?
I'm afraid so.
She's ordering us
to withdraw support.
What? No!
I've already spoken to Legal.
There's nothing we can do.
I am truly, truly sorry.
Maggie, I had no idea...
You feeling
a little better, sweetheart?
Well, it's still early,
but it looks like
her fever's breaking.
I think the antibiotics
may be starting to work.
I'll be back in
a bit to check in again.
Thank you, Doctor.
I think Hayley's
turning the corner.
Yeah, Erik's perking
up a little bit too.
Extubating him was risky.
But it was a good call.
I found our link.
An endoscope?
Hayley, Erik's roommate,
the patient at East Mercy...
All had endoscopies
here in the last week.
Okay, but we're
always gowned and gloved,
and everything
gets sterilized.
So, this crevice along the tip
is just wide enough
to harbor bacteria
and small enough
that even following
the manufacturer's guidelines,
it doesn't always
clean that groove.
Well, we have to tell the FDA.
They know. They're
the ones that told us.
Wait.
What?
The FDA knows?
Yes.
Our hospital has
dozens of these.
There must be thousands in use
across the country.
That's why the FDA
hasn't pulled them.
They don't want to cause
an endoscope shortage.
So the agency created
to protect patients is...
Made a cost-benefit analysis.
I have to tell
Hayley's parents.
No, no, no, that's my job.
Thank you all.
Thank you.
They knew about it.
Unbelievable.
It really is.
But I was right about
one thing. Told you it
wasn't your fault.
It's great,
what you two have.
I'm sorry?
You and Dr. Halstead,
you're really good together.
Straight edges, opaque.
It looks man-made,
like there was something
under Danny on the table.
No, this is definitely
inside of him.
I could be wrong, but I think
this might be
a tracking device.
A what?
A transponder.
Emits a homing signal.
Would explain how
that woman found him.
You mean his mom?
Yeah. Is she, though?
I mean, think about it...
The guarded behavior,
heroin abuse.
Wait, you think
he's a drug mule?
Resistance to examination
by male doctors,
suggesting a history
of abuse by other men.
I've seen this before.
I think that Danny
might be a victim
of sex trafficking.
Sex trafficking?
So that woman...
Is his pimp.
Wait, Sarah.
Dr. Reese. Stop.
We can't just
let her take him.
He is not a minor,
so we have no right
to intercede
unless he explicitly
asks us to.
But he wanted me
to find the chip.
He wanted me to know.
Well, what did he say?
What exactly did he say?
He didn't say anything,
but with his...
See, Sarah, it's not enough.
Crazy as it sounds,
we need to know that
he's psychologically
ready to be extricated.
We do this the wrong way,
we call the police,
could be very,
very bad for him.
It's why we need to hear
it from his own lips.
Trust me.
Then I need to talk to him.
Danny?
Thanks for all your help.
What's gonna happen to him?
Hey.
Hi.
Fellowship programs?
Yeah, I'm just wondering
if staying here was a mistake.
Why?
Latham. The man is odd.
He says that he is not good
with ambiguity.
That is an understatement.
He is from Mars.
I am constantly trying
to figure out who the hell
is this guy,
and I don't know if I can
handle working
with him every day
for the next two years.
Is he?
I get why you'd feel that way.
I just think he takes
some getting used to.
Did you just say, "Is he?"
Why don't you come meet us
on the balcony tonight
around 7:00?
Why should I do that?
Because I think
there's more to him
than meets the eye.
Okay.
Mr. Hall.
You're awake.
You a doctor?
Yes.
We were worried about you.
That girl.
Laurie.
You should know,
through all of this,
she was your
strongest advocate.
I'm sure.
Sir?
I'm her...
What's that word?
Gravy train.
Is that the word?
Okay.
You can't take it with you.
How's he doing?
Surprisingly well.
You made the right decision,
Dr. Choi.
Did I?
I don't know.
It could have gone either way.
Combat medicine
was always so simple.
Just save whoever
they put in front of you.
Never any questions.
"Should I?"
"Shouldn't I?"
Never really had to
deal with that before.
Tell Mom I said hi.