Jay. Red eye, triple espresso.
Thank you.
Man, you're gonna be wired
till Thursday
with that much caffeine.
This is not for me.
You need all the energy
you can get for tonight.
Should've seen that coming.
You know, you and Nat are very
lucky that I'm letting you
have a joint
bachelor-bachelorette party.
So, what do you want
to talk about?
'Cause I got some other
surprises I got to set up
for tonight.
All right,
what am I looking at?
The EKG I got of Ray's heart
when I was planting the bug.
Okay. So?
It's abnormal.
I need to bring him
to the hospital.
Run some tests...
Whoa, whoa.
You are not actually
his doctor,
you know that, right?
Jay, come on.
You did your part.
Now lay low until Agent Lee
says otherwise. That's it.
Ricky. Irish whiskey and Oban.
Yeah, only the finest.
I'll see you tonight.
Ah!
Hello.
Can I help you with something?
No, Maggie. Please.
Oh! Yes. Hey, Will.
Can you tell your fiancé
to stop being a killjoy?
Huh?
She's got
to wear this, tonight.
Maggie, I would like
to maintain
a little bit of dignity.
You're wearing it.
This one's nonnegotiable.
Hey, you two, you're up.
Ambo's pulling in
with a car crash.
How many victims?
Driver and passenger.
Trauma Two.
Got it.
Daria Carson.
29-year-old female,
restrained passenger.
Driver lost control
of the wheel
and went into the guardrail.
GCS 15. Vitals stable.
Refused board and collar.
Where's the driver?
Her husband, Adam.
Wouldn't let us check him out.
I'm fine, really.
Just take care of my wife,
please. I'm right here, honey.
All right,
let's transfer on my count.
Ready? One, two, three.
Thanks, guys.
Yup.
Breath sounds are normal.
Periorbital bruising.
Battle sign
over the right mastoid.
Possible skull fracture.
Hey, why don't we go next door
so I can examine you?
I want to stay with my wife.
We're new, new to be married.
Newlyweds.
Congratulations.
Still working on the English.
Sounds pretty good to me.
At least let me check
your blood pressure.
We can do it right here.
All right, let me know if you
feel any pain or discomfort,
okay?
Does it hurt right there?
No, it doesn't hurt.
Let me take a look.
It's from crash.
Geez, babe.
You really slammed that dash,
didn't you?
Your blood pressure's
a little high.
It's just the adrenaline.
Let's get a chest x-ray
and then send her over
for a CT head
with a four vessel angio
for her neck
as well as her chest,
abdomen and pelvis, okay?
We'll be right back.
Hey, Adam, if you feel
lightheaded at all...
I know where to find you,
Doc, thanks.
That guy worships her.
Won't leave her side.
Yeah, I don't think that's it.
The contusions on her torso,
they're old.
They're not from the crash,
and the one on her side
looks like the tread
of a boot.
Son of a bitch.
Let me guess, unicorn.
Nope, cotton candy.
Oh?
My mom made it, actually.
Ten bags of cotton,
hand-painted
and sewn to a leotard.
Impressive.
That is quite a labor of love.
I always lacked imagination
in that department.
Pretty sure I was sheriff
all of elementary school.
Mr. and Mrs. Phillips,
Gabby appears to have
some swelling
in her lower legs as well.
She's been eating vegetarian.
Latest fad at school.
Could it be her diet?
I don't think so.
The swelling,
paired with vomiting
and jaundice
makes me think this may be
a liver issue.
Ultrasound?
Gabby, mind if we take
a closer look?
We just assumed
it was a stomach bug.
We would've brought her in
sooner if we thought
it could be serious.
Let's take a look.
Gallbladder looks normal.
But her liver is nodular.
Looks cirrhotic.
Cirrhosis? Isn't that
from drinking?
I don't drink.
Gabby's never even
tasted alcohol.
Cirrhosis just means there's
scar tissue in her liver,
so there are plenty of other
causes besides alcohol.
We'll run some tests
to help us narrow things down.
April, CBC, CMP, LFT,
CT abdomen and pelvis,
and give her 4 milligrams
of Zofran
and 1 liter saline IV.
Got it.
But I was supposed to set up
for my Halloween dance
tonight.
I have to be there.
Hey, worse comes to worst,
Dad will drop off
the decorations for you,
honey, okay?
We'll let you know
as soon as the results are in.
Could you give us a moment?
Thanks.
All right.
I go inside?
Yes, soon.
I wanted to speak
with you first.
The bruises on your body,
they're not all
from the accident, are they?
Is someone hurting you?
No.
Is your husband hurting you?
As your doctor,
whatever you say
to me stays between us.
He won't know.
We meet online.
When Adam comes to Ukraine
to see me,
he's gentleman,
handsome, kind.
I fall in love.
How did you end up
in the States?
A year ago, there is
trouble for my family.
I must leave.
Adam brings me here
on visa to marry,
but when I come,
he's a different man.
Everything I do, he get mad.
Today, in car, I say something
he doesn't like and...
That's why the car went
into the rail.
Daria, we can report this
to the police.
No, no. No police.
Adam, he kill me.
There are shelters
you can stay at.
No, I cannot leave him.
He will send me back,
no papers.
Deport you?
But you're married.
He never files
for my green card.
He says I'm a bad wife.
You say I can trust you.
Yes, you can trust me.
Please, no police. I beg you.
She still visiting Bernie
every day?
Yeah. How can she stay
with him?
He lied to her
about being married.
Come on, don't tell me
you approve of this.
It doesn't matter
what I or you think.
It's Emily's call to make.
I tried talking some sense
into her.
Now somehow I'm the bad guy.
He's the father
of her child, Ethan.
Yeah, and?
So it's not insane for her
to want at least try
to make it work.
And why can't she leave him?
Well, Daria didn't go
into detail,
but I gather being deported
would put her life in danger.
Yeah, a fear Adam is clearly
preying on.
Well, it's not uncommon.
Abusive spouses using
the victim's
immigration status
to control or manipulate.
If she isn't legal,
she's likely financially
dependent on him, too.
He won't even let her
leave the house.
Yeah, the prick
has her trapped.
Let me talk
to an immigration attorney,
see if we can't find a way out
for Mrs. Carson.
Thank you.
Dr. Choi,
Gabby's been short of breath
for the last few minutes.
Sats are at 91.
April, let's get her
on oxygen.
Is there any news?
That's what I came
to speak to you about. Please.
Gabby's CT did in fact
show cirrhosis,
and her labs, I'm afraid,
are consistent
with liver failure.
Oh, my God.
What? How could that be?
I have a theory, but I'd like
to do a quick exam to confirm.
Excuse me.
Hey, Gabby.
Can you look
in the light for me?
There.
See the golden color
around her pupils?
Those are called
Kayser-Fleischer rings.
They're a sign
of Wilson's disease.
What is that?
Well,
when our bodies
consume copper,
our livers get rid
of the excess.
But with Wilson's,
the copper's improperly
eliminated so it builds up
in our vital organs.
It's a hereditary disorder.
Any family history
on either side?
No.
I'm not sure.
No. No.
Can we step outside
for a moment?
I'll keep Gabby company.
Thanks.
Right now,
we're going to start Gabby
on plasmapheresis
to remove the copper
from her blood,
but ultimately,
she will need
a liver transplant.
Well, can we donate?
Is that possible?
Yes, because
the liver regenerates,
it's possible
to donate a segment.
We just need a test to see if
either of you are a match.
Can friends and family get
tested as well?
The wider the net, the better.
Good, we'll reach out
to everyone we know.
In the meantime, we'll set you
both up to get evaluated.
Thank you.
Yes! So cute!
Who are you guys
supposed to be?
"The Pink Ladies."
Yes!
Who are they?
What?
Dr. Lanik, I changed
the dressing on the patient
in Treatment Six,
and found the journal articles
you requested,
and here's your latte.
Wow.
You know, I'm all about
giving the med students
the occasional scutwork,
but having them
fetch you coffee,
that's classy.
He wanted to.
Rising star, that kid.
Real pleaser.
Dr. Rhodes.
Dr. Bekker.
What's on tap for you today?
Back to back CABG's.
You got time for lunch later?
I'll see
if I can squeeze you in.
Need some help over here.
Terry, come and help!
Dr. Rhodes,
you're going to Baghdad!
What happened?
Working a job
a couple blocks away.
Piece of sheet metal
fell on Mitch.
Ripped his leg open.
The blood,
never seen anything like it.
All right, Maggie, tag in.
We might have to move
to the hybrid OR.
I got you.
Pupils are sluggish.
Pulse is thready.
Maggie, get an IV in,
trigger the MTP.
I'm on it.
Large laceration
through the muscle.
Femoral artery's severed.
Prognosis?
Trauma to the femoral artery
can cause massive
and rapid blood loss.
Bad. Prognosis is bad.
Breath sounds are weak.
I'm gonna intubate.
Give me a laryngoscope.
On it.
I can get a 22 in the hand.
That'll have to do.
100 of sux, 20 of etomidate.
Lanik, get
an eight French line
in the groin.
Terry, you're up.
A central line?
I've only done practice runs.
Then you're ready. Get to it.
Beats scutwork, right?
I can't see the cords.
Guy's really anterior.
Maggie, cricoid pressure.
Yep, got it.
Come on, hurry up.
Get the catheter
and the dilator over the wire.
BP's dropping.
Lanik, step in.
Come on, Terry. Guy's dying.
The guy needs blood.
Lanik, step in or I will.
I'm in, bag him.
Done. I got it.
Why is there so much blood?
What happened?
Damn it. You missed the vein.
You went into the artery.
All right,
we can't use that line.
Give me a kit.
I've got to get a line
in the subclavian.
I'm sorry.
I was having trouble
finding my landmarks.
Everything was moving so fast.
I...
Well, next time we'll just ask
the guy to stop dying
so you can catch up.
All right.
Let's get the blood going.
Move him over
to the hybrid OR.
We'll shunt the leg there.
You heard the man.
Let's get ready to travel.
Hey, results are back
for Gabby's dad.
They couldn't test her mom.
How come?
Preexisting condition?
Lupus.
Dad?
Unfortunately,
he's not a match.
John's blood type is AB.
Gabby's type O.
He can't be
her biological father.
Remember how Jeanette changed
her answer
when I asked them
about their family history?
John probably has no idea.
I'm going to pull in
Dr. Charles.
The radiologist just read
Daria's scans.
So, you see that blip,
right there?
That's called
a pseudoaneurysm.
The impact from the crash
tore the vessel,
and now there's
a small blood clot
is covering the hole.
If it ruptures, it could cause
a life-threatening bleed.
So what's the treatment?
We'll put you on medication
to keep
your blood pressure low,
and we'll monitor you
for the next 24-48 hours.
I'm here, too, you know.
Then we'll
start anticoagulants
and reimage you.
If your condition worsens,
we will need
to perform surgery.
In the interim,
it is very important
that we keep Daria calm.
Any stress or agitation
could spike her blood pressure
and cause the pseudoaneurysm
to rupture.
We'll need to restrict
all visitors.
You don't mean me.
Yes, actually we do.
I hope you understand.
She'll get nervous
if I'm not here.
Babe, you don't want me
to leave.
I'll stay.
Your wife needs rest.
Hey, man, do you have a
problem with me?
No, Mr. Carson.
Once a room opens up,
we'll move you upstairs.
Thank you.
Will.
Give me three minutes alone
with that guy.
If we show him our cards,
he'll suspect we're onto him.
It'll put Daria
at even greater risk.
Be smart about this.
So, if John's not a match
and I can't donate, what now?
Ms. Phillips,
it is not at all our intention
to pry
into your private affairs,
but at the same time
it's important to us to give
your daughter
the best care possible.
Okay.
And in reviewing you
and your husband's
test results,
it became evident that John
is not Gabby's
biological father.
And we wanted to meet with you
in private because we
weren't sure that John knew.
No, no.
It's not what you think.
Gabby's adopted.
When I asked
about your family history,
you didn't...
No, we didn't want to say
anything in front of Gabby.
She doesn't know.
Mrs. Phillips,
I know it's a stretch,
but if we could locate any
of Gabby's blood relatives...
That's not possible.
Gabby was a ward of the state
when we adopted her.
Her biological parents
were deceased and she had
no other known relatives.
Well, in that case,
we'll want to get Gabby
onto the transplant list
right away.
Okay. Thank you.
Artery shunted.
Clamps are off.
Let's get him up to the ICU
to rewarm and resuscitate.
What about the line
in his artery?
Don't you need to pull it out?
So we can watch him bleed out?
We can't do that right now.
He's too cold
and coagulopathic.
We'll fix it when his pressure
and clotting are better.
Where do you get off
treating him like that?
What happened
was your responsibility.
I didn't stick
that guy's artery.
You were supposed
to be supervising.
Look, the only way they learn
is under pressure.
Not when it endangers
my patient.
Look, would you just relax?
You got your line in.
Disaster was averted.
No harm, no foul.
If you ever pull something
like that again...
Hey, you might've been
the golden boy up in CT,
but down here I'm in charge.
And I will supervise
my med students
in whatever way I see fit.
Glad to see you found
a new sparring partner
down here.
Would hate to see you getting
rusty in my absence.
That guy is an egomaniac.
Well, takes one to know one,
right?
Come on. Buy you lunch?
Yeah.
Dr. Charles?
Hey, I was wondering,
how long does Gabby have to be
on the transplant list
before she gets a new liver?
Please, just level with me.
I'm afraid I can't give you
a definitive answer.
It can take days. Weeks.
Sometimes, honestly,
even years.
Years?
Well, unfortunately,
demand vastly
outweighs supply.
It's why living donor
transplantation was developed.
It's not possible
for a drug addict to donate,
is it?
A drug addict?
Honey.
I got you a coffee.
Thank you.
Any word from Paula?
No, she can't...
She's having a seizure.
5 of Ativan IV.
Gabby.
Let's get a brain CT,
just to make sure
there are no bleeds.
Bleeding in the brain?
What are you talking...
It's just a precaution.
Here, let's let them
do their job.
John?
Ativan's in.
Okay, okay.
Easy.
You know, some people
have this great knack
for hearing cardiac murmurs
or palpating a pulse.
But no one picks up a scalpel
and instinctively knows
how to open a chest.
Procedures take practice
and repetition.
You'll get better with time.
But what if I don't?
Maybe this was a mistake.
What was a mistake?
Med school.
I gave up an NFL contract
to come here.
Could've paid off
my mom's mortgage,
put my little brother
through school.
My family relies on me
financially, if I fail out...
Whoa, you are getting
way ahead of yourself.
You keep at this,
you'll get better.
Now do it again.
Get a grip on yourself
or it'll be Gabby who suffers.
Dr. Charles, my wife...
This whole thing
has been really hard on her.
She and Gabby haven't spent
more than a night apart
since the day we adopted her.
I imagine it's incredibly hard
on both of you. Right?
I mean, the stress,
emotion's gonna run high.
We all say things,
do things we regret. Right?
Look, not for nothing,
I'm here.
You want to talk
about anything?
Anything at all?
No, you know what?
You make a good point.
I should find Jeanette.
I owe her an apology.
Any word on Gabby's CT?
It was negative.
Oh! That's good.
Look, I've been thinking.
Why don't we see if we
can get a look
at Gabby's adoption records?
Sometimes courts will unseal
them in the case of imminent
medical need.
But didn't the parents say
Gabby's a ward of the state
with no surviving relatives?
Yeah, but at this point,
I'm pretty sure
there's something
they're not telling us.
I'll make the call.
I spoke
with the immigration attorney.
Under provisions
in the Violence
Against Women Act,
battered immigrant spouses
can self-petition
for legal residency.
Without their
spouse's knowledge?
Yes, and if Mrs. Carson's
petition is approved,
she'll be eligible to work
in the U.S.
Thank you, Ms. Goodwin.
I'll go speak with Daria.
All right.
Where's Adam?
He goes for food,
but he comes back soon.
I only need a second.
Daria, there is a way
for you to stay
in this country
without Adam's help.
You can even get a work visa.
But if Adam finds out...
That's the thing.
He won't find out.
Dr. Manning.
I was just checking on Daria.
You know, I was thinking,
if we're just going to watch
and wait,
we may as well go home.
You'd be more
comfortable there.
Right, babe?
Babe?
Mr. Carson,
I don't think you understand
the gravity
of your wife's situation.
We're not just watching
and waiting.
It is imperative that Daria
remain in the hospital.
That's your opinion.
Yes, my medical opinion.
What's going on here?
We'd like to be discharged.
No. That would be
against medical advice.
So we've been told. It's fine.
Well, that's not up to you.
That's the patient's decision.
Tell them you want to leave.
Daria, you do realize that
if you leave the hospital
in your condition,
you will be exposing yourself
to significant health risks?
Yes. I want to go. Please.
Okay, then.
We'll get
the paperwork started.
Goodwin found Daria
a legal fix
for the long-term,
but if she walks out the door
with him...
It won't matter.
Next time he hits her,
it'll kill her.
Hey, got your page.
Hey.
Just heard back.
We can't get
Gabby's adoption records.
Why not?
Because they don't exist.
Okay, so the state
made a clerical error,
or they lost
our adoption record.
I fail to understand
how this is our fault.
No one was blaming you.
Then what were you doing
going behind our backs
without our consent
in the first place?
Mr. Phillips, please,
just try to stay calm.
Jeanette, you asked me before
if an addict can donate.
Leave my wife alone!
I need you to know
that if they're clean now,
they very well could.
Really?
I know how much
you both love your daughter.
But if you're withholding
information that could help us
save her life,
now is absolutely the time
to tell us.
We had to do something,
we couldn't just
leave her there.
Gabby was just a baby.
She wasn't even a year old.
And she'd leave her out
in the hallway for hours
in this ratty old bassinet.
We could hear her wailing
from our apartment.
Who would leave her?
That woman. The mother.
She was inside getting high,
getting strung out
on who knows what.
We were just going to take her
up to our apartment
for a night, I swear.
Give her a bath, get her fed.
Wait, you kidnapped her?
No, it's not like that.
We had to save her.
I'm sorry, but you know
we have to report this.
We know.
Look, could we have a moment
with Gabby?
To try to explain?
Of course.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
It's okay.
It's going to be okay.
What's going on?
Pressure just dropped.
No pulse. He's in V-fib.
What happened?
Why did he arrest?
Don't know yet.
What were his last labs?
PH was 7.1, but we've been
correcting it.
Take over. Charge to 200.
Charging.
Clear.
Lab just called
with a critical value.
Potassium is 9.
All right, two amps of bicarb,
amp of D50,
and charge to 200 again.
Got it.
Why the hell's his potassium
so high?
Bicarb's in.
Clear.
He's back to sinus rhythm.
Well, your shunt
must have failed.
There's no bleeding.
Strong pulse
in the right foot.
Damn it.
No pulse in the left foot.
Compartments are hard
as a rock.
The line in the artery
must've thrombosed the leg.
The line I put in.
The muscle's dying,
dumping potassium
into the bloodstream.
The leg's gotta go.
You're going to amputate
his good leg?
We don't have a choice.
Whoa, whoa. Hold on.
What are you doing?
I've got to book an OR.
No, I mean what are you doing,
sawing off this guy's leg?
It's going to keep dumping
potassium and stopping
his heart.
Even if you take off the leg
and he stops arresting,
he's never waking up.
You don't know that.
His pupils were sluggish
when he got here.
He'd already lost
a massive amount of blood.
You're saying he suffered
an anoxic injury in the field?
Of course, he did.
The guy was a goner
when he got here.
He's on his way to brain death
no matter what we do.
Unbelievable.
You're worried that he might
just pull through, aren't you?
You're reaching.
No way he's pulling through.
That's what
you're counting on, right?
That he dies?
What do you mean?
Dr. Lanik is worried about
a malpractice suit.
The patient survives,
he's accountable.
Guy wakes up,
he's going to wonder why we
amputated his good leg, right?
You're a coward.
Get over yourself.
All you're doing is
rearranging deck chairs
on the Titanic.
As long as this guy
has a fighting chance,
I am going to do
everything I can to save him.
The leg comes off.
You know,
it's not just my neck
on the chopping block.
He put the line in.
So if I take a hit,
you can be sure as hell
the kid goes down, too.
Mr. Carson?
What? More paperwork
for me to fill out?
Given the high risk associated
with discharging Daria...
The hospital's
Ethics Committee is convening
an emergency meeting.
You got to be kidding me.
I know my rights.
You can't keep us here
against our will.
Dr. Manning, Dr. Halstead.
I need you. It's Daria.
No pulse.
What?
The aneurysm
must've ruptured.
She was fine a second ago.
Maggie, start bagging.
Got you.
She's asystolic.
Do something.
You're not helping her.
Step outside. Now.
Milligram of epi.
Epi's in.
Another milligram of epi.
Stay with me, Daria.
Stay with me.
Pulse?
Epi.
Come on, Daria.
No.
She's gone.
Time of death, 17:32.
The birth mom,
Alyssa Thompson,
is on her way in.
We were able to track her down
with the info
the Phillips provided.
Is she clean and sober?
Seems like it.
Been working as a hotel maid
for the past six years.
Good. Hopefully, she'll be
willing to get tested
to be a donor.
Yeah.
Nearly had a heart attack
when we told her
we found her daughter.
What's...
Mr. and Mrs. Phillips?
I'm going to need you to come
with me.
Wait, wait...
No.
We're so sorry, baby.
No, please. Please.
We have no choice.
So sorry.
Can you do something?
Can you...
Please forgive us.
I know this is very scary...
This is all of your fault.
Mr. Carson,
we're sorry for your loss.
What happens now?
What sort of arrangements
do I have to make?
After the autopsy is complete,
likely in about six
to eight weeks...
Wait, autopsy?
Yes, it's the law
that all traumatic deaths
go for an autopsy to determine
the cause of death.
But we already know
what happened.
Well, the crash
is the presumed
cause of death.
The medical examiner will need
to rule out
other possibilities.
Like what?
There was bruising
in her initial exam
that is not consistent
with the mechanism of injury
from the crash.
Daria wouldn't have wanted
an autopsy.
People poking and prodding
her body.
As her next of kin, I refuse.
The ME has jurisdiction
to perform the autopsy
with or without your consent.
But feel free to voice your
objections directly.
She'll be here to take
your statement shortly.
You can wait here.
We'll retrieve you
when she arrives.
How's the husband taking it?
He's worried.
Just what we expected.
Daria.
Daria, it's okay.
He's gone?
He will not come back?
No, trust me.
He's going to stay as far away
from this hospital
as he possibly can.
We know this was
an unorthodox intervention.
No, Dr. Manning,
this was a complete
misappropriation
of medical care.
What if your fake code had
caused the patient to rupture?
The compressions were staged.
I wasn't using full force.
And light compressions
wouldn't spike
blood pressure...
Save it, Dr. Halstead.
If Carson hadn't bought
your little charade,
do you have any idea
of the legal ramifications?
He would've gone
after your medical licenses,
and then you pulled Maggie in.
I can't believe she allowed
herself to be involved.
Ms. Goodwin, if we could have
stayed within the lines,
we would have.
But in this instance,
that would have meant
sending a woman out the door
knowing she would
very possibly die.
Enough.
Another stunt like this,
and both of you
will be looking
for work elsewhere.
And just so you know,
an immigration attorney
is meeting
with Mrs. Carson shortly
and a social worker
is standing by to find
a shelter for her.
Thank you.
Dr. Rhodes.
BP and heart rate
suddenly spiked.
Now he's bradycardic.
Both pupils
are blown bilaterally.
No corneal.
No gag.
We'll need an apnea test
to confirm,
but it appears that he's...
He's brain-dead.
Herniated due to
an anoxic brain injury
from prolonged downtime
in the field.
Just like I said he would.
You should be happy.
Dodged that bullet.
Will you excuse me?
From now on,
you'll stay out of my way.
Likewise.
Is that Kylie?
She goes by Gabby now.
I can't believe...
All these years,
I thought she was dead.
Would you like to meet her?
Yes.
Gabby, I think you have
a visitor.
Alyssa is here.
Hi.
I'm so happy to see you.
You are so beautiful.
Get away from me.
You're not my mama.
Gabby, I know this is...
I want her out of here.
I don't care.
I'm not here to hurt you.
Get out.
Get out!
I get it.
I wouldn't expect her to...
But I just thank God
that I get a second chance
to be in her life in some way.
To be some kind of mother.
Thank you for agreeing
to get tested.
Anything. Anything she needs.
If you follow me,
I'll get you started.
Excuse me.
The couple that took her,
where are they?
They're in police custody.
I was hoping I may be
able to thank them.
They saved her life.
"Thank them." Wow.
Motherhood, you know.
Mysterious powerful thing.
Something you and me
will never fully understand.
We took a huge risk today.
No regrets. I'd do it again.
Aren't you
forgetting something?
Your sash.
You really think
she'll notice?
Nat, it's Maggie.
Fine, but I am not putting
it on until we're out
of the hospital.
All right.
Okay, I'll be right back.
I don't need another lecture
right now.
And I'm not here to do that.
Listen, Em,
I may not understand your
decision to stay with Bernie,
but I'm not in your shoes,
and you need to do what you
think is best.
Really?
Yeah.
I'm so glad to hear that.
I have some news,
kind of big news.
Okay.
As soon
as Bernie's discharged,
we're going to move
to Las Vegas.
Okay, Em.
Okay.
Awesome. Okay.
First one's the hardest.
Huh?
You didn't cause his death.
You know that, right?
That's not it.
When Mitch died,
for a moment,
for a split-second,
I was relieved to be
in the clear.
You're human.
Now, look, the minute that you
walk into this hospital,
the only person relying on you
needs to be your patient.
This is already
a high-pressure gig
and you need to find a way
to leave everything else
at the door.
You got me?
I hear you.
Thanks, Dr. Rhodes.
You hang in there, Terry.
You're going to be fine.
Arr, matey.
You clean up nice, Dr. Bekker.
You're not so bad yourself.
Shall we?
Thanks for coming.
Whoa! Yeah!
I'll go get us another round.
All right.
Congrats, man.
Hey, can I talk to you
for a quick sec?
Yeah, sure.
What's going on, man?
I'm just giving you
a heads-up,
out of respect.
Okay.
I'm bringing Ray Burke in
for an echo and an MRI...
Jesus, Will,
you're not his doctor.
And I can't,
in good conscience,
withhold possibly
life-threatening information
from him.
If you make a move
in his direction
without our go-ahead,
I promise you,
you will regret it.
Look, man, because of the bug
that you planted,
the task force has intel
that Ray is meeting
with his crew in a week.
They're this close
to taking him down.
He'll get treated in custody.
Now, if you don't mind,
I'd like
to get back to your party.