- Previously on The Resident...
- Tell me about your mom.
- Nic.
- Mom or dad, you pick.
Parents split, my dad
kept me from my mom.
And then she passed
away, you know that.
The love of my
life turned out to be
a psychopathic doctor who
poisoned her own patients.
Oh, come on, Bell, we all know
you're the most
eligible bachelor.
- Jessie.
- I screwed up.
- Look at me, what did you take?
- What's going on?
My sister. She OD'd on oxy.
- She could've died.
- Eight months clean.
Happiest I've been in forever.
Just like that I
threw it all away.
We got to get you
better for good this time.
Whatever it takes.
I'm such a liability.
Trick or treat!
Trick or treat.
Oh, please.
Aah!
Oh... oh, God.
No!
- No, no!
- She's having an episode.
What's her name?
Laurie Dante.
- Can you hear me?
- Laurie, you're okay.
Two of Lorazepam
I-M for sedation. Go, go.
She must have dozed off.
She said she
hadn't slept in days.
- Oh, make them stop.
- All right, Laurie,
Laurie. You're
okay. You're safe.
Hey. Laurie.
You're in the hospital.
We'll take care of you, okay?
Let's admit her
to the fifth floor.
- And page Conrad, stat.
- Okay.
♪ ♪
Guess what this is?
I know what that is.
Yeah, but have
you ever tasted it...
The chocolate, caramel, nougat?
You're hilarious.
Let's break some
rules, Conrad Hawkins.
- After all, it is Halloween.
- Mmm.
I'm listening.
Get a resident to cover for you.
Pick a costume.
I'm thinking something
from the Marvel universe.
Come to Mina's party.
And I can't believe
I'm gonna say this,
but eat a bunch
of candy with me.
That sounds scary.
And amazing.
I wish I could,
- but I can't.
- Mm.
We're understaffed.
It's Halloween night.
You know how crazy it can get.
- Are you waiting for someone?
- My dad.
I was supposed to meet him
before work 45 minutes ago.
That's strange. Maybe he forgot.
Yeah. Very strange. He
never forgets. Anything.
Go.
Get out of here.
Have enough fun for both of us.
Oh, I plan on it.
Happy Halloween.
I admitted Laurie Dante.
Nightmare girl with
the psychotic breaks?
Yep.
How is she?
Oh, she's scared.
Conrad's on his way.
Good. I'm off for the night.
The place is all yours.
First Halloween
in the ER. Enjoy.
What are these?
Costumes. For Mina's party.
I have backups on hand
because Mina must approve
before she lets you in the door.
Last year I got rejected.
Twice. But not this year, baby.
This year, I'm money.
What are you gonna be?
Werewolf.
Good luck, buddy.
Concussion. Needs
observation for another four hours.
I got it.
Vampire in two should
have stuck to drinking blood.
Hang two liters of
saline and discharge
when he can count
backwards from ten.
You suck for taking tonight
off and leaving me here
with the most juvenile
med student in history.
I can't argue with you on that
one, but here's the good news:
Halloween is a notoriously
slow night in the ER.
You're a terrible liar.
Now leave, please.
Hey, right arm for reattachment.
Patient is still
trapped in his vehicle.
We have to get back to scene.
Dr. Feldman has the details.
- Thank you.
- You knew about this?
The call might have come
in about 15 minutes ago.
I thought it would
be a fun surprise.
You know, trick or treat?
Let's get this arm on ice.
Hold down the fort, Pravesh.
Keep that arm viable
for reattachment.
Hmm. Girlfriends?
They're cool. I got one myself.
Isn't that your name?
Yeah. What?
I cannot believe that you
made these by yourself.
Well, when you don't
leave the house very often,
you look for things to do.
How long has it been?
Since I've had a wild night out
or since I got sober?
I'm kidding.
Four weeks rehab.
Two weeks sober living.
One week on your couch.
- Well, I am proud of you.
- Thank you.
And thanks for inviting me
tonight. I'm really excited.
Are you kidding me?
The costume's at Mina's
Halloween parties are legendary.
Everybody should
experience it at least once.
Well, I know you're
worried about me staying
son the straight and
narrow, but I just want to say,
I'm not just doing
this for me anymore,
I'm staying clean
for both of us. Okay?
I'm not worried.
Do I look worried?
Yeah, you have like
a resting worried face.
Laurie, I'm Dr. Conrad Hawkins.
I'm here to help, okay?
I'm really sorry.
This is embarrassing, actually.
I-I just have bad dreams.
You have people
who need you. I...
I'm not even sure I should
have come in. I'm-I'm fine.
Laurie, I'm happy you're here,
because I'd like to make
sure it's nothing serious.
Sound like a plan?
All right, tell me...
When'd you start
having these episodes?
Uh, couple weeks ago.
I figured they'd just go away,
but they keep happening.
Getting more intense.
Now...
I'm afraid to fall asleep.
Go ahead...
Tell me to go home, that
there's nothing wrong with me.
It's exactly what the
other three doctors said.
Actually, women under 35 are
the most misdiagnosed subset
of patients in the
country, so, no,
I don't want to tell you that.
Whatever you're experiencing
is taking a toll on you.
That's very clear.
Dang it.
I'm sorry.
Sorry, I don't know
why I'm crying.
Because you're scared.
Laurie, just tell me everything.
Where you work. The
medications you're on.
Don't leave anything out.
The smallest of things
can lead me to a diagnosis.
No meds.
I don't have a regular job.
I... nanny for a
family in Inman Park.
- There's nothing wrong
with that.
- Says you.
My family hates the whole idea.
We have a farm near Statesboro.
They didn't want
me moving to Atlanta.
They think I'm gonna get
into trouble in the big city.
We don't talk much anymore.
Actually, we don't talk at all.
That sounds difficult. That
must put a lot of stress on you.
They're wrong.
I can handle it.
I'm gonna run some
tests... Blood panel,
lumbar puncture, MRI.
We're gonna get to the
bottom of this together.
What would cause a website
not to load on my computer?
Uh, the hospital
server blocks porn.
I'm the CEO of the hospital.
I don't look at porn.
Everyone looks at porn.
I'm not watching porn.
Right, 'cause it's blocked.
Remind me why I hired you?
Uh, 'cause your
last assistant quit
and my dad is Zip Betournay.
He owns the Crystal
Springs Golf Club.
Pretty sure he
jumped you to the top
of the wait-list to get in.
That was rhetorical.
Oh.
There is nothing
abnormal, is there?
Radiologist will have
to give the final read,
but it looks that way.
- Have transpo
take her to her room.
- Okay.
Dad.
I'm sorry I missed you earlier.
I had some
business to attend to.
At 9:00 at night?
Can I make it up to you?
I'll swing by Chastain later.
I'm on a shift.
Could be a long one.
Of course.
I understand.
- Where are you taking me?
- It's gonna be okay.
- Let me out of here.
- I got to go.
- I'll find you.
I'm gonna take you
to your room, okay?
No, t-take me
out of this building!
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
what's the problem?
She wants to get discharged.
You can't keep me
here against my will.
Laurie, we talked about this.
I need to run some more tests
so we can figure
out what's wrong.
Who are you?
I'm your doctor.
No.
My doctor is Conrad Hawkins.
I just talked to him.
I've never met you
before in my life.
Pravesh, I got a page about
a reattachment surgery...
A delicate operation that
demands my unique skills.
Where's the arm?
I'm keeping it cool on ice.
Good. I'll start its
admission process.
But you can't admit an arm.
It's not alive. It
doesn't have insurance.
Doesn't have a name.
Okay, I'll give it
a name. Clyde.
Clyde? That's the
best you can do?
Well, it's uninspired,
but whatever.
When I reattach
Clyde to the patient,
it will be both
alive and insured.
All right.
I don't know who did that.
It wasn't me.
Relax. Clyde has
a sense of humor.
I approve.
Okay.
- ♪ Bring it back now, baby ♪
- Wow.
- You look amazing.
- Oh, thank you.
And you look...
homemade.
That's a good thing, right?
- She's very hard to read.
- Yeah.
Uh, A-minus.
- B-minus for effort.
- B-minus?
Plus, I like you
both. You may enter.
♪ Bring it back now, babe ♪
♪ I hate when I have
to watch you go ♪
♪ Oh, Lord, I love ♪
- ♪ To watch you leave, I want ♪
- Roar!
- ♪ Your hands all over me ♪
- No.
♪ Won't you bring it back? ♪
Damn it.
♪ Bring it back now, baby ♪
♪ Bring it back now, babe ♪
Oh.
Hello. I'm a sucker for
a man in leopard skin.
You know, for a bunch of doctors
and nurses, I thought
this party would be...
- Tame?
- No offense.
No, nothing I do is tame.
The prescription drugs
that you have for your clinic...
Are they in the
apartment tonight?
Please give me some
credit. I'm not a fool.
Perhaps you should
let go of Kitty's leash.
♪ Bring it back now, baby ♪
♪ Bring it back now, babe. ♪
If you really are Dr. Hawkins,
why can't I recognize you?
It's called Capgras
syndrome. It's very rare.
People see a familiar face, but
the emotional charge necessary
for recognition is lost.
It's lost because
the area in the brain
that controls emotions has
some sort of disconnect there.
And that disconnect
is telling you
that you are seeing an
imposter when you really aren't.
But why is it happening?
There's a number
of possible causes.
Earlier, you told
me not to hold back.
So you do the same.
Just tell me the truth.
Do you have any family
history of schizophrenia?
Oh, God.
My cousin was schizophrenic.
H-He heard voices.
He couldn't take it.
He jumped off the
Jackson Street Bridge
- two years ago.
- Slow down. Hey, hey, hey.
There is a lot of ground to
cover between where we are
right now and diagnosing
what's really going on.
I've paged a neurologist.
He will be here very soon,
and he will walk us
through everything.
What a noob.
Lag. Lag. Why is
it lagging? Okay...
Clear out your desk.
It's your first and last day.
Wait, no, are... R-Really?
This is called a job.
You may not be
familiar with jobs.
They usually entail work.
You've done no work.
You can break the
news to your dad.
I'll find myself a new club.
I get fired, he
kills me. For real.
Well, that's something for
you to consider in your next job.
If you ever get one.
I can hook you up.
- Excuse me?
- I've seen you
swiping right all day.
I can find you a
smoking hot date, tonight.
Have you lost your mind?
Look, just hear me out.
I match people together, okay?
It's a thing I do.
I have no skills
in life whatsoever
except for my ability
to put man and woman together.
Sometimes man and man,
sometimes lady and lady.
All types. Last-minute.
Short-term, long-term, whatever.
It's a gift that I
have, and it's a gift
that I can give to you tonight.
This is painfully inappropriate.
Or it's delightfully perfect.
Okay? I-I have someone in mind.
Capgras, huh? Ah,
that's a tough one.
I have a few tests we should do.
Rule out the possibility
of biological causes.
Where's my patient?
Laurie.
Uh, she wanted to grab some air.
Uh, did I do something wrong?
♪ ♪
Laurie?
I'm never gonna be
normal again, am I?
We don't know that.
We only just
started doing tests.
Let's give it some time.
I don't know if I can.
I'll be there with you
every step of the way.
We'll do this.
We'll do this together.
- You're gonna be fine. Hang in there.
- Mm-hmm, yeah.
Okay, who did this?
Wow.
- No, it's not funny.
- Yeah, but don't look at me.
The Raptor does not prank.
Although he appreciates pranks.
A man lost his arm.
And he could very well
be dying, for all we know.
Still seem funny
to you? Is this why
you wanted to become a doctor?
Chill, Pravesh.
I'll reattach Clyde the Arm
to the living body it belongs to
as soon as it gets to Chastain.
Incoming! Left
leg. Same patient.
Patient is still trapped
at scene. 20 minute ETA.
We're gonna need more surgeons.
♪ I'm looking for some
good conversation ♪
♪ Looking for a
little inspiration ♪
♪ 'Cause you won't catch
me out, catch me out often ♪
♪ But tonight I'm all
about participation, mm ♪
♪ If you ain't makin'
moves then I'm off it ♪
♪ Particular when it
comes to involvement ♪
You're being codependent.
How 'bout "Great party.
You having a good time?"
I don't ask questions I
already know the answers to.
♪ I'm-a work myself to
death if no one stop me ♪
Emergency surgery.
I have to go back to Chastain.
Okay, you're in charge now.
- What?
- Three things:
one, don't let anyone
throw up on my rug;
two, don't let Irving in
without a better costume;
and, three, you can have
the weight of the world
on your shoulders at Chastain
but not in my apartment.
Not tonight.
♪ I'm-a work myself to
death if no one stop me ♪
All right.
How about you fill
in all the numbers
on this clock for me?
The fact that you
drew all the numbers
on one side of the clock means
that there's a biological
basis for your illness.
This is actually good news.
- Because I'm not schizophrenic?
- Exactly. The test
shows us that only
one half of your brain
seems to be interacting
with the outside world.
You don't know
what's causing it yet?
No. There's still
something going on
that our tests
didn't pick up yet.
- What could it be?
- Inflammation.
Autoimmune diseases. Toxins.
I want to keep you in
the hospital overnight.
We're gonna order an EEG,
start you on empiric antibiotics
to treat for possible
infectious causes.
I keep thinking...
I brought this on myself.
I-I walked away from my family.
Maybe it's karma or something.
Had I never left, maybe
none of this would be
happening to me. I-I
deserve the nightmares.
Everyone gets nightmares.
I get my own from time to time.
You didn't bring
this upon yourself.
We're gonna give you a
sedative through your IV.
Should help you get
a good night's rest.
Whatever's
happening in her brain,
it's progressing quickly.
We need to find the source fast
to avoid any permanent damage.
Check her in an hour.
If she needs more meds,
we'll do it then.
She gonna be okay?
Diagnosis is a
needle in a haystack.
But I'll keep
looking till I find it.
You seem tired.
You sleeping much?
Residents don't get to sleep.
Son, when was the last time
you took just a few days off
to recharge your batteries?
I have no idea.
I did the same thing
when I was your age.
Burned it at both
ends until I burned out.
You going somewhere with this?
I'd like to go
somewhere together.
You and me.
I have a place in Anguilla.
Condo by the beach.
We could fly out
for a long weekend.
Why didn't you show
up for coffee tonight?
I told you, I had
business crosstown.
Do you want to try
that explanation again?
Because I have never known
you to miss an appointment.
Riley, sweetie, watch
your sisters, okay?
Where's my husband?
Frank Tanner.
- Uh, he was in a car accident.
- The tattoos.
Riley, Gemma, Eve.
Not lovers. Children.
And I just got word:
Frank is one minute out.
All right, I'll move them
to the waiting room.
Ms. Tanner, I'm
Dr. Devon Pravesh.
Come with me.
Your husband hasn't
made it to the ER yet,
but the moment he does,
we'll take care of him,
okay? Just wait there.
- Okay. Girls.
- Guys, come on.
46-year-old male.
Prolonged extrication.
- Oh, my God, Frank!
- Suffered amputation
of his arm and leg.
- Oh, my God!
- Multiple liters
of blood loss on scene.
- Ten.
- Frank!
- Wait here.
Okay.
One, two, three.
Get me cordis.
Call out vitals.
70/40. Pulse is 50 and falling.
- Hey, he's about to code.
- I know.
Start a rapid transfuser.
Hang two units of O neg now.
Heart rate dropping. 30.
All right.
One of epinephrine.
Get me the pacer pads.
Heart rate at 20.
Ten.
Zero. All right, somebody
better start pumping.
Let me do it. I can do this.
Okay.
Hold compressions. Check pulses.
- Nothing.
- Come on, Pravesh.
Frank dies, I've got nobody
to operate on tonight.
Is he breathing?
Shock him.
Charging.
Clear.
Nice. Frank lives.
For now. Send
him for a pan-scan.
OR Numero Uno is where I'll be.
- ♪ Why not take me away... ♪
- Hey. Hey!
- Stop that. I mean... Oh, my God, I...
- Nic.
My hero. Thanks
for letting me in.
This party is epic.
Is it, though?
Uh, hello?
There's a 40% chance I'm
making out with Bo-Peep.
Uh, actually there's a
100% chance that Bo-Peep
- is making out with Hercules.
- Oh.
She'll come around.
You okay?
I will be once I find
Jessie. She's MIA.
Check the closets. Lots
of activity in the closets.
♪ Why not, why not ♪
♪ Why not, what
you got to lose ♪
♪ I ain't like the molecule ♪
♪ Why not, why not ♪
♪ Why not, baby, why not ♪
♪ I spot my type in the lineup ♪
♪ I'm up on it
like we grinding ♪
♪ But behind it
like your spine is ♪
♪ I ain't go to college ♪
♪ I was wiling
with them riders ♪
♪ Thank God that
I survived it... ♪
Hey, not on the
bed. Off the bed.
♪ I know ♪
♪ Do you want to... ♪
Mm!
You, uh, want to
make it even better?
I'm gonna save
them for later, okay?
Occupied.
- Jessie, come on, open up.
- Hey.
- You first.
- I couldn't find you anywhere. I was just...
Following me around all
night and having zero fun?
I'm making out with Tarzan.
- Is that okay with you?
- Okay, you know what,
this was a mistake. I shouldn't
have brought you here.
- You said you trusted me.
- I guess I thought...
I don't need a babysitter,
Nic. And you're not Mom.
- Mom would never act like this. You know why?
- Oh, come on.
Because she actually
made things better.
So why don't you leave me alone
and go out there and drink
something with alcohol in it,
and I'll drive us home
because, guess what,
- I'm sober.
- Jess.
Trick or treat.
Laurie!
Lau... Laurie.
- No...
- Laurie! Laurie!
Laurie!
Laurie, stop!
It's okay. It's okay.
- No, no, no, no, no!
- It's okay, it's okay.
We can help you. John!
Ma'am, ma'am, ma'am...
Femoral bleed!
Gauze, now!
Hawkins, help me hold her down!
I'm on it.
I got her. We're
good, we're good.
40 of ketamine.
Come on. Ready?
- Ready.
- All right,
ready when you are.
I got-I got pressure
on the artery.
CT angio and then
prep for the OR.
- You have a handle on this one?
- Thought I did. It's unlike
anything I've ever seen before.
Well, find me if you
need fresh eyes.
I will.
♪ ♪
Nic, what are you doing?
- I can't breathe. I can't breathe.
- Okay. Okay.
Are you having a panic attack?
Since when do you
have panic attacks?
Hey, hey. Leave the room.
Genie, back in your bottle.
- Since when?
- It's not something I advertise.
Seriously? How long?
Over a year.
You can't just take care
of everyone except you,
you know that, right?
- Look, I'm managing.
- Are you? Because you're sitting
on a kitchen floor,
hyperventilating.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
You're okay.
You're okay. Just breathe.
- I'm trying to.
- I know.
It's so scary.
I'm right here. I'm
right here, okay?
Look who you're talking to.
You're always here for
me, Nic. I'm here for you.
Lean back.
Bell told me what's up.
Give me good news.
Decent'll have to do.
Surgery on Laurie's femoral
artery's gonna take about
a half hour if there's
no other arteries or veins
that are severed.
All indications are they aren't.
Let me know if that changes
once you get in the OR.
Will do.
Dr. Nolan.
Check Laurie's lower abdomen
while you're in there, between
the right hip and umbilicus.
I'll be nearby, getting
proximal control for the repair,
but I prefer to stay
out of her abdomen.
Why do you want me to do that?
Oh, that's-that's
an incidentaloma.
- It's a benign growth. It's nothing.
- Yeah, or it could be
something that
explains everything.
I'll give it a look.
Dr. Bell.
Vivian.
Oh.
Comes with the territory.
You save their life?
- I did.
- You do this often?
Save lives?
Get set up on a blind
date by your assistant.
Never.
Me either.
I'm not kicking
myself at the moment.
Me either.
Go save your patient.
And I'll do my best
to be patient.
Dr. Bell. Sorry about
the 11th-hour page.
I thought three surgeons
would do the trick.
You definitely need a fourth.
I can go arm, leg, or
float between the two.
I don't know, Dr. Voss
here is excited
to reattach homeboy's
missing getaway stick.
You and I will rock
the arm, all right?
Well, wouldn't it be
great if we could give
this father of three the
ability to walk his daughter
down the aisle one day?
Hate to break your delicate
heart, Dr. Austin, but...
I'll take Mina.
There, it's settled.
Ladies on the leg.
All-stars on the arm.
Is there a person to
go with the limbs, or...
He's crashing.
Austin, you're on the
scans. Voss, circulation.
Pressure's 70/55.
Plummeting fast.
- He have any other injuries?
- Uh, broken ribs, bruised lungs.
Contained mediastinal
bleeding we need to watch.
Abdomen and pelvis look good.
This is all hemorrhagic shock.
Are we good with the
massive transfusion protocol?
Got four units in the ER.
Well, hang another
two, get the TXA ready,
and call down to the blood bank.
We're gonna need everything
- they've got.
- So much for walking
down the aisle.
Let's make sure he lives
to see his children again.
Quote: "In nothing
do men more nearly
approach the gods than
in giving health to men."
- Cicero.
- Quote:
"Check Laurie's abdomen."
Hawkins.
Uh, Andy, I'm gonna need you
to give me a little bit
more of that in this.
How long has the
leg been severed?
Somewhere around five hours.
I'm guessing 20 minutes
before that limb loses viability.
Then perhaps the focus should be
on the limb you're
trying to save.
Uh, correction, lovey.
The limb we are saving.
Suction.
Sponge.
Clamp.
All right, keep
transfusing. Put him on
Trendenlenburg.
He's bleeding out.
You're taking too
much blood away
- from the leg. He'll necrose.
- We're losing the arm.
- And who's blunder was that?
- The artery was weakened.
- What's taking so long?
- I don't know
what you're talking about.
The problem's solved.
New problem.
He's bradying down.
Get the ultrasound.
Tamponade compressed his heart.
The mediastinal bleed
must have opened up.
Lacerated P-A.
Sternal saw to me.
- Need to go on pump?
- No. We're good.
Another two units PRBCs.
Still trending down.
I'm gonna need
more cardiac support.
Slam that blood into him.
Vitals are improving.
KIT and MINA: Show-off.
Hey, if you got it, flaunt it.
As we were.
#TeamChastain, baby.
Laurie's recovering.
You were right.
Checking the abdomen
was a good call.
- This thing has teeth.
- It has a tooth.
It's a teratoma. It's not
gonna bite you, Ricky.
Teratomas are genetic
anomalies that reproduce organs,
or sometimes bone or teeth,
all within a pocket of flesh.
Rare. Unpleasant.
Perfectly appropriate discovery
on All Hallows' Eve.
Some teratomas create
antibodies that attack the brain,
and this can lead
to encephalitis.
- They can.
- We'll rerun her CSF panel
for Anti-NMDA antibodies.
I think we got this.
Okay, that's enough.
I'm really gonna be okay?
Yes. Yes!
Yeah. You have
Anti-NMDA encephalitis.
It's a rare infection
of the brain.
It was causing
all your symptoms.
We're gonna give
you a combination
of steroids and immunoglobulins.
Your night terrors
might persist for a bit, but
you should be back to
your normal life in no time.
Ah. I haven't
spoken to my family
in two years, but right now...
can't wait to tell them
I'm gonna be okay.
I just hope they
pick up the phone.
Family is complicated.
You just have to hope
that they'll be there
for you in the end.
You were right.
I should string a few days
together, recharge my batteries.
- Just say the word.
- I will.
When you tell me the truth.
Where were you today?
Maybe when you stop lying to me,
I'll consider going
to an island with you.
Sharing everything all the time
is not something
I'm interested in.
Well, I am.
Son, I'm a lot of things,
but a hypocrite
isn't one of them.
What's that supposed to mean?
I'm not exactly sitting
across from an open book.
You left home and didn't tell
me where you were for ten years.
I had to hire a private
investigator to track you down.
So don't ask of me
what you refuse
to ask of yourself.
Get some rest.
Welcome back, Frank.
What... what happened to me?
Wee bit of a car accident.
Dr. Voss and I were part
of the team that reattached
your arm and your leg.
Did-did I almost die?
Couple of times.
The important thing
is you're here now.
Yeah, m-my wife?
And daughters?
Do-do they know?
Yeah. They're on
their way up here now.
Hi.
Hi. Um...
Oh, it's-it's okay,
sweetie. It's okay.
Daddy loves you, honey.
Nice assist in the
ER today, Pravesh.
Thanks, Dr. Austin.
And what you
pulled off in the OR...
Shh. I know what I did well.
Isn't this the loveliest
part of the job?
What part are we talking about?
The part that makes you want
to pick up the phone
and call your own kids.
American Bobtail and a Maine
Coon are the only kids I got.
Wait. You have human kids?
Two, from my first marriage.
All grown now.
And one of my kids has a kid.
Good night, chaps.
Her kid has a kid.
She's a grandmother.
You know, I...
You know, I was thinking
that this indelible session
would be...
One time. No strings.
I now find myself reconsidering.
- Me too.
- Hmm.
I got to say, my new
assistant was right
about his matchmaking skills.
We raised him right.
My ex-husband is so hard on
Grayson, but I'm proud of him.
He's a good son.
What?
Uh, where's Nic?
Oh, I gave her the night off.
So, the damage:
three broken glasses,
a clogged sink, and...
Holly Golightly spilled
a drink on your rug.
It's never coming
out. I know. I'm sorry.
Stop it.
No, you stop it.
You silly little minx.
Oh, it's been
going on for a while.
- It's actually kind of adorable.
- Stop it.
What a nightmare.
Mom!
MAN ; Go now, boy.
Get out of here, boy!
Dad, no! Please!
Please.
Shh, shh. It's okay.
Shh.
Want to talk about it?
Captioned by Media
Access Group at WGBH