Previously, on
"New Amsterdam"...
She was dealing with a lot.
Maybe she needed
to deal with that alone.
I know she did,
'cause she told me.
I don't know how
to be a single man.
Your profile is set to only
matches over 90 years old.
If you just toggle that...
Oh, my gosh.
I'm looking
for a Horace Reynolds.
Hey, look, I heard
he got really sick.
It sounds like
a textbook example of someone
with bipolar disorder.
There's been a change
of plans.
I think I might
have to crash here.
The truth is
you'd be doing me a favor.
Hmm.
Somebody's been practicing.
Yeah, yeah.
Found a nice deaf instructor
on YouTube
who convinced me
to go premium.
You roll... y...
I just got the word "you."
Rolling... will you help me here?
I think you got this.
You do?
Was it roll?
Who... who door clock?
No, sorry.
Who are you door...
Who are you door punching?
That doesn't make any sense.
Here.
Would you just...
type it?
- Please.
- Hmm.
Hmm.
Great.
Thank you.
*NEW AMSTERDAM (2018)*
Season 05  Episode 03
Episode Title: "Big Day"
Aired on: October 04, 2022.
- We're all here.
- What's the big news?
You dating another
married woman?
Ladies, ladies.
Let's give him some grace, huh?
Floyd, what's going on?
Right.
So as you all know,
I've been spending
- a lot of time with Dad.
- Floyd.
And I think that there
may be an explanation
for his behavior
through all these years.
I think he has
bipolar disorder.
Why on Earth
would you think that?
Well, he was acting
very strangely the other day,
and the chair of psychiatry
suggested to me that his...
Have you lost your mind
along with him?
Oh, come on, Mama,
can't you see it?
The erratic behavior,
his... his mania,
all those awful stories
you told us
about how he behaved
before he left...
It all makes sense now.
Floyd, lots of people
have issues,
but they find a way
to stick around.
Your father didn't leave us
because he was mentally ill.
He left us because he didn't
love us enough to try!
OK, OK.
All right.
Well, let's not repeat
his mistake, right?
Let's... let's find
enough love to reach out.
The only way
to cut through decades
of untreated mental illness
is just to show him
what he could have
if he tries...
- A family.
- Oh.
I don't wanna hear this.
Lost his mind.
I honestly didn't
think you could top
having a baby in a threesome.
Hmm.
♪ Bury me alive
or just kill me ♪
♪ 'Cause honestly I'm tired
of just feeling ♪
♪ Just another
black hole feeling ♪
♪ 'Cause there's shit I've
seen that I can't forget ♪
♪ Will you, oh
♪ Don't you miss me when,
miss me when ♪
♪ I'm gone
♪ Because you're the reason
that I'm not around ♪
What are you...
Put that plate back.
It's dirty.
Yeah, this is
also my apartment.
How about some breakfast?
God, no.
Where are the... where are
the pills I had here?
Oh, I took those hours ago.
God, Mom screwed us up.
So, listen, there is work
being done on my apartment,
like some really involved
plumbing thing.
It's gonna be
at least a month,
and I was thinking
that maybe I could stay...
Hell no.
I'll pay rent.
All right, fine,
but you're paying up front.
Because who knows
when you're going
to disappear on me again?
Oh, big mistake.
Big, huge.
Are you quoting
"Pretty Woman"?
Yes, because those
dead-eyed bitches
snubbing Vivian
is the same level of dumb
as you moving in
with your sister.
You're sober, Lauren.
You can't handle
that kind of temptation.
What I can't handle
is guilt, OK?
She's a mess because
I left her there with my mom.
She's a mess
because she gobbles up drugs
like they're Skittles.
A sober person living with her
isn't gonna change that.
You haven't told her
you're sober?
- Not yet.
- When?
- Soon.
- Tonight.
I miss Casey.
I'll take this one.
Fire at a wedding venue
caused a stampede for the exit.
Groom was crushed
against the wall.
- Mostly likely broken ribs.
- OK, O2 stats are low.
Respirations are high.
Let's get him to Trauma 1
and prepare for intubation.
- Got another one.
- On it.
Cordelia Kaplan, 32,
minor abrasions
and severe smoke inhalation.
OK, vitals are stable.
Let's park her
at the nurse's station
and get her on 100% O2.
Hey, how many more
can we expect?
The whole damn wedding.
Hey, page everyone.
Hey, where do you want me?
Bay 27.
Ring bearer with facial lac.
Hey, nice suit.
- Collapsed lung?
- 70% on chest X-ray.
OK.
I will place the chest tube.
You take the esophageal rupture
up to the OR.
- On it.
- How can I help?
Is there a vax set?
Wilder's in Trauma 1.
Massive bleed.
Copy.
Excuse me.
Hey, where are we?
We got
a lacerated femoral artery.
Trying to close him up,
but I can't stop the bleed.
- He's the groom.
- How's the pressure?
106/58.
Thank you.
Severe cyanosis
on both hands.
Wait, wait, wait on the blood.
It's O negative.
Check his pockets.
His blood type
is Lutheran B negative.
His cells have an atypical
protein, making it very rare.
What does that mean?
It means that O negative is
not a universal blood for him,
and it could kill him.
Hey, do we have any
Lutheran B negative on hand?
No.
OK, Ellie, well, it's
looking pretty cleaned out,
so we'll get you
a couple stitches,
and we'll get you out of here.
- Your mom's gonna be OK.
- See?
Everything's gonna be OK,
just like I told you.
Lily?
You doing OK, Lily?
That's a beautiful bouquet.
Should we get them some water?
Honey?
Can you tell me
how you're feeling, Lily?
OK, you stay right here.
I'm gonna go
and get some water.
- What's wrong?
- I'm not sure.
- Close her up.
- On it.
- Iggy?
- Yeah, yeah.
Put it up over your nose.
Deep breaths, okay?
Yeah?
OK, so the flower girl,
she's got no visible injuries,
but she's unresponsive
to verbal and physical cues.
OK, oh, yeah,
I'll check that out.
Deep breaths, OK?
Deep, slow.
You have to clear this area.
I'm so sorry.
Whoa!
This is why
I'm never getting married.
Ottawa usually has two
frozen units, but they're out.
OK, so what's
the next closest?
- Perth.
- Australia?
It's 26 hours away.
Our guy has maybe 12 hours
before complete organ failure.
I mean, this is why
rare blood banks exist.
- How can none of them have any?
- Seriously?
Covid, staffing limitations,
poor donor turnout.
Mexico City has nothing.
You're smiling.
Does that mean somebody...
Toronto General has two units
of Lutheran B negative
ready to make the trip.
I'm gonna get
the helicopter ready.
I will go find the bride
and let her know
that her wedding day
is finally looking up.
It was just awful.
Not the venue,
which I had my doubts about,
but turned out
to be quite lovely
until all hell broke loose.
Well, the good news is
is most of these cuts
appear to be superficial.
Let's start hitting them
with antibiotic ointment,
and let's get as many
of them glued as possible.
- On it.
- What happened to your elbow?
Oh, my.
- I'm deformed!
- I'm sorry.
I'm sure this isn't what
you pictured when you RSVP'd.
Ow.
No, it wasn't.
Knowing the family, I expected
subpar food and a cash bar,
but not an explosion
during the I dos.
An explosion?
I thought it was a fire.
Kaboom.
Suddenly, the room was full
of smoke, the thick kind,
- like at Korean barbecue.
- Oh.
And you said
you're feeling back pain?
Oh, like when
you swallow wrong,
and it feels like
the food is stabbing your back
from the inside.
Dr. Turan,
help me get him on the side.
Nice and easy,
nice and easy, now.
You got it.
Were you
at the wedding alone?
Alone?
I've been married for 40 years.
I'm never anywhere alone.
My wife's a few beds over.
Glad she's OK.
The minute it happened,
everyone started
screaming, running.
My wife needed me,
and I couldn't find her.
Oh!
All right,
start an IV of Toradol.
All right, Stan, I'm gonna have
to cut off your tux.
But it's a rental.
Agh!
Oh.
That actually feels better.
Pass me some of those 4x4s.
I'm gonna get started
on this side.
Set aside a week.
Do you have
any idea what could have
- caused so many tiny cuts?
- I don't know.
Maybe when I ran through
the champagne glass tower.
- Face-first.
- Need to irrigate.
You sure
you didn't fall on your back?
Yes, because I remember
pushing myself up,
like a push-up,
to look for Tamara.
That's when the entire wedding
ran across my back.
Everything look OK?
Is there any chance
you might have been shot?
- Shot?
- Who would do that?
Who would erect
a 10-foot-tall crystal monster
in the middle of a party?
Even if there hadn't been
an explosion,
someone was going
through that thing.
All right.
Well, I think
you're good to go.
Oh, but what about my ankle?
Tamara, wow.
It's just the wedding
that keeps on giving.
- Uh-huh.
- OK, OK.
Ow, ow!
Is it broken?
Sprained is my guess,
but we should
probably get an X-ray
just to be safe.
Ow.
What?
Go ahead and dress the wound.
Oh, how's Tamara Leckie doing?
Well, I think
she's done with weddings,
but she's gonna be fine.
How's her husband?
Well, I was convinced
he had been shot,
but there's
three inches of something
jammed through his back.
What do you mean, something?
It's definitely not a bullet,
but whatever it is,
it's long and thin.
Yeah.
- Yeah.
- Okay.
Just give me
a few minutes.
Hi.
Hey, Lily.
So I thought
it might be helpful
to get you out
of all that chaos
for a few minutes, right?
A little peace and quiet.
Also, Lily, your mom is
right outside of that window,
so if you need her
for anything, you let me know.
I'll take you right to her.
Deal?
Bit of good news,
your physical exams
all came back,
and they show
no bodily harm whatsoever.
I don't know
what you saw at that wedding.
I bet it was really scary,
but I promise you,
you are safe now.
- Safe now.
- Yes.
Yes, safe.
I promise.
Lily, do you think I can
ask you some questions?
Lily, I need you to try
to stay with me please.
Please.
OK, I'll be right back.
I saw her speaking.
That's good, right?
So this is not...
just trauma.
Your daughter
is suffering from catatonia.
That's not... she just needs
to go home and rest.
No, she needs to be admitted
to the behavioral health ward.
Right now.
- No pulse.
- Go again.
He's back.
The blood just arrived
in New York.
- I need it here.
- I know.
They should be calling me
any second.
- How'd the bride react?
- I couldn't find her.
They must have
taken her to Baptist.
Hold on.
Yeah.
Let's get more Propofol.
No, no, no.
I don't really care
about protocol.
There's
an extenuating circumstance.
I have... can you...
If you'd listen...
The blood is stuck in customs.
Homeland Security
won't release it
for two to three days.
This man
will be dead before that.
Yeah, hi,
this is Dr. Max Goodwin,
medical director
of New Amsterdam.
Can you do me a favor
and connect me with the head
of Memorial's rare blood bank?
So you're OK letting
a precious lifesaving resource
rot in a warehouse
because of red tape?
Yes, yes, that's two units
of Lutheran B negative.
Memorial Hospital in Seattle
said you might have some.
Just say you are OK with
someone dying because of it.
- I will leave you alone.
- You're my fifth call.
- You are my ninth call.
- Lutheran B negative.
- You are my 11th call.
- You're my 14th...
- Call.
- No?
What?
I know.
I know it's a long shot,
but this guy
is getting married today,
and I was kind of hoping
for a miracle.
You're not gonna believe it.
You found
Lutheran B negative?
I found Rh-null.
- Are you serious?
- Sorry. What is Rh-null?
Rh-null is the only
universal blood for people
with rare blood types.
One in 3,000 people
who have Lutheran B negative,
but less than 50 people
have ever been known
to have Rh-null.
I mean ever.
- That's why they call it...
- Golden blood.
And there are
two fresh units of it
waiting for us
at a small hospital
in Hamilton, Bermuda.
- In Bermuda?
- 90 minutes away.
That won't help us.
Any blood that we import
is gonna get stuck in customs.
I know, and that's why we're
not gonna import the blood.
OK, so what
are we gonna do?
We're gonna
import the donor.
And we're gonna leave
in 45 minutes.
♪ 'Cause when you see me
So the medical director
of Hamilton United designated
two units of Rh-null blood
to be released to you
upon completing
this export request.
Actually, change of plans.
We don't need the blood.
We just need the...
The donor.
Yeah, well,
I'm afraid, unfortunately,
donor information
is confidential.
They may not even live here.
People donate
in other cities all the time.
Mm-hm,
but the two units of blood
set aside for me
weren't frozen,
which means they were donated
in the last 42 days,
and this bank
has had a steady supply
of Rh-null
since 2017, which tells me
that the donor does live here.
I just really need you
to tell me where that is.
Understood.
Again, I cannot give out
personal information.
You can.
You can, actually.
We have...
Sir, would you mind just...
Just taking a look
at the donor's file.
You don't have
to show it to us.
Just take a look at it.
OK.
I'm looking at it.
OK, now look
at all the donations
that he or she has given
in the last five years.
I mean, think about all
the lives that they have saved.
This is...
This is someone who really
wants to help other people.
Look, I'm sorry,
but I can't just...
Listen...
All I can give you
is the forms.
Somebody's gonna die
unless you
give us this information.
No, what?
- No, it's fine.
- It's not fine.
No, we... we flew here for...
What are you...
We should go.
It's fine.
- It's fine.
- Thank you.
- Hey, thank you.
- Have a good day.
Uh, I'm sorry.
What... what was that?
I mean, what was that?
Will you help me out?
We came all this way, and you
push me out of the room?
I'm one minute away.
What?
There's no need.
He looked at the donor's file
long enough
for me to get this.
What is that?
That's the donor's address.
How?
Well, when you're deaf,
you pay a lot more attention
to reflections.
You know, like, glasses,
for example.
- Hm.
- Oh, you're good.
I know.
- She's good.
- I know.
- Let's go!
- Well, let's go.
- Yeah, we're going, OK.
- All right.
She's tenacious.
Oh, my Lord.
Yep, that definitely
is a high heel.
Yeah, and it is
really in there.
You were trying to rescue me,
like my knight
in shining armor,
and I trampled you.
- Honey, honey.
- Don't be nice to me.
I ran over you like roadkill.
You've been walking
all over me for 40 years.
Now we have a picture
to commemorate it.
The good news is that it
missed all your vital organs.
Which means that,
despite the last several hours,
you two are actually
pretty lucky.
- Whoa, whoa!
- Tamara!
- Need a little help here.
- No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Do not move, OK?
If the heel moves
in the wrong way,
- you could die.
- But what's happening?
There's nothing
blocking her airways.
All right, all right.
OK, OK.
I got you.
I got... wait, what's...
What are these cuts?
What are all these cuts?
When everyone
rushed the door,
she crashed
into the champagne tower.
She inhaled the glass.
It's shredding
her intestines.
We need to get her
to an OR now.
Is she gonna be OK?
Hey.
The waiting is hell, I know.
Did the doctors explain
the meds she's on?
They tried.
I could barely focus.
Was it benzo
something, something?
Benzodiazepine, yeah.
It's basically a calming agent.
It's often very effective
at easing people
out of catatonic states, so...
Often, not always?
Yeah.
What if she
doesn't come back?
Hey, hey.
I promise you we're doing
everything we can.
- OK?
- She's got to wake up.
Please make her wake up.
I keep replaying it in my mind.
After that maniac
started the fire,
- she must have been so scared.
- I'm sorry.
I thought... someone started
the fire on purpose?
I thought it was an explosion.
Protect your children.
We all need
to protect our children.
What's happening?
- I need a team in here now!
- She's seizing!
- Crash cart!
- I'm right behind you.
Come on, guys,
make room, make room.
- All right, on it.
- Call zero stats.
- Paging OR 3.
- Start on Lorazepam drip.
- Give me an army-navy.
- But there's no time to work...
Heart rate's rising.
- She's bleeding.
- From where?
I cleared the stomach.
No glass.
BP's dropping.
Give me another unit a blood.
Must have passed
into her small intestine.
I'm gonna run the valve.
OK.
All right,
how are you doing, Stan?
I abandoned my wife.
Stan, even if you didn't
have a serious injury,
there's no way they would have
let you in the OR with her.
No, I abandoned her
at the wedding.
A tetanus jab, please.
When I heard
that explosion,
I just took off.
I didn't look for her.
I didn't even think about her.
I ran.
I left her behind.
Now she might die
because of it.
Hey, you can't
blame yourself for that.
Watch me.
Oh, you don't know
what it is to know
you failed someone you love...
to know they're hurt
because of you.
And you think
back to that moment,
wishing you could have
done something different,
but you couldn't
because you weren't in control.
Your body decided
that it had to survive.
And now your soul's stuck
picking up the pieces.
Right?
I'm telling you
you can't blame yourself.
No good comes of it.
All you can try to do is atone.
How do I do that?
By telling her the truth.
Come on, come on.
God.
I'm not feeling any resistance.
BP down 60 over palp.
It's got to be
in here somewhere.
Dr. Reynolds,
we're losing her.
The shard, It's cut
its way out of the bowel.
It's in her abdomen.
HR, 78 BPM.
Dr. Reynolds,
use the forceps.
I've got to be able
to feel the glass.
It could cut your glove.
Come on.
Where are you?
Up on the monitor.
One minute,
you're Mr. By-The-Book,
the next,
you're "Indiana Jones",
just going at it on your own.
Yeah, well,
I should have waited.
Maybe she's alive
because you didn't.
All right, let's repair
the bowel and close her up.
Whew.
- Yes, can I help you?
- I really hope so.
I'm Max Goodwin,
medical director
of New Amsterdam Hospital
in New York City.
This is Dr. Wilder,
the chair of hematology,
and we are here because we are
trying to save a man's life,
and we are running out of time.
Is there someone in this home
with Rh-null blood type?
How did you get this address?
Uh...
Well, um, we stole it
from the donor registry
at the blood bank.
Uh, wow.
OK, yeah, we did do that.
But does that person live here?
If you stole it,
you know they do.
- Can we speak to that person?
- No.
No, you can't.
Showing up to someone's house
to demand their blood is...
I don't even have
a word for it.
You're doctors.
Yes, we are,
which is why we're trying
to save our patient's life
the only way we know how,
and that is to bring the donor
back to New York with us
in one hour where they can
donate their blood in person.
Please leave.
Respectfully,
we can't do that.
We need to speak to the donor.
The donor
doesn't need to talk to you.
All they do is give and give
to doctors, to scientists,
to anyone who begs them
for their blood,
even when there's
none left to give,
even when they turn yellow
from anemia,
even when they need
their family
to carry them to bed
because they're too weak
to make it up the stairs.
Today, their daughter
is giving birth,
and I'm not
gonna let them miss it.
For once, they're gonna get
to be just like everyone else.
But they are not
like everyone else.
They're special.
They can save lives
that nobody else can save.
What is a better legacy
to bestow on a child than that?
Don't come back here.
Ma'am, please, if we...
Hey, Lily.
My gosh, you gave us all
quite the scare earlier.
But you know, we got your meds
right in the sweet spot now.
Everything's looking good.
How are you feeling?
You... you hurt anywhere?
You OK?
You know, no one
is gonna make you talk.
I promise you that,
but if you want to,
I'm here, OK?
No rush,
no pressure whatsoever.
In fact, I'm low-key
kind of psyched,
because that means I get to do
with you what I never
get to do with my patients.
I get to talk.
Yes.
Lucky you.
Dr. Frome is in the building.
You know, your day today
in a lot of ways
reminded me of my own wedding,
believe it or not.
So I decided to bring along
these bad boys to show you.
Look at this.
See?
Two grooms, me and my husband.
I know, he's very handsome,
isn't he?
We had an officiant
who was an ordained priest
but also a stand-up comedian,
so that was a lot.
And... oh, my niece.
My niece was the flower girl.
And what's fun about her is
that during my father-in-law's
lovely toast, she decided
to tackle the ring bearer,
grab the ring,
and try to eat it.
She's four.
It's not her fault.
But I would say that,
all in all,
if I had to choose one word
to describe that day,
it would be beautiful.
It was a beautiful day.
What about you?
If you had
to describe the wedding
that you were at today
in one word,
what would that word be?
Well, I wasn't there,
but I would go
with something like scary?
You know, your mom told me
the fire was not an accident,
and I don't think there's
anything scarier
than seeing somebody
do something bad.
You know these scared feelings
you have?
They're tricky because
they don't... they don't go away
unless you talk about them.
And it's totally OK
if you don't
have the words to tell me.
You know,
that's why I brought this.
I find that it's helpful
if you make the story
about them and not about you.
All right, so why don't we...
Why don't we start easy, OK?
Why don't you show me
where the bride
and the groom were?
Can you do that?
Nice.
OK.
Good.
Good, very good.
All right.
Let's keep this party
rolling here.
What about the flower girl
and the ring bearer?
Where were they?
Can you do the same thing?
Show me where they were.
Thank you.
Yes, good.
So good, so good.
Where was the person
who started the fire?
Where were they?
Do you know them?
Oh, a mask?
They were wearing a mask?
OK.
All right.
So a...
A man wearing a full mask
standing next to the bride
started the fire on purpose.
That's good.
Lily, that's really good.
Thank you.
You know,
I know today was scary,
but you are by far
the bravest flower girl
I have ever met.
Yeah, I know what I know.
Yeah.
Is he OK?
Who?
My husband.
Welcom to L.A.
It's the hospital.
I'll let them know.
Hey.
Wait, wait.
What about CPS?
No, no, no, just... just
lock down the whole hospital
until the police get there, OK?
Yeah.
What's wrong?
Tell me.
The groom, the man
that we've been flying
between countries to save,
he was about to marry
a little girl.
It was a child wedding.
Dr. Goodwin?
Did the donor
change their mind?
Yes, I did.
I wouldn't be able
to look at my granddaughter
knowing that someone died
because I didn't help them.
I don't... I don't get it.
I mean, we've all treated
bad people before.
This time
just feels different.
Different is
an understatement.
I feel like
I need 10 showers.
I mean,
I've treated murderers
and straight-up killers.
I shouldn't feel like this.
So why do we?
Because it was all of them.
It wasn't just
the mother or the groom.
It was every one of those
patients supported this.
So...
It turns out it wasn't a fire.
It was a smoke bomb.
Lily's older brother,
who was only 15 himself,
he wasn't trying
to hurt anybody.
He was just... he was trying
to save his sister.
Yeah, well, at least
there's one sane person
in that poor girl's family.
The police should lock up
every last one of those people
and lose the key.
Yeah.
Nobody's getting arrested.
What?
Because there's
no federal law
against child marriage
in this country.
That's why.
Because it only became illegal
in New York last year,
so Lily's mother
drove up to West Virginia
and got herself
a 100% legal marriage license.
In some of these states,
they could have married her off
when she was five.
Right, so nobody is
gonna get punished for this.
Just Lily.
♪ So we're walking through
the valley of a place ♪
♪ We shouldn't go
♪ And it might
be hard for you to know it ♪
♪ But the less you know,
the better ♪
Iggy.
Uh...
- It... it's not your night.
- I know, I know.
Can I just, um...
Can I just see the kids?
Yeah.
Yeah, babe, of course.
♪ Trusting me coming down
♪ If we can pass this test
♪ There's hope
- Hey.
Listen, there's something
that I want to tell you and...
You know what?
Me first.
Look, I'm sorry
for how I acted this morning.
It's... I mean,
it's complicated, right?
We're... we're complicated,
but I really appreciate
that you're trying
to make up for stuff, and I...
I love that we're...
you know, bonding.
Or, I don't know,
whatever this is.
So...
Me too, Ness.
♪ And it might
be hard for you to know ♪
Uh, OK.
So, sorry, you... you wanted
to tell me something.
It was just that I love you.
Uh, you know what?
To the Bloom sisters.
Barely functional,
but a ton of fun.
All right, cheers.
Ah.
May I come in?
I don't remember us
making any plans.
Uh, Dad.
I got to say something
that's gonna be hard to hear.
I think you may be bipolar.
Bipolar?
Yes, and I think
that you've been living
with it for most of your life.
So all the times
you made choices that, uh,
caused you to...
lose things, I...
I think this is...
I think this is why.
So this bipolar,
this is
a real medical condition?
Yes.
So all the stuff
I did to you, your mama,
to your sisters...
It's not your fault.
It's not my fault?
No, Dad.
Everybody been making me out
to be the bad guy,
but I'm just a sick man?
That's right.
So I'm gonna need you
to come in to New Amsterdam
- tomorrow, OK?
- For what?
Oh, for testing,
and so we can come up
with a plan for treatment.
I don't want
to do any of that,
but I do think your mama
owes me an apology.
- Your sisters too.
- What?
I'm not
all those names
they've been calling me
for years.
None of it is my fault.
I couldn't control none of it.
I'm sick!
I got a condition.
I got to make some calls!
♪ Hardly fanciful
♪ And it might be
in your interest too ♪
♪ Remember nights I
- Hey
- Hey.
Yeah, I was breaking down ♪
♪ And I won't wait a moment
till you drown ♪
♪ Till you drown
♪ You won't trust in me
coming down, oh ♪
♪ You feed, and the price
he picks is hope ♪
♪ She says hello
♪ And I say hello
♪ To all the people
I'd abandon anymore ♪
♪ And I say hello
to all the people ♪
Go?
Hug.
Mm-hmm.
Hey, Lu,
you know what I was thinking?
What?
Maybe I'll sleep here
with you tonight.
- What do you think?
- Good.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Goodnight, baby.
Goodnight.
- Love you, Lu.
- Love you.
Synchronized by srjanapala