Packed you some of
last night's lasagna.
Oh, thank you, baby.
Okay.
You good?
Yes. Bye.
Bye.
Oh, wait. Almost forgot.
Uh, I bought you these.
Memory foam,
on your feet all day.
I don't know what
I'd do without you.
Yeah.
Yes.
"Yes", what?
I'm sorry that
it took so long,
but I do wanna marry you.
I mean, if the offer
still stands.
I've been sitting
on this for months,
just waiting.
What?
Yeah.
Oh, my God.
It's beautiful.
Tate, yes!
Hey.
Wait, I thought you were
picking up an extra shift.
Yeah, I was hoping to,
but Goodwin put
a moratorium on overtime.
Oh, I do not wanna
go home right now
and face Mandelbrot.
What, is your new roomie
still leaving toe nail
clippings on the couch?
Worse. Now, he's doing
jumping jacks in the nude.
Okay, you really
need a new roommate.
I can't make
rent without him.
Well, hey, if worst
comes to worst,
I got plenty of beds
down in the morgue.
Yeah.
Yeah, I bet you do.
I might take you up on that.
Have a good day.
Um, Dr. Halstead?
Yeah?
I, uh... I don't
mean to pry,
but it sounds to me
like you may be
in need of
a little extra cash flow.
Now, just hear me out
for one sec.
I think I can help.
Dr. Manning,
incoming, Trauma Three.
Sixty-one-year-old male,
BP 140 over 90, fever 101.
Called it in himself,
but could hardly breathe
by the time we got there.
Please...
Sir, I need you
to just relax.
Listen to me.
Try to relax, okay?
All right, let's start
a neb treatment
and get 125 milligrams
Solu-Medrol IV.
Okay, got it.
And an ABG kit...
All right,
let's transfer him.
On my count.
Ready? One, two, three.
Let's get it out.
Let's get that
neb treatment.
Coming up.
Just try to relax, sir.
All right, I need you
to take a deep
breath for me, okay?
There you go.
Do you have any
family we should notify?
No, I need...
I need to speak to Sharon.
Deep breath.
Relax, relax.
Sharon...
Take this in.
McGee.
What did he say?
Something about a Sharon.
"McGee", he said "McGee".
That's Goodwin's
maiden name.
Keep taking
deep breaths, sir.
I had a fever and a headache
for the past week,
figured I had the flu.
Next thing I know,
I can't catch my breath.
Any history of illness?
Had a flare-up
of colitis
a few months back.
Doctor put me on
a course of steroids.
Reggie Dixon.
There she is.
Just like I remember.
It has been way too long.
Oh!
Oh, it sure has.
Reggie and I grew up
in the same neighborhood.
Haven't seen each other
since when?
The summer after
my senior year
in high school.
That's right. That's right.
I'd just gotten
back from Vietnam.
You served?
Sort of. Only thing I ever
shot was my Pentax 1000.
Oh, Reggie was
a photographer with
Stars and Stripes.
Now, they said that
you're having trouble
catching your breath?
Well, I can't say
you're making it any easier.
Stop it.
Mr. Dixon, um, the doctor
that put you on steroids,
can you get us
his information?
I can, but, uh,
he's in Paris.
In Paris?
Yeah, Reuters had me
stationed there,
and I transferred back here.
Time to start
the next chapter.
And is there anyone
we could call?
Are your folks
still living?
How about a wife?
Never married.
Never put down
any roots.
Heard you were
running the show
at this place,
so, I told the dispatcher
to route me here.
Knew you'd have my back.
Yeah.
You know that's right.
I'm glad you did.
Uh, Nurse Doris here's
gonna draw some blood,
so we can order a few tests.
I'll be right back.
Thank you.
So, what are we
looking at here?
Well, he was on a course
of steroids, um,
which could have weakened
his immune system.
We could be looking at
a respiratory infection.
We'll get a chest X-ray
and start him on
broad-spectrum antibiotics.
See what
the labs say, Maggie.
Copy.
If you suspect anything,
run it down, and you
let me know the second
you get results.
Of course.
Yes, ma'am.
Okay.
Was it just me, or...
No, she was
definitely flirting.
Yeah.
Please help.
April,
what is wrong?
Please, my arm,
it's killing me.
From the weight of this...
What?
Look at the sparkle
on that thing.
Oh!
You are gonna
need some sunglasses.
Congratulations, April.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
Hey, Mags,
you see this thing?
It's hard to miss.
Reese.
So beautiful.
Treatment Two.
Tried to assign him
to someone else,
but he said he would
only talk to you.
Okay.
This is big.
Danny, what's wrong?
My stomach,
it's tied up in knots.
Let's take a look.
Don't they have
a clinic at the shelter?
I'm not at
the shelter anymore.
What?
A woman came in
with her newborn.
They said
they needed the bed.
Told me I had to leave.
They kicked you out?
I spent the night
on the street.
I barely slept.
Hey, can you
close the curtain?
What's going on?
I don't want them
to find me.
We took your
tracking chip out.
They know that I was here.
Don't worry.
I'm gonna keep you safe.
Double-iced latte
with one pump of
sugar-free vanilla.
For Robin.
Excuse me.
Oh, I'm sorry,
you just ordered the
exact same drink as me.
Vanilla? A little
dainty for a surgeon.
What are the odds?
Well, if you limit
the data set
to just lattes,
you've got ice or no ice,
caff or decaf...
Don't forget
the vanilla.
I'd say the odds of
any two random people
ordering the same thing
are about one in 36.
Good with numbers.
Ah! Of course.
Epidemiology.
Wait, are you...
Are you that Charles?
I'll see you later.
Okay, designed it myself.
With one swipe,
you get a board-certified
physician
on your doorstep
within the hour.
A house-call app?
I prefer
"medicinal concierge".
Look, I just launched the beta
and I already got
a write-up in TechCrunch.
Subscriber base
is set to explode
within the next quarter.
And I've got a few
residents on board,
but with an attending,
we can make a killing.
A killing making
house calls?
How does $200 a call sound?
This is the future of
medicine. All right?
And you have
the option to get in
on the ground floor,
without that
annoying roommate.
Oh.
Here's one right now.
A 23-year-old male
with a persistent nosebleed.
So, what do you say?
Chicago PD dropped
her off this morning.
They found her
loitering outside of
a convenience store,
jabbering to herself,
disoriented,
no idea where
she'd come from,
or how she got there.
Pamela? I'm Dr. Charles.
You're not Bob.
No.
But you can call me Daniel.
Um, do you mind
if we ask you
a couple of questions?
Dr. Wheeler was
thinking that maybe,
you're feeling
a bit out of sorts.
Do you know
why you're here?
I just wanted some
ice cream, and...
You know what? I think
I might be able to
help you out with that.
What flavor were
you thinking?
Cookie dough.
Oh, dang.
That's my favorite.
You mind if I...
If I look at your hand?
Oh, boy.
You have really
beautiful nails.
You know what, Pamela?
I'm gonna see what
I can do about that
cookie dough, okay?
Okay.
Thanks.
I need a CBC, CMP,
and you better
page cardiology.
Why? I called you in
for a psych consult.
She's not psychotic,
she has endocarditis.
You didn't notice the fever?
The splinter hemorrhages
under her nails?
The cops said
that she was having
a psychotic episode,
so I just assumed that...
An infection is
attacking her heart
and sending micro-strokes
to her brain.
Okay, so, we should
page cardiology, right?
You know what, Jason?
I think I'm gonna
take this myself,
but good work,
really. I mean it.
Maggie?
Already on it.
I was thinking it might be
a good idea to loop in
epidemiology, you know?
Maybe Dr. Robin Charles?
Just to be safe.
Help, help.
My belly. My belly!
My belly is on fire!
It's on fire!
Okay, okay.
Help!
He's got a rash.
It feels... God,
it feels like something's
alive in there.
It's not a rash.
These are worms.
How the hell
did I get worms?
Have you traveled
recently to any
underdeveloped countries?
Anywhere tropical?
The south of France
is as tropical
as I've gotten in
the past 20 years.
What about before that?
You said you served
with Stars and Stripes.
Did you do any
time in the country?
I was with the 7th Cav
when they took Quang Tri.
What, does that have
something to do with this?
What aren't they
telling me?
Let's not get ahead
of ourselves.
I wanna get a stool sample.
See what the labs say.
Yeah. Just try to rest,
Mr. Dixon.
We'll be back soon.
So, what were you
driving at in there?
I think we're looking at
a parasitic roundworm
called "strongyloides".
Seen a bunch of
cases at the VA.
I'm guessing he picked
it up in Vietnam.
But that was
over 40 years ago.
The worms embed themselves
in the intestinal wall
and can remain
dormant for decades.
The steroids he was on
to treat his colitis
must have suppressed
his immune system,
allowing the larvae
to proliferate.
So, we put him on
an anti-parasitic.
That should
clear him up, right?
The worms have reached
the surface of his skin.
I'd say he's in
a hyperinfective state.
Ms. Goodwin,
I'm sorry,
but most patients
don't survive this.
I don't want you two
throwing in the towel
before we've even started.
Ms. Goodwin, we're just
presenting our
medical opinion.
I don't want your opinion.
I want you to
keep him alive.
So, what'd you find?
Uh, MRSA's
definitely a possibility.
But it's hard to confirm
without a detailed history.
Is there any family
we could talk to?
You know, so far,
nobody that seems
to be in the picture,
but we're still trying.
Then I'll grow some cultures
and fill in the rest
of the puzzle myself.
Look,
before you go, um,
your mom told me
you just broke up
with your boyfriend.
Wow.
I'm sorry. You keep
canceling coffee.
We'll get to it.
Okay.
Look, it's so not
a big deal, but I got
this thing in my office,
it's a pashmina
scarf, you know?
It's been up there
for a while.
We could go up
and get it.
Thank you, Dad.
But I really gotta
get cracking on this.
Of course, you do.
Maybe later.
Kids. People say
the hardest part
is when they decide
they don't need you anymore.
Oh, yeah.
Daniel? Daniel, Daniel.
Where are they taking me?
My friend, Dr. Berger,
Alvin, is taking you
upstairs for a quick test.
Gonna take about
five minutes.
No, please.
Please, don't leave me,
Daniel. Please,
don't leave me.
Okay. All right.
Listen, Pamela, Dr. Berger,
Alvin, really knows
what he's doing,
and this is gonna
literally take about
five minutes, okay?
Why don't I take you
upstairs and get you
settled, okay?
Okay.
Okay, here we go.
So, when did
the bleeding start?
This morning.
Couldn't have
come at a worse time.
I don't get 10,000
lines of code written
by the end of the week,
my VC's gonna pull
our series B round.
Series B?
That's pre-IPO.
Besides the bleed,
anything else
bothering you?
Uh, I've got
this headache,
but that's probably
from staring at a screen
for the last 48 hours.
Any history of
autoimmune disorders
or cancer in the family?
Nada.
Any past addiction,
drug use?
Only thing I'm addicted to
is my work.
Seen hundreds
of bleeds in my day,
most of them
from far worse
places than a nose.
Just try to relax, Eliot.
We're gonna get you
all fixed up.
Protective custody?
Mmm-hmm.
We don't have
a suspect, much less
an open investigation.
We legally can't
protect Danny,
unless he gives us
information about the
people who held him captive.
So, talk to him.
I did. I tried.
I went to the shelter
and he wouldn't talk to me.
Well, now, he's gonna
have to sleep on
the street tonight.
Are you okay with that?
No, of course not.
So, can we talk
to him together?
'Cause maybe he'll
open up with me there.
Let's give it a shot.
Okay.
Did you ever hear any of them
call each other by a name,
or a nickname?
Look, you don't have
to be afraid anymore.
You can help us catch them.
Detective
Lindsay's our friend.
If you answer her questions,
she can keep you safe.
It might be a small
detail you remember
about the place
that they kept you.
A landmark,
or any unusual sounds.
My stomach hurts.
I'm gonna let you rest, okay?
You can call me anytime.
I'll be right back, Danny.
He's not ready.
He's obviously terrified.
And I wish that I could help,
but my hands are tied here.
Let me know if
he changes his mind.
Okay.
Good luck.
Hey.
So, Tate stepped up.
What made you finally
accept the man's proposal?
He's been so great
through everything.
And now that it seems
like the TB's gonna
remain inactive, I...
Did you two resolve
all the other issues?
Issues?
You told me that
he didn't want
you working anymore.
Oh, that...
That was just one time.
You didn't discuss it?
How about his ex-wife?
Or you becoming a stepmom?
We talk about
everything, and
I love him. I mean...
This is the happiest day
of my life, and
you're pissing on it.
That's not what I'm doing.
You know what?
Next time you feel
the need to weigh in, don't.
What?
I thought I made it
out of 'Nam alive.
I didn't know there
was a 40-year delay
on that grenade.
Don't talk
like that, Reggie.
I'm a newsman.
Mordant humor
comes with the job.
Do you remember that time
we watched the sun rise
at Rainbow Beach?
Yeah.
Stayed up all night.
All night.
It was good you
brought that flask
of Hennessy to keep us warm.
Corrupting a minor.
Indeed.
Listen, about
when you left...
We were just in
different places
in our lives.
Chalk it up
to bad timing.
I heard through
the grapevine that
you got married.
I did. We had a good run.
But now, we're separated.
I'm really sorry
about that.
Maybe...
Maybe our timing
will be better
this go-round.
Sharon.
Reggie?
I can't...
I need some help in here!
BP's diving.
What happened?
Gastric hemorrhage.
Let's get him on
the rapid transfuser.
Two of red cells,
two of plasma, and
a five pack of platelets.
I need an NG tube.
Got it.
Here, Nat.
Excuse me.
I need cold saline.
Yes, Doctor.
Reggie? Reggie,
stay with me, I'm here.
It's not clearing.
Start a PPI drip,
vasopressin, and page GI.
We need to get
control of this bleed.
On it.
GI's got his bleeding
under control, but his
sats are down to 88,
his lungs are deteriorating.
So, what now?
We'll see how
he responds to the
inhaled nitric oxide.
He's on a PEEP of 10.
There's still
room to increase.
If his sats don't improve,
we might consider
a paralytic drip.
So, we do still
have some options.
Why don't we
put him on ECMO?
Oh, I don't want to
speak for Dr. Choi,
but while putting him
on ECMO might
protect his lungs,
it wouldn't be
addressing
the inflammation
affecting the
rest of his organs.
I agree. ECMO might
buy us a little time,
but it won't help
him fight off
the hyperinfection.
So, you're against it?
Both of you?
Yeah.
That's right.
See what else you
can come up with.
It'd be nice to get
ahead of this thing
instead of always
playing from behind.
Hey, Dr. Charles,
I just got off
the phone with cardiology.
Your patient, Pamela,
they just confirmed.
Endocarditis.
They, um, they putting
her on antibiotics?
No, the plan is to
remove the vegetations,
and reconstruct her aorta.
She's going
into surgery now.
Surgery?
Who authorized that?
Hey, Dr. Vanilla Latte.
I need to collect
another blood sample
from Pamela. I can't
grow a decent culture.
I can do you one better.
I can get you
the infected valve itself.
Great.
I'm scrubbing in.
Once again,
we're in the same place
at the same time,
wanting the same thing.
Would you care to run that
through your calculator?
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
What's going on here?
Evidently, there's
an issue with consent.
Surgery's been canceled.
Canceled by who?
By me.
Hey, Pamela.
Now, I laid out
everything for her.
I explained the risks,
her alternative.
I have her signature
right here.
That scrawl?
Doesn't matter if you
approve of her penmanship,
I have her consent.
Not her
informed consent.
She's way too impaired
to make that kind of
decision right now.
So, you're gonna
make the decision for her?
We can't get the consent
that you are insisting on
without first
performing surgery.
Sounds like a catch-22.
She needs the surgery.
It's urgent and necessary.
Of course you think that.
You're a surgeon.
Your inherent bias
is to cut.
What about you, the shrink?
You don't have a bias?
Well, I'm not afraid
to admit that I'm biased.
My job gets a lot easier
if I can get my hands
on that infected valve.
You know what?
Unfortunately,
not really open for debate.
Performing surgery
without actual
informed consent
is by law, assault.
I mean, you should
thank me, Doctor.
I'm trying to save you
a lot of legal bills.
Well, Dr. Charles, I hope
that when you're done
trying to prove a point,
I still have time
to save her.
Now, if you'll excuse me.
I'm gonna need to
remove that, okay?
All right.
Do your thing, Doc.
Looks like
the bleeding subsided.
Hey, what do you
call that thing again?
A Rhino Rocket.
Cool.
All right,
what do I owe you?
$350, flat rate.
Sounds fair to me.
You got a Square?
Sure do.
Now, before we
finish up, have you
gone swimming lately?
Specifically
in fresh water?
Yeah, I got a couple
acres lakeside up in
Lake Geneva. Why?
Yeah, I'd like to bring
you back to the ED
with us for more tests.
Wait, the hospital?
Guys, er, I'm kind of busy
here. I thought we got
this all fixed up.
We did, probably,
and I'm 95% sure
it isn't serious.
What isn't serious?
Well, there's an infection
I'd like to rule out,
naegleriasis.
And that's
extremely unlikely.
Excuse me, Dr. Halstead,
can I speak with you
for a moment?
Excuse us.
Really, uh, you think
he caught a warm-water
amoeba
in a Wisconsin lake
in October?
Tell me it hasn't been
unseasonably hot lately.
And it would explain
the persistent nose bleeds.
But this app is
about convenience.
Dragging our customers
into the ED
cuts against the value
proposition, okay?
First rule of
customer service.
A satisfied customer
tells two people.
A dissatisfied one
tells 2,000.
I minored in econ,
Noah, I get it.
But surely,
what our customers want
above anything else
is to get better, no?
Of course...
Not to mention
if we suspect something
and don't test for it...
Talk about liability.
A brain-eating amoeba?
You really think
I might have this?
You didn't find me
a place to stay.
No. Not yet.
I'm gonna recommend
admitting you
for the night
if the pain in your
stomach doesn't subside.
My stomach's actually
feeling a little better.
If anyone asks, just
keep saying that it hurts.
Are you angry with me?
What? No... No. I just
want you to stay safe.
I'll, uh, I'll check
back in with you soon.
I... I have an idea.
I could stay at
your place tonight.
If you're worried
about me using,
then don't be.
I'm totally clean. I...
I could sleep on the couch,
or the floor, even.
You'd hardly even
know I was there.
Danny, I don't...
I get it. Never mind.
No, no.
You just, uh...
You caught me off guard.
No, please, I've seen
that look before.
You don't want someone
like me staying at your place.
I'm trash.
No.
The hospital has
strict policies
about doctor-patient
relationships,
and I'm just
a first-year resident.
I will figure
something out, okay?
Okay.
There you go.
Okay,
let's lift. Yep.
Don't move him like that.
If you want him more
upright, adjust the bed.
I'm sorry, Ms. Goodwin.
I'll do it myself.
I'm gonna go check on
the latest blood gas.
I've never seen
Goodwin like this before.
Nat, all I know is that
when Sharon was graduating
from high school,
Reggie came back from 'Nam.
They practically spent
the entire summer together.
It was her first real love.
So, why didn't it
work out?
Well, Reggie wanted her
to travel the world with him,
but Sharon was going
to college in the fall,
and then Bert came along
and there was just...
If you had listened
to me earlier, we wouldn't
be out of options.
I'm sorry,
Ms. Goodwin.
What's going on?
The infiltrate's
in Reggie's lungs.
Complete white out.
They're
barely functioning.
So, what do we do now?
Ms. Goodwin, the condition
his lungs are in,
there's very little
hope for recovery.
We should try to
make him comfortable.
What about ECMO?
I'm afraid all ECMO will do
is delay the inevitable.
I have been listening
to your advice all day,
and look where we are.
Ms. Goodwin, all due respect,
both Dr. Manning and I
are telling you that
it isn't gonna help.
Your concerns
are noted, Dr. Choi.
Put him on ECMO.
I can assign this case
to another doctor,
if you prefer.
Sharon.
We'll do it.
What?
We will put
Reggie on ECMO.
Call up to the ICU.
I'll take care of
the arrangements myself.
Thank you, April.
Yeah.
Hey, what did Dr. Halstead
order in there?
Er, CBC, metabolic panel,
urinalysis, sed rate
and a head CT.
Oh, man. Can...
Can we scale that back?
Or is there some kind of
employee discount
I'm eligible for?
It's not coming out
of your pocket, is it?
It's gonna come
out of somebody's.
Well,
talk to Will about it.
I already tried.
You know, why'd I think
it'd be a good idea
to hire my attending,
you know?
How am I gonna
be his boss
when he knows more
about medicine than I do?
It looks like he's
getting along with
your client really well.
We'll see.
I've gotta work on
my managerial skills.
Wait a second.
Is that...
Oh. Yeah.
Oh, yeah!
This is... This is huge...
Oh, no, what is he
up to now?
Oh, um...
Let's celebrate
later, okay?
Okay.
All right.
Oh!
Excuse me, sorry.
Oh, April, listen.
About earlier, sorry.
Don't worry about it.
Okay.
No, really.
It's not the first time
my mouth's gotten me
in trouble.
I shouldn't
have said anything.
I was just trying
to protect you.
I've had so long
to think about this,
and what Tate
and I have is real.
Well, okay.
In that case,
if you need anyone
to go dress shopping
with, I'm available.
Danny wants to
stay at your place?
Yeah.
I mean, makes
perfect sense, right?
I mean, now that
he's free of the traffickers,
there's this big void
in his life,
which he wants
to fill with you.
Obviously, it can't
be entertained.
Then again, rejecting
him now could
just be reinforcing
the abandonment issues
he's already feeling.
Wait.
Did you come here
to ask my permission?
The system's incapable
of keeping a roof
over his head.
We can't let him
sleep on the streets.
It's too dangerous.
It'd be just
for the one night.
Dr. Reese, having
a patient stay
in your home?
Maintaining
professional boundaries
is a fundamental part
of our work.
Again, to protect
both our patients...
I'm sorry, but I don't
see any other options.
Sarah.
Sarah!
Hey, does this look
like it'll fit Danny?
I guess. Listen,
about Danny...
Oh, could you
do me a favor?
See if they have
any extra blankets
in the store room,
I wanna take some home.
Where is he?
I'm sorry,
I tried to stop him,
but he was so desperate
to get out of here.
Did he say where
he was going?
Just said that
he was going back
where he belongs.
He's gone. I never
should have hesitated.
I knew
it wouldn't help
and so did you.
I figured we had
safety in numbers.
I know.
But if we'd had
an alternative plan
to save his life,
yeah, I would've
held firm with you.
But we didn't.
So, we tried
the Hail Mary.
And Goodwin knows
that we did everything
we could for her.
For her?
Goodwin's not our
patient, Reggie is.
Right now, he's suffering.
Best thing we could've
done for him
was to let him
die with dignity.
Ms. Goodwin?
You're here to
tell me my options.
I just wanted to know
if you needed anything.
No. I'm fine.
Okay.
What is it about
first love that just
sticks with you.
It's like...
It's like those last
40 years don't even exist.
One day, he's saying
goodbye to me,
and the next,
he's showing up
here on a gurney.
Reggie Dixon.
These machines
aren't gonna save him.
No.
Yeah.
Excuse me,
Ms. Goodwin?
I've collected
two signatures.
One from my attending,
Dr. Latham,
the other from Dr. Walters,
Director of Cardiology.
I don't care if
you have 200 signatures,
it doesn't change the fact
the patient is too impaired
to consent to
a high-risk surgery.
They were both
willing to sign
their names
to the opinion
that Pamela's
surgery is, indeed,
both urgent and necessary.
This is
a blatant end around.
It's just legal cover
to keep us all
from getting sued.
Am I actually the only person
who's got this girl's
best interest at heart?
Are you
sure the surgery
is the best course
of action?
Yes.
And you're confident
you can fix it?
I am.
Then go do it.
Thank you, Ms. Goodwin.
Mmm-hmm.
Wait, wait, wait.
Are you kidding me,
Sharon?
You're gonna let
a couple of surgeons
tell you who's
mentally competent?
I'm the chief psychiatrist
in the building.
It's a double doc.
That overrides you,
Daniel.
So, we're just
running this hospital
by majority rule now?
No, no, no. But after
the day I've had,
I'm wary of challenging
the collective wisdom
of our doctors.
Okay, okay.
So, let's just set
the law aside for now.
Are we abandoning
the ethical argument
altogether, as well?
It's done, Daniel.
If you want to file
a complaint, be my guest.
Mr. Kaplan,
Eliot, good news.
Test came back negative.
You don't have naegleriasis.
My brain's not being
eaten by an amoeba.
I guess that's
a good thing.
Yeah.
We're all about
customer satisfaction.
Okay, so all in,
it comes
to $2,134.68.
You told me
it would be $350.
Well, there was the,
uh, the blood panel...
Mmm-hmm.
Urinalysis, er, CT Scan.
It's all in our
terms and conditions.
Wait a minute.
You're upcharging me
for something
I don't even have.
Well, it's a good thing
we ran those tests.
We did find your
liver function markers
slightly elevated.
Now, a good excuse
to cut back on
your alcohol intake.
Now, you're telling me
I'm an alcoholic.
Just get me
out of here. Okay?
Um...
Would you like me to
email you the receipt?
See that?
Congratulations.
You just went anti-viral.
I didn't expect that.
I thought
he'd be relieved.
Yeah, uh, it's,
uh, it's hard.
Concierge patients.
You know, you were just
trying to be thorough.
Yeah, thanks. Listen,
Noah, I appreciate
the opportunity,
but maybe this
just isn't for me.
Really?
Yeah.
Damn, I'm sorry
to hear that.
If I'm leaving you
in a tight spot,
I can stay on until
you find someone...
Oh, no, no. I appreciate it,
but I think I can handle it.
Pamela?
Pamela Blake. How you doing?
I just came to see how
everything was going.
Much better, thank you.
Great. I'm really
glad to hear it.
I'm sorry, you are?
I'm Dr. Charles.
Daniel. We, um...
We met earlier today
when you got to the
hospital, you remember?
Oh, yeah. Right, yeah.
Yeah. Okay, well,
I'm happy to see
you're doing so well.
Glad to see she's
finally coming around.
Yeah.
We're gonna have to
agree to disagree on
this one, aren't we?
Yeah, we can just disagree,
too. That'd be all right.
Hey, Connor,
the lab ID'd the bacteria
from her infected valve.
Q fever?
Mmm-hmm.
She works on a dairy farm
down-state on weekends.
I'm heading down
to the cafeteria
to write up my report
for the health department.
If you're free, I was
hoping you might help me
fill in a few details.
Uh, yeah, I just have to
sign over a few patients.
I'll meet you
down there in 10?
Great.
You wanted to know
why I broke up
with my boyfriend.
He was too soft.
He rolled over every time
we had a fight.
But that guy,
though.
Anyway, I better
get downstairs.
See you later?
Are you ready?
Time of death, 20:53.
Hey, hear anything
from Detective Lindsay?
Not yet.
Hang in there.
The kid's a survivor.
PD will find him.
I'm not just gonna sit
around and do nothing.
What, you're gonna go
out looking for him?
Come on, Sarah,
it's a big city. Sarah.
Give me a minute.
I'll come with you.
He offered me
stock options.
Stock options?
And you turned him down?
Yeah, I know.
I'm kind of kicking
myself a little,
but it's not for me.
I'll figure out another
way to make some cash.
Or just save some.
How about you
move in with me?
Nina, come on.
I appreciate the offer,
but if I'm gonna
move in with you,
I don't want it to
be because of money.
It's not about
the money.
It's because I really think
this has a chance to work.
So, what do you say?
It's $8.50.
Thanks.
Thank you.
Let me give you a hand.
All right.
Hey, April, you okay?
You sure?
April, you're burning up.
Sorry.
All right, thank you.
Thank you.