So, who was that?
A housekeeper.
Leaving your place
at 7:00 in the morning?
I was interviewing her.
You're hiring a housekeeper
for a studio apartment?
I'm not hiring her. Her
clothes don't match.
Right.
You're such an
ass-hat, Shaun Murphy.
Today, we realize
a dream, seeing our
international humanitarian
program come to fruition.
Our cardiothoracic
surgeon Dr. Neil Melendez,
in consultation with our head
cardiologist Dr. Avi Mehta,
evaluated children from
Tanzania, to Malawi, to Guinea.
They screened over 100
candidates, each of them needing
life-saving surgeries.
Ultimately, we decided on
a particularly inspiring
young boy named Gabriel,
who hails from the
Democratic Republic of Congo,
with severe congenital
heart anomalies.
We identified three
perfect candidates,
children I can actually help.
Gabriel wasn't one of them.
Yes and no.
I signed off on your choices.
But I wouldn't have
necessarily eliminated Gabriel
based on the echo I saw.
A non-surgeon
undermining a surgeon on his
selection of
surgical candidates?
It's healthy when colleagues
challenge each other's decisions.
It doesn't make any sense.
We gave you good candidates.
You're not a doctor, why
wouldn't you stick with the list?
There were several intangibles.
Can you say hi to Dr. Melendez?
One of those intangibles,
I'm guessing, is cuteness.
Family displaced during the war.
Mother took care of her husband
until he died of yellow fever.
He bled out at home.
A month later Gabriel was born.
People tend to give more
when the cause is not only noble,
but photogenic.
Adorable kids and sympathetic
moms may work on donors,
but they won't work on me, and they
certainly won't work on echo results.
Kinda working on me.
Before you say no, at
least do your own work-up.
Mommy, why can't I come?
The hospital's worried
that children bring in germs.
I won't, Mommy, I promise.
Oh, Boo. It's just the rules.
Okay, baby, I have to go now.
Do what Aunt Maggie
says. I'll call you later, okay?
I love you to the moon.
And back.
Can't imagine voice rest could
be very easy with a 3-year-old.
Yeah. Not very effective for
my podcast audience either.
Of which, by the
way, I'm a huge fan.
Grim irony though, right? A
podcaster who loses her voice?
Elizabeth, I'm sure the
nodule will be benign,
and this'll be nothing
more than inspiration
for another great episode.
And if it's not benign, Isabel?
Let's not get ahead of ourselves.
Today we're just focused on removing
the nodule and doing the biopsy.
And you've done
everything you could do.
And when the hoarseness started,
you sought early
care from the best.
And I sent you to the best.
You work perfectly together,
kind of ping-and-pong-ish.
It's nice. A lot of doctors who are
married are more like Miss and Match.
Mrs. Bangura, this is
Dr. Murphy and Dr. Kalu.
They're gonna help me
run some tests on Gabriel.
I heard that you and Gabriel have
never been away from home before.
I was hoping that these
would make him feel welcome.
Yes. You are kind.
I brought one for myself, too.
Hey, how about we
all do some medicine?
He really needs our help.
"He needs our help"?
He sounds like he's got
a blow-dryer in his chest.
Exactly. Which is
why he needs our help.
This is the problem
with cardiologists.
You're really good at telling
people when something's broken,
not so good at knowing
when they can't be fixed.
If that kid is dying, I'm not
gonna tell his mother that
unless I'm damn sure.
You heard that heart.
I heard that heart, and
it sounded like crap.
But until we do a
transesophageal echo,
I don't know anything.
Do a transesophageal echo.
She has a master's degree in
sociology, impeccable credentials,
excellent references. And
you turned her away because
her clothes didn't match?
It's relevant. If a life
skills coach can't select
a complementing
wardrobe, they lack life skills.
But she's not gonna pick out your
clothes for you. She's not a nanny.
She's there to help you
with problem-solving,
financial, social interaction...
You're doing this
because I did not react well
to a man with a gun
robbing a store I was in.
Statistically, that is very unlikely
to ever happen to me again.
Social interactions will happen
again, and again, and again.
Statistically irrefutable.
Now, if you learn how to get
along with people a little bit better,
you'll have a fuller
life. A happier life.
If you don't like this woman,
we'll find somebody else.
I am happy.
- You could be happier.
- I don't think so.
My neighbor, Lea. If she were
ever in a fire, she'd be rescued first.
Why's that?
Dr. Melendez says attractive
people have advantages.
Dr. Melendez says that, does he?
Why is that funny?
I don't know. It's just some people
consider Dr. Melendez attractive.
So, how's it going with Lea?
She doesn't like me.
Why do you say that?
She said I was an ass-hat.
Yeah? What was she
doing when she said that?
Touching me.
She was flirting with you.
Sometimes people say the
opposite of what they mean.
They use teasing as a way of
saying something they don't mean,
instead of saying
something that they do.
I haven't seen any data on the use
of antonyms as a flirting technique.
Okay. Well, um,
here's what to look for.
- Are you ready?
- Yes.
Okay. The pretentious giggle.
The squirm.
And the hair sweep. I
call it the flirting trifecta.
Hair scuffing is used in both
animals and humans, Claire.
Secreting glands are
located in the scalp and fur.
Scuffing sends hormones
out into the environment
to let a potential mate
know they're interested.
Or it could be ringworm.
Yeah, I suppose you have
to factor for that possibility.
Nice touch.
Beauty increases happiness.
Happiness improves outlook.
Still on mission Carpe Diem?
You might wanna try it.
I'm doing fine.
We're having dinner at the sink.
No, we're enjoying dinner at
the sink. Although if you keep
talking like that...
Andrews. Well, look
again. It has to be there.
Yeah. Okay.
Who was that?
The lab. They misplaced
Elizabeth's specimen.
Oh, my God.
Don't worry, they'll find it.
Satisfied?
It's somewhere.
Somewhere else. I love how everyone
in surgery is so fast to blame the lab.
Well, double-checking
can't hurt.
Actually, it can. Because you
are here when you should be
double-checking surgery.
I saw the specimen
go in the container.
It means it has to be here.
No, all that means is that it was
put in a container. It doesn't mean that
that container was actually put
in the surgery refrigerator, or that it
was actually picked
up by the courier.
He's even worse than we thought.
Yeah. Hypertrophic obstructive
cardiomyopathy, atrial septal defect,
abnormal insertion of
the mitral valve leaflet.
I've never seen so many
anomalies in one heart.
I'm sorry I pushed
for additional testing.
That only got his
mother's hopes up.
Any medication that'll help?
Beta-blockers. Maybe metoprolol.
It's not like they'll get
him playing soccer,
but they might help him
get to the field to watch.
For a couple of years, anyway.
It's better than dying on the
table tomorrow. You tell Aoki.
I'll break it to the mom.
It's called sakara,
given by our shaman.
It's his heartbeat.
It follows the sound.
Reminds it to
beat until you fix it.
Mrs. Bangura, I've
completed all the tests.
And I'm sorry that
you've come this way.
When Gabriel was in my
belly, evil spirits came to him.
Invade his heart.
Our village shaman
tried to rid them.
He could not.
Then a vision came to him.
A stronger healer would come.
You.
You will save Gabriel.
I don't know about evil spirits.
All I know is that your son was
born with a heart that I can't fix.
I'm sorry.
Would not have come
so far if I did not believe.
We'll give him medicine
to make him feel better,
and then you can take him home.
We tell her we're sorry, we
have no news yet, and then...
Nope. Can't say that,
it's an expensive word.
Sorry?
You can act sorry,
you can feel sorry.
In fact, you should feel
sorry, you just can't say it.
Okay. I feel bad for you because
we made a mistake. And...
Nope.
A mistake isn't a mistake?
Well, it's an unanticipated
outcome of an expected action.
You can't use language that
implies blameworthy conduct.
But if we did lose the specimen,
isn't it actually a mistake,
and aren't we sorry, and
aren't we blame worthy?
Yes. Doesn't mean we can
make it any easier for her attorney.
Hello, Elizabeth. I'm Jessica Preston
from Risk Management. How are you?
I don't like the sound of that.
I know, I really
need a new job title.
It seems that we've encountered
an unexpected occurrence.
The laboratory has been unable
to locate your tissue specimen.
We don't want you to
be unnecessarily alarmed,
but we want you to be fully
aware of what's going on.
But how will I know if I have
cancer if you don't find it?
We are looking everywhere.
We will find it. As
long as it's in formalin
or a refrigerator,
everything will be fine.
For how long?
At least 24 hours,
maybe even 36.
Well, then you better find it.
Because I will be damned if I'm
gonna have my voice-box removed just
because somebody screwed up.
I've implemented a
proactive educational plan.
Well, that's terrific, Shaun.
Why are we talking
about that here?
I'm not stupid.
I didn't say you were stupid,
Shaun. Nobody said you were stupid.
But sometimes you lack common
sense. I'm so sorry to bother you...
This patient is deaf.
Oh.
I started flirting
lessons yesterday.
"Flirting lessons"? Wish they
had that when I was young.
Yes. I learned about
the flirting trifecta.
There's the
pretentious giggle...
Shaun, what are you getting at?
Flirting, it requires primarily
non-verbal interactions.
Being perceptive in one
social dimension translates well
to other social skills.
You're studying flirting?
Are you lonely, Shaun?
'Cause, you know, there are
websites now where you can...
I like being alone.
Yeah, well, being alone and
being lonely are two different things.
Sometimes we're lonely
and we don't even know it.
How would I know it?
Well, uh, loneliness,
it's kind of a dull...
It's like a dark...
Are you lonely?
Yeah, sometimes. You
know, sometimes, very much.
You should learn the trifecta.
Hey. Hey. We're looking for a
lost specimen that I am positive
left the OR.
And I'm positive it
didn't make it to the lab.
And since you're the
link between the two,
we wanted to ask you about
your 3:00 run yesterday.
So, you took everything that
was in the refrigerator in the OR.
In the refrigerator,
out of the refrigerator,
everything that's
meant to go, I took.
Did you stop on the way?
No. Straight from surgery to
the lab, just like the rules say.
Well, did you stop at the
restroom? Or the coffee machine?
The cafeteria?
Yeah, believe it or not, I can go a
whole 30 minutes without stopping
for a cream puff.
We're just desperate. All
we care about is the specimen
and avoiding a
full-on investigation.
Investigation?
Yeah. Yeah. If we don't find it, then
the legal department gets involved.
Everyone who was
in contact with it,
who might have
been in contact with it,
goes under a magnifying
glass. I'm not looking forward to it.
You looking forward to it?
She's not looking forward to it.
They're gonna check your
social media, your computer...
Blood tests.
But if you find
it before then...
Then life goes on,
same as it always has.
I did stop at the cafeteria.
The cashier is smokin'. I might
have been distracted for a little while.
Okay. Thanks.
Water.
Always more water.
Even more.
I know it's scary.
You are good with children.
You are father?
No. One day, I hope.
Page rapid-response team, stat.
The meds should've improved
his arrhythmia, not made it worse.
Maybe in addition
to his other problems
he's developed endocarditis.
His echo didn't reveal vegetations
on his valves or endocardium.
He has not developed a fever.
Let's be sure. Get blood cultures.
Order them times two, 15 minutes.
It's in the wrong place.
It was in the wrong place.
Okay. Times two,
15 minutes apart.
Hey. Um...
Leonard says that he
stops by here to see you.
Yeah, he pretends the
cafeteria's on his route.
Like I don't know
where the lab is.
Yesterday around 3:00, Gwen,
notice anything on the food trays
that wasn't food?
Around 3:00? Just the usual.
Uh, Tupperware, sunglasses,
cell phones, a condom.
Around 4:00, I
found a glass eye.
- See a biohazard bag?
- Uh...
- The Ziploc bag with the red circles?
- Yeah.
Come on.
You can move the mitral valve.
Thanks for the visual aid.
You can't move the mitral valve.
Now, if Mr. Potato Head had an
atrial septal nose and hypertrophy...
I believe the abnormal
insertion of the mitral valve
- can be...
- Stop.
Follow me.
Pretty sure I saw a biohazard
bag in here yesterday.
You're lucky you came when you
did, it's due to get dumped in two hours.
Ugh, dentures.
They're the worst.
You know, every patient gets a
denture cup with their name on it.
So tell me, why are the
dentures never in the cup?
And if they are,
it's the wrong cup.
One of life's mysteries?
Biohazard bag sighting.
A biohazard bag for
a coin purse? Really?
Finally, a septal myectomy
will open the outflow tract,
and the mitral valve
can be reimplanted
into a more normal position.
Thank you. That's my idea.
Can you do this
procedure on Gabriel?
No. It's a terrible
idea and it won't work.
So, what was the point of
this dog and pony show?
'Cause you seemed keen on
making medical decisions for me.
So just insubordination?
And we were probably gonna
wind up coming to you anyway.
Once Dr. Murphy gets
an idea, he stays with it,
regardless of what anyone says.
This can work.
Yes, this can work. And
it would be a great idea
if the boy had
two hours to live.
Is fear of failure a good
reason not to do this?
No. But you know what is?
The thought that he might
have a few more birthdays.
Or make a best friend.
I don't know. I'm not
sending him home in a box.
We gotta go. Gabriel's
arrhythmia, it's gotten worse.
You still haven't found it?
I can get Ms. Preston to
address any questions...
She wasn't in the
surgery, you were.
She's the point person for
all therapeutic misadventures.
Are you kidding me? I may lose
my voice for absolutely no reason,
and you're using canned jargon?
That sample cup
doesn't have toothpaste,
or socks, or sun block
in it, okay? It has my life.
I'm sorry.
Thank you.
Good for you.
Yeah, right. I just
broke about eight rules.
Maybe. Ms. Preston
won't hear about it from me.
You should go find
that sample, though.
Yes.
Meds aren't working.
The question is why.
Maybe the arrhythmia is
just another manifestation
of Gabriel's LV dysfunction.
We'd still be seeing at least a
modest decline in his ectopy.
Maybe his gradient is worse. We
could try calcium channel blockers.
There's a much
simpler explanation.
Good news about his
endocarditis, heart inflammation.
His tests are normal.
But we still are concerned.
For some reason, his
medication isn't helping.
Our best explanation is, he
hasn't been taking his medication.
I am trying to save his life.
By withholding his medicine?
By keeping him here.
If he takes the medicine
and becomes better,
you send him home to die.
But there is nothing else
that we can do for him here.
You do not understand
where I live, what it is like.
I don't know your village,
but I do know what
it's like to be poor.
I grew up with nothing.
My sister was disabled,
and my parents couldn't
afford her meds or treatments.
And it killed them, and me,
to watch her suffer.
But when nothing can be
done, nothing can be done.
You became a doctor?
You did not accept being poor.
No.
Then you do not
understand at all.
We want for everything.
Food, peace, medicine.
But our greatest want is hope.
If we leave here, we
leave hope behind.
Okay. I'll do what I can.
I dropped by to see Elizabeth.
Not surprisingly, she's very upset.
There wasn't much I could
offer in the way of comfort.
If only people did their jobs...
Which people?
Scrub nurses,
couriers, lab techs...
That's a curiously limited list.
I did the surgery correctly. I don't
think it's too much to expect others
to do their jobs
correctly as well.
So, not your fault,
not your problem.
What are you trying to
do, make me feel guilty?
Yes. I want you
to feel horrible.
It's the only thing that's
gonna make you change.
Into what?
The guy I married. The guy who
cared more about patients than politics.
Oh, okay, I get it.
This is about me vying
for president of the hospital.
Which we discussed
at length, which you said
you were 100
percent behind me on.
I didn't realize how far behind.
You think I've left you behind?
Hmm. Uh...
Tuesday. "Capital expenditures
meeting delayed. Will be late."
Wednesday. "Fund-raising
event ran over. Don't wait up."
- Thursday...
- Iz, there are things about my job...
Right. Not your fault.
Hello.
Hey.
Do you know that specimens
in formalin go to one place,
exempt specimens somewhere else,
aerobic and anaerobic
cultures two different places,
um, radioactive, medical device,
forensic specimens, all different,
and all handled by different
staff? Did you know that?
- Yes.
- Oh.
I made a chart, too.
A qualitative observation
log of what you taught me.
What did I teach you?
Flirting. Every time I saw
someone flirt, I noted it
and cross-referenced the subject,
object and non-verbal gestures.
I knew it.
Gwen the cashier.
She made out that it
was all the courier, but...
That's my name.
Yes, you made flirting gestures.
- No, I didn't.
- Yes, you did.
You brushed your hair back.
Right hand side-sweeping.
At Dr. Melendez?
No, I don't think so.
Shaun, no.
Yes. You were at the nurses'
station, and he said, "Good for you."
And you said, "Yeah, right. I just
broke about eight rules," and smiled,
and giggled, and
brushed your hair back.
Ms. Preston won't
hear about it from me.
It's possible you have ringworm.
Shaun, sometimes people toss
their hair just 'cause it's in their face.
Murphy, I'd like you to
elaborate on your idea.
My terrible idea?
That's the one.
You can move the anterior
leaflet of the valve and reattach it.
No, we can't. This is an
exact replica of the kid's heart.
There's no anchor
point to reattach it.
So, that part of your
idea? Still terrible.
Okay.
But the rest of it?
We're dealing with a huge
septum. It's 25 millimeters.
What would that number
be in a healthy kid?
About eight.
If we go anywhere
near that number,
it won't have enough
support for the valve.
But let's say we
took that down to 20.
And that won't be enough to
relieve the outflow obstruction.
Okay. Eighteen.
Okay.
Let's take him off bypass.
- He's dead.
- Again. Sixteen.
I'm really tired.
I used to think that I wanted to
be the best surgeon in history.
But my new goal is just not to
get washed out of my residency.
You have a surgery now?
No. I'm here to
see how I can help.
The chief of surgery
joining the search party?
Should I take a selfie?
Show my friends that
this really happened.
This is a team problem, it
should be a team solution.
How do you get a boss like this?
What do we know so far?
Let's take him off bypass.
His outflow is perfect
at 13 millimeters.
Which is irrelevant
when the mitral valve
doesn't have enough
support to close.
He's dead.
Again.
Dr. Browne.
Any reason you assumed
responsibility on behalf of the hospital?
Told Elizabeth you were sorry?
Because I was.
Well, I hope we don't
see the price tag on that.
And I think you're out of time.
Let's take him off bypass.
Yes.
Fourteen millimeters.
Exactly.
Yeah, exactly.
Our margin of error
is exceedingly low.
Good luck.
You believe in luck?
It's something people
say in difficult situations.
Neither do I. Again.
The reality is, even if we
found your specimen now,
it's unlikely it'd
still be viable.
You don't know if I have cancer
and there's no way to find out.
So my choices are
surgery I may not need,
that will leave me
without speech,
or I do nothing and maybe die.
Unfortunately, yes.
Oh
That ancient light, weigh
On your shoulders
And the river of time
Love is all that's left to lose
Lust, love, I'm
not alone anymore
This ancient light
This ancient light...
Knife.
Three hours, 30 minutes.
You didn't want him on bypass
any longer than five hours.
"Wynken and Blynken
are two little eyes.
"And Nod is a little head.
"And the wooden shoe
that sailed the skies,
"is a wee one's trundle bed.
"So shut your eyes
"while Mother sings."
How does it look, Dr. Murphy?
Fourteen millimeters. Exactly.
Perfect.
His septal tissue...
It's stiffer than I anticipated.
I don't think it's gonna be
enough for adequate outflow.
I'm taking the
septum down to 13.
Okay. The valve wasn't
supported at 13, the patient died.
That was a model, not a patient.
We're at five hours
and three minutes.
We're taking him down to 13.
Field.
All quiet for the time-out.
Patient is Elizabeth McLaren.
No known allergies. We'll
be doing a total laryngectomy
with a Gluck-Sorenson
U-shaped incision.
Is everyone in agreement?
Antibiotics in?
One gram of cefotaxime
has been infused.
We anticipate a specimen.
I've requested
labels be printed.
Pen?
Prepare to intubate.
Dentures.
You've gotta hold the surgery.
Uh, just give me a little time.
That's 13.
Damn it.
Too thin?
The valve doesn't
have adequate support.
It won't be able to close.
I was wrong.
Whoa, there's a
reattachment point.
We must not have seen it at 14
'cause it was obscured
by the subvalvular tissue.
We can use that as an anchor
point and move the valve.
Your terrible idea just got
a hell of a lot better. Stitch.
Five hours, 23 minutes.
Hey.
Dentures. They always
end up in the wrong cup,
which is why they're so
hard to get back to the owner.
Okay.
Right. What if the label on
the specimen was wrong?
What if the nodule is here,
but the container has
the wrong name on it?
I'm reconciling the operative records
to the surgery schedule to specimen.
I'll read the cases,
check the containers,
and feel like a
jerk for judging you.
Well, you're only
a jerk if I'm right.
Pump time?
Six hours, 48 minutes.
Get Mehta in here.
Let's take him off bypass.
Twelve seconds.
Should I get the paddles?
Not yet. Come on, Gabriel.
How long has he been on bypass?
Nearly two hours too long.
We need to jump start...
Not yet!
Yeah? Yes!
Dr. Murphy, close him up.
And I will hold you tight
Like the moon in
the arms of the sky
And I will keep you warm
I will build...
It's beating just
fine on its own.
And I'll build a fire,
you fetch the water
And I'll lay the table
And in our hearts, we still
pray for sons and daughters
Marcus.
And all those evenings out in
the garden, the red, red wine
These quiet hours
turning to years
There was a specimen cup
in the OR prior to your surgery.
It was supposed to be
used for a bullet removal,
but they left the
bullet in the body,
and the cup was used
accidentally for your specimen.
Not only was it in formalin,
but it was refrigerated
and fresh as a daisy.
Elizabeth, you
don't have cancer.
Thank you.
Doctor.
And I'll build a fire, you fetch
the water and I'll lay the table
And in our hearts, we still
pray for sons and daughters
Intangibles.
Hello.
I had a very good day today.
Yes, you did. That was
a hell of an operation.
Yes. And I caught
Claire flirting.
With you? Shaun, I
think you might be...
With Dr. Melendez.
Ah, Dr. Melendez.
I conducted observations,
successfully interpreted
them and logged them.
Romance in a
spreadsheet. I love it.
I was aware of the cues
even when Claire wasn't.
I think she needs
a life skills coach.
Extrapolating. I like that, too.
That's great, Shaun.
You're paying
attention, you're learning.
And when we find you a life
coach, one with a fashion sense,
then you're gonna be learning
better, you're gonna be learning faster.
Are you giving up on me?
What? No. I haven't
given up on you.
I don't want a
stranger helping me.
I know, Shaun, but...
And I can't, uh...
I can't always be there.
I can't always help you the
way you need to be helped,
the way you
deserve to be helped.
I don't want a
stranger helping me.
Congratulations.
You, too, on your
mad sleuthing skills.
Something to fall back on
if this surgery thing gets old.
- You did a nice job, Claire.
- Thanks.
And here is our price
tag. We've been served.
But we found it.
Elizabeth's fine.
I know. But we put her
through two days of hell
and she wants to make sure it
doesn't happen to anybody else.
I mean, good for her.
What is this?
Gabriel's pacemaker.
I heard you were
brilliant again today.
I got lucky.
Do you think Armen would
kill me if I got a pet hedgehog?
I mean, I read that
they're actually...
- Lea.
- Yes, Shaun?
You look absurd in that sweater.
I have apples. Do
you want an apple?
Yeah.